<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1864/pa.fr.vs.1864.10.12">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Amy Murrell</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/05/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 4/24/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1864-10-12">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="10">October</month>
            <day>12</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.10.12.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Speech of Hon. William Allen, of Ohio in the Chicago Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Rousing concluding speech from the Democratic Convention in Chicago
                    predicts that a Democratic administration will restore the Union and return the
                    nation to "happiness and prosperity."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 1-4; previously published political notices, columns
                5-6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.10.12.02">
            <div type="l">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>To the Officers of the Several Boards of Election of Franklin County</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>W. S. Stenger, Chairman of the Dem. County Ex. Com., and T. J. Nill,
                    Chairman of the Union County Ex. Com.</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stenger</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nill</ln>
                        <fn>T. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Party leaders request that the county boards of election count the votes
                    for Congress first on election night.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Way to Peace</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that the only way to peace is through the restoration of the Union,
                    not through the abolition of slavery.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>How They Talk</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"By this sort of bamboozling they manage to make dupes of a certain class
                    of brainless boobies, who never think for themselves, but gulp down as gospel
                    all the twaddle the unprincipled placehunters of this unprincipled party blurt
                    out on every stump they mount."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Says that the unfulfilled Republican campaign promises of 1860 are an
                    "insult" to the American people.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Says that the Repository misquoted the Valley Spirit in an article about
                    the Pennsylvania legislature. Points out that the Valley Spirit called it an
                    "Abolition legislature," not a "Union legislature."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Every Man to His Post</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Reelect Abraham Lincoln for another term of four years and you sign the
                    death warrant of your liberties."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Suggests that the upcoming election will determine the future of popular
                    government in the United States.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Spurious Tickets</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Warns readers that "spurious tickets" for the election are circulating
                    around town.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Facts for the People</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Vote against the corrupt Abolition party, which bestows all its sympathy
                    on the negro and squanders the people's money in his behalf whilst the
                    unprotected white citizens of the border are left to suffer in penury and want."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Says that the US government is spending $30,000,000 per year to aid freed
                    blacks, while only giving Chambersburg residents $100,000 to help recover from
                    the fire.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Signs of Fraud</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Accuses Republicans of resorting to fraud in order to carry the November
                    election. Cites the movement of troops into "doubtful districts" as evidence
                    that the Republicans will force their victory.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Richmond Enquirer for Lincoln</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that the Richmond Enquirer's support for Lincoln, whose "irrational
                    and pernicious policy" helped unite the Southern people, is good reason why
                    Northern voters should go with McClellan.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>White Men Read! Negroes for the Forge, the Workshop and the Social Circle! The
                    Next Step--Negroes at the Ballot Box</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"What will be the next step, when Labor has been reduced to the negro
                    standard of cheapness, and the poor whites shall be compelled to consort with
                    the blacks as their equals? Why MISCEGENATION."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Negroes For The Forge, The Workshop And The Social Circle! <lb/>The Next
                        Step--Negroes At The Ballot Box! <lb/>Black and Yellow the National Colors
                        of the New Abolition Republic--and the Red, White and Blue Nowhere!</p>
                    <p>A grand saturnalia of the Shoddyites of Pittsburg [sic] was held in that city
                        on Thursday last. We take the following from the report of the procession as
                        published in the <emph rend="italic">Dispatch</emph>:</p>
                    <p>"A wagon drawn by nine horses and filled with colored men brought up the
                        rear. The procession passed along the route as published, and halted on the
                        West Common."</p>
                    <p>Does not this show the strongly increasing desire of the Shoddy party to make
                        voters of negroes? Why should they be honored with a place in a procession
                        of <emph rend="italic">voters</emph>--in the ranks of a party making a
                        display of its strength for the <emph rend="italic">ballot box?</emph> They
                        were not put there as <emph rend="italic">ornaments</emph>--they certainly
                        added no grace to the display. They could only have been given a place among
                        white men as <emph rend="italic">symbols</emph> of the manner in which the
                        war for the Union has been prostituted to the elevation of the black race,
                        or as indicating a design on the part of the Shoddy miscegenationists to
                        share with negroes the amenities of the social circle and all the rights at
                        the ballot box. No man who cares for the future of his country, and detests
                        the hybridizing contemplated by such elevation of an antagonistic race can
                        fail to understand the placing of negroes in a Repu[b]lican procession
                        alongside of <emph rend="italic">Voters!</emph></p>
                    <p>But more. From the same report we clip the following. Read it, white Laborers
                        and Mechanics of the North! "Oliver Adams' blacksmith shop of South
                        Pittsburg followed. A forge, worked by colored men, was kept in operation on
                        this vehicle."</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Here is the destiny of Northern Labor,
                        foreshadowed!</emph> Negroes To Work The Forges! Negroes To Take The Place
                        Of White Men Who Are Killed In This "War For The African And His Race." And
                        To Fill The Work Shops Of The North!--White Men, <emph rend="italic">do you
                            understand the</emph> Symbol? <emph rend="italic">Negroes working a
                            forge upon a wagon in a Republican procession</emph> Means That Negroes
                        Shall Take Your Place In The Field Of Labor--Reduce The Wages Of Labor,
                            <emph rend="italic">and take the bread from your children's
                        mouths!</emph></p>
                    <p>The Shoddy party have declared that <emph rend="italic">"the war is for the
                            Africans and his race"--that "the war shall not cease till slavery is
                            destroyed"</emph>--and, while our brave soldiers, the <emph
                            rend="italic">laborers and mechanics of the North, are bravely shedding
                            their blood for the</emph> Union--<emph rend="italic">Shoddy supporters
                            of Lincoln are filling their places of labor at home with</emph> Negroes
                        and are <emph rend="italic">preparing to offer them the right of suffrage on
                            perfect equality with and to control the votes of those same gallant
                            white soldiers should they be spared to return home</emph>.</p>
                    <p>What will be the next step, when Labor has been reduced to the negro standard
                        of cheapness, and the poor whites shall be compelled to consort with the
                        blacks as their equals? Why Miscegenation--the Shoddy hope and prayer--<emph
                            rend="italic">is what is to follow</emph>.</p>
                    <p>White men! Laborers! Mechanics! Can you vote for Abe Lincoln--knowing these
                        designs of the party whose candidate he is? No, <emph rend="italic">you
                            cannot!</emph> You will prove false to <emph rend="italic"
                            >yourselves--to your homes--to your children, and to your
                        posterity</emph> if you do! Vote for McClellan and all the Democratic
                        candidates, and Forever crush this <emph rend="italic">hideous, damnable
                            negro mania!</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Says that the placement of blacks alongside voters in a Republican
                    procession in Pittsburgh foreshadows what will happen to Northern society if the
                    slaves are freed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coffroth</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>General</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Says the Repository is wrong to suggest that congressional candidate
                    General Coffroth had nothing to do with making it possible for conscripts to
                    report in their own counties.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koontz</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>General</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Accuses congressional candidate General W. H. Koontz of carrying around a
                    woman's petticoat in case he is ordered into service and wants to hide.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharpe</ln>
                        <fn>J. McDowell</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mitchell</ln>
                        <fn>William S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Says than any man who favors government compensation for the victims of the
                    Chambersburg fire should vote for J. McDowell Sharpe and William S. Mitchell for
                    the state assembly.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Lincoln Offers to Give McClellan the Highest Command in the Army!!!</head>
                <origin>Lancaster Intelligencer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Accuses Lincoln of trying to buy off McClellan for the presidency by
                    offering him the command of any army he wants or by promising to use his
                    influence to help McClellan win the 1868 election.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stenger</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kimmell</ln>
                        <fn>F. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that the county's Democrats have demonstrated an "unwavering" zeal
                    in attending recent meetings. Notes that W. S. Stenger, Esq. and F. M. Kimmell
                    have addressed each of the meetings.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Calls the Repository's allegation that Confederate Generals Lee and Early,
                    as well as President Davis, support McClellan a "lie."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Says that any voter who wants to see the Union restored and the rights of
                    the people protected should vote Democratic.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Reason Why</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharpe</ln>
                        <fn>J. McDowell</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mitchell</ln>
                        <fn>William S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>A. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Argues that a distrust in Colonel A. K. McClure is why the Pennsylvania
                    legislature opposed giving Chambersburg relief money. Suggests that voters
                    choose J. McDowell Sharpe and William S. Mitchell instead to represent Franklin
                    County in the future.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>To the Polls</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges Democrats to work "unceasingly" to make sure everyone makes it to the
                    polls in the upcoming election.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"He must lately have had a confidential interview with the incendiary
                    McCausland, as he informs the people that he (McCausland) would be willing to
                    burn another town in order to secure the election of the Democratic ticket."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Calls the Repository editor a "dangerous man," and suggests that he has
                    been consorting with Confederate generals since he knows so much about their
                    thoughts and future plans.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Rich Against Poor</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Poor men! who under this Lincoln dynasty have to pay enormous prices for
                    everything, what do you think of this Abolition argument against McClellan, now
                    that winter with its piercing blasts is coming rapidly on?"</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Appeals to "poor men" by pointing out that Republicans in Schuylkill County
                    have called on rich coal operators to oppose McClellan, since his nomination has
                    brought down the price of coal.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Democrats Beware!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Warns readers that Republicans are trying to win by distributing
                    "Democratic" tickets with the names of Republican candidates written on them.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nill</ln>
                        <fn>T. Jefferson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Suggests that T. Jefferson Nill, an outspoken abolitionist, change his name
                    to T. Lincoln Nill.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cessna</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kimmell</ln>
                        <fn>Francis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Points out that John Cessna, who has criticized Judge Kimmell for changing
                    parties once a judicial vacancy opened up, also switched parties after the
                    Democrats failed to nominate him for governor of Pennsylvania.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Accuses the Repository editor of facilitating General Sheridan's losses in
                    the Valley by feeding information to Confederate generals.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Previously published political news, column 1</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.10.12.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Another Abolition Gathering</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cessna</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports on a Republican meeting in Chambersburg last Thursday and chastises
                    the featured speaker, Hon. John Cessna, for denouncing the Democratic party (of
                    which he was formerly a member).</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Tells readers that voting in next Tuesday's election will fulfill their
                    duty to their country.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Thanks the Valley Spirit's Democratic friends for helping the paper to
                    reconstruct its files of old issues.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Republican Delusions</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lists twenty "delusions" under which Republican leaders are operating,
                    including the belief that "every campaign [is] to be the last."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>"To Whom it May Concern"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Juxtaposes two essays written by Lincoln from March 4, 1861, and July 9,
                    1864. The former includes Lincoln's disavowal of any attempt to abolish slavery,
                    and the latter shows how Lincoln changed to later support the abandonment of
                    that institution.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Previously published political notices, column 2; political poetry, column 3;
                classified ads, columns 3-7</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.10.12.04">
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 1-7</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
