<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1864/pa.fr.vs.1864.07.06">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Amy Murrell</taggerName>
            <tagDate>10/21/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 4/22/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1864-07-06">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day>6</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.07.06.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Exclusive Loyalty</head>
                <origin>Age</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Chastizes Lincoln for suggesting that only those men who vote for him are
                    truly "loyal" to the Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Slow</head>
                <origin>Journal of Commerce</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Defends General McClellan against criticism that he was "slow" when he was
                    in command.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>'Horrid War'--The Dead in the Wilderness</head>
                <origin>Rochester Democrat</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prints letter from a New York soldier that describes the carnage he saw in
                    the Wilderness after the battle there.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Rebels Endorse Lincoln and Johnson. They Chuckle Over Their Nomination</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that Richmond newspapers have been applauding the renomination of
                    Lincoln and have suggested that Lincoln has made the South "the most united
                    people ever."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Another Abolition Rascal</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on more Republican leaders who have been charged with fraud and
                    other crimes of corruption.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>No Commutation Hereafter</head>
                <origin>New York Herald</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"It is not to be disguised that the whole country is thoroughly alarmed and
                    disgusted at these incessant calls for more soldiers."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Criticizes the recent congressional vote to eliminate commutation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Poetry, column 1</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.07.06.02">
            <pageNote>Poetry and fiction, columns 1-4; classified ads, columns 5-6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.07.06.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Patriotic Gardening</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"There are few gardens so small that they will not afford something which
                    will be acceptable to the boys who are sick or wounded. They long for home
                    comforts, and a thing tastes all the better if it is 'just as mother used to
                    make it.'"</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges readers to plant a few more vegetables to send to sick and wounded
                    soldiers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 2-6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.07.06.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Deceiving the People</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"They effected to despise the courage of the South, underrated her
                    resources, told the people the war would be a mere breakfast job for the
                    North--that the Southern people were all cowards and would run at the firing of
                    the first gun. We well remember when it was considered treason in our own town
                    to say that the South would fight, and the man who was rash enough to go upon
                    the streets and let an expression of that kind drop from his lips, stood in the
                    greatest danger of being lynched."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The systematic efforts so unceasingly made by the leaders of the Republican
                        party to deceive the people are utterly inexcusable and disgraceful. The
                        practicing of deception and fraud seems to be their trade. Ever since the
                        commencement of the war they have been only too successful in playing upon
                        the credulity of the people and misleading the public mind in reference to
                        the real condition of the country. These men, who are as bad as they are
                        bold, and as corrupt as they are ambitious, by artful devices and unblushing
                        falsehoods, have thus far been pretty successful in duping and misleading
                        the honest, unsuspecting masses of the country, by which means they have
                        been able to carry out their wicked schemes of personal ambition and
                        self-aggrandizement to the almost total ruin of the country.</p>
                    <p>At the beginning of our troubles they treated the matter lightly, as of very
                        little account. They effected to despise the courage of the South,
                        underrated her resources, told the people the war would be a mere breakfast
                        job for the North--that the Southern people were all cowards and would run
                        at the firing of the first gun. We well remember when it was considered
                        treason in our own town to say that the South would fight, and the man who
                        was rash enough to go upon the streets and let an expression of that kind
                        drop from his lips, stood in the greatest danger of being lynched. He at
                        least would have been <emph rend="italic">threatened</emph> with a rope.
                        This was all the result of the deception practiced on the masses of the
                        Republican party by their leaders.</p>
                    <p>The announcement, by Secretary Seward, that the war would be over in sixty or
                        ninety days, is still fresh in the memory of all who take any interest in
                        the affairs of the country; and we remember distinctly of hearing the
                        present chief editor of the <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph> make the
                        safe remark in the summer of 1861, when Patterson's army was lying in the
                        vicinity of Charleston, Va., that if Gen. Fremont had been placed in command
                        of the column instead of Patterson he would have been in Richmond before
                        then! Nothing was too absurd for them to believe, or affect to believe; and
                        no falsehood was too great for them to attempt to palm off on the people as
                        truth. Mr. Seward's sixty or ninety days have rolled into the past more than
                        a dozen times since the prediction was uttered, and the war still rages with
                        unabated fury. General Fremont was subsequently placed in command of a
                        column in Virginia, but did not get much nearer Richmond than Patterson. So
                        much for latter-day prophets.</p>
                    <p>One would naturally suppose that by this time the most credulous would be
                        convinced that the age of prophets had gone by. But not so. Thousands there
                        are who still permit themselves to be deluded by the absurd prognostications
                        of unprincipled demagogues, and who still look for the suppression of the
                        rebellion at the end of every sixty or ninety days. Experience is a dear
                        school, but fools will learn in no other, says the old adage; but republican
                        fools will not even learn in this, dear as it is.</p>
                    <p>Before the last State election in Pennsylvania, the people were assured that
                        the rebellion was "on its last legs," that the war was well nigh over, that
                        all that was yet needed was for the people to sustain the administration
                        once more by voting for Curtin, and the thing would be closed out. There
                        would be no more men called for, and very little, if any, fighting to be
                        done, provided the people would vote for Curtin. "Vote For Curtin and Save
                        the Draft," was the rallying cry. Well, the people deliberately walked into
                        the snare that was set for them. They <emph rend="italic">did</emph> vote
                        for Curtin, and three days after they had deposited their ballots, to wit,
                        on the 17th day of October, 1863, to their utter amazement, they read in the
                        newspapers, a proclamation from "father Abraham" calling for "300,000 more"
                        men to suppress a rebellion, which they, in the simplicity of their hearts,
                        supposed they had dispatched with their votes. But it did not stop here. A
                        little later 200,000 more were called for; and a little later still, again
                        200,000 more, making the enormous aggregate of 700,000 men wanted by this
                        administration, to end a war which the people had been assured was
                        substantially ended prior to the second Tuesday of last October. But
                        notwithstanding the magnitude of the call, the people went to work with a
                        will to raise the men. large local bounties were paid by the several
                        sub-districts, in addition to the United States bounty, to obtain volunteers
                        to fill their respective quotas, and thus avoid the draft altogether. Many
                        of the districts were entirely successful; others were nearly so.</p>
                    <p>To stimulate volunteering, and to encourage the people to bear patiently the
                        heavy drain upon their resources, they were told by the administration
                        leaders that this would positively be the last call that would be made upon
                        them for men; that the war would certainly be brought to a close early in
                        the spring, and that the government simply wanted so large a number of men
                        for the purpose of making assurance doubly sure. The idea was to frighten
                        the South into submission by overwhelming numbers. Even our neighbor, the
                            <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph>, assured us that the war would
                        end, without fail, in the spring campaign, "perhaps without another great
                        battle."</p>
                    <p>How have the predictions and assurances of these imposters [sic] been
                        verified? Let the recent bloody campaign of General Grant from the banks of
                        the Rapidan to the fortifications of Petersburg, and the repeal of the $300
                        commutation clause in Congress, with another remorseless conscription in
                        prospect, afford the answer.</p>
                    <p>How long will the people continue to be deceived by these monstrous political
                        quacks and humbugs? How long will they permit themselves to be deluded on to
                        their ruin? Under the policy of the present Administration, this war <emph
                            rend="italic">can never end!</emph> Their <emph rend="italic"
                        >policy</emph> precludes the possibility of such a result. It is against the
                        law of reason, of human nature, and of God. From the very nature of the case
                        the war must be interminable.</p>
                    <p>If the people want peace they must go back to the principles of common sense
                        from which they have departed. They must hurl from power this imbecile,
                        wicked and corrupt administration. They must elect Statesmen to preside over
                        the destinies of the nation instead of buffoons. Then they may expect to
                        obtain peace and a restored Union, and not until then.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Accuses the Republican party of spreading falsehoods and generally
                    deceiving the people into thinking that the North will win the war easily.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Questions the Repository's accusation that the Valley Spirit is a "partisan
                    journal" by suggesting that the Repository is hardly an independent journal
                    itself.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Rights of the Government</head>
                <origin>World</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The whole Republican press seems to labor under the delusion that in a war
                    all the civil functions of officials exist only by the sufferance of an
                    administration."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that the war is not an excuse for the President and his government
                    to assume dictatorial powers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>(No Title)</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt> "The <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph> is a very fair paper. It is so
                    fair that it wouldn't misrepresent an opponent for the world. It is also very
                    honorable. We do not think it could be bribed into doing a dishonorable act. It
                    is likewise very truthful. It would rather cut off its right hand than tell a
                    falsehood." </excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph> is a very fair paper. It is so fair
                        that it wouldn't misrepresent an opponent for the world. It is also very
                        honorable. We do not think it could be bribed into doing a dishonorable act.
                        It is likewise very truthful. It would rather cut off its right hand than
                        tell a falsehood. In addition to this it is extremely honest. It would never
                        be guilty of <emph rend="italic">publicly</emph> advocating the claims of a
                        buffoon to the Presidency, whilst <emph rend="italic">privately</emph>
                        entertaining the opinion that "he is not the man for the crisis." In short
                        the <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph> is a paragon of fairness,
                        honorableness, truthfulness and honesty! In proof of which we need only
                        refer to the assertion in its last issue that "the Spirit denounces
                    Grant."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Sarcastically suggests that the Repository is "honorable" and "very fair"
                    to be supporting Lincoln for President even as it privately doubts his fitness
                    for the job.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Evils of Party</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Accuses Republican newspapers of "hypocrisy" for speaking out against the
                    danger of political parties and factions.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Suggests that the Repository has never written anything "profound."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Wonders if Lincoln is involved in "shoddy" businesses since he seems to
                    have money even though he claims he is not drawing a salary as president.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Caesar, Sambo and Pompey</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"It is scarcely possible to take up a newspaper in the interest of Lincoln
                    and Johnson which does not contain grandiloquent spread eagle flourishes about
                    the black troops, and comparisons disparaging to our white veterans. Of course
                    there is a reason for all this. Soon it is hoped to extend the right of suffrage
                    to 'American citizens of African descent,' and that party which has been
                    foremost in laudation of charcoal, and has gone farthest in advocacy of the
                    'divine commingling of races' will be most likely, it is thought, to get the
                    votes of Caesar, Sambo and Pompey."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>There is a class of people among us who affected to believe that negro
                        soldiers could never be made to fight, and they still pretend to have a
                        contempt for their fighting qualities. But in the Department of the South
                        they have acquitted themselves nobly under circumstances the most trying.
                        They have won imperishable honors at Port Hudson, in Florida, and at
                        Petersburg; and there also comes a highly flattering account of their heroic
                        courage and patient endurance in the fight at Guntown, under the unfortunate
                        Gen Sturgis, who seems to have been, as Western journals have it, "either
                        drunk or crazy." A despatch from Memphis stated that the <emph rend="italic"
                            >black soldiers</emph>, who came into Memphis after the defeat of Gen.
                        Sturgis, brought their guns with them, while the white ones left theirs
                        behind. If we should "give the, ---well, we will not offend ears polite by
                        naming him--"his due," then surely, we can afford to render to Caesar, Sambo
                        and Pompey all the honors to which they are justly entitled.--<emph
                            rend="italic">Philadelphia News</emph>.</p>
                    <p>The above indicates the probable amount of consideration the Lincolnites have
                        for our white soldiers in general. It is scarcely possible to take up a
                        newspaper in the interest of Lincoln and Johnson which does not contain
                        grandiloquent spread eagle flourishes about the black troops, and
                        comparisons disparaging to our white veterans. Of course there is a reason
                        for all this. Soon it is hoped to extend the right of suffrage to "American
                        citizens of African descent," and that party which has been foremost in
                        laudation of charcoal, and has gone farthest in advocacy of the "divine
                        commingling of races" will be most likely, it is thought, to get the votes
                        of Caesar, Sambo and Pompey. Shoddy will do anything for a little brief
                        authority and a large slice of plunder. The following exaggerations of the
                        Sturgis affair are from other shoddy organs, which read and blush for your
                        poor white relations:</p>
                    <p>"The colored troops were the last to give way." "The negro troops gathered
                        ammunition from the cast away accoutrements of the white troops, and thus
                        were enabled to keep up the fight until they reached Memphis." "One body of
                        1,600 (white) infantry which were cut off and supposed to have been
                        captured, were defended by 200 negro troops from the repeated assaults of
                        the rebel cavalry." "Another body of negro troops came in (to Memphis)
                        having escaped by various roads. All brought their arms and accoutrements
                        with them."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Wonders what will come next after black men prove themselves to be good
                    soldiers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Dispatch from Kentucky, column 5-6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.07.06.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Rebel Invasion</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"It was also, we are informed, the determination of Gen. Couch to put the
                    town under martial law and compel every man to take up arms and defend his home.
                    This course would have been approved by every loyal citizen, or man of spirit,
                    in the place. Those skulking cowards who fly on the first sound of approaching
                    danger, but whose 'voice is still for war,' and who preach up 'extermination,'
                    would thus have been afforded a fine opportunity to put their doctrines into
                    practice."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On Sunday afternoon intelligence reached General Couch's headquarters, at
                        this place, that a considerable force of Confederates were moving down the
                        Shenandoah Valley. This was about the sum and substance of the dispatch but
                        as soon as it was made known it assumed every shape that the active
                        imaginations of our people could possibly give it, and created a terrible
                        state of excitement in the community. Our merchants at once commenced
                        packing their goods. The Railroad shops were stripped of their machinery and
                        everything valuable about the premises put aboard the cars. Our streets soon
                        began to fill up with wagons, drays, carriages and wheelbarrows moving in
                        all directions while the side-walks were blocked up with dry goods,
                        groceries and merchandize of every description in readiness for
                        transportation. The exodus of the farmers with their stock soon set in and
                        through Sunday night until noon on Monday it was one continuous stream of
                        horses, mules, cattle and negroes moving in the direction of the
                        Susquehanna. An army wagon train with a large lot of horses from the camp
                        about Hagerstown passed through early on Monday morning. The rebels would
                        have found but little material for plunder between the Potomac and the
                        Susquehanna had they concluded to come over. They, however, would have found
                        one thing that they have not met with on their previous marauding
                        excursions. Every step of their advance down this valley would have been
                        resisted and met with a force they little expected to find here. Gen. Couch
                        on being apprised of their advance made ample preparations to meet and check
                        it effectually. A battery of artillery with a force of infantry and cavalry
                        were brought here so quickly and so quietly that our citizens were as much
                        astonished to find it here as the rebels would have been had they run
                        against it. It was also, we are informed, the determination of Gen. Couch to
                        put the town under martial law and compel every man to take up arms and
                        defend his home. This course would have been approved by every loyal
                        citizen, or man of spirit, in the place. Those skulking cowards who fly on
                        the first sound of approaching danger, but whose "voice is still for war,"
                        and who preach up "extermination," would thus have been afforded a fine
                        opportunity to put their doctrines into practice. It also afforded us much
                        gratification to see the efforts of Gen. Couch promptly seconded by a number
                        of our citizens who had formerly been in the military service. They issued a
                        call, with their names attached, for the formation of companies for "Home
                        Defence," and were very active in their exertions to make all needful
                        preparations to meet the expected invasion. We hope to see this spirit kept
                        up for although the excitement is over the danger may not be passed. We must
                        do something to put an end to the disgrace of skedaddling for which our
                        people are becoming so noted on every idle rumor of a rebel raid.</p>
                    <p>All is quiet here at the present writing. The excitement and alarm has passed
                        from the minds of the people and business has been resumed and going on as
                        formerly. Many of the farmers have already returned with their stock and
                        commenced harvesting again as if nothing had happened to interrupt it. We
                        have many conflicting rumors in circulation as to the whereabouts of the
                        rebels but the general belief is that we are in no great danger of either a
                        raid or an invasion in force at this time.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Discusses the alarm that resulted from indications that Confederate troops
                    were moving down the Valley.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Another Accident</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fitzpatrick</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strock</ln>
                        <fn>Jonathan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that Michael Fitzpatrick lost a foot in a mower accident on
                    Jonathan Strock's farm.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Sanitary</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges readers to keep their premises clean and asks that municipal
                    officials do something about filthy streets.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>An Item for the Ladies</head>
                <origin>Patriot and Union</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We saw one of these respectable Dorothy Draggletails promenading Market
                    street, the other day, with a silk train fit for a Duchess in the royal 'drawing
                    room,' sweeping upon the pavement, and, by way of descant at once upon the
                    wasteful extravagance and the folly of the age, dragging after them the wreck of
                    a three-story bonnet and of a double breasted hoop skirt which had been thrown
                    into the street, and which had become entangled in the fine lady's finery. The
                    wearer of the train had no suspicion of the real state of affairs, and she strut
                    along like a peacock with his tail spread, fondly imagining that the sensation
                    she was creating was a tribute to her stunning make-up."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>While the ladies throughout the country are forming dress covenants, and
                        pledging themselves not to purchase or wear any article of foreign luxury
                        during the continuance of the war, a co[n]temporary suggests whether it
                        would not be well for them to start another movement, looking not to the
                        prevention of the use of rich materials, but to the prevention of their
                        abuse and waste. With all due deference to the gentler sex, there is still
                        no disguising the fact that some of the present fashions are ridiculous; and
                        sinfully ridiculous, because they are scandalously wasteful. While a silk
                        dress on the back of a woman is an elegant and becoming article of attire,
                        (and the ladies, themselves, say a rather economical one,) the case is
                        widely altered when the costly fabric is made to sweep the sidewalk and to
                        perform a sort of small scavengering. It is no unusual circumstance to see
                        ladies of extravagant tastes not only dragging a yard or two of silk after
                        them upon the pavement, having the bottom of their skirts adorned with lace
                        or quilling, (we believe they call it,) or some other costly gimerackery, to
                        entangle the feet of passers-by, cause dislocations of "gathers," damage to
                        dress and temper, promote unpardonable waste, and add to the general
                        dirtiness. We saw one of these respectable Dorothy Draggletails promenading
                        Market street, the other day, with a silk train fit for a Duchess in the
                        royal "drawing room," sweeping upon the pavement, and, by way of descant at
                        once upon the wasteful extravagance and the folly of the age, dragging after
                        them the wreck of a three-story bonnet and of a double breasted hoop skirt
                        which had been thrown into the street, and which had become entangled in the
                        fine lady's finery. The wearer of the train had no suspicion of the real
                        state of affairs, and she strut along like a peacock with his tail spread,
                        fondly imagining that the sensation she was creating was a tribute to her
                        stunning make-up. We thought of Burns' fine lady at church, with a louse
                        promenading upon her bonnet, and of the familiar lines suggested thereby:</p>
                    <p>"O wad some power the giftie gie us,</p>
                    <p>To see ourselves as others see us."</p>
                    <p>We like to see a woman dress elegantly, and have no objection to her dressing
                        as costly as her means will afford; but we do think that silk is too
                        expensive a material to be used for street cleaning purposes; and further,
                        that the ladies should leave that occupation to the homes when employed by
                        the City Fathers. It is the wasting and not the wearing of silk dresses that
                        is sinful.--<emph rend="italic">Patriot and Union</emph>.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Calls some of the latest women's fashions "scandalously wasteful."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Another Victim</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Washinger</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Washinger was robbed of sixty dollars at the train depot yesterday
                    morning.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Official Corruption</head>
                <origin>Chicago Tribune</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Tribune, a Republican newspaper, tells of several recent acts of
                    corruption on the part of Union officers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>P. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fulker</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Knisely</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. P. S. Davis married William A. Fulker and Rebecca S. Knisely on June
                    25.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dyson</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Briggs</ln>
                        <fn>J. Clemson</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rhoads</ln>
                        <fn>Helen S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. F. Dyson married J. Clemson Briggs, Esq., of Philadelphia, and Helen
                    S. Rhoads on July 4.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCullom</ln>
                        <fn>B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carson</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mullan</ln>
                        <fn>Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. B. McCullom married Robert Carson and Ann Mullan on June 28.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 4-6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.07.06.06">
            <pageNote>Dispatches from Petersburg, Virginia, Georgia, Maryland, and Arkansas, columns
                1-3, classified ads, columns 4-6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.07.06.07">
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 1-6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.07.06.08">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Army of the Potomac</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"All the track was composed of strap iron, placed upon wooden supports. The
                    one destroyed the other, as the track was torn up and placed upon the wooden
                    sleepers and burned until it was bent and useless. A locomotive and train of
                    cars were surprised at one station, and before the engineer could move off, all
                    were in the hands of our men."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Wilson's Cavalry at Ream's Station--Their Retreat cut off.</p>
                    <p>Near Petersburg, June 23, 11 P.M.</p>
                    <p>A large body of rebel cavalry that moved around our left is now at Ream's
                        Station, on the Petersburg and Weldon Railroad.</p>
                    <p>General Wilson's 3d Division of cavalry passed this place a few days ago, en
                        route for the Danville and Richmond Railroad. They were too slow, and Wilson
                        reached the road, destroying many miles of track before he retraced his
                        steps, meeting no opposition until he neared the point from which he
                        started.</p>
                    <p>All the track was composed of strap iron, placed upon wooden supports. The
                        one destroyed the other, as the track was torn up and placed upon the wooden
                        sleepers and burned until it was bent and useless. A locomotive and train of
                        cars were surprised at one station, and before the engineer could move off,
                        all were in the hands of our men. The cars were crowded with refugees from
                        Petersburg. All the cars, with the locomotive were destroyed. Having
                        accomplished his work in a most successful manner, General Wilson returned.</p>
                    <p>Over twenty miles of this valuable road was rendered completely useless in a
                        few hours. When his advance neared Ream's Station the enemy was discovered
                        in force. They had been patiently awaiting his return at this place, and all
                        the cavalry they could muster was spread out between our gallant raiders and
                        their infantry supports. They fought all night and during the morning of
                        this day. Wilson could not push through them, and consequently found he must
                        fight till reinforced. An officer succeeded in reaching General Meade's
                        headquarters with intelligence of their awkward position, and the 6th Corps
                        being on the extreme left and nearest the scene of strife, was instantly
                        despatched there to divert the enemy's attention. A division of the 2d Corps
                        soon followed, supported by Col Collis' provisional brigade. It was thought
                        the rebels in our immediate front would have opened on us savagely, but all
                        were disappointed, their troops having been moving all the afternoon in the
                        direction of our left and rear, on Burnside's line. The rebels begin to use
                        their shells nightly, throwing shell with more accuracy than is their usual
                        habit.</p>
                    <p>Generals Grant, Meade and Butler met at Gen. Burnside's headquarters to-day.
                        The meeting was unofficial, being of a purely accidental nature.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>General</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Meade</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>General</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Collis</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Colonel</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Butler</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>General</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grant</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>General</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burnside</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>General</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Describes the destruction of twenty miles of railroad near Petersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Confederate Advance on the Baltimore and Ohio Railroad--Martinsburg Evacuated.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"At the last account, no injury had been done to the road or bridge. It is
                    supposed that the invading force is the same sent against Hunter, who is
                    understood to have retired into Western Virginia, toward Ganley, to await the
                    arrival of supplies and ammunition. Finding that Hunter had eluded them it is
                    probable the rebels are now attempting a raid into Maryland."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Baltimore, July 3</p>
                    <p>Rumors have been circulating here all day that a large force, under command
                        of General Ewell, had attacked the Federal troops at Martinsburg and
                        compelled the evacuation of the place. The following information in regard
                        to the matter has been received at headquarters, based principally upon
                        despatches from Harper's Ferry.</p>
                    <p>About daybreak this morning intelligence reached headquarters at Martinsburg
                        to the effect that the rebels were actually approaching in three separate
                        columns; one by way of the turnpike towards Shepardstown, another towards
                        Martinsburg, not far from the line of the railroad, and a third west of it.</p>
                    <p>It will be remembered that the Department of the Railroad is that of Gen.
                        Hunter, who is assisted by Gen. Sigel, with Brigadier Generals Kelly and Max
                        Weber. Gen. Kelly's force is at Cumberland, where no alarm or excitement
                        exists. General Sigel on receiving information at once prepared to check the
                        approach of the enemy, in order that no movable property should be
                        destroyed.</p>
                    <p>The troops were drawn up, and at five o'clock fighting commenced in the
                        neighborhood of Bunker Hill, continuing for four or five hours, during which
                        the cavalry fell back to the infantry supports. Ascertaining that the force
                        of the enemy was largely superior to his own, Gen. Sigel determined to
                        evacuate Martinsburg, which was accomplished in good order. He telegraphed
                        to the railroad company here as to the state of affairs and all the movable
                        property was safely carried away. Some heavy trains, filled with supplies
                        for Gen. Hunter, were also gotten off to a place of safety.</p>
                    <p>A force of the enemy also came by way of North Mountain, 7 miles to the west,
                        with the view, no doubt, of flanking our force, but in this they were
                        disappointed. A despatch received at five o'clock, this evening states that
                        fighting has been going on all day near Lectown, about ten miles from
                        Harper's Ferry and three miles to the left of the railroad, between a force
                        of the enemy that was moving in the direction of Shepardstown pike, and a
                        command that Gen. Sigel had left there to occupy the place. Both forces here
                        engaged are small, and it is reported officially that our troops there had
                        repelled successfully all attacks.</p>
                    <p>All the freight and passenger trains of the Company were worked successfully
                        through last night, but no express train for the west left Baltimore this
                        evening.</p>
                    <p>At the last account, no injury had been done to the road or bridge. It is
                        supposed that the invading force is the same sent against Hunter, who is
                        understood to have retired into Western Virginia, toward Ganley, to await
                        the arrival of supplies and ammunition. Finding that Hunter had eluded them
                        it is probable the rebels are now attempting a raid into Maryland.</p>
                    <p>It is thought the strength of their force has been greatly exag[g]erated and
                        will dwindle down to only a small raiding party; and that they will scarcely
                        venture far beyond the Potomac.</p>
                    <p>Gen. Sigel has fallen back to Harper's Ferry and holds the strong position on
                        Maryland Heights.</p>
                    <p>There was great excitement at Hagerstown and Frederick to-day, owing to the
                        exaggerated reports brought by fugitives from Martinsburg.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ewell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>General</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sigel</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>General</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kelley</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Brigadier General</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weber</ln>
                        <fn>Max</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Brigadier General</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunter</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>General</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Describes General Ewell's assault on Federal troops at Martinsburg and the
                    subsequent evacuation of the city.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 1-6</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
