<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1864/pa.fr.vs.1864.04.27">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Amy Murrell</taggerName>
            <tagDate>10/21/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 4/2/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1864-04-27">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day>27</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.04.27.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Bounty Law: An Act Relating to the Payment of Bounties to Volunteers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prints transcript of a law before the Pennsylvania legislature that would
                    make cities, wards, and boroughs throughout the state responsible for paying
                    bounties to soldiers who volunteer for service.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>A Page of History</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reviews the events surrounding the removal of General McClellan from his
                    command in August 1862. Criticizes War Department officials for treating
                    McClellan with "contemptuous indifference."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.04.27.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Patronizing the Poor</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Suggests that the "working man" may be tired of hearing lectures about good
                    living habits.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Who Are the Happy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The mechanics and working men who can maintain their families are, in my
                    opinion, the happiest body of men."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Quotes Lord Byron's praise of the working men who work hard to care for
                    their families.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>"Miscegenation"</head>
                <origin>Ex.</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt> "But when the worship of negroes has been introduced by the dominant
                    party--when Massachusetts girls are sent to Hilton Head to carry out practically
                    the ideas which the term <emph rend="italic">'miscegenation'</emph> was
                    introduced to represent, there is ground to fear the disgusting pit which has
                    been dug for the degradation of the white race. The Devil is busy still." </excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We notice this word now much used which is not to be found in the
                        Dictionaries, and we suppose was never before used in the English language.
                        It has been introduced by the radicals of the Wendell Phillips school, to
                        soften the horrible ideas which are conjured up by the term amalgamation.
                        When under the rule of wise and great men our country was prosperous, and
                        happy, we needed no word to modify the disgusting idea of white people
                        marrying negroes, or of having negro babies without being married. But when
                        the worship of negroes has been introduced by the dominant party--when
                        Massachusetts girls are sent to Hilton Head to carry out practically the
                        ideas which the term <emph rend="italic">'miscegenation'</emph> was
                        introduced to represent, there is ground to fear the disgusting pit which
                        has been dug for the degradation of the white race. The Devil is busy
                            still.--<emph rend="italic">Ex.</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that the common use of the word "miscegenation," which does not
                    appear in the dictionary, is evidence that more people are turning to the
                    "worship of negroes."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that a U.S. Senator offered a resolution requesting that the Senate
                    Chaplain refrain from speaking on political issues.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Says that a congressional bill to encourage immigration with a government
                    lien on the labor of the emigrant would mean treating the poor white laborer
                    worse than the black freedman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Poetry and fiction, columns 1-4, classified ads, column 6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.04.27.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Selection of Fruit Trees</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Offers suggestions on how to raise perfect fruit trees.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Uses of the Potato</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Cites examples from European cuisine to suggest that the potato can be used
                    in a wide variety of dishes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>How to Get Early Tomatoes</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Explains that tomatoes can be grown early by planting the seeds in a
                    turnip.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 2-6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.04.27.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Administration of Justice</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Let it be once understood that the law no longer affords protection--that
                    suits at law are decided through motives of friendship or malice, or any other
                    motive than that of an honest desire to see the law vindicated and justice
                    satisfied--then indeed will we have fallen upon evil times. Then will it be
                    realized that we have embarked on a sea of anarchy, confusion and blood, which
                    would find its only parallel in the horrid scenes of the French revolution."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In our last issue we made allusion to a growing sense of uneasiness and
                        insecurity in the public mind with reference to the execution of the laws
                        and the administration of that even-handed Justice which secures every man
                        in the enjoyment of his rights of person and property. In another column of
                        to-day's paper will be found a communication touching on the same subject,
                        written by a highly intelligent citizen of our town who is, in every
                        respect, well qualified to discuss the subject on which he writes. Of the
                        truth of the facts alluded to, those familiar with the proceedings of our
                        Court are as able to judge as ourselves.</p>
                    <p>That any Court of Justice could so far forget its sworn duty as to be
                        governed in its decisions by political bias, or any consideration other than
                        a desire to execute the laws fairly and impartially we cannot believe. Yet
                        it must be admitted, we think, that the facts mentioned by our correspondent
                        show a strong tendency in one direction, and this apparent leaning of the
                        Court, (we say apparent for we cannot think it real or intentional) in our
                        judgment, has much to do with that feeling of distrust and apprehension to
                        which we have alluded.</p>
                    <p>But whether the apprehension is real or imaginary, it is the duty of all good
                        citizens to use all proper efforts to have it removed, for if it be
                        permitted to run on it will sap the very foundations of our civil rights and
                        eventually cause the whole fabric of human society to totter and fall. And
                        in this connection we conceive it to be the duty of all persons entrusted
                        with the administration of the laws, in whatever capacity, to studiously
                        avoid everything that bears even a resemblance to partiality or favoritism
                        in the performance of their high and responsible functions. In this way only
                        can the confidence of the people in our Courts of Justice be maintained.</p>
                    <p>That political feeling has much to do with this matter there can be no doubt.
                        Party feeling has become so intense and embittered that one party naturally
                        distrusts the other, and each is regarded as incapable of doing justice to
                        those of opposite poiltical [sic] opinions. To such an extent does this idea
                        prevail that at the recent session of our court, the most strenuous efforts
                        were made by over-zealous counsel to obtain Juries composed entirely of
                        Republicans in some cases, whilst in others equally strong efforts were made
                        to get Democratic Juries. Now, in our opinion, this is all wrong. Instead of
                        pandering to the supposed prejudices of the people, it should be the aim of
                        all, but more especially lawyers, to elevate the minds of the citizens above
                        political prejudices or partisan influences. Their highest object should be
                        the aim of all, but more especially lawyers, to elevate the minds of the
                        citizens above political prejudices or partisan influences. Their highest
                        object should be, on all occasions and under all circumstances, to inculcate
                        into the minds of the people a just appreciation of the sanctity of the
                        laws, and the imperative necessity of their rigid enforcement against <emph
                            rend="italic">all</emph> offenders of whatever creed or party, "without
                        fear, favor, or affection. If this were done, there would be no need for
                        partisan Juries.</p>
                    <p>A deep and profound reverence for the sanctity of the laws on the part of the
                        people, and the rigid and impartial execution of the same on the part of
                        those whose duty it is to administer Justice, is our only safety. Let it be
                        once understood that the law no longer affords protection--that suits at law
                        are decided through motives of friendship or malice, or any other motive
                        than that of an honest desire to see the law vindicated and justice
                        satisfied--then indeed will we have fallen upon evil times. Then will it be
                        realized that we have embarked on a sea of anarchy, confusion and blood,
                        which would find its only parallel in the horrid scenes of the French
                        revolution.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Amid speculation that local judges are not administering justice
                    even-handedly, the author suggests that readers should not expect protection
                    from the law unless they share a judge's political beliefs.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Peace Advocates</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that men who support conciliation as a means to restore the Union
                    are not traitors, as Republican newspapers have been calling them.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Valley Sentinel</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Sends best wishes to the editor of a new Democratic newspaper in nearby
                    Shippensburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Word Abolitionist</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Gives the word "abolitionist" an acrostic treatment that chastises such men
                    and women for their views.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Communicated</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"They may not do it willingly, but so secret and powerful are the workings
                    of party spirit within the breast, that the judgment bends to its low
                    whisperings almost without knowing it. Party spirit thus becomes the fatal
                    poison which taints the life-blood of a Republic. Under its influence, social
                    ties are severed, business relations are disturbed, schisms arise in the Church,
                    trial by jury becomes a farce, Courts are deemed a solemn mockery, and the State
                    totters and falls."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Messrs. Editors: One of the duties of a public journal is to keep constantly
                        before the people the necessity of a high regard for and faithful observance
                        of the laws of the land. The security of property, person and life demands
                        it. Once yield the right to any citizen to violate the law with impunity and
                        society will be torn by innumerable dissensions and fearful anarchy will
                        hold its sway. The majority, the vast majority of our people are law-abiding
                        citizens, and they should see to it that every man who transgresses the law
                        should receive his just punishment. In times of great political excitement,
                        party spirit runs very high, violence is committed, life is taken and
                        through political bias or legal trickery the offenders or unwhipped of
                        justice. Some men there are--blind, partisan bigots--who exult in this for
                        they would stop at nothing to gratify their political animosities. Party
                        spirit has become so strongly rooted and grounded in their nature, that it
                        gives coloring to their opinions on all subjects. Like the wild, mad
                        revolutionists who deluged France in blood they would erect the guillotine
                        here if they dared, in order to stifle the voice of antagonistic public
                        sentiment. Such men would willingly act the part of the bloody Jeffries on
                        the bench or commit shameless perjury in the jury-box.</p>
                    <p>Other men there are, whose minds are frequently biased <emph rend="italic"
                            >unconsciously</emph>, by their political feelings. The mist of
                        political prejudices shuts out the light of truth from their reasons. Human
                        nature is weak and frail and partisan principles, partialities or
                        antipathies so warp the mind that they yield to these influences without a
                        struggle. They may not do it willingly, but so secret and powerful are the
                        workings of party spirit within the breast, that the judgment bends to its
                        low whisperings almost without knowing it. Party spirit thus becomes the
                        fatal poison which taints the life-blood of a Republic. Under its influence,
                        social ties are severed, business relations are disturbed, schisms arise in
                        the Church, trial by jury becomes a farce, Courts are deemed a solemn
                        mockery, and the State totters and falls.</p>
                    <p>Government is founded on law. It is absolutely essential to the existence of
                        Government that its laws should be founded in wisdom and justice. But this
                        is not enough. The people must respect and obey the laws, and the Court must
                        administer even-handed justice under the laws. A Court is a place where
                        justice is judicially administered. The people respect it as such. They look
                        to it for protection in property, person, reputation and life. They regard
                        the Judge upon the bench as the expounder of the law which is the custodian
                        of these great interests. Hence they would have him to divest himself of all
                        personal preferences or dislikes, and all political bias or prejudice, for
                        if he be influenced by any of these, be the laws never so wise and never so
                        just, they become to them of no more value than the paper on which they are
                        written. Jurors, acting under the charge of the Court, thus become the
                        instruments in its hands of the grossest injustice, unless they have the
                        manliness to speak out trumpet-tongued against such a pernicious influence.
                        Judges and jurors must make their personal and political feelings succumb to
                        the law and the testimony, or our whole governmental fabric must fall. The
                        people must be brought to think deeply upon the subject, to anticipate the
                        consequences of a disregard of law, for the times and the signs of the times
                        around us, imperatively demand it. They must remember to sit as jurors in
                        any case, that, higher than their own private feelings and
                        sympathies--higher than their social relations--higher than their political
                        affinities, is the sanctity of the law. And, that above all these, higher
                        than their duty to the accused, to society, to the Commonwealth--higher than
                        the sanctity of the law even, is the solemn oath, taken in the presence of
                        men and registered in Heaven "that they will well and truly try and a true
                        deliverance make between the Commonwealth and the prisoner at the bar (whom
                        they shall have in charge) <emph rend="italic">and a true verdict give
                            according to the evidence</emph>.</p>
                    <p>A man is arrested by citizens (himself a citizen) without warrant or process
                        of law, is taken before a Justice of the Peace who demands excessive bail.
                        In default of bail, he is sent by this Justice without a written commitment,
                        without even making so much as the scrape of a pen on his docket, to the
                        County Jail. He remains there one week and is discharged because no one
                        appears against him. He prosecutes the parties who arrested him, for false
                        imprisonment. On the trial testimony is admitted showing every thing that
                        the man said in his life, and under the charge of the Court, the jury
                        saddles him with one eighth of the costs and acquits the men who committed
                        the outrage. The man is a Democrat.</p>
                    <p>Another, a stout, hearty man, makes a gross, unprovoked assault upon an
                        inoffensive weak German citizen and beats him terribly. The German
                        prosecutes. The jury finds a verdict of guilty and the Court "making
                        allowance for the excitement of the times" fines the defendant five dollars
                        and costs. Defendant is a Republican.</p>
                    <p>Another strikes one who calls him "a traitor and says he ought to be hung."
                        The testimony is conflicting as to whether he struck with a club or his
                        fist. The man who receives the blow wears spectacles, a piece of the glass
                        enters his eye and his sight is thus destroyed. He prosecutes for Mayhem and
                        Aggravated Assault and Battery only, and recommend him for mercy. The Court
                        sentences him, making no allowance for the excitement of the times, to one
                        year's imprisonment in the Eastern Penitentiary. Defendant is a Democrat.</p>
                    <p>A private soldier pretending to be a Lieutenant enters the house of a citizen
                        at 11 o'clock at night, breaking in the door, presents revolver to the
                        breasts of the aged couple inside, swears he will blow their hearts out if
                        they say a word, and passes through the house under pretence [sic] of
                        authority to search for soldiers. He is indicted for Malicious Mischief and
                        Assault and Battery, is convicted on both indictments and the Court sentence
                        him <emph rend="italic">five</emph> days to the County Jail. Defendant is a
                        soldier and as a matter of course "loyal."</p>
                    <p>Another soldier is indicted for the murder of a citizen. The homicide occurs
                        on the night of an election. The deceased was a constable in the discharge
                        of his duty. It is admitted that he came to his death by means of a pistol
                        in the hands of the prisoner. The prisoner says it was done by accident and
                        offers evidence to prove it. The Commonwealth's testimony if believed,
                        altogether precludes the idea of an accident. There was no <emph
                            rend="italic">post mortem</emph> examination made of the body of the
                        deceased but he expired in three minutes after the fatal short was fired.
                        The Court held that there being no <emph rend="italic">post mortem</emph>
                        examination and the testimony being conflicting as to whether deceased came
                        to his death by accident or design he would instruct the jury to render a
                        verdict of not guilty. Deceased was a Democrat, the prisoner a Republican.
                        It seems to me the question was for the <emph rend="italic">jury</emph>
                        whether the death was the result of accident or design.</p>
                    <p>I impugn the motives of no man or set of men. The feelings and passions of
                        men, shut up within their narrow prison-houses, may be as pure as the
                        sparkling water or as foul as the miasma of the swamps. I only say that the
                        people ask, <emph rend="italic">why</emph>?</p>
                    <p>While I would cultivate the highest regard for Courts of Justice, I would
                        have the Courts show themselves worthy of that regard. Let Courts and Juries
                        be governed by the law and the testimony and all our rights will be secure.
                        It is unsafe for any party to seek to attain its ends by overriding the law
                        while holding the reins of power. Men's minds change. Parties are born and
                        die in a day. Those who sow the wind to-day may reap the whilwind [sic]
                        to-morrow. The refluent wave of public opinion may sweep to obscurity and to
                        destruction the men who perpetrate and those who sanction such enormities.
                        The only security for all is an impartial administration of</p>
                    <p>Justice.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Justice</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Author condemns recent court decisions that reveal partiality on the
                    judges' part.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Reports of troop movement in Louisiana and North Carolina, columns
            5-6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.04.27.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Pennsylvania Reserves</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The treatment of our gallant reserves, on the part of the government, has
                    been shameful ever since they entered Washington, four days after the battle of
                    Bull Run fifteen thousand strong."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Expresses disgust with the War Department's refusal to allow the
                    Pennsylvania Reserve Corps to return home in order to recruit and replenish
                    their ranks.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Income Tax</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Provides an overview of the national income tax rules and procedures.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Value of Currency</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Offers a chart explaining the current value of US currency relative to
                    gold.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Waynesboro Items</head>
                <origin>Record</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"On Tuesday last Dr. Brotherton, Sr., who for some time, has been infirm,
                    met with a serious accident by falling on the pavement, his head striking the
                    stones and causing a severe contusion."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On Tuesday last Dr. Brotherton, Sr., who for some time, has been infirm, met
                        with a serious accident by falling on the pavement, his head striking the
                        stones and causing a severe contusion. His situation is critical.</p>
                    <p>The Hotel proprietors of Waynesboro have increased the price of boarding,
                        liquors, &amp;c.</p>
                    <p>Together again.--The notice published by Mrs. Grayson, a refugee from
                        Virginia, a few weeks since, desiring information as to the whereabouts of
                        her husband, who was compelled to abandon his home in 1862, has, we are
                        pleased to learn, been the means of bringing the couple together. The notice
                        was copied into the Baltimore American, and coming to the notice of a friend
                        of Mr. G., near Sharpsburg, Md., he was at once apprised of it, and the next
                        morning set out for this place. When within about two and ahalf [sic] miles
                        of town he was observed by Mrs. G. from the house at which she was stopping,
                        and consequently their first meeting after so long a separation was upon the
                        public road. That it was a joyful one the reader can well imagine. They are
                        represented as a worthy and intelligent couple, and have been kindly and
                        hospitably treated by the family with which she had been staying.--<emph
                            rend="italic">Record</emph>.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brotherton</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf>Sr.</sf>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grayson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports on various news items from Waynesboro, including an accident
                    involving Dr. Brotherton Sr. that has left him infirm, and the reunion of a Mr.
                    and Mrs. Grayson, both refugees from Virginia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Strength of the Union Armies</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the Union army now has 306,000 more men than it did in January
                    1863.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Altered Greenbacks</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges readers to examine all paper money carefully as counterfeits have
                    been spotted recently.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Hotel Sold</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brand</ln>
                        <fn>A. Jackson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that A. Jackson Brand sold the Chambersburg Hotel to Jacob S. Brand
                    for a sum of $5,800.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Borough Elections</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reminds readers that Chambersburg borough elections will take place next
                    Monday and urges them to elect "competent" men to deal with town problems.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Great Rebellion</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snider</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces that copies of a new book, "The Great Rebellion: a history of the
                    Civil War in the United States," can be obtained from B. F. Snider.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>A Card of Thanks</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Edward N. Jacobs</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jacobs</ln>
                        <fn>Edward N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mull</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snider</ln>
                        <fn>Nicholas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gehr</ln>
                        <fn>D. O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wunderlich</ln>
                        <fn>D. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Thanks John Mull, Nicholas Snider, D. O. Gehr, D. K. Wunderlich and their
                    families for their kindness to a stranger.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thomas</ln>
                        <fn>R. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dickhout</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carson</ln>
                        <fn>Anna T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On April 19, Rev. R. P. Thomas married Samuel H. Dickhout and Anna T.
                    Carson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnhart</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Matthias R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Graul</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On April 20, Rev. Thomas Barnhart married Matthias R. Brown, of Indiana
                    County, and Mary Graul.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kester</ln>
                        <fn>A. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hering</ln>
                        <fn>E. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamilton</ln>
                        <fn>Frances M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. A. M. Kester married E. A. Hering and Frances M. Hamilton on April 19.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Apple</ln>
                        <fn>T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLaughlin</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Divilbir</ln>
                        <fn>Adella</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. T. Apple married Robert McLaughlin and Adella Divilbir on April 25.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolff</ln>
                        <fn>B.C.</fn>
                        <sf>D. D.</sf>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Apple</ln>
                        <fn>T. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolff</ln>
                        <fn>C. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hartman</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. B. C. Wolff, D.D., assisted by Rev. T. G. Apple, married Rev. C. B.
                    Wolff and Susan Hartman on April 21.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Eliza</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kissecker</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Eliza Brumbaugh, daughter of John Kissecker, died on April 14 at age 6.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>William L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William L. Myers died on April 16 at age 30.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elby</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On April 11, Sarah Elby died at age 4.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kuhn</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine Shirey</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kuhn</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kuhn</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Catharine Shirey Kuhn, daughter of John and Mary Ann Kuhn, died on April 3
                    at age 3.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kuhn</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kuhn</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary Ann Kuhn, wife of John Kuhn, died on April 14 at age 39.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 4-6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.04.27.06">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Congressional</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Summarizes recent proceedings of the US Congress, including consideration
                    of bills to amend the pension law and to regulate the pay of officers in the
                    army.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Army of the Potomac</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on recent movements of the Army of the Potomac, including talk of
                    an early movement of the troops into Virginia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Report of a rebel assault in Plymouth, North Carolina, column 2, classified
                ads, columns 3-6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.04.27.07">
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 1-6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.04.27.08">
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 1-6</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
