<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1864/pa.fr.vs.1864.12.07">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Amy Murrell</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/05/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 5/11/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1864-12-07">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="12">December</month>
            <day>7</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.12.07.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Attempt to Abolitionize the Methodist Episcopal Church</head>
                <origin>Rochester Union</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"I respect the clergy, their calling is the most sacred, most dignified and
                    important on earth . . . but when they lay their sacradotal robes aside, become
                    brawling politicians, embassadors of the Republican party and Abraham Lincoln
                    rather than the blessed Saviour, and preach partisan politics instead of the
                    Gospel, I can but look upon the picture they present with sadness and disgust,
                    fallen from the most elevated calling."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Speech of Hon. D. A. Ogden, a "prominent layman," condemns the Methodist
                    Episcopal Church of New York for passing a resolution that effectively brands
                    anyone a "traitor" who does not support Lincoln.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 1-5; essay on dogs, column 7</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.12.07.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>To Our Patrons--Special Notice</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Explains that the present high price of paper makes it necessary to raise
                    the Valley Spirit's subscription price from $2.00 to $2.50 per year.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We have arrived at such a pass in our elections, that to our Shoddy
                    friends, an illegal vote is as good as a legal one if it will serve their
                    purposes."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coffroth</ln>
                        <fn>A. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koontz</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Argues that A.H. Coffroth is the winner of the congressional race, and that
                    the military votes still uncounted are illegal and should never be counted.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The Soldier was refused his right of suffrage because he wanted to vote
                    the Democratic ticket, and for no other reason whatever."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Disputes a Repository claim that the story of a soldier who was denied the
                    vote because he wanted to vote for McClellan is false.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Political Pulpit</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Praises those ministers who have refrained from getting involved in
                    politics and regrets that those who have become politicized have diminished the
                    church's power.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Sanitary Expenses</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"This is charity with a vengeance. . . . People generally suppose when they
                    give their money to help the sick and wounded soldiers that it goes through the
                    hands of kind hearted people, direct to the camp and hospital."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Criticizes the Sanitary Commission for spending $3.00 in administrative
                    costs for every $4.00 in relief given to soldiers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Says that the Valley Spirit will not substantiate its charges of fraud
                    against the Repository editor until he backs up his claim that the Valley Spirit
                    tried to "cheat" its favorite candidates into office.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Elections in Pennsylvania--an Authoritative Statement of Results</head>
                <origin>World</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>C. L. Ward, Chairman of the Democratic State Central Committee of
                    Pennsylvania</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Explains that when the army vote and the proxy votes are all counted,
                    McClellan will have proven victorious in Pennsylvania.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Necessity of Party Opposition</head>
                <origin>Sunday Mercury</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that despite being a minority, the Democratic party may be able to
                    impose a check on Republican power by resisting its policies.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Charles Santer, John Wiest, A. L. Kaub, Chas. Wannemacher, Geo. Gilbach,
                    Wm. Mayburry, Philadelphia, November 1864</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Members of the Synod of the German Reformed Church in Philadelphia solicit
                    contributions to help restore the church's printing establishment, which was
                    burned in the Chambersburg fire, and to move it to Philadelphia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Benefits of War</head>
                <origin>N. Y. Commercial Advertiser</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Looking at it simply in its effect upon individuals, or upon classes which
                    are composed of individuals, the war has undoubtedly caused an immense deal of
                    trouble, suffering, and misfortune."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Debates whether the war has produced any blessings and concludes that it
                    has yet to produce one.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Proposed Amendment to the Constitution</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The state of the times, recent and present, and the state of public
                    sentiment, warrant and encourage the attempt to secure the amendment of the
                    Constitution."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Convention relative to the proposed amendment to the National
                        Constitution, acknowledging God, continued its sessions in the West Arch
                        Street Presbyterian Church. The attendance was large. Rev. Dr. Edwards
                        presided.</p>
                    <p>Letters from Hon. B. Gratz Brown of Missouri, Prof. J.F. Winkler of Buffalo,
                        Rev. L. W. Habil of Wisconsin, Rev. Dr. Durfield of Detroit, and others,
                        favoring the movement were read.</p>
                    <p>Revs. A.M. Whitstone, A.C. Todd, James McDonald, Prof. McIlvaine, and others
                        delivered addresses upon the doings of auxiliary societies formed in various
                        States.</p>
                    <p>A session was held during the afternoon, and a number of addresses on the
                        subject were made.</p>
                    <p>In the evening, Dr. Edwards called the meeting to order; when the following
                        resolutions were adopted:</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That a national recognition of God, the
                        Lord Jesus Christ and the Holy Scriptures, as proposed in the memorial of
                        this Association to Congress, is clearly a Scriptural duty which it is
                        national peril to disregard.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That in consideration of the general
                        diffusion of religious intelligence, principles and institutions throughout
                        our country; in view of the many express recognitions of Christianity by the
                        Constitutions, and the legislative enactments of the several States, and in
                        view also, of the religious history of the founding of this Government, it
                        is a striking and solemn fact that our present National Constitution is so
                        devoid of any distinctive Christian feature that one of our Chief
                        Magistrates once refused to appoint a day of fasting and prayer in an hour
                        of public calamity because the nation in its Constitution recognized no God
                        and another, in contracting a treaty with a Mahomedan Power, hesitated not
                        to declare that the Government of the United States is not in any sense
                        founded on the Christian religion. It has in itself no character of enmity
                        against the laws and religion of Mussulmen.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That the measures proposed by this
                        Association are not sectional nor sectarian, nor partisan, but the general
                        voice of Christian patriotism, asking that which is right and wholesome,
                        which is keeping with our antecedents, and which will not operate
                        oppressively upon the conscience of any citizen.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, that the state of the times, recent and
                        present, and the state of pu[b]lic sentiment, warrant and encourage the
                        attempt to secure the amendment of the Constitution which is proposed by
                        this Association.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That the hour of chastisement is the
                        hour of repentance, amendment and reform, and that in such a day of national
                        trouble and rebuke as has befallen us, every reformation from sin is
                        valuable and important; it is clear that in acknowledging God, in exalting
                        His Son and in diffusing the principles of His word through all our
                        Government and Administration, not only is there no mistake committed, but
                        an end of the first dignity and importance is secured.</p>
                    <p>The convention adjourned with prayer.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on the proceedings of the national convention that is proposing a
                    constitutional amendment recognizing God.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Arrest of Editors in Kentucky</head>
                <origin>Cairo (KY) Democrat</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Democratic newspaper editors in Kentucky are being arrested
                    and sent beyond the lines.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>War news from Georgia and Baltimore, column 7</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.12.07.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Childrens' Aid Societies</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Expresses regret that a childrens' aid society is moving into nearby
                    Shippensburg. Says this will mean more juvenile crime and depravity for the
                    area.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Fatal Occurrence</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on the shooting death of a soldier in an ale shop in the eastern
                    part of Chambersburg. The shooting occurred when a lieutenant entered the shop,
                    demanded to see the passes of three soldiers sitting there, and shot one of them
                    when the three tried to escape.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Barbarous Custom</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The children of our town have fallen into a confirmed habit of flocking in
                    a body to any house in which a death has occurred, for the purpose of gazing
                    upon the remains. At such a time the grief of survivors in a family from which a
                    loved one has been taken is too sacred for such rude intrusion, and parents
                    should see that their children are not permitted to make these untimely visits."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Under this caption the Newville <emph rend="italic">Star of the Valley</emph>
                        remarks:</p>
                    <p>The children of our town have fallen into a confirmed habit of flocking in a
                        body to any house in which a death has occurred, for the purpose of gazing
                        upon the remains. At such a time the grief of survivors in a family from
                        which a loved one has been taken is too sacred for such rude intrusion, and
                        parents should see that their children are not permitted to make these
                        untimely visits.</p>
                    <p>The above applies with equal force to our own community. No death can occur
                        without crowds of rude ill-mannered children rushing into the house
                        containing the corpse, to the annoyance of relatives and friends. The
                        nuisance has become almost intolerable and some of our citizens on the
                        occasion of a death in the family, have been compelled to lock their doors
                        in order to keep out these rude intruders.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Chastizes local children for running to see the corpse after hearing about
                    a death in the community.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Ladies' Fair</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that the ladies of Waynesboro are planning a fair to be held in the
                    town hall over the holidays. The fair will benefit the Christian Commission's
                    work for sick and disabled soldiers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Court Martial</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that a general court martial is taking place now at the Franklin
                    Railroad Depot.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Enrollment of State Militia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Explains the rules surrounding the enrollment of the state militia,
                    including who is to be enrolled and who is exempt.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Oller</ln>
                        <fn>J. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Good</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoler</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. J. F. Oller married John W. Good and Sarah Ann Stoler on November 24
                    at the residence of the bride's parents.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Oller</ln>
                        <fn>J. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Price</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>Rachael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. J. F. Oller married Jacob Price and Rachael Davis on November 27.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Krebs</ln>
                        <fn>W. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Funk</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sibbett</ln>
                        <fn>Mary B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William H. Funk and Mary B. Sibbett were married on December 1 by Rev. W.
                    E. Krebs.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bishop</ln>
                        <fn>James M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nigh</ln>
                        <fn>David W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tarner</ln>
                        <fn>Nancy Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. James M. Bishop married David W. Nigh and Nancy Ann Tarner on November
                    1 at Pleasant Retreat Parsonage.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grier</ln>
                        <fn>J. Smith</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. Smith Grier died last Saturday morning after a "protracted and painful
                    illness." His age was not given.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 4-7</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.12.07.04">
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 1-7</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
