<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1864/pa.fr.vs.1864.09.14">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Amy Murrell</taggerName>
            <tagDate>11/21/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 4/23/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1864-09-14">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day>14</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.09.14.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Speech of Hon. J. M'D. Sharpe of Franklin County</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharpe</ln>
                        <fn>J. M'D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Prints speech given by J. M'D. Sharpe to the Pennsylvania legislature in
                    which he seeks to increase the amount of money that will be given toward the
                    relief of Chambersburg residents.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Transcript of speech continues on page 2, classified ads, columns
            1-4</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.09.14.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Serenade to Hon. George H. Pendleton--His Response</head>
                <origin>Cincinnati Inquirer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We are about to enter on a warm, excited contest. It will try you--try
                    your principles--try the strength of the institutions of free government. Let us
                    indulge in no personal animosities, no personal abuse. Let us remember that the
                    cause is too sacred--the consequences too important--the results too vast, for
                    such party instrumentalities."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prints remarks on the upcoming election given by Democratic vice
                    presidential candidate George H. Pendleton to a crowd that serenaded him in
                    Cincinnati.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Dreadful Accident on the Pennsylvania Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that a "dreadful" accident on the Pennsylvania Railroad, one and a
                    half miles west of Latrobe, resulted in three deaths and the destruction of six
                    cattle cars.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>General McClellan's Letter of Acceptance</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"As soon as it is clear, or even probable, that our present adversaries are
                    ready for peace upon the basis of the Union, we should exhibit all the resources
                    of statesmanship practiced by civilized nations and taught by the traditions of
                    the American people, consistent with the interests of the country, to secure
                    such peace, re-establish the union and guarantee for the future the conditional
                    rights of every state."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Union Must be Preserved at all Hazards!</p>
                    <p>New York, Sept. 8.--The following is the letter of General McClellan
                        accepting the Chicago nomination:</p>
                    <p>Orange, N.J., Sept. 8, 1864.--Gentlemen: I have the honor to acknowledge the
                        receipt of your letter informing me of my nomination by the Democratic
                        National Convention, recently assembled at Chicago, as their candidate at
                        the next election for President of the United States.</p>
                    <p>It is unnecessary for me to say to you that this nomination comes to me
                        unsought.</p>
                    <p>I am happy to know that when the nomination was made the record of my public
                        life was kept in view.</p>
                    <p>The effect of long and varied service in the army during war and peace has
                        been to strengthen and make indelible in my mind and heart the love and
                        reverence for the Union. Constitution, laws and flag of our country
                        impressed upon me in my early youth.</p>
                    <p>These feelings have thus far guided the course of my life and must continue
                        to do so to its end.</p>
                    <p>The existence of more than one Government over the region which once owned
                        our flag is incompatible with the peace, the power and the happiness of the
                        people.</p>
                    <p>The preservation of our Union was the sole avowed object for which the war
                        was commenced, and it should have been conducted in accordance with those
                        principles, which I took occasion to declare when in active service. Thus
                        conducted, the work of reconciliation would have been easy, and we might
                        have reaped the benefits of our many victories on the land and the sea.</p>
                    <p>The Union was originally formed by the exercise of a spirit of conciliation
                        and compromise, and to restore and preserve it the same spirit must prevail
                        in our councils and in the hearts of the people. The re-establishment of the
                        Union in all its integrity is and must continue to be the indispensable
                        condition in any settlement.</p>
                    <p>As soon as it is clear, or even probable, that our present adversaries are
                        ready for for [sic] peace upon the basis of the Union, we should exhibit all
                        the resources of statesmanship practiced by civilized nations and taught by
                        the traditions of the American people, consistent with the honor and
                        interests of the country, to secure such peace, re-establish the Union and
                        guarantee for the future the conditional rights of every State. The Union is
                        the one condition of peace, and we ask no more.</p>
                    <p>Let me add what I doubt not was, although unexpressed, the sentiment of the
                        Convention as it is of the people they represent, that when any one State is
                        willing to return to the Union it should be received at once with a full
                        guarantee of al its constitutional rights. If a frank, earnest and
                        persistent effort to obtain these objects should fail, the responsibility
                        for ulterior consequences will fall upon those who remain in arms against
                        the Union, but the Union must be preserved at all hazards.</p>
                    <p>I could not look in the face of my gallant comrades of the army and navy, who
                        have survived so many bloody battles, and tell them that their labors and
                        the sacrifice of so many of our slain and wounded brethren had been in
                        vain--that we had abandoned that Union for which we have so often periled
                        our lives.</p>
                    <p>A vast majority of our people, whether in the army and navy or at home,
                        would, as I would, hail with unbounded joy the permanent restoration of
                        peace, on the basis of the Union under the Constitution, without the
                        effusion of another drop of blood, but no peace can be permanent without
                        Union.</p>
                    <p>As to the other subjects presented in the resolutions of the Convention, I
                        need only say that I should seek in the Constitution of the United States,
                        and the laws framed in accordance therewith, the rule of my duty and the
                        limitations of executive power, endeavoring to restore economy in public
                        expenditure, re-establish the supremacy of law, and by the operation of a
                        more vigorous nationality, resume our commanding position among the nations
                        of the earth.</p>
                    <p>The condition of our finances, the depreciation of the paper money, and the
                        burdens thereby imposed on labor and capital, show the necessity of a return
                        to a sound financial system, while the rights of citizens and the rights of
                        States, and the binding authority of law over the President, the army and
                        the people, are subjects of not less vital importance in war than in peace.</p>
                    <p>Believing that the views here expressed are those of the Convention and the
                        people you represent, I accept the nomination. I realize the weight of the
                        responsibility to be borne, should the people ratify your choice.</p>
                    <p>Conscious of my own weakness, I can only seek fervently the guidance of the
                        Ruler of the Universe and relying on His all-powerful aid, do my best to
                        restore Union and peace to a suffering people and to establish and guard
                        their liberties and rights.</p>
                    <p>I am, gentlemen, very respectfully,</p>
                    <p>Your obedient servant, <lb/>George B. McClellan.</p>
                    <p>Hon. Horation Seymour, and others, Committee.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>George B. McClellan</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>McClellan's letter accepting the Democratic nomination for President
                    outlines his views on the future direction of the war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Horatio Seymour, Chairman, John Bigler, of California, Alfred P. Edgerton,
                    of Indiana, Isaac Lawrence, of Rhode Island, John Merritt, of Delaware, John
                    Cain, of Vermont, Hugh McCurdy, of Michigan, Joseph E. Smith, of Maine, George
                    H. Carman, of Maryland, Benjamin Stark, of Oregon, John M. Douglas, of Illinois,
                    Charles Negus, of Iowa.</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prints official letter from a committee of the National Democratic
                    Convention that offers General McClellan the presidential nomination.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Mr. Lincoln's Jokes</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Alleges that Lincoln recently told a story mocking the war dead that was
                    "the most disgusting specimen of obscenity we have ever heard."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>General McClellan's Letter</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"His letter is brief: but every sentence is compact with the earnest,
                    high-toned and devout patriotism, characteristic of the man. Its explicit,
                    square, unflinching enunciation of principles which should guide the government
                    in restoring Union, peace and liberty to the nation, will command the admiration
                    as well as the assent of every honest and loyal man."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Holds up General McClellan's acceptance letter as proof of his worthiness
                    for the presidency.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Nero fiddled while Rome was burning, Cromwell bedaubed in the face of
                    another judge with ink while he was signing the death warrant of Charles L., and
                    Abraham Lincoln called for a comic negro song when he was surrounded by corpses
                    upon the battle-field of Antietam!"</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Accuses Lincoln of being insensitive to the war dead.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Why the People are Rising</head>
                <origin>Age</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the nomination of General McClellan by the Democrats has
                    "awakened universal enthusiasm" all over the country.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The National Intelligencer on Gen. McClellan's Nomination</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Our only hope of Union and peace, as also of a return to the normal sway
                    of the laws within the Loyal States, is therefore reposed in a change of men in
                    the administration of the Government, to be followed by a change of policy in
                    the management of our affairs, and, so thinking, we shall not hesitate to give
                    our cordial support to the nomination of General McClellan."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prints an "old line Whig" newspaper's endorsement of General McClellan for
                    President.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Previously published presidential election news, column 3</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.09.14.03">
            <div type="c">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Democratic Meetings!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>W. S. Stenger, Chairman of the Democratic County Ex. Com.</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lists the dates on which Democratic meetings will be held in various places
                    in Franklin County between September 19 and October 1: Waynesboro, September 19;
                    Greencastle, September 20; Mercersburg, September 21; Loudon, September 22;
                    Welsh Run, September 22; Orrstown, September 23; Greenwood, September 23; St.
                    Thomas, September 24; Funkstown, September 24; Fannettsburg, September 26;
                    Fayetteville, September 26; Dry Run, September 27; Greenvillage, September 27;
                    Concord, September 28; Marion, September 28; Amberson's Valley, September 29;
                    Roxbury, September 29; Red School House, September 29; Strasburg, September 30;
                    New Franklin, September 30; Quincy, October 1.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>An Interesting Incident</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"'I want to know whether you are going along with me?'/'No I ain't.'/'You
                    ain't, you d--d rebel'--when down came yankee's carbine on a level with the head
                    of Johnny, Click went the lock and--the cap exploded without discharging the
                    load. Quick as a flash yankee wheeled and the reb vaulted into his saddle
                    exclaiming, 'Now I've got you, you d--d yankee,' and drawing his revolver,
                    commenced the pursuit of yankee through the woods"</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On Saturday, the 30th day of July, when our town was being consumed by the
                        devouring element, kindled by the hands of the rebel scoundrels under
                        McCausland, an interesting and somewhat exciting incident occurred in the
                        southern end of what is generally known as "Shetter's Woods," about half a
                        mile east of the borough. A number of citizens, men, women and children, had
                        fled from their burning houses and taken refuge in these woods. The women
                        and children were left there in the charge of several gentlemen, whilst the
                        other males of the party returned to the burning town to secure, if
                        possible, some of their valuables left behind in their flight.</p>
                    <p>Whilst resting from their fatigue and recovering somewhat from the excitement
                        of their hasty and perillous [sic] flight, they were startled by the
                        approach of a mounted rebel; anticipating insult, if not robbery and murder,
                        at his hands; he, however, passed by with a "good day ladies," and halting
                        about two hundred yards beyond, took a survey of the surrounding country,
                        and then returning stopped his horse, dismounted, and entered into
                        conversation with the ladies. Whilst thus engaged, a squad of cavalry,
                        numbering about a dozen, was observed to halt at the north end of the woods,
                        on the Baltimore turnpike, about five hundred yards distant, one of whom
                        entered the woods, came in the direction of the party, and when within a
                        short distance cocked his carbine and elevating its muzzle rode up, when the
                        following scene occurred, the rebel still standing by his horse, with his
                        hand resting on the pommel of the saddle. (The newcomer was supposed by our
                        informant to be a rebel, but he was considerably relieved when the stranger
                        addressed him):</p>
                    <p>"Did you see anything of any Johnnies about here?"</p>
                    <p>"There has been no person here but this gentleman, (his companion) myself,
                        and that soldier, who I suppose is one of your men." Newcomer, looking at
                        reb--"Say, mister, I want you to go along with me."</p>
                    <p>To this request the reb paid no attention when he was again hailed with,</p>
                    <p>"I say I want you to go along with me, and that pretty quick too."</p>
                    <p>"You ain't in a hurry, are you?"</p>
                    <p>"That's not what I asked you. I want to know whether you are going along with
                        me?"</p>
                    <p>"No I ain't."</p>
                    <p>"You ain't, you d--d rebel"--when down came yankee's carbine on a level with
                        the head of Johnny, Click went the lock and--the cap exploded without
                        discharging the load. Quick as a flash yankee wheeled and the reb vaulted
                        into his saddle exclaiming, "Now I've got you, you d--d yankee," and drawing
                        his revolver, commenced the pursuit of yankee through the woods, firing at
                        every jump, until his six loads were expended, without, however, doing any
                        more damage than slightly wounding the horse of the pursued. Down the woods
                        in the direction of the turnpike, at full speed went yankee, with reb about
                        fifteen yards in his rear, until they reached the road, when eight or ten
                        shots were heard, in quick succession, and our spunky reb, with several
                        bullets in his carcass, was "gobbled up" by Averill's men.</p>
                    <p>Our informant did not learn what became of the Johnny, further than that he
                        followed after his brother scoundrels in the train of Gen. Averill, and if
                        he has not died of his wounds, is now, no doubt, meditating in one of Uncle
                        Sam's Forts, on the folly of running into a hornet's nest.</p>
                    <p>If this sketch should meet the eye of our yankee friend, we hope he will
                        inform us what his sensations were about the time his carbine missed fire,
                        and whether he didn't regret having undertaken to "pick up" <emph
                            rend="italic">that</emph> greyback.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Tells about an encounter between a Confederate soldier and Chambersburg
                    citizens seeking refuge from the fire.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Proceedings of the Democratic County Committee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>W. S. Stenger, Chairman, B. Y. Hamsher, Sec'y</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stenger</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duncan</ln>
                        <fn>C. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamsher</ln>
                        <fn>B. Y.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports on a Democratic county committee meeting in which members voted to
                    have a debate with the local Republican party.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Enlisting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that "many" of the Franklin County districts have filled their quotas
                    of volunteers and that the others are making good progress.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Poor Richard's Reasons for Buying United States Securities</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Tells the story of "poor Richard," who decided to buy U.S. stocks over
                    railroad stocks because he believes that they will pay better dividends and help
                    the war effort.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Says Lincoln's renomination will do a "favor" for the Confederates since
                    the election campaign will distract him from the activity on the battlefield.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 4-7, previously published political news, column
            1</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.09.14.04">
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 1-7</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
