<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1864/pa.fr.vs.1864.05.25">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Amy Murrell</taggerName>
            <tagDate>10/21/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 4/2/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1864-05-25">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day>25</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.05.25.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Extracts of a Speech Delivered in the US Senate by Senator Powell, of Kentucky</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"I tell the conservative men, the Democracy, the old Whigs, the honest
                    Republicans, everywhere--and I wish to God my voice could extend to the remote
                    parts of this country--to be of good cheer; and if those in power attempt to
                    enslave them, to put chains upon their limbs, to prevent their free tongues from
                    wagging in words of honest and burning censure against those who are striking
                    down their liberties, if the minions of power attempt to interfere with the
                    freedom of the press, I would advise the people throughout the length and
                    breadth of the land to insist on freedom, and give their lives in its defence."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Condemns Republicans in power for suppressing free speech in the Senate.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The New State Tax Law</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Provides abstract of a new tax law that will affect transportation and
                    manufacturing companies.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>General McClellan Defended by a Republican</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Gen. McClellan is a true man, because good and true soldiers of the United
                    States army respect and honor him as an officer and a soldier--a man who is
                    ready to sacrifice his life to save the Government of a people who will revere
                    his name long after his traducers are dead and forgotten."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Applauds an attempt by a Republican newspaper in Vermont to defend General
                    McClellan against accusations of disloyalty by other Republican papers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.05.25.02">
            <pageNote>Fiction and poetry, columns 1-3, classified ads, columns 4-6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.05.25.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Best Potatoes to Raise for Market</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes the type of potatoes that will command the highest prices in the
                    market.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 2-6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.05.25.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Union as it Was</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"It is assumed that we are a nation independent of the Constitution; that
                    in such an emergency as the present, the Constitution must be laid aside until
                    the nation is saved. Nothing could express a more decided condemnation of the
                    Constitution than to say its provisions are inadequate to the common necessities
                    of the nation."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Acknowledges that a latent hostility toward the old Union has emerged in
                    the free states. Suggests that the Constitution as it is written is inadequate
                    for the present time for many reasons, including its acceptance of slavery.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>No Government</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"He had been taught by the sad experience of other Generals the great
                    danger of permitting the intermeddling fools at Washington to advise or dictate,
                    and he wisely erected a barrier between himself and them."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Supports General Grant's decision to cut off communication with the
                    government in Washington once he began his march toward Richmond.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Wendell Phillips</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"It is clear that if these crack brained fanatics had their own way, the
                    white race would soon be extinct in this country, and their places filled by
                    hybrids."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that Wendell Phillips spoke to abolitionists in Boston recently with
                    a "saddle colored female" next to him on stage.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Army Correspondence</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The Franklin County men are generally well and in good spirits over the
                    late war news, all hoping that in a year hence the war will be over and they can
                    again enjoy the blessing of peace in their homes in old Franklin."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Fort Marcy, Va., May 13, 1864.</p>
                    <p>Editors of the Valley Spirit:</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Gentlemen:</emph>--A few weeks ago I became a member of
                        Battery (Company) B, of the 2d Penna. Artillery. Soon after I was ushered
                        among the boys I ascertained that the Battery was partly composed of
                        Franklin county men, with whom I had no difficulty in associating, from the
                        fact that they are, generally, as well as a majority of the rest of the
                        Battery respectable, sociable and unassuming men.</p>
                    <p>In connection with the many newspapers that are received here I see the
                        Valley Spirit is a regular visitor to some of the boys. Its contents are
                        read and its doctrine approved by a number of the members of Battery B. At
                        the option of the Editors I will endeavor to give the readers of the Spirit
                        a few items of information which may be of interest to them.</p>
                    <p>Fort Marcy, which we at present garrison, is situated on the Virginia side,
                        about one-fourth mile from the banks of the Potomac river, in close
                        proximity with the large fort Ethan Allen and about five miles from the
                        National Capital. It is beautifully located on the summit of a hill, a
                        little more elevated than the many surrounding knolls; affording therefore a
                        splendid view of the surrounded devastated and war blighted country. From
                        the parapet of the fort can be seen the waters of the famous river Potomac
                        as they noiselessly approach in the distance, when they rapidly pass by
                        tossing, foaming and furiously splashing as they roll over uneven rocks, and
                        until they again, some miles below, assume the calmness so peculiar to this
                        element when undisturbed.</p>
                    <p>The fort mounts twenty-two guns ranging in different directions which from
                        their elevated position can be turned upon an object at a great distance.
                        These guns are manned by the members of Batteries B. C. and M., the rest of
                        the regiment being at fort Ethan Allen. From the condition of the fort and
                        guns and being manned by troops well versed in artillery, as well as
                        infantry tactics, as the men of these respective Batteries are, I have not
                        the least hesitancy in saying that an approaching enemy would be severely
                        dealt with.</p>
                    <p>Our officers deserve much credit for the careful attention they pay to
                        properly drilling and providing for their men. Col. A. A. Gibson, commanding
                        the regiment, is highly deserving of the popularity which he has gained for
                        himself and is well qualified for the high position he holds. He is
                        reasonably indulgent and kind to his men, but necessarily stern and resolute
                        in the enforcement of that discipline so indispensable to the efficiency of
                        military organizations.</p>
                    <p>Capt. Barney, late commander of Battery B, having been favored with the
                        colonelcy of the new regiment formed out of the excess of men enlisted for
                        the 2d artillery, the Battery is now under command of Lieut. Guisinger. He
                        is a man of noble qualities--unassuming and in every way gentlemanly. An old
                        adage and frequently expressed, says, "We all have our enemies," but I must
                        say this for Lieut. Guisinger, that I do not believe he has one enemy among
                        the men under his command. All seem to entertain the greatest respect and
                        kindest regard for him, of which his conduct makes him highly deserving.</p>
                    <p>Our orderly or first Sergeant, Mr Gayette, is by birth a Frenchman. Men are
                        few in number who are so well calculated to fill the important position of
                        Orderly Sergeant in a military company. His military qualification and his
                        energy in the discharge of his duties qualify him for a higher position.</p>
                    <p>I am under obligations to Corporal Beldel from Chambersburg for the patience,
                        and interest he has manifested in teaching me military tactics and "how to
                        shoot." The Franklin county men are generally well and in good spirits over
                        the late war news, all hoping that in a year hence the war will be over and
                        they can again enjoy the blessing of peace in their homes in old Franklin.</p>
                    <p>RAW RECRUIT.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Raw Recruit</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gibson</ln>
                        <fn>A. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barney</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guisinger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gayette</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>First Sergeant</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beidel</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Corporal</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A member of Company B, 2nd Pennsylvania Artillery, describes Fort Marcy,
                    where some Franklin County men are stationed, and describes the officers who are
                    leading their company.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Important to Those Liable to Draft</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges readers to help submit names of all the men who will be eligible for
                    the next draft.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Report of the General Conference of the M.E. Church, column 6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.05.25.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Draft</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Provost Marshal of this district, Captain George Eyster, announces that
                    the draft will take place on April 30.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Court Proceedings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nill</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Graham</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes that a special term of the Court of Common Pleas commenced last
                    Monday with Judges Nill and Graham presiding.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Buckley</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McConnell</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf>Sr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Briggs</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hetser</ln>
                        <fn>Mary A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On May 12, Rev. J. Buckley married George Briggs and Mary A. Hetser at the
                    residence of H. McConnell, Sr.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Apple</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn>J. Clinton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henerberger</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On May 25, Rev. Mr. Apple married J. Clinton Gordon and Mary Henerberger.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Breidenbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shoemaker</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wallace</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On May 10, Rev. E. Breidenbaugh married William Shoemaker and Mary Wallace
                    at the Franklin Hotel.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Breidenbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Collier</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf>U.S.M.C.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Michael</ln>
                        <fn>Ann E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. E. Breidenbaugh married George W. Collier, U.S.M.C., of Washington
                    City, and Ann E. Michael on May 18.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Breidenbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Williamson</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lute</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. E. Breidenbaugh married Samuel E. Williamson, of Virginia, and Sarah
                    C. Lute on May 19 at the Lutheran Parsonage in Greencastle.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Negly</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Joseph Negly died on May 13 at age 82.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>William Augustus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Augustus Harbaugh, son of Frederick and Catharine Harbaugh, died on
                    May 12 at age 1 year, 4 months.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fitzhugh</ln>
                        <fn>Maria</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On April 26 in Mont Alto, Maria Fitzhugh died of spotted fever.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fitzgerald</ln>
                        <fn>Hannah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On May 17, Hannah Fitzgerald died at age 75.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 1-6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.05.25.06">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Latest Telegraphic News!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Series of dispatches from Washington and Virginia indicate that the Army of
                    the Potomac is making progress in its movement toward Richmond.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 4-6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.05.25.07">
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 1-6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.05.25.08">
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 1-6</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
