<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1864/pa.fr.vs.1864.11.16">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Amy Murrell</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/05/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 5/11/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1864-11-16">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="11">November</month>
            <day>16</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.11.16.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Lady Doctors</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Explains why women are not fit to be doctors.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Preserving Roots</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Offers suggestions for storing roots in dry conditions over the winter to
                    ensure that next spring's root crops will be plentiful.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Hard Times Fruit Cake</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Provides a recipe for "hard times fruit cake": two cups dried apple soaked
                    overnight, chopped coarsely; three cups of molasses; one egg; two-thirds cup of
                    butter; one teaspoonful of soda; "all kinds of spice"; and "flour as you would
                    cup-cake." This recipe makes two loaves.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 1-3; poetry and an essay on the French imperial
                family, column 4</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.11.16.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Late Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Appalling as the thought of a new lease of Republican administration, even
                    this terrible alternative is preferable to an abandonment of the Union."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges the victorious Republicans to use their power "wisely, humanely, and
                    with a sole view to the good of the whole country."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Election: Pennsylvania</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lists the final voting majorities in the presidential race by county. In
                    Franklin County, McClellan received a forty-six-vote majority. Also lists the
                    final vote in each Pennsylvania regiment: the 107th Pennsylvania Volunteers
                    voted 96 for McClellan and 102 for Lincoln, and the 21st Pennsylvania Cavalry
                    voted 106 for McClellan and 244 for Lincoln.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Next Congress</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"It will be seen from the above statement that the Abolitionists will have
                    full swing. There will be no check upon them. . . . We scarcely dare to hope for
                    good sense and a proper regard for the true interests of the nation from them."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that thirty-eight Republicans and fourteen Democrats will comprise
                    the US Senate in its next term. Also predicts that the Republicans will have a
                    seventy-member majority in the next session of the House of Representatives.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Political Preachers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"These persons, forgetful not only of their calling, but of the very spirit
                    of the Gospel, read the account of a battle with the most violent emotions; and
                    provided the victory falls on their favorite side, they exult and triumph in
                    proportion to the number of thousands that have been slain!"</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prints comments from a clergymen who denounced his fellow ministers for
                    reading the newspaper more closely than the Bible.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We were threatened with a little of the 'millennium' last Saturday night,
                    a small body of Rebs having crossed the Potomac at Shepherdstown; they were so
                    swift in their movements, however, that the 'millennium' didn't get a start."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Mocks the conclusion of several newspapers that the millennium has come.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that General McClellan resigned his commission as a major general in
                    the army last Thursday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Vote for President Among the Union Prisoners in Richmond</head>
                <origin>Richmond Examiner</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A Richmond newspaper reports that a poll taken of Northern prisoners showed
                    McClellan receiving a majority among noncommissioned officers and privates and
                    Lincoln a majority among commissioned officers. The article also notes that
                    black soldiers were denied the opportunity to participate in the poll.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Shenandoah Valley</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"General Sheridan has received informa[tion] that the rebels intend to
                    immediately assume the offensive."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Ewell Supercedes Early--The Enemy Expected to Assume the Offensive.</p>
                    <p>Hd.Qrs., Middle Military Div. <lb/>November 8.</p>
                    <p>General Sheridan has received informa[tion] that the rebels intend to
                        immediately assume the offensive. General Ewell has superseded General Early
                        in command of the rebel troops in the valley. Yesterday Fitzhugh Lee's
                        Division of cavalry was at Wardensville, on Cacapon River. Imboden was also
                        reported there. The rebel force at this point was over five thousand strong.
                        Mosby has been reinforced by a regiment of Virginia cavalry, and was
                        yesterday at Berryville.</p>
                    <p>A raid is expected on Winchester, or on the line of General Sheridan's
                        communications. The rebel movements have already been counteracted. To-day a
                        force from General Kelley's command successfully attacked a rebel force that
                        was moving towards Moorfield. A general engagement is now looked for in a
                        day or two. There is much indicating that the rebels will attempt to flank
                        General Sheridan in his position at Cedar Creek. Early has gone to
                    Richmond.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on news of a possible rebel offensive in the Valley.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Important From the South: Remarks on Lincoln's</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that Richmond newspapers are predicting that the reelection of
                    Lincoln will mean more "tyranny" for Northern citizens.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Gen. McClellan and the President</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Lincoln will not accept McClellan's resignation and instead
                    wants to assign the General to an important command in order to "harmonize"
                    relations between Northern political parties.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Damnable Outrage--Soldiers Hanging Democrats by Authority</head>
                <origin>Western Sun [Indiana]</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Condemns the actions of a squad of Indiana soldiers who hung and released
                    Democrats in that state who were suspected of being (but never found to be)
                    disloyal.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>News from the South: What is Said About Peace</head>
                <origin>Savannah Republican</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We confess we could never contemplate the contingency of McClellan's
                    success without an instinctive shudder at the possible consequences of such an
                    event."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A Savannah newspaper explains that Lincoln's election has simplified the
                    war goals of Southerners: "subjugation" or "independence."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>News of troop movement and skirmishing in Georgia and Arkansas, column
            5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.11.16.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Desecration of the Pulpit</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We are astonished that Christian professors can countenance such a mockery
                    of religion--such a prostitution of the sacred office of the minister--such a
                    violation of the holy Sabbath day--such a desecration of the pulpit and
                    sanctuary of the most High God!"</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On last Sunday morning a week--the Sunday immediately preceding the
                        Presidential Election--the Lutheran congregation of the place were regaled
                        with another Abolition harangue from the lips of the Rev. F. W. Conrad, the
                        Pastor in charge. We were not present to hear him, but we are told that such
                        his "speech" was disgusting and insulting in the extreme. As is well known,
                        no sooner had this man Conrad taken charge of the congregation than his
                        pulpit was converted into a political rostrum for the fulmination of
                        Abolition heresies and unqualified denunciation of all who did not fully
                        square up to the new standard of "loyalty" as laid down by Abraham Lincoln
                        and his worshippers; but it is said this last effort capped the climax of
                        fanaticism, and some few to our certain knowledge who still had a little
                        faith in him as a christian minister, have none at all now--having becoming
                        thoroughly convinced that he is nothing more than a noisy, windy,
                        half-crazed bigot and fanatic.</p>
                    <p>We regret exceedingly to be compelled to speak thus plainly of a professed
                        minister of Christ. We have heretofore refrained from saying aught while
                        urged to do so by others. But forbearance has ceased to be a virtue. We
                        conceive it to be our duty, as it is that of all right-thinking persons, to
                        raise our voice against this glaring evil which is rending in twain the
                        Church of the Redeemer. We write more in sorrow than in anger; for the Rev.
                        F. W. Conrad's Church is <emph rend="italic">our</emph> Church. In her
                        worship we took delight, and in her communion and fellowship we realized
                        many seasons of enjoyment in the days when men were <emph rend="italic"
                        >not</emph> reviled and persecuted by their brethren for entertaining honest
                        and conscientious political convictions, and before the pulpit of the Church
                        was turned into a rostrum and the demon of fanaticism had usurped the place
                        of the Prince of Peace.</p>
                    <p>On the occassion [sic] referred to the reverend gentleman, we are informed,
                        undertook to instruct this hearers <emph rend="italic">how to vote!</emph>
                        He in effect stated that all who did not vote for Abraham Lincoln would be
                        eternally damned! Did mortal man ever hear of such a bold and shameless
                        assumption? Where does the Reverend Conrad obtain the right to instruct the
                        people how to vote? Where does he find his authority for making the
                        political opinions of a man the ground of his damnation? Surely not in the
                        great commission which directs him to go into all the world and preach the
                            <emph rend="italic">Gospel</emph> (not politics) to every creature. We
                        are astonished that christian professors can countenance such a mockery of
                        religion--such a prostitution of the sacred office of the ministry--such a
                        violation of the holy Sabbath day--such a desecration of the pulpit and
                        sanctuary of the most High God!</p>
                    <p>Among the most mischievous influences which inaugurated the civil war now
                        raging in the land, and have since exasperated to diabolical hatred and
                        inhuman thirst for blood thousands of otherwise well meaning men, and even
                        inflamed to fury many of the gentler sex, is the prostitution of the pulpit
                        to partisan purposes and the degredation [sic] of clergymen from their
                        former position of usefulness to that of blatant advocates of destruction.
                        The preaching of the Reverend Conrad is of this character and has this
                        tendency. His speeches, or sermons if you please, are generally more noted
                        for rhapsody and denunciation, than for logic or truthfulness. His style is
                        of the transcendental type, largely partaking of the ranting and
                        enthusiastic. With all the zeal of a monomaniac, he combats an imaginary
                        foe--places him in a vulnerable position, and then demolishes with a
                        ruthless hand, the creation of his own brain, and claims with great egotism
                        a tremendous victory.</p>
                    <p>The introduction of politics into the pulpit by a faithless ministry, is the
                        main cause of the low state of religion in the land; and we cannot
                        reasonably expect the Church to prosper so long as the ministry are recreant
                        to their ordination vows, and continue to prostitute their sacred office.
                        While they minister in unholy things, and inflame the passions of the
                        people, and alienate a large portion of the community by their fanatical
                        course--the worship of God will wane--the courts of the sanctuary will be
                        neglected--and Zion will languish. Their ministration will be partial, and
                        pertain almost exclusively to things that are earthly and transient. Instead
                        of luring the soul to the skies, they chain it to the earth. Instead of
                        Christ, they preach an earthly potentate. Instead of promoting charity and
                        good will, they stir up strife and contention.</p>
                    <p>We pity a fallen minister, whose apostacy can be traced to extraordinary
                        temptations; but we execrate one who deliberately "steals the livery of
                        Heaven to serve the Devil in." We honor the minister who stoops not to soil
                        his office with unministerial acts, one who can preach Christ to <emph
                            rend="italic">all</emph>--who has access to <emph rend="italic"
                        >all</emph>--who can beseech <emph rend="italic">all</emph> to be reconciled
                        to God. Alas, how few yet remain in the pulpit who have not by their foolish
                        course, destroyed their usefulness. We could record numerous instances where
                        excellent and pious families have been driven from the Church by this
                        suicidal crime. No church can prosper under such a ministry.</p>
                    <p>To the class of ministers we have been describing belongs the Reverend
                        Conrad. Reverend Conrad, a professed follower of the meek and lowly Jesus;
                        Reverend Conrad, who chose the profession of preaching salvation to a fallen
                        race; Reverend Conrad, who came to announce glad tidings of the gospel of
                        peace and to save souls from perdition, (except "copperheads"); Reverend
                        Conrad, whose Master declared His kingdom was not of this world, and who
                        prayed not for the world but for those whom the Father had given him out of
                        the world; Reverend Conrad, a wolf in sheep's clothing, who preaches to the
                            <emph rend="italic">animal</emph> and not to the <emph rend="italic"
                            >spiritual</emph> man, for the applause of the multitude, and not for a
                        crown of life. In so doing, does he follow the example of the great Teacher,
                        during his mission on the earth? Did the Savior ever make political
                        speeches? Did the Apostles ever go along with the Cabal, idolizing and
                        glorifying man? Did the Disciples who were to go into all the world and
                        preach the gospel to every creature, betray their mission and make stump
                        speeches in the synogogue [sic] or elsewhere? Truly is the prophecy
                        fulfilled that in the last days perilous times shall come, with false
                        teachers having itching ears, turning many from the faith. From such turn
                        away.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Conrad</ln>
                        <fn>F. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Expresses anger that the Rev. F. W. Conrad has been preaching abolitionists
                    themes to the local Lutheran congregation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Franklin County--Official</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coffroth</ln>
                        <fn>A. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koontz</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lists the official returns for Franklin County in both the congressional
                    and presidential elections, according to each township: ANTRIM--Coffroth
                    (Democrat) (423), Koontz (Republican) (431), McClellan (443), Lincoln (468);
                    CHAMBERSBURG, NORTH WARD--Coffroth (140), Koontz (251), McClellan (143), Lincoln
                    (278); CHAMBERSBURG, SOUTH WARD--Coffroth (201), Koontz (261), McClellan (143),
                    Lincoln (278); CONCORD--Coffroth (87), Koontz (19), McClellan (93), Lincoln
                    (22); FAYETTEVILLE--Coffroth (179), Koontz (208), McClellan (190), Lincoln
                    (232); GREEN--Coffroth (102), Koontz (163), McClellan (109), Lincoln (163);
                    GUILFORD--Coffroth (183), Koontz (165), McClellan (197), Lincoln (175);
                    HAMILTON--Coffroth (132), Koontz (99), McClellan (142), Lincoln (116);
                    LETTERKENNY--Coffroth (212), Koontz (128), McClellan (227), Lincoln (136);
                    LURGAN--Coffroth (130), Koontz (80), McClellan (139), Lincoln (83);
                    METAL--Coffroth (74), Koontz (119), McClellan (83), Lincoln (124);
                    MONTGOMERY--Coffroth (139), Koontz (202), McClellan (147), Lincoln (214);
                    MORRISTOWN--Coffroth (95), Koontz (90), McClellan (98), Lincoln (94);
                    LOUDON--Coffroth (87), Koontz (78), McClellan (92), Lincoln (78);
                    PETERS--Coffroth (48), Koontz (132), McClellan (53), Lincoln (152);
                    QUINCY--Coffroth (282), Koontz (170), McClellan (209), Lincoln (181);
                    ORRSTOWN--Coffroth (110), Koontz (71), McClellan (119), Lincoln (76);
                    SOUTHAMPTON--Coffroth (67), Koontz (49), McClellan (71), Lincoln (53); SULPHUR
                    SPRING--Coffroth (41), Koontz (23), McClellan (48), Lincoln (23); ST.
                    THOMAS--Coffroth (167), Koontz (131), McClellan (169), Lincoln (138);
                    WASHINGTON--Coffroth (239), Koontz (277), McClellan (262), Lincoln (312); WELSH
                    RUN--Coffroth (135), Koontz (77), McClellan (145), Lincoln (92);
                    WARREN--Coffroth (47), Koontz (36), McClellan (57), Lincoln (50); ARMY
                    VOTE--Coffroth (137), Koontz (248), McClellan (n/a), Lincoln (n/a). The total
                    vote: Coffroth (3457), Koontz (3508), McClellan (3562), and Lincoln (3516).</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Rebels About</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Chambersburg was prepared on Saturday night for a second rebel
                    raid that did not happen. Also notes that three rebel spies were captured on the
                    Cumberland Valley Railroad.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Found Dead--Probably Murder</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"After a thorough examination of the body, and a searching investigation of
                    the circumstances attending the case, the jury found that she came to her death
                    by means of poison administered with an intent to produce abortion . . . "</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On Wednesday morning last about 10 o'clock, Mrs. Snoke, wife of William
                        Snoke, now a prisoner in Richmond, was found dead in the tenant house of Mr.
                        Henry Shearer, in which she resided, about one mile from Orrstown, in this
                        county. A jury of inquest was promptly summoned by William H. Blair, Esq.,
                        and a post-mortem examination of the corpse was made by Drs. Kennedy, of
                        Orrstown, and Hunter, of Strasburg. After a thorough examination of the
                        body, and a searching investigation of the circumstances attending the case,
                        the jury found that she came to her death by means of poison administered
                        with an intent to produce abortion; the deceased being in an advanced stage
                        of pregnancy. On Saturday last, Dr. S. D. Kell, a physician of Orrstown, was
                        arrested with the perpetration of the crime and was brought to this place
                        and confined in prison. He was brought before one of the Judges of our Court
                        on Monday last and admitted to bail in the sum of $5,000. It seems to us
                        that the bail taken in this case is insufficient, and that persons charged
                        with crimes of such high grade should be held in a larger amount. Some of
                        our Judges, however, appear to have reversed the usual order of things and
                        demand bail in an inverse ratio to the grade of crime charged; as an
                        evidence of which we would refer our readers to a recent case of <emph
                            rend="italic">Assault and Battery</emph> in which $5,000 bail was
                        demanded.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snoke</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snoke</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shearer</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blair</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunter</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kell</ln>
                        <fn>S. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that Mrs. Snoke, wife of William Snoke, a prisoner in Richmond, was
                    found dead last Wednesday morning, a victim of poisoning. The poison was found
                    to be intended to produce an abortion, and Dr. S. D. Kell of Orrstown was later
                    arrested and charged with the crime. Article complains that his $5,000 bail is
                    "insufficient."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Accident</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robinson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Tells about the wounding of Samuel Miller, son of John H. Miller, after he
                    and his friends were playing with a pistol that accidentally discharged. His
                    wound to the hand was dressed by Dr. Robinson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="j">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Court Proceedings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paxton</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Andrew</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eberly</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Williams</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trotpman</ln>
                        <fn>Philip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Radebaugh</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yeager</ln>
                        <fn>Leonard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Caseman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoner</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>Caleb</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Butler</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weisgarver</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kissecker</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Needy</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitmore</ln>
                        <fn>Ann C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoner</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bohn</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hetts</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Black</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zellers</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rule</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Philipy</ln>
                        <fn>Mathias</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ashway</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lochbaum</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lambert</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huber</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports on the results of the court session of Monday the 14th, with Judge
                    King and his associates, Judges Carson and Paxton, on the bench. In Com. vs.
                    John Andrew, in which John Andrew was charged with assault and battery for
                    "immoderately" whipping his son at school, the defendant was found not guilty.
                    Prosecutor Joseph Eberly was ordered to pay two-thirds of the court costs; In
                    Com. vs. William Williams, the defendant was found not guilty of larceny; In
                    Com. vs. Philip Troptman, a case prosecuted by John Radebaugh, the defendant was
                    found not guilty of throwing stones on the grounds of "insanity," and was
                    ordered to the Poor House for confinement; In Com. vs. Leonard Yeager, the
                    defendant was found not guilty of assault and battery. Yeager and the
                    prosecutor, John Caseman, were ordered to each pay one half of the court costs;
                    In Com. vs. William Stoner, the defendant was found guilty of assault and
                    battery. James Harris was the prosecutor in that case; In Com. vs. Caleb Harris,
                    the defendant was found not guilty of assault and battery; In Com. vs. William
                    Butler, the defendant, "a colored boy about 16 years of age," was found guilty
                    of larceny and sentenced to the House of Refuge. J. W. Weisgarver prosecuted the
                    case; In Com. vs George Smith, the defendant plead guilty for horse stealing and
                    the court ordered him to serve two years and nine months in Eastern
                    Penitentiary. John Kissecker was the prosecutor; In Com. vs. Jacob Needy, the
                    defendant was found guilty of assault and battery. Prosecutrix Ann C. Whitmore
                    and the defendant were ordered to split the court costs; In Com. vs. James Bohn
                    and John Hetts, the defendants, "small orphan boys," were found guilty of
                    larceny and sent to the House of Refuge. Robert Black was the prosecutor.
                    Results from the Court of Common Pleas: In Michael Zellers vs. James Rule, the
                    verdict was for the plaintiff, who was awarded $46.00; In Mathias Philipy vs.
                    John Ashway, the verdict was for the plaintiff, who was awarded $10.19; In
                    Andrew J. Lochbaum vs. Dr. John Lambert and John Huber, the verdict was for the
                    plaintiff, who was awarded $155.00. Also notes that the court met in the
                    basement story of the Methodist Church, which was "small and not very suitable."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Crops for the Year 1864</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"There is shown to be an abundance of food for the population. The
                    surprising part of it is that the production should be so large with so many men
                    engaged in war, and so much destruction of animal life for war purposes."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that a US Agricultural Department report shows that overall, crop
                    yields of wheat and corn were up in Northern states in 1864.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Forney</ln>
                        <fn>C. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that C. H. Forney was appointed to the eldership of the Church of
                    God representing Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hummelbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>H. Y.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cashman</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deheaven</ln>
                        <fn>Mary J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. H. Y. Hummelbaugh married Jacob Cashman, formerly of Adams County, and
                    Mary J. Deheaven on November 3.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>Ruth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Ruth Patterson, widow of the late John Patterson, of Letterkenny Township,
                    died on October 20 at age 80.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 4-7</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.11.16.04">
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 1-7</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
