<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1864/pa.fr.vs.1864.09.21">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Amy Murrell</taggerName>
            <tagDate>11/21/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 4/24/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1864-09-21">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day>21</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.09.21.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>How to Make Peace</head>
                <origin>National Intelligencer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that if it is true, as the New York Tribune has stated, that
                    two-thirds of the people on each side of the dividing line want peace, then that
                    peace plan should come from the people--and not from the Lincoln and Davis
                    administrations.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Real Issue</head>
                <origin>Age</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Familiar as are the tricks and falsehoods of the unprincipled faction,
                    which in one short term of its domination has dragged us to the brink of anarchy
                    and ruin, they are none the less dangerous on that account. The people have been
                    fed with lies, until they can scarcely recognize the truth. Their passions have
                    been stimulated by every appliance of diabolical malignity, until reason has
                    lost half of its control and nearly all its vigilance."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>There is nothing in which the perverse mendacity of the Administration and
                        its parasites is now so industriously occupied, as in falsifying the issues
                        before us, and misrepresenting the relation which is borne to them by the
                        Democratic party. In proclaiming themselves the advocates of peace, the
                        Democracy is charged with espousing the cause of the Southern Confederacy.
                        By denouncing the follies and crimes of the Administration, they are accused
                        of arraying themselves against the Government of their country, and giving
                        aid and comfort to its enemies. In appealing to the constitutional right and
                        patriotic duty of the citizen to rebuke bad rulers and take from them the
                        power they abuse, we are told that we are weakening the hands which we
                        should strengthen, and aiming side-blows at the cause which they uphold.</p>
                    <p>Familiar as are the tricks and falsehoods of the unprincipled faction, which
                        in one short term of its domination has dragged us to the brink of anarchy
                        and ruin, they are none the less dangerous on that account. The people have
                        been fed with lies, until they can scarcely recognize the truth. Their
                        passions have been stimulated by every appliance of diabolical malignity,
                        until reason has lost half of its control and nearly all its vigilance.
                        Every generous impulse has been so basely played upon--every pure and noble
                        purpose has been so systematically and wickedly distorted--that the minds
                        and hearts of men are no longer in their normal condition. The elements
                        within us are at war, like the elements without, and a truce is as needful
                        to save us from moral desolation, as from the chaos of bloody barbarism
                        towards which, as a nation, we are rushing. If the Democratic party has not
                        virtue and strength enough for the work, we are without hope, and there is a
                        darkness over the future which it is fearful to behold, and may be far more
                        fearful to penetrate. The purposes and aims of the party, therefore, should
                        not be left subject to misinterpretation, or misrepresentation. They should
                        be made as distinct and clear as they are patriotic and elevated. No man
                        should be able to misunderstand them, unless wil[l]fully.</p>
                    <p>Once for all, then, the great end and object of the Democratic party, in this
                        struggle, is the vindication of the rights and liberties of our own people,
                        and the re-establishment of republican institutions among ourselves, under a
                        constitutional government and honest rulers. To this great consummation all
                        other things tend, and everything else is merely tributary. The system of
                        government which our fathers gave us, had for its chief, great end, the
                        liberty of the citizen. All the institutional [illegible] which it provides
                        were but auxiliary to this. The Union itself was devised but as a means of
                        fortifying individual freedom, by building around to the bulwarks of
                        national independence and power. The freedom and security, then, of the
                        citizen, are what the Democratic party is now fighting for. Without law and
                        Constitution, neither freedom, nor security can exist, and the Democratic
                        party, therefore, is fighting for Constitution and law. The corrupt and
                        bloody dynasty which it is laboring to over-turn, has trampled down the laws
                        and laughed the Constitution to scorn. The Democratic party, therefore, is
                        the sworn enemy of the profligate usurpers at Washington, and, in the name
                        of republican liberty, has summoned the people to cast them out.</p>
                    <p>The question, then, in the canvass which is opening, is not merely between
                        peace and war, but between military despotism and constitutional right. The
                        Democratic party is the herald and champion of peace--not because it
                        sympathises with rebellion, but because it is on the side of its own
                        birth-right. It is against the further prosecution of an iniquitous and
                        bloody war--not merely because it leans to humanity and civilization; not
                        merely because it sees, in the mad policy of State coercion, a violation of
                        the spirit and faith of the compact and a wicked futility and crime; but
                        because it feels and knows that a military organization which can crush the
                        South, will be too strong for the freedom of the North. It has already felt
                        the iron hand of military despotism. Its presses have been silenced by armed
                        force. Its best citizens have been dragged from dungeon to dungeon, or
                        exiled from home and country, for no crime but their opinions. The ballot
                        box has been fenced around by bayonets and the right of suffrage has been
                        made a soldier's mockery. State legislatures have been suppressed, and State
                        rights turned into jest. To combine and organize as a party, under the
                        shield of the law and the guarantees of the Constitution, is to
                        "conspire"--to purchase arms for self-protection, is to be in rebellion and
                        challenge the hangman. Free speech has become "disloyalty" free thought is
                        "moral treason." Military commissions have superseded trial by jury, and
                        military arrogance has set judicial process at defiance. The President's
                        mere order has been made, by act of Congress, a flat bar to prosecution for
                        every crime, and to all civil remedy for every outrage committed under it.
                        There is no home sacred, no sex secure, no age respected, no right
                        inviolate. Aggressions multiply every day, with increasing insolence and
                        aggravation. While the war lasts, they will go on multiplying, for the
                        necessities of war are their sole pretext. Peace, then, is their only cure,
                        and our only salvation. It is for this that the Democracy covet peace, and
                        will spare no honorable or manly effort to secure it. They are not willing
                        to become enslaved, themselves, in the vain and iniquitous attempt to compel
                        "the abandonment of slavery," elsewhere. They will not consent that the red
                        hand of the conscription shall be on their throat, under pretense of
                        throttling the rebels. They will not surrender their own liberties for the
                        unholy purpose of subjugating or exterminating a people, but yesterday their
                        brethren.</p>
                    <p>These, then, are the issues. To the South, the Administration proposes that
                        its people shall live with us on our terms, or die. To the people of the
                        North, it declares that they shall abandon their own freedom, to trample the
                        South into submission or annihilation. The Democratic party will submit to
                        neither alternative. It will be neither savage nor serf. Its policy towards
                        the South will be guided by justice and humanity, and will be developed in
                        due time; but its present concern is the salvation of the North. Its present
                        battle is one of self-preservation. Peace and war, slavery and emancipation,
                        victories and defeats, all matters of policy and detail, it holds as
                        nothing, beside the great fundamental and absorbing question of public and
                        private liberty. There it has taken its stand, and around it, if there be
                        manhood and virtue left in the people, virtue and manhood will rally unto
                            victory.--<emph rend="italic">Age</emph>.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Criticizes the Lincoln administration for suggesting that the Democratic
                    party is supporting the Confederacy. Argues instead that the Democratic party
                    only wants peace.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Historical Record</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lists the names of all the Presidents and Vice Presidents who have ever
                    served the United States. Also lists the opponents faced by these men in their
                    respective elections.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 1-4</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.09.21.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Our Office</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wunderlich</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nead</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces that the Valley Spirit's new office is located in the warehouse
                    of Messrs. Wunderlich and Nead.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Peace</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Agrees with the remarks of Senator Semmes of Louisiana to the rebels there
                    in which he suggests that Southern hopes for peace are dependent on the success
                    of the Democratic party in the North.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Don't Like It</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"It is interesting, as well as amusing, to witness the contortions of our
                    neighbor of the Repository. He stamps and foams and morts, under the stinging
                    force of this letter, like a mad bull in fly-time."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Calls the Repository's criticism of General McClellan's letter accepting
                    the Democratic nomination an "absurdity."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Democratic Party and Peace</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Refutes a Republican claim that Democrats support a "humiliating peace."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>For Little Mac and the Union</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lists names of prominent former Whigs or current Republicans who have
                    decided to support McClellan, including ex-President Filmore.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Conferee Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coffroth</ln>
                        <fn>A. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>General</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kimmel</ln>
                        <fn>Francis M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that the Democratic conferees of the 16th congressional district
                    met on September 12 and unanimously nominated Gen. A. H. Coffroth for Congress.
                    Also notes that the judicial conference met at the same time and unanimously
                    nominated Hon. Francis M. Kimmel for president judge.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Congressional Conference</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>William M. McClane, Pres., John Palmer, Sec.</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClane</ln>
                        <fn>William M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palmer</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duncan</ln>
                        <fn>Augustus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Croft</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duncan</ln>
                        <fn>C. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes that at the September 12 meeting of the 16th congressional district
                    conferees, Augustus Duncan, John Croft, and C. M. Duncan represented Franklin
                    County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Judicial Conference</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>W. S. Nelson, Pres., O. E. Shannon, Sec.</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nelson</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shannon</ln>
                        <fn>O. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Croft</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn>James B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duncan</ln>
                        <fn>C. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that Democrats John Croft, James B. Orr, and C. M. Duncan
                    represented Franklin County at the September 12 meeting of the 16th judicial
                    district.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Hon. F. M. Kimmel</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kimmel</ln>
                        <fn>F. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Hails the nomination by the Democrats of F. M. Kimmel for the president
                    judge of this district.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>McClellan's Midnight Letter to Lincoln</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Discusses a letter written by McClellan to Lincoln right before he was
                    removed from command, which suggests that McClellan was not guilty of "treason"
                    but instead was "patriotic."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Richmond Enquirer for Lincoln</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the Richmond Enquirer published a column in support of Lincoln
                    for President. The Enquirer reasoned that it would be easier for the South to
                    make peace with an "anti-slavery fanatic" than with an "earnest Unionist."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Suggests that the election of McClellan will help the Southern people to
                    "throw off the grasp of their leaders" and get back into a Union where their
                    rights and institutions will be protected.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>"What Cheer"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Everywhere the nomination of Gen. McClellan has roused the utmost
                    enthusiasm in the ranks of the Democracy. Every Democratic vote will be polled
                    in November, and no one needs to be told that victory perches on the banners of
                    the party whose candidates elicit a full party vote."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We are constantly cheered with such evidences of the zeal, the vigor, and the
                        confidence of Democrats in all parts of the country that it is our duty to
                        make the facts known to all our friends who are hard at work, each in his
                        own vicinity, and who may desire to know "what cheer" comes from
                        fellow-workers beyond their own range of observation.</p>
                    <p>1. Everywhere the nomination of Gen. McClellan has roused the utmost
                        enthusiasm in the ranks of the Democracy. Every Democratic vote will be
                        polled in November, and no one needs to be told that victory perches on the
                        banners of the party whose candidates elicit a full party vote.</p>
                    <p>Moreover, the young men are with us everywhere. The young men who have come
                        of age since the last presidential election will vote the young men's
                        ticket. "Little Mac" is the man they want for President.</p>
                    <p>2. The defections from the Republican party are increasing daily, and they
                        have only begun to be counted. Our correspondents write us from almost every
                        state, of this man or that man, prominent in his city or county, who voted
                        for Mr. Lincoln in 1860, but who will vote for McClellan in November. The
                        changes of this sort which are well known of in this city will be matched in
                        every other city in the North. Party ties are straw to American citizens,
                        when by disregarding them a vote can be given for Union and peace. We hear
                        of several distinguished men, recognized leaders in this and adjoining
                        states, who have strained a point to support the administration while it was
                        charged with the responsibilities of government, who will seize the
                        opportunity to vote out the men who have so wretchedly failed to discharge
                        their responsibilities. These men mean not only to vote for, but to work
                        hard for the election of General McClellan.</p>
                    <p>3. The influence which the discharged and disabled soldiers of the republic
                        are exerting in favor of Gen. McClellan is tremendous. Every one of them has
                        cycle of friends, and they are making proselytes by the hundred. The
                        calumnies of the Lincoln organs against their favorite commander only
                        inflame them into more ardent exertions. Soldiers who have served in the
                        Army of the Potomac can't listen to these wholesale slanders with much
                        patience, and there are enough of them scattered over the country to nail
                        every new lie to the counter as fast as it is uttered.</p>
                    <p>4. We speak what we know when we say that there will be no defection from the
                        ranks of the Democratic party worth considering--no "bolt" worth counting.
                        The mistake made by our anxious Republican friends, and by the few bolters
                        themselves, was in supposing that the Democratic masses wanted peace at the
                        expense of the Union, that they would for a moment think of purchasing peace
                        at the price even of one hour's risk of disunion. Gentlemen of the
                        administration party, you reckoned without your host. You made the blunder
                        of believing your own slanders of the patriots arrayed against you!</p>
                    <p>And mark! For every disunion "bolter" who has left us, and so purified the
                        party, one hundred Union and peace-loving men will march out of your ranks
                        into ours!</p>
                    <p>5. The pledge of the Chicago platform, which Gen. McClellan accepted, of
                        course, when he accepted the nomination of the Chicago Convention, was that
                        one earnest, frank and fraternal effort should be made for peace--for peace
                        if possible "without the effusion of another drop of blood"--for the peace
                        which every honest man "would hail with unbounded joy"--for peace on the
                        basis of the Union--the condition <emph rend="italic">sine qua non</emph>.
                        And whenever there is good reason to believe that the rebels are "ready for
                        such a peace" in God's name, should we not make all haste to give them
                        peace?" Will any Republican who loves his country and his fellow-men answer
                        us that?</p>
                    <p>This is what the "peace sentiment of the Democratic party" means. We share
                        this peace sentiment, avow it, and now and at all times will uphold and
                        defend it. This is all that it means. There is no division in our ranks. If
                        any man who has called himself a Democrat means more than this--which is
                        fairly implied in the much-abused Chicago platform, and clearly expressed in
                        the much-praised letter of acceptance of Gen. McClellan--then he is a
                        Democrat no longer.</p>
                    <p>And we wish to be understood as meaning precisely what we say when we add
                        that this and nothing but this is the peace sentiment of the great West, and
                        that, in full and satisfied expression of this sentiment, the whole
                        Democracy of the West will cast its vote for McClellan and Pendleton next
                        November, God sparing their lives.--<emph rend="italic">World</emph>.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes "the zeal, the vigor, and the confidence" of Democrats in
                    Franklin County for those supporters who live out in the country and cannot
                    witness the enthusiasm for themselves.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Previously published political notices, column 1</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.09.21.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>"No Partyism" in the Army</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on an incident in which a Democratic soldier was passed up for a
                    first lieutenant commission in favor of a Republican.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Discouraging Enlistments</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Accuses the Repository of discouraging men from enlisting. Points to a
                    report of three workers in a machine shop who decided against enlisting after
                    reading the paper.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Sword Presentation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kuhn</ln>
                        <fn>N. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Embich</ln>
                        <fn>Milton A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports on the ceremony surrounding the presentation of a sword by Milton
                    A. Embich and other members of the 209th Pennsylvania Volunteers to Lieut. N. W.
                    Kuhn.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Come to Grief</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that a member of the 202nd Pennsylvania Volunteers tried escaping
                    from jail last Sunday but fell and severely injured himself in the process.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>State Fair</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that the Pennsylvania State Agricultural Society will hold its
                    next fair in Easton, Pennsylvania, on September 27-30, 1864.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beys</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foust</ln>
                        <fn>Margaretta</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev.M. Snyder married Henry Beys and Margaretta Foust on September 13.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Previously published political notices, column 1; reports on skirmishing in
                Virginia at Coggin's Point, column 3; classified ads, columns 4-7</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.09.21.04">
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 1-7</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
