<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1864/pa.fr.vs.1864.05.18">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Amy Murrell</taggerName>
            <tagDate>10/21/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 4/2/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1864-05-18">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day>18</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.05.18.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Ecclesiastical Indolence</head>
                <origin>New York Democratic Press</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"'This duty of unconditional, unreversed loyalty,' says the Reverend R. . .
                    . . 'to the constitutionally elected government of the nation, we desire to
                    reaffirm as a principle of our holy religion and a part of our allegiance to
                    God.' Was there ever a sillier piece of nonsense than this written?"</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Condemns the "pulpit politicians" of the North for calling support for the
                    US government a Christian duty.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Week of Battles</head>
                <origin>New York World</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"At the close of the seven days fight upon the Peninsula we had occasion
                    for thankfulness that so many of our brave men had been spared; at the period of
                    writing we have the record of a series of victories, which may probably result
                    in the speedy crushing of the rebellion. We now see light and hope where all
                    before was midnight gloom, and look forward to a brilliant future for our arms
                    and the cause in which they are engaged."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>From the New York World.</p>
                    <p>Washington, May 10</p>
                    <p>But once before, in the history of this rebellion, have we been called upon
                        to record a series of engagements extending over a period of one week. That
                        occasion was when General McClellan, after failing in his attempt to capture
                        Richmond, when the best devised plans had come to naught, was compelled to
                        save his army by a retrograde movement to the James river, and was followed
                        at every step by the overwhelming hosts of the enemy. The details of those
                        dreadful battles filled the mind with horror and almost with despair, with
                        scarcely a ray of hope for the future to illume the darkness that then
                        pervaded the dead horizon. The contrast now is far different. We record the
                        heroic deeds of a gallant army now as we did then, and accord the full meed
                        of praise to those who fought as only men can fight who are impelled by the
                        purest and most patriotic motives. We painted them as we do now, the gallant
                        deeds of those noble men in their brightest colors, mourned with those who
                        were called upon to mourn, and rejoiced with those who had cause for
                        congratulation. At the close of the seven days fight upon the Peninsula we
                        had occasion for thankfulness that so many of our brave men had been spared;
                        at the period of writing we have the record of a series of victories, which
                        may probably result in the speedy crushing of the rebellion. We now see
                        light and hope where all before was midnight gloom, and look forward to a
                        brilliant future for our arms and the cause in which they are engaged. We
                        give herewith a comprehensive resume of the battles of the week. When the
                        shades of Tuesday, May 3, fell upon the Army of the Potomac, that vast
                        tented field gave forth no sign of movement. All was serene as it had been
                        for months before, but all was ready for the signal from the lips of him
                        whom the nation had called to the command of its armies. By midnight,
                        however, this peaceful scene had changed. Every corps of the army was in
                        motion, marching to a destination unknown even to the corps commanders and
                        directed to the accomplishments of the well-matured plans of General Grant.
                        By the morning of Wednesday, the late camps had been abandoned, and men had
                        marched to new scenes and fairly entered upon the campaign which was
                        destined to be one of victory or defeat. The hosts of Lee's army lay upon
                        the south bank of the Rapidan, where they had entrenched themselves and
                        rested comparatively undisturbed since the battle of Mine run, late in the
                        autumn. All day on Wednesday the Army of the Potomac pursued its way over a
                        distance of more than fifteen miles across Germania and Ely's fords of the
                        Rapidan, to execute a well devised flank movement. All day long the steady
                        stream of men and munitions of war continued to file along the roads and
                        across the river. Quietly they moved, stepping with the tread of veterans,
                        each man determined to do his duty manfully and nobly, be the consequences
                        what they might. By dark on Wednesday night the Fifth corps, General Warren,
                        the Sixth, General Sedgwick, and the Second General Hancock, had crossed the
                        Rapidan and bivouacked upon the south bank and the historic field of
                        Chancellorsville. The cavalry advance, which preceded the main army some
                        distance, had encountered a small force of the enemy, but no engagement of
                        importance took place and the reconnoissance was affected with slight loss.
                        Thus far the advance had been successful, and that night the mighty army
                        rested from the fatigues of the day in order to prepare for the bloody
                        scenes of the morrow. All felt that Thursday's sun would not set without
                        witnessing a battle, for the lines had been thrown so far forward that a
                        collision must inevitably follow any further advance. Notwithstanding this,
                        however, not a man faltered nor a cheek blanched with fear. The issues must
                        be met; the period for action had arrived; the army was prepared; and each
                        strove to do his duty in this trying hour.</p>
                    <p>The Battle of Thursday, May 5.</p>
                    <p>Early in the morning the Fifth and Sixth corps were in motion, and about 8
                        o'clock the center of the Fifth had reached the intersection of the turnpike
                        and plank roads leading from Fredericksburg to Orange Court House, and near
                        the "Wilderness." In its front was a broken and very irregular table land,
                        densely covered with plank timber and undergrowth, and almost impassable.
                        The eye could penetrate but a short distance into the maze of forest, and
                        nature seemed to have exerted her curious handiwork to vail [sic] all
                        beyond. Here was a dark curtain completely hiding the country in front, and
                        presenting a barrier to rapid progress, or even the most careful
                        maneuvering. The turnpike at this point was crossed at right angles by the
                        road leading to Spottsylvania Court House. The army halted in column. The
                        Second corps was on the left, and the Fifth and Sixth occupied the center
                        and right respectively. The army thus remained motionless, momentarily
                        expecting the order to march, until about noon, when the headquarters
                        standard was fixed near Wilderness Tavern, and corps commanders began to
                        gather around it awaiting the order for a further movement. A consultation
                        ensued, notes were examined, but still no welcome order to march. At last
                        Gen. Warren left headquarters, took the head corps, and the Fifth filed over
                        the point of a hill to the left of Wilderness Tavern, and upon the summit of
                        this eminence headquarters were removed. Line of battle was then formed with
                        the whole army and scarcely had this been accomplis[h]ed when the sound of
                        dropping shot indicated that skirmishing had begun. These evidences of
                        strife were heard to the right and south of Wilderness Tavern, and proceeded
                        from the engagement of a brigade of Griffin's division of the Fifth corps
                        with the enemy, who had thrown one of his corps forward, preliminary to an
                        attack on the whole line. The battle raged fiercely with this portion of the
                        command until noon, when it became general. The brigade had scarcely formed
                        for action when it was met by a heavy volley of musketry and the rebels,
                        taking advantage of the momentary confusion, rushed forward at a charge. The
                        ground had not been perfectly reconnoitered and in an attempt to employ
                        artillery in repulsing the charge, two guns of battery D, First New York,
                        were captured. These, however, were all the trophies the rebels succeeded in
                        taking during the entire action. The charge was repulsed with infantry and
                        Warren's corps soon became engaged against heavy masses of the enemy.
                        Shortly after Gen. Sedgwick's army became involved. The rebels pressed
                        forward steadily but were as steadily forced back, and the lines of the
                        army, after repeated assaults, remained intact. The strife here was trifling
                        compared with that in which General Hancock was engaged. Against him
                        Longstreet; one of Lee's ablest lieutenants, had been thrown, and such was
                        the nature of the ground that the fight was one almost wholly of musketry.
                        No artillery could be brought to bear, and as the fight progressed the sound
                        of small arms was terrific. Charge after charge by Longstreet was met and
                        repulsed by volleys of musketry, delivered at short range and with terrible
                        effect. Gradually, however, the enemy drew off, the firing ceased, night
                        fell, and the battle was over for the day. The enemy had failed to drive us
                        back from the field, although his efforts to do so were most persistent. He
                        had had advantage of a naturally protected field of operations in which to
                        maneuver, and this enabled him to handle his forces with the utmost
                        rapidity, secrecy, and skill. The army was compelled to remain watchful
                        along the whole line, not knowing at what point the enemy might be most
                        expected, and uncertain how to maneuver to foil the adversary. Yet with all
                        these advantages, Lee was unable to accomplish his object; and, though
                        victory did not perch upon our eagles, it certainly did not rest upon his.
                        Lee, in his official despatch to the rebel Secretary of War states that the
                        attack was made by our troops; whereas it is evident from our accounts that
                        the rebels themselves made the attack; for they came out from their
                        entrenchments on Mine run with the probable intention of driving the Army of
                        the Potomac back across the Rapidan. In this engagement the rebels lost
                        General J.M. Jones, and Col. Warren of the 10th Virginia, killed, and Gen.
                        Stafford mortally wounded. We lost heavily in the battle, and among the
                        officers killed was Gen. Alex. Hays, of Pennsylvania. Lee made two
                        ineffectual attempts on this day to out our army in two, but did not
                        succeed. his strength was developed by the movement, and Gen. Grant deemed
                        it advisable to order up Gen. Burnside's corps which had been left as a
                        reserve near Manassas. This reinforcement made a most extraordinary march in
                        order to obey the command, and arrived within supporting distance of the
                        army before nightfall. Lieut. Gen. Grant was upon the field during the
                        afternoon, and seemed satisfied with the progress of affairs.</p>
                    <p>The Battle of Friday May 6.</p>
                    <p>This day scarcely dawned ere the engagement was resumed, Longstreet massing
                        his column against General Hancock's corps with great determination. It was
                        alternately pushed backward and charged forward, and once was driven close
                        to his field-works; but rallying again he drove the rebels before him with
                        great slaughter. He had been fighting with indomitable courage for several
                        hours, until finally he was reinforced by Burnside, and the contest on this
                        portion of the line ceased. But the corps had suffered terribly; they fought
                        with the utmost heroism, and are deserving of the highest praise. The enemy
                        failing to pierce the lines at this point, next hurled his masses against
                        Sedgwick's corps, the Sixth. This attack was conducted by A.P. Hill, and was
                        most desperately made. The right of the Sixth was turned and almost
                        instantly Milroy's old brigade was swallowed up, with the loss of
                        Brigadier-General Seymour, of Olustee fame, and General Shaler, who were
                        taken prisoners. The disaster was retrieved, however, and the enemy in turn
                        met with a repulse. The safety of the army, at this moment, was insured by
                        General Sedgwick, for, had the rebels succeeded in overpowering him, the
                        Army of the Potomac would have been cut in twain, and it would have required
                        the utmost skill of the generals, as well as the most indomitable courage
                        and heroic self-sacrifices of the men, to have checked the onward tide of
                        the enemy and saved the army from ruin. Happily, however, the danger was
                        averted, and the rebels, having been foiled in their purpose, withdrew from
                        the field.--in the early part of the day the enemy made an attempt to pierce
                        General Warren's corps, but failed as signally as they did in their later
                        efforts. During the engagement of this day Brigadier General Wadsworth was
                        killed. Thus had the enemy attempted to pursue the tactics, peculiar to Lee,
                        of hurling heavy mas[s]es of troops, first upon one and and [sic] then upon
                        the other wing and center of our army. He failed in every endeavor, however,
                        and was compelled to give up the contest at nightfall, baffled at all
                        points.--thus closed the second day of the battle of the Wilderness.</p>
                    <p>Operations of Saturday May 7.</p>
                    <p>After the terrible struggle of the last two days, and the vigor with which
                        the enemy had fallen upon and had outflanked General Sedgwick's corps at the
                        very last moment on Friday, the Union army was in any thing but a a [sic]
                        hopeful condition. Judging by the [sic] temper of the men, the feeling was
                        that our troops although repulsing every attack had perhaps on the whole,
                        the worst of the fighting. The valor of the rebels was so desperate and the
                        handling of Lee's troops so masterly, that our men, at least many of them
                        felt they had a harder job before them than they had anticipated. The battle
                        commenced however at daylight between the advance pickets of the two armies.
                        From all appearances Lee seemed intent upon turning our right so as to get
                        between the Union army and Lieutenant general Grant, and General Grant and
                        General Meade came up to the scene of action. The men, who had been fighting
                        all day, gladly hailed the lieutenant general by loud cheers. The weather
                        throughout was exceedingly warm, and many of the men were sun-struck.</p>
                    <p>The Position of Affairs, Monday May 7.</p>
                    <p>After the continuons [sic] march and fighting of a whole week the army
                        impratively [sic] demanded rest. The six days' provisions, with which the
                        troops had marched out on the Wednesday preceedeing [sic] had about run out,
                        and it became necessary to replenish the haversacks and company wagons. A
                        halt was therefore made till the supply wagons should be emptied. The number
                        of wounded also was fearfully large, and it would be inhuman not to bend the
                        whole energies of the army to have them conveyed to the rear and attended
                        to. The wounded and all, are estimated as high as nineteen thousand men,
                        which includes of course all the battles. The killed outright are supposed
                        to number three thousand five hundred, while of missing there are are [sic]
                        in the neighborhood of five thousand, almost all of whom had been captured
                        in the fights of Thursday and Friday. Monday was well spent in bringing
                        forward the artillery, in getting the army in motion, unloading the supply
                        wagons, getting new cartridges, and making preparations for the advance on
                        Spottsylvania Court House which took place during the afternoon of that day.
                        By evening the whole army was well advanced, and, unexpected to the enemy,
                        General Hancock's second corps, which was the freshest of the various
                        commands, was ordered to the front to drive the rebels from the village, and
                        occupy the lower bank of the Po. Ewel's corps contested the advance, but
                        Hancock's command went valiantly on, and for two hours one of the most
                        desperate fights of the whole four took place. There are two theories
                        current in the army touching the movements of Lee; one is that it is only
                        Ewell's corps with which we have been fighting for the last two days, and
                        that the rest of Lee's army has fallen back to Richmond to overwhelm the
                        forces under Generals Smith and Gilmore. The general opinion, however, is
                        that all of Lee's army is still near to the front, and that they will resist
                        our forces at every river crossing, drawing us thereby farther and farther
                        from our base of supplies, while they get nearer to theirs, and are
                        strengthened thereby. There have been rumors in the army that the forces of
                        Generals Gilmore and Smith are coming up the Rappahannock to Fredericsburg
                        with the view of reinforcing the army by the overland route. If this should
                        prove true it would make our success certain; but it is not believed that
                        there are transports enough or that such a movement enters into the plan of
                        campaign which governs against Richmond.</p>
                    <p>The Battle of Tuesday May 8. <lb/> The Sixth and most Desperate Battle of the
                        Campaign--Graphic Account of the Conflict by Eyewitnesses--Our Men Scale the
                        Enemy's Breastworks with their hands--Nine Hundred Prisoners Captured.</p>
                    <p>Headquarters Army of the Potomac, <lb/>Battle Field Near Spottsylvania,
                        <lb/>May 11--8 o'clock A.M.</p>
                    <p>The battles of the Wilderness were continued yesterday in the most sanguinary
                        of six bloody engagements which have distinguished this campaign. The army
                        was disposed at early morning as follows, slightly in advance of the
                        position occupied the previous day. The Second corps on the right, west of
                        the River Po, and nearly in a line with the road running from Shady Grove
                        Church to Spottsylvania Court House; the Fifth corps in the center east of
                        the river and facing southwestward of Spottsylvania, and the Sixth corps on
                        the left, facing toward Spottsylvania. Batteries were posted inthe [sic]
                        rear at all available points--Burns's Arnold's, Sleeper's, Rodgers's, and
                        Ayell's batteries supporting the right and protecting the bridge across the
                        Po river, formed of three pontoons.</p>
                    <p>Meade's and Stewart's batteries were disposed toward the left of the Fifth
                        corps in front of a wood. The country is quite as wretched and barbarous for
                        fighting purposes as that beyond the old Wilderness tavern on the Germania
                        plank-road.</p>
                    <p>There are a few scattered openings across which our lines of battle could be
                        seen at intervals, but the main position of our own army and that of the
                        enemy was concealed as heretofore by the dense forest which made the battle
                        almost a mystery. Desultory fighting began early in the day. Our artillery
                        at from eight o'clock A.M. until after dark, was never silent. From every
                        position wherever the enemy's lines were at all exposed the guns belched
                        forth upon them a tempest of shrieking shot and shell.</p>
                    <p>Mink's battery, attached to the Fifth corps, and posted on the edge of the
                        forest mentioned, evidently did terrible execution; and about eleven o'clock
                        in the day a charge of the enemy, intended to effect its capture, was
                        repulsed. Musketry firing by sharpshooters and fierce skirmishes continued
                        at different points during the forenoon.</p>
                    <p>The enemy had evidently massed the greater portion of his troops on his left
                        and left center. It having been determined to assault his center, the
                        divisions of Gibbons and Birney, belonging to the Second corps, were
                        withdrawn across the Po river to assist the attack. The first brigade,
                        Robinson's, and the Second brigade of Cutter's division Fifth corps, General
                        Rice, commenced the fighting. Griffin's division and the main portion of the
                        Fifth corps, and Gibbons's division of the Second, then advanced, driving
                        the enemy into their rifle pits after several hours of battle, during which
                        the roar of musketry was louder and more continuous [t]han at Gettysburg.
                            <emph rend="italic">The works were not taken</emph>.</p>
                    <p>General Rice was killed early in the fight, while getting his column into
                        position.</p>
                    <p>Meanwhile, Barlow's division of the Second corps, left across the Po river,
                        and facing in a line nearly perpendicular to our general line, was attacked
                        by a heavy body of the enemy in flank, and forced to swing round. A second
                        charge of the rebels in overwhelming force <emph rend="italic">drove the
                            right of the division still further around,</emph> its rear in line with
                        the river. Holding its own for a time, it finally withdrew across the bridge
                        still fighting.</p>
                    <p>Officers returning from the right exaggerated the occurrence into a position
                        very dangerous to army headquarters, tents, &amp;c., which were suddenly
                        struck, and the force evacuated at double quick.</p>
                    <p>The loss in all this fighting was very severe, both in men and officers.</p>
                    <p>General Barlow, being still pressed after retiring across the river, kept on
                        fighting until dark.</p>
                    <p>Meanwhile the dispositions for a general assault by our whole line, which had
                        been made in the afternoon to take place at 5 o'clock, were postponed until
                        nearly dark. At 6 o'clock a withering fire upon the enemy's lines was opened
                        by all our batteries in position; the roar and shrieking of shell and
                        garpe-shot [sic] was awful. Generals Grant and Meade, with their staffs,
                        took position, on a hill overlooking the woods, but from which very little
                        of the battle itself could be seen.</p>
                    <p>At 6 1/2 o'clock precisely the engagement began with vindictive vigor. A
                        portion of General Upton's brigades, of the Sixth corps, consisting of the
                        One Hundred and Twenty-first New York, Fifteenth Maine, Ninety-sixth and One
                        Hundred and Nineteenth Pennsylvania, the Fifth Wisconsin, Sixth Maine and
                        Forty-ninth Pennsylvania, of General Russell's old brigade, and the
                        Seventy-seventh New York, Forty-third Wisconsin, Second, Fifth and Sixth
                        Vermont, with the Ninety-fifth Pennsylvania, Sixtieth New York, and Second
                        New Jersey, partially in reserve, moved against the enemy's rifle-pits some
                        three hundred yards in their front. A portion of the route was across an
                        open space, where the lines were subjected to a deadly fire of grape and
                        canister. <emph rend="italic">They moved steadily forward, however, without
                            firing a shot until they reached the breastworks, which they scaled with
                            their hands and knees, driving the enemy out and capturing nine hundred
                            prisoners.</emph> The assault was at the same time made by the Fifth and
                        a portion of the Second corps to the right and center in the following
                        order: Ward's brigade, of Birney's division, in rear on the right;
                        Crawford's division Pennsylvania Reserves, in two lines in front on the
                        right; Gibbons's division next on the left; the Fifth corps troops in
                        center; Griffin's division on the left. The assault was undertaken with
                        varying enthusiasm, <emph rend="italic">but failed</emph>. Our men were
                        nearly exhausted and fell back. <emph rend="italic">We did not take any
                            position of the enemy</emph>.</p>
                    <p>General Upton, whose achievements on the left are described, finding himself
                        so far in advance of the main army, hard pressed and unsupported, retired
                        from his position. <emph rend="italic">I cannot perceive that the day's
                            fighting has brought us any substantial advantage</emph>. We had
                        advanced beyond the line occupied by us the previous night. Our right wing,
                        at least, has <emph rend="italic">been forced, from its position; the enemy
                            still hold their own</emph>, and we rest on our arms this morning,
                        having suffered since, the same hour yesterday, a loss which to estimate is
                        quite impossible.</p>
                    <p>It is note-worthy that in yesterday's engagements, in which we suffered so
                        seriously, the enemy did not employ much artillery, we had the advantage of
                        position for artillery from the fire of which the foe must have greatly
                        suffered, but in positions for troops <emph rend="italic">they held that
                            dreaded advantage which the formation of the country enables them to
                            maintain</emph>. I believe we shall get Richmond in time. <emph
                            rend="italic">Not even General Grant can quite overcome the difficulties
                            of this route</emph>. The enemy retiring before our troops, select their
                        own fighting ground, are covered by the woods and protected by abatis and
                        intrenchments, while our own troops, as during yesterday, <emph
                            rend="italic">are forced to expose themselves in charges across open
                            fields, where both artillery and musketry do tremendous
                        execution</emph>.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Provides a general overview of troop movements and battles in Virginia May
                    5-8. Acknowledges setbacks but predicts that Union soldiers will take Richmond
                    before long.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.05.18.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>A Confusion of Ideas</head>
                <origin>Pittsburgh Post</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Applauds an abolitionist newspaper in Massachusetts for recognizing that
                    the Democratic party is the only "truthful" party around, the only one not
                    founded on "fast principles."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Why Generals Are Removed</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The merits of the officer or his past achievements will do him no good,
                    because personal hostility to McClellan is considered of more importance than
                    crushing the rebellion."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Criticizes the arbitrary ways by which the government has dismissed
                    generals, such as George McClellan. Suggests that "the people" would be better
                    able to determine whether a general should stay in his position.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Poetry and fiction, columns 1-3, classified ads, columns 4-6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.05.18.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>What a Garden May Be</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Offers suggestions for making gardens produce more vegetables more
                    efficiently.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 2-6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.05.18.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Military Situation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"It will be seen that after eight days of the bloodiest fighting of the
                    war, the two hostile armies still confront each other on the banks of the Po
                    river. Whilst our army has been gradually gaining ground on the enemy, its
                    advance has been met with a stubbornness of resistance which still holds victory
                    trembling in the balance."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Our readers will find in to-day's paper an account of the military operations
                        of the past week, as far as received up to the time of going to press. It
                        will be seen that after eight days of the bloodiest fighting of the war, the
                        two hostile armies still confront each other on the banks of the Po river.
                        Whilst our army has been gradually gaining ground on the enemy, its advance
                        has been met with a stubborness of resistance which still holds victory
                        trembling in the balance. After the battles on the Rapidan, Lee fell back to
                        the neighborhood of Spottsylvania Court House, where a series of battles
                        were fought, the heaviest of which took place on Thursday. The battle was
                        opened early on Thursday morning by General Hancock surprising the eastern
                        flank of the enemy and capturing one whole division and thirty cannon.
                        During the day the rebels re-captured twelve of the cannon. The fight closed
                        late in the evening without any decisive result, leaving us in possession of
                        eighteen cannon and from three to four thousand prisoners. Our men slept on
                        their arms during the night, expecting to renew the attack in the morning.
                        When morning came it was found that the enemy had withdrawn to a new line
                        about four miles beyond, on the banks of the Po river, where he now is
                        strongly intrenched. Since then there has been no fighting of which we have
                        heard. The latest news from General Grant states that owing to the late
                        heavy rains and consequent muddy condition of the roads, the army is unable
                        to operate. The loss in these battles, in killed, wounded and missing, has
                        been terrific. Ours has been estimated as high as seventy thousand, and that
                        of the enemy equal, if not greater.</p>
                    <p>The line of battle formed by the enemy on Thursday was six miles South of
                        Chancelorsville, and nine miles south of the Rappahannock at United States
                        Ford. Their new line is thirteen miles from the Rappahannock. From
                        Spottsylvania to Hanover Junction is twenty-four miles. From Spottsylvania
                        to Richmond is forty-seven miles. South of the Po and between it and the
                        South Anna, there are various streams all about the size of the Po and
                        running through a similar country. First comes the Ta; then the Mat; then
                        the East Northeast creek; then Polecat river; then the North Anna; then
                        Little river; Newfound river and the South Anna. The two armies, as before
                        stated, now confront each other on the Po, that river running between them.</p>
                    <p>General Sheridan has made an extensive cavalry raid in the rear of Lee's
                        army. He cut the Virginia Central railroad, destroyed a large quantity of
                        provisions and several trains of cars, passed the fortifications of Richmond
                        and found them very strong, had several severe contests with the enemy, and
                        finally reached the James river and formed a junction with General Butler.
                        Nothing late has been heard from Butler, except that he is laying siege to
                        Fort Darling.</p>
                    <p>The news from the southwest is encouraging. Dalton has been evacuated, and a
                        dispatch just received states that a two days' battle has been fought
                        between Sherman and Joe. Johnston in the vicinity of Resaca, in which
                        Sherman was successful. No details are given.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Cautions readers that despite recent gains in Virginia, the Union army has
                    a long way to go.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Indemnity Bill</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Let us pull aside the mask, and show honest men how their sacred rights
                    are scoffed at and trampled upon by place-holders [Republicans], who grow fat
                    upon their unsuspecting loyalty."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Condemns Republicans in the state legislature for failing to support a bill
                    that would reimburse civilians for property damaged in the war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>General Sherman</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Questions the wisdom of General Sherman's latest statements that express
                    his willingness to respect southern political views, regardless of how absurd
                    these ideas seem.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Southern Rule</head>
                <origin>Nashville Press</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that the tyrannical nature of the Confederate government is no
                    excuse for the US to become similarly oppressive.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Important to Wounded Soldiers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Calls attention to recent laws passed that would compensate soldiers and
                    their families for any wounds received in combat.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Everett</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>A. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nixon</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>James C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Messersmith</ln>
                        <fn>G. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Culbertson</ln>
                        <fn>J. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kuhn</ln>
                        <fn>Emanuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>F. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Downey</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ruthrauff</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keefer</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Immell</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greenewalt</ln>
                        <fn>S. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>W. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davison</ln>
                        <fn>H. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davison</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brossert</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gehr</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Immell</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lists the officers and managers of the Farmers and Mechanics Industrial
                    Association of Franklin County who were elected on May 9: President, Col. A. K.
                    McClure; Vice Presidents, J. S. Nixon, James C. Eyster, G. R. Messersmith, and
                    Samuel Myers; Recording Secretary, W. S. Everett; Corresponding Secretary, J. P.
                    Culbertson; Treasurer, Emanuel Kuhn; Managers, F. S. Stumbaugh, John Downer,
                    John Ruthrauff, Henry Keefer, J. Immell, S. F. Greenwalt, W. W. Skinner, H. B.
                    Davison, Andrew Davison, William Brossert, Daniel O. Gehr, and G. W. Immell.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Classis</head>
                <origin>Record</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deatrich</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes that the Mercersburg Classis met last Friday. The forty members who
                    were present elected Dr. Fisher, of Chambersburg, President, and Rev. Mr.
                    Deatrich, of Charlesville, the stated Clerk.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>W. W. Paxton, J. Hoke, and P. Dyson, Committee</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Conrad</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paxton</ln>
                        <fn>W. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoke</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dyson</ln>
                        <fn>P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes that an anniversary celebration for the Franklin County Bible Society
                    will be held on May 29 at the German Reformed Church. Rev. Mr. Conrad, of the
                    Lutheran Church, will deliver an address.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.05.18.05">
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillen</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McHenry</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Butler</ln>
                        <fn>Martha Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. S. McHenry married Benjamin Martin and Martha Ann Butler on May 10 at
                    the residence of Samuel Gillen.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McHenry</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sollenberger</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keller</ln>
                        <fn>Amanda</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On May 12, Rev. S. McHenry married Daniel Sollenberger and Amanda Keller.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yost</ln>
                        <fn>Anna Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Anna Elizabeth Yost died on May 12 at age 59.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Switzer</ln>
                        <fn>Ann M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Switzer</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Ann M. Switzer, wife of Henry Switzer, died on May 3 at age 20.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Unger</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Elizabeth Unger died on May 4 at age 66.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jane Hays died on April 30 at age 75.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shetler</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On April 26, William Shetler died at age 76.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Hays died on May 1 near Concord, Pennsylvania.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tritle</ln>
                        <fn>Anna Maria</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Anna Maria Tritle died on May 4 at age 3.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shaffer</ln>
                        <fn>George Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George Daniel Shaffer died on May 6 at age 8.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Easton</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sarah Catharine Easton died on May 13 at age 3.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 1-6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.05.18.06">
            <pageNote>Reports of troop movement in Louisiana, column 1, continued coverage of
                Virginia campaign, columns 2-4, classified ads, columns 5-6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.05.18.07">
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 1-6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.05.18.08">
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 1-6</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
