<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1865/va.au.ss.1865.12.12">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>John Riedl</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/03/99</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1865-12-12">
            <year>1865</year>
            <month norm="12">December</month>
            <day>12</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1865.12.12.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Governor's Message</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Extracts from the Governor's Message, on topics including Railroads,
                    Collection of Taxes, and Freedmen.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1865.12.12.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>President's Message</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The President opens his message with an expression of gratitude to God of the
                        preservation of the United States.</p>
                    <p>He explains his views of the mutual relations of the Government and the
                        States, and says this government of the United States is a limited
                        government, and States with proper limitation of power are essential to the
                        existence of the Constitution of the United States. After the closing of
                        hostilities, the first question that presented itself for his decision was,
                        whether the territory, within the limits of the recovered States should be
                        held as conquered territory, under military and authority emanating from the
                        President as the head of the army. He opposed the policy of military rule,
                        for various reasons. The true history is, that all pretended acts of
                        secession were from the beginning, null and void. If any States neglects or
                        refuses to perform its offices, there is more need that the general
                        government should maintain all its authority, and as soon as practicable,
                        resume the exercise of all its functions, which, happily for us all brings
                        with it a blessing to the STates over which they are extended. He has felt
                        it necessary to assert one other power of the general government, the power
                        of pardon, connected with the clearest recognition of the binding force of
                        the laws of the United States, and an acknowledgement of the change in
                        regard to slavery. The next step which he says he has taken to restore the
                        constitutional relations of the States has been an invitation to them to
                        participate in the high office of amending the Constitution. The adoption of
                        the proposed amendment re-unites us beyond all power of disruption. It will
                        efface the sad memory of the past, and bind us more than ever to mutual
                        affection and support. Every patriot must wish for general amnesty at the
                        earliest epoch consistent with the public good. For this great end there is
                        need of a concurrence of all opinions, and a spirit of mutual conciliation.
                        The amendment to the Constitution being adopted, it would remain for the
                        States whose powers have been so long in abeyance to resume their places in
                        the two branches of the national legislature and thereby complete the work
                        of restoration. "Here," says the President, "it is for you, fellow-citizens
                        of the Senate and House of Representatives, to judge each for yourselves, of
                        the election returns and the qualification of your own members."</p>
                    <p>He refers to the unwillingness of the Chief Justice to hold a term of the
                        United States Circuit Court in Richmond, "until Congress should have an
                        opportunity to consider and act on the whole subject." He hopes that
                        Congress may make an early provision for the resumption of all its judicial
                        functions. Persons charged with treason should have fair and impartial
                        trials in the highest civil tribunals of the country. The truth should be
                        affirmed, that treason is a crime, and traitors should be punished, and the
                        offence made infamous, that the question should be judicially settled, that
                        no State has the right of its own will to renounce its place in the Union.</p>
                    <p>In relation to the question of extending the right of suffrage to the
                        freedmen emancipated by the war, and of necessity to the free colored men in
                        all the States of the Union the President expresses his well-known views and
                        policy of referring it to the several States. He says it may prove that the
                        colored men will receive the kindliest usage from some of those on whom they
                        have heretofore most closely depended. But while he has no doubt that now,
                        after the close of he war, it is not competent for the general government to
                        extend the elective franchise to the several States, it is equally clear
                        that good faith requires the necessity of the freedmen in their property,
                        their right to labor and to claim the just return of their labor. Now that
                        the monopoly of slave labor has been removed from the States nearest the
                        Gulf of Mexico, the influx of free labor will people those regions with
                        numerous and enterprising population which will vie with any in the Union in
                        compactness, inventive genious, wealth and industry. The constitutional
                        freedom of commerce between the States is referred to, and the right of any
                        State to tax the transit between States denied. It constitutes one of the
                        worst forms of monopoly, and the evil is increased if coupled with a denial
                        of the choice of the route. Every such obstacle ought to be sternly guarded
                        against by appropriate legislation within the limits of the Constitution.
                        These remarks, it will be supposed, have a bearing on such railroads as are
                        burdened with a consolidation tax, passing from one State to another.</p>
                    <p>The report of the SEcretary of the Interior presents evidence of the
                        successful operation of the homestead act, over one million and a half acres
                        having been entered the past fiscal year and occupied by industrious
                        settlers. The business of the Pension Bureau has largely increased the
                        number of pensioners being now 85,9986, requiring for their annual pay over
                        $8,000,000. He says a grateful people will not hesitate to [unclear] any
                        measure for the relief of soldiers (or their wives) who have assisted to
                        preserve national existence.</p>
                    <p>the report of the Postmaster General presents an encouraging exhibit, leaving
                        a surplus of receipts over expenditures. Progress has been made in restoring
                        the postal service in the Southern States. He also refers to the report of
                        the Secretary of War, which states that the volunteer force has already been
                        reduced by the discharge of over 800,000 troops. It is proposed to reduce
                        the regular army to 50,000 men, so organized that the ranks may be filled up
                        to 82,000 whenever required.</p>
                    <p>The report of the Secretary of the Treasury is commended, and it is urged
                        that "it is our duty to prepare for the ever increasing evils of an
                        unredeemable currency," and by conducting business as nearly as possible on
                        a system of cast payments or short credits, the people will be prepared to
                        return to the standard of good and silver. The duty is heartily recognized
                        is diminishing the amount of paper money now in circulation.</p>
                    <p>He refers to the nations with which we are in friendly alliance, and then
                        reviews the conduct of Great Britain, and the attempt of the British
                        minister to justify the action of his government towards this country.</p>
                    <p>While he feels bound to declare his opinion before Congress and the world
                        that justification cannot be sustained by the tribunal of nations, yet he
                        does not advise to any present attempt at redress by acts of legislation. In
                        relation to the invasion of some parts of America, in the interests of
                        monarchy, the President says "he relies upon the wisdom and justice of the
                        European powers to respect the system of non-interference, which has so long
                        been sanctioned by time, and which by its good results has approved itself
                        to both continents." "We should regard it a great calamity should any
                        European power challenge the American people to the defence of Republicanism
                        against foreign interference." The correspondence with France and England
                        will, at proper time, be laid before Congress.</p>
                    <p>The message closes with an eulogy upon the greatness of our country and upon
                        the republican model of government as exhibited in our institutions, and
                        solemnly invokes every citizen of our favored land to aid in perpetuating
                        our own free constitution.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A summary of Andrew Johnson's Message, characterized in another column of
                    the Spectator as "a wet blanket upon the radical fires" in Congress.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Tournament</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burk</ln>
                        <fn>Butler</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Curry</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>Mattie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>At "the closing and crowning tournament of the season among the Valley
                    Knights" at Bridgewater, men from Augusta county took the top four finishes and
                    Mattie Walker, also of Augusta, was crowned Queen of Love and Beauty. Also
                    addresses a report from the Charlottesville Chronicle on a "kullud tournament"
                    near the University of Virginia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Congress</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Congress met, with a quorum in each house on the 4th inst. The House was
                        organized by the re-election of Speaker Colfax and other subordinate
                        officer. The radical republicans under the lead of Thad. Stevens in the
                        House, and Sumner and Wade in the Senate forthwith commenced their old
                        policy of "agitation," by introducing resolutions intended to harass the
                        South, and embarrass re-construction unless conducted on their peculiar
                        plan. A joint resolution, previously agreed upon in a republican canvass,
                        was introduced in each house, to exclude all members elect from the Southern
                        States untill a committee (of radicals of course) should report upon the
                        subject. On the next day the President's able, and liberal message was read,
                        which is supposed to have been a wet blanket upon the radical fires.
                        Congress then adjourned over until the 14th inst.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that "the radical republicans" in the House met on December 4 and
                    immediately "commenced their old policy of 'agitation' by introducing
                    resolutions intended to harass the South," among them the resolution to exclude
                    "all members elect" from the South pending a committee report on the subject.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Tribute to the Ladies</head>
                <origin>Richmond Sentinel</origin>
                <commentary>"The Richmond Sentinel pays the following handsome tribute to the ladies
                    of the South for the part they have borne in the trials of the last five years:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Richmond <emph rend="italics">Sentinel</emph> pays the following handsome
                        tribute to the ladies of the South for the part they have borne in the
                        trials of the last five years:</p>
                    <p>"Cheerful under privations, patient under suffering, heroic amid danger,
                        "ministering angels" beside the cot where pain and anguish were wringing the
                        brow of the sick and the wounded soldier; readily renouncing accustomed
                        comforts, and cheerfully undergoing unaccustomed toils;--their example has
                        been, indeed, an inspiration and a joy, and added fresh attractions to that
                        loveliness,and fresh power to that away, to which Southern gallantry has
                        always delighted to do homage. Whosoever shall write the story of those
                        times, will slander his theme if he assign not to the ladies of the South --
                        God bless them! -- a peculiar merit and a special praise."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Praises "the ladies of the South" for "particular merit and a special
                    praise" for their efforts during the war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Bob Jones</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>Bob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>This letter from a member of the Fire Company reports that, despite efforts
                    to restore the company in recent weeks, they still lack "requirements necessary
                    to do their duty" which have not been furnished by the town council.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1865.12.12.03">
            <pageNote/>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Fire Company</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>Bob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Encourages "the town authorities" to read the letter from Bob Jones in
                    another column of the Spectator and urges that the Fire Company be "fully
                    equipped at once."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Attacked by Freedmen</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dudley</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that Mr. G. W. Dudley "was attacked by two negroes" while traveling
                    to his home in Mint Spring from Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClanahan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armstrong</ln>
                        <fn>Archibald</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brubeck</ln>
                        <fn>Eliza</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On November 16 Eliza Brubeck and Archibald Armstrong were married by Rev.
                    William McClanahan.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClanahan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Golladay</ln>
                        <fn>Washington</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>Eliza</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Eliza Wright and Washington Golladay were married on November 29 by the
                    Rev. William McClanahan.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClanahan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hite</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Golladay</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Elizabeth Golladay and John Hite were married on November 30 by the Rev.
                    William McClanahan.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huff</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gaver</ln>
                        <fn>H. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thomasson</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huff</ln>
                        <fn>Kate</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Kate Huff, of Waynesboro, and George Thomasson, of Richmond, were married
                    on November 23 by the Rev. H. A. Gaver.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Killian</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>Simon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>Marion</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>Julia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On November 23 Julia Koiner and Marion Koiner were married by the Rev. J.
                    Killian.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shirey</ln>
                        <fn>J. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Holtz</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary Holtz and James Snyder were married on November 30 by the Rev. J. D.
                    Shirey.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shirey</ln>
                        <fn>J. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wiseman</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fix</ln>
                        <fn>Henrietta</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Wiseman and Henrietta Fix were married on December 7 by the Rev. J.
                    D. Shirey. Editorializes that "it is not the first wise man that ever found
                    himself in a fix."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shirey</ln>
                        <fn>J. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dudley</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wiseman</ln>
                        <fn>Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Ann Wiseman and George Dudley were married on December 7 by the Rev. J. D.
                    Shirey.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vanlear</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Earman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vanlear</ln>
                        <fn>Martha</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Martha Vanlear and John Earman were married on December 7 by the Rev.
                    William Baker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burford</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Morrison</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Elizabeth Morrison and John Burford were married on December 7 by the Rev.
                    William Baker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1865.12.12.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Blackbird</head>
                <origin>New York Mercury</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This poem uses the refrain of "nevermore" as it follows an exchange between
                    the narrator, who ponders "the war of the Rebellion," and a freedman who refuses
                    to work for wages.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
