<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1865/va.au.ss.1865.08.29">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>John Riedl</taggerName>
            <tagDate>10/6/99</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1865-08-29">
            <year>1865</year>
            <month norm="08">August</month>
            <day>29</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1865.08.29.01">
            <div type="l">
                <column>06</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Veritas</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lewis</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A letter endorsing John F. Lewis as a candidate for Congress from the 6th
                    District.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Congressional Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>This letter suggests calling upon Alexander H. H. Stuart to serve as a
                    Congressional representative.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>A Literary Place</head>
                <origin>Charlottesville Chronicle</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article from the Charlottesville Chronicle mocks the efforts of "the
                    whole colored population" to garner an education.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1865.08.29.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Great and Sudden Changes</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Before the proclamation of President Lincoln calling for 75,000 men of
                        suppress a little insurrection at the South, a large majority of the
                        Southern people were opposed to secession. But as soon as that proclamation
                        was issued, there was an almost unanimous determination to resist force with
                        force. I this section of the State of Virginia, where before, the Union
                        sentiment, approximated unanimity, there was exhibited upon the publication
                        of that proclamation a unanimity of determination to resist coercion, "at
                        all hazards an to the last extremity," which was truly marvellous. As
                        instantaneous as the electric flash, the strongest Unionists were converted
                        into dis-Unionists, and the strongest peace men into war men. The spectacle
                        was, in the higher degree, sublime. The want of the magician never wrought
                        such a change.</p>
                    <p>From that time til the surrender of Gen'l Lee, the people of the South were
                        nearly unanimous in their opposition to a coerced Union. As near an
                        approximation to unanimity was never before exhibited in any country upon
                        any occasion. Whilst this was the case, the Press of the North persistently
                        maintained, and the Government acted upon the assumption, that a majority of
                        the people were still in favor of the Union, and that they were kept down
                        and ruled by the military despotism of a small minority. When the people of
                        the South were, by thousands, sacrificing their lives for the sake of
                        Independence, it was insisted that the majority of them were good Union men.</p>
                    <p>Now that the war is over, and the people of the South acknowledge themselves
                        defeated; now that they have abandoned all hopes of Independence, and have
                        solemnly sworn allegiance to the Government of the United States; now that
                        they desire to be obedient "loyal citizens" of the Union, presto change! the
                        Press of the North maintain, and the Government seems to act upon the
                        assumption, that, in spite of the solemn avowals and sworn allegiances, a
                        vast majority of the Southern people are still "rebels," and that "loyal"
                        men are as "scarce as hens' teeth." What has become of all the time good
                        Union men, that "loyal" majority who were kept in such dire subjections by
                        the military despotism of the few? Southern military despotism no longer
                        exists. Gen'l Grant lifted the burdensome yoke off their galled shoulder --
                        they are now as free as any oderiferous "unbleached Americans citizens of
                        African descent." If it be true that a majority of the people of the South
                        have been, all the time, good Union men, why keep a military force in the
                        South, now that the "rebels" have been disarmed, even granting the most
                        monstrous idea, that their oaths of allegiance were but acts of the bleakest
                        perjury? The truth is, during the war, rebels were almost as numerous in the
                        South as the</p>
                    <lb/>
                    <p>"Leaves in Vallambrosa's vale,"</p>
                    <lb/>
                    <p>whilst the Union were nearly as scarce as white crows.</p>
                    <p>Upon the surrender of the Confederate armies, a change as sudden and
                        remarkable as that which occurred at the beginning of the war took place,
                        and of a precisely opposite character. The proclamation for 75,000 men made
                        the people of the South almost a [unclear] for war; the capitulation of Gen.
                        Lee made them a unit for peace. In the world's history, we suppose there are
                        never was an occasion before when so many persons were so suddenly and
                        unanimously inspired with a desire for peace. At the first sound of the
                        harsh tocsin of war, the people of the South sprang to arms -- they rushed
                        impetuously to meet the foe, planted their banners upon the "perilous edges
                        of battle," rallied manfully around them, fought like heroes and wreathed
                        their brows with unfading chaplets of laurel. Tho' they failed to secure
                        Independence, they did not fail to gain an immortality of fame.</p>
                    <lb/>
                    <p>"Peace hath her victories</p>
                    <p>No less renewed than those of war."</p>
                    <lb/>
                    <p>In war, the North were successful; in peace the victory is with the South.</p>
                    <p>Since the surrender, the people of the South have conquered their prejudice,
                        subdued their passions, overcome their feelings of hostility, surrendered
                        their fondest hopes, submitted with patience to their fate, philosophically
                        accepted the "situation," and have resolved to be, in future, loyal citizens
                        of the Union.</p>
                    <p>On the contrary, the people of the North are still the victims of distrust
                        and suspicion, -- they are afraid to trust the loyalty of their Southern
                        brethren with whom they were so loth to part -- they are still the slaves of
                        their prejudices ans cannot wholly subdue their spirit of hostility.</p>
                    <p>The South has gained the greater victory; for "greater is he that ruleth his
                        spirit, than he that taketh a city."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor explains his belief that Lincoln's call for 75,000 men in 1861
                    "made the people of the South almost a unit for war" and that "the capitulation
                    of Gen. Lee made them a unit for peace," resolved to be "loyal citizens of the
                    Union."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gray</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lewis</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woods</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>An article listing the candidates for Congress.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kuacofe</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newman</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Argenbright</ln>
                        <fn>Amanda</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Amanda Argenbright and Joseph Newman were married on August 22 by the Rev.
                    Kuacofe.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bledsoe</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bledsoe</ln>
                        <fn>Mattie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bledsoe</ln>
                        <fn>Lucy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Thomas and Mattie Bledsoe were "bereft of their jewell," nine month old
                    daughter Lucy Lee, who died on July 11.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1865.08.29.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>County Court of Augusta</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The grand jury of Franklin county, P., have returned true bills to the Court
                        against Gen. McCausland, Maj. Gilmore and Capt. Smith for arson, and others
                        are pending for highway robbery against Gilmore and Smith, and robbers and
                        murder against McCausland. Requisitions have been issued by Geo. Curtin,
                        upon Gov. Boreman, of West Virginia, for the rendition of McCausland and
                        upon Gov. Pierpont for the rendition of Smith.--The Franklin Repository says
                        that "its is probable that the late rebel Gen. Jubal A. Early will also be
                        indicted for murder, arson and highway robbery, as his order was shown in
                        Chambersburg directing the freebooter's tribute to be levied, and, in
                        default of payment, the burning of the town."</p>
                    <p>Give us even-handed justice, and let us see Genl. Hunter tried and convicted
                        and punished for the destruction of private property and the murder of Mr.
                        David Creigh.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>D. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sterritt</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kuhn</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Towberman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Details the proceedings of the first County Court "under the restored state
                    of affairs."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Nominations by County Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lynn</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>Nicholas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vanlear</ln>
                        <fn>D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lists the nominees for various offices selected at a meeting at the Court
                    House.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that "there are 720 Freedmen in Staunton, as ascertained by the
                    census just taken by the Freedmen's Bureau of this District."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1865.08.29.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>General News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The New York News reports "that the negroes of the South, under the
                    management of their masters" produced 3,500 million of the 4,500 million dollars
                    worth of goods exported from America from 1821 to 1859.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
