<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1865/va.au.ss.1865.10.31">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>John Riedl</taggerName>
            <tagDate>11/23/99</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1865-10-31">
            <year>1865</year>
            <month norm="10">October</month>
            <day>31</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1865.10.31.01">
            <div type="e">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Women and Men</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Very intelligent women, we find by observation, are seldom beautiful. The
                        formation of their features, and particularly their forehead is more or less
                        masculine. Miss Lander was rather pretty and feminine in the face; but Miss
                        Sedgwick, Miss Pardue, Miss Leslie, and the late Anna Mariah and Jane
                        Porter, the contrary. One of the Misses Porter had a forehead as high as
                        that of an intellectual man. We never knew of any very talented man who was
                        admitted for his personal beauty. Pope was awful ugly; Dr. Johnson was no
                        better; Mirabeau was the ugliest man in all France, and yet he was the
                        greatest favorite with the ladies. Women more frequently prize men for their
                        sterling qualities of the mind, than men do women. Dr. Johnson chose a woman
                        who had scarcely an idea above an oyster. He thought her the loveliest
                        creature in existence, if we may judge by the inscription he left on her
                        tomb.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The writer explains that "very intelligent women, we find by observation,
                    are seldom beautiful" and suggests that men prefer beauty to intellect, pointing
                    out that Dr. Johnson "chose a woman who had scarcely an idea above an oyster."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>The United Brethren Church and Negro Equality</head>
                <origin>Religious Telescope</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>J. J. Glossbrenner</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>This letter to the editor of the Religious Telescope, from a preacher of
                    the United Brethren Church, attempts to clarify the meaning of "equality" in
                    resolutions passed by their General Conference, published in a previous issue of
                    the Spectator, resolutions that prompted accusations of "amalgamation." The
                    writer explains that he has "always abhorred" the idea of "social equality," and
                    seeks only equality before the law.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1865.10.31.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The "Freedmen"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>There is no problem more difficult of the solution, than the future of the
                        "freedmen." Half a million of ignorant and helpless people, have been turned
                        loose in Virginia, with no capital to begin business, no skill in mechanic
                        arts, and no means of providing for themselves and families. In the first
                        paroxysm of delight at being released from bondage, they have generally
                        hurried to the towns and country stores, with characteristic improvidence,
                        to spend, in tobacco and cigars and finery, their little hoardings and
                        earnings. During the Summer and early Fall, they have been able to live
                        without much difficulty. The hay-loft furnished a comfortable lodging, and
                        the gardens and orchards and corn fields the means of subsistence. But cold
                        weather is coming -- the paroxysm of joy at the release from labor has
                        subsided, and the more thoughtful are beginning to find that freedom is not
                        the unalloyed blessing they supposed it to be. It does not mean exemption
                        from work, but on the contrary it involves a higher strain than ever, on
                        their physical powers.</p>
                    <p>No observing man can have filed to notice the traces of care and anxiety on
                        the faces of the once happy negro. We no longer hear the "loud laugh that
                        speak the vacant mind." A moody and anxious expression marks their
                        countenances. It is not surprising that it should be so, for a gloomy time
                        is before them in the coming Winter.</p>
                    <p>The fate of the poor negro is a hard one. Their professed friends in the
                        North have cut loose the ties which bound them to their masters and secured
                        for them comfortable homes and ample provision for all their wants in
                        sickness and in health, and having set them, as it were, adrift, they leave
                        them to float on to destruction. We have been informed that there is a large
                        demand for agricultural labor in the great gain-growing State of Illinois,
                        and yet the people of that State will not allow the poor negroes to come
                        among them. A short time ago, an enterprising man from Edgar County, went to
                        Cairo, and engaged 150 able bodied negroes, to got to that county, to work
                        on the farms, but the people rose in mass, and compelled him to send them
                        back. Yet, in th face of facts like these, may northern men pretend to be in
                        favor of negro suffrage and negro equality! If they wish to get credit it
                        for sincerity, they must show by their own example, their readiness to
                        recognize this equality of rights, let them commence the work at home, --
                        then we may, possibly, profit by their example.</p>
                    <p>The negro seems now destined to be crushed between the upper and the nether
                        millstone. The South does not want him, and the North will not have him.
                        What is the poor darkey to do? He must live in some way. He will not
                        willingly starve. If he cannot get work, he must steal.</p>
                    <p>This brings before us the question: "What is the policy and duty of the South
                        in regard to him?"</p>
                    <p>We are inclined to think that if the Legislature will pass a system of wise
                        laws to secure the fulfillment of labor contracts, similar in its general
                        features, to the regulations prescribed for the freedmen of Tennessee, it
                        will be best for Southern people to employ negroes. They are among us --
                        they are accustomed to the cultivation of our staples -- they suit our
                        climate -- and they delight in corn bread and bacon, the peculiar diet of
                        Virginia. When the intoxication of freedom passes, and the pressure of want
                        comes, they can be made to work.</p>
                    <p>Many of our people are anxious to import foreign labor to take the place of
                        the negro in the cultivation of our farms. It would be well if the people of
                        Virginia would consider this matter maturely before they act. There are
                        difficulties attending such a radical innovation. Among these are: 1st. The
                        inconveniences of communication arising out of a want of knowledge of
                        language of the foreigner. 2nd Their want of acquaintance with our habits,
                        climate, and peculiar systems of culture. 3rd. The difference in diet. the
                        foreigner will not corn bread and fat bacon. They will require the kind of
                        food they have been accustomed to. These and many other points of
                        disagreement may and probably will lead to dissatisfaction and difficulty.</p>
                    <p>Better employ the industrious negroes who know our ways, and will eat corn
                        bread and fat middling. Large proprietors will probably find it to their
                        interest to lease parcels of their lands to the better class of negroes, on
                        what may be termed improving leases. Why may we not have a system of black
                        peasantry? In every neighborhood we know industrious, well behaved negroes.
                        Why not rent them, say fifty or seventy-five acres with a cabin, to be
                        cultivated on shares. We believe it may be done with profit to the landlord
                        and benefit to the negro. The owner will, of course, prescribe the rotation
                        of crops and the system of culture. Under such a system the lands might be
                        cleared and improved. The stimulus of interest would be brought to bear to
                        encourage the negro to effort. His little crops and his pigs and poultry,
                        would enable him to support his family, and as his children grow up, he may,
                        with their aid extend his operation. Humanity and enlightened self-interest
                        ought to prompt our farmers to make experiment of this kind. We are
                        persuaded it would answer well. At first, the proprietor would have to break
                        up the land, or furnish the means of breaking it up, but in a few years the
                        negro could get horses and plows of his own, accumulate manure, and improve
                        his homestead.</p>
                    <p>We pray our people, therefore, not to take counsel from their prejudices, but
                        to consider this suggestion calmly and carefully. The great objection to the
                        system of leasing is, that with white men if you get a good tenant you can
                        not keep him. He has aspirations for the ownership of a home of his own, and
                        as soon as he can collect a little property he is off for the west of buys a
                        spot of his own. With the negro it would be different. He has strong local
                        attachment, and not much enterprise. He will not be at liberty to got to the
                        West. He will be content, when he is doing well, to remain where he is.</p>
                    <p>Who will set the example? Who desires to be a public benefactor?</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Ruminates on "the fate of the poor negro" in the South, discouraging plans
                    "to import foreign labor," advocating instead "a system of black tenantry."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Constitutional Amendment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports the "virtually unanimous" vote in favor of amending the Alexandria
                    Constitution's provision which prevented "any one to 'vote or hold office' who
                    held office under the Confederate or Virginia Government during the war."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Southern Representatives in Congress</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Speculation about the Clerk of the House's ability and likelihood of
                    denying the Southern representatives their seats. The writer remains optimistic
                    that "Conservative Republicans will unite with the so-called Democratic element
                    in sustaining the President's policy of Reconstruction."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stringer</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hopewell</ln>
                        <fn>Jonathon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vines</ln>
                        <fn>Francis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On October 24 the Rev. W. Stringer joined Jonathon Hopewell, of Augusta,
                    and Frances Vines in marriage at the M. E. Church in Fairfield. The printers
                    express their thanks for a piece of the wedding cake.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1865.10.31.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local--"Painful"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Contests the Charlottesville Chronicle's labeling of Staunton as a "fussy
                    little town that makes a great hullabahoo every time a new gutter is put up" by
                    pointing toward the many improvements at the office of the Spectator.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local--Land Buyers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on heightened interest in purchasing lands in the "Valley of
                    Virginia." The Valley is noted for its "fertility, salubrity, and scenery" as
                    well as being "comparatively free from the objection of having large numbers of
                    free negroes in its limits."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local--Freedmen's School</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The "Freedmen's Bureau" are about establishing a Free School, in Staunton,
                        for "teaching young (darkey) ideas how to shoot." Female teachers from the
                        North have arrived, and rooms were fitted up in the fury rooms of the Court
                        House for the School. The County Court, however, having protested against
                        such use and occupation of the building, where the public archives are
                        deposited, and public business transacted, it is understood that the
                        commanding general has ordered that other rooms be procured for these
                        interesting Schools.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports, and mocks, the creation of a Freedmen's school in Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Local--County Roads</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that "the public roads of the County are in worse order than ever
                    before" because of the impossibility of keeping them in order during the war,
                    but efforts are under way to improve the condition of the roads.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1865.10.31.04">
            <div type="l">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Women's Heroism</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>MR. EDITOR:--What is more touching beautiful, and sublime than the heroism
                        and courage of woman? How many striking illustrations of this have been
                        recorded during our late war; and many, many more have been performed amidst
                        the bustle and confusion of stirring events, and have been passed by
                        unnoticed, save by a few interested persons. The fame and heroism of the
                        Grecian woman have been immortalized by the poets' verse; how, when their
                        land was invaded by hosts as countless as the "leaves in Vallambrosa's
                        Vale," they gave their hair for bowstrings and their girdles for sword-belts
                        and while their heart-strings were cracking sent their lovers from their
                        arms to fight and perish for their country." The bravery and heroism of the
                        woman of all ages have been recorded by the impartial historian; but I
                        candidly think, that heroism of that pure, unselfish and self sacrificing
                        class, such as has been exhibited by our noble women of the south, in our
                        recent struggle for independence, is unsurpassed, aye, even unparalleled in
                        the History of either Ancient or Modern times? How much they have suffered
                        anguish and privations endured, no pen can describe, much less such a feeble
                        one as mine.</p>
                    <p>While we toiled and bled and suffered, the fair daughters of the South,
                        reared and nurtured in the lap of luxury, and whom we "permitted not the
                        winds of summer to visit too roughly," with their fairy hands, wrought our
                        uniforms, (and at the same time, cast a golden woof around our hearts,)
                        cooled the parched and burning tongue of the sick as they law in crowded
                        hospitals, far from home and friends; wept o'er the curse of "only a
                        soldier" as it was borne to the common soldiers' resting place; and when the
                        poor fellow returned from the field of slaughter on crutches, bleeding and
                        black with the smoke of battle, it was then that their spirits rose within
                        them, and they shone forth from their highest and purest attitudes. Whether
                        with the sick, wounded and dying in hospitals, strewing flowers along the
                        stony and rugged paths of the weary soldier, or mounted behind an officer
                        and piloting him on the advance or retreat, they have exhibited that heroism
                        and devotion to their country, which I am afraid we "lords of Creation"
                        cannot boast. And no we frequently bear young men who fought valiantly,
                        exclaim, "I have no inducement to remain here; I have nothing here to live
                        for." Selfish, narrow hearted creatures! They have never taken one calm,
                        comprehensive view of the situation of their country, which now more than
                        ever needs their assistance. And then to talk of turning their backs upon
                        this beautiful land, and deserting it in the midst of its trials, and
                        affliction. They can see no brightening day in our future; the clouds of
                        adversity have hidden the sun of prosperity from their view, and they have
                        forgotten that those clouds have a silver lining. We have returned from the
                        field of slaughter, which has drunk the best blood of our sunny South.</p>
                    <p>This soil has been hallowed, and consecrated by the blood of our fathers, and
                        brothers which was poured freely in what they believed to be a just cause;
                        and now are we not the most sacredly bound by all the times of
                        consanguinity, and respect, and veneration for the fallen braves, to live
                        and labor in this devoted land? Most indubitably we are. We also have these
                        hills, rock-ribbed [unclear], and ancient as the sun; these vales stretching
                        in pensive quietness between; these venerable woods; rivers that move in
                        majesty, and the complaining brooks that make the meadows green," all o'er
                        shadowed by these towering mountains, whose bald peaks rear their heads
                        above the clouds. Truly this is a beautiful land, though filled with
                        desolation. The impress of the hand of the destroyer is upon it. For four
                        years it was scourged with fire and sword, and has been turned into a vast
                        charnal-house. And now who is to raise it out of the dust to its former
                        magnificence and glory? Is it not our duty? We, who by the all-wise
                        providence of God, have been permitted to see the end of the struggle? Aye,
                        most emphatically it is, I say.</p>
                    <p>The spirits of Jackson, Johnston, Polk, Stuart, Rhodes, Ashby, Pegram and
                        other gallant dead, "Who being dead yet speaketh," call upon us not to
                        desert our land. <emph rend="italics">And we will not.</emph> We will go to
                        work, and and by the assistance, and counsel of those fair creatures, who
                        watched, and prayed for our success and safe return, those "Modern
                        Maccarias," will fulfil a higher destiny than we anticipated, and by a
                        life-long devotion to them, will endeavor to repay them for their privations
                        which they endured for us. In conclusion, I would say to them, "We could not
                        love you, dears, so much, loved we not honor more."</p>
                    <p>MOREGAN</p>
                    <p>BLEAK HOUSE, Oct. 12, 1865.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Mohegan</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Praises the heroism of "the noble women of the South" for the difficulties
                    they endured during the war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>R.</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>"R." calls on all residents of the county to declare that "the widows and
                    orphans of those who have laid down their lives for me and mine shall not
                    suffer" and begin efforts to ameliorate their condition.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
