<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1865/va.au.ss.1865.11.28">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>John Riedl</taggerName>
            <tagDate>11/29/99</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1865-11-28">
            <year>1865</year>
            <month norm="11">November</month>
            <day>28</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1865.11.28.01">
            <div type="l">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Reply to Bishop Glossbrenner</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>J. M. McCue</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Glossbrenner</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>This is the latest in an ongoing debate over the resolutions passed at the
                    General Conference of the United Brethren. In this letter, J. M. McCue defends
                    himself against allegations that he is prone to "meddle" in the affairs of
                    others, charges made by Bishop Glossbrenner in the previous issue of the
                    Spectator. McCue also offers a useful summary of the events that occurred in the
                    months prior to the controversy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1865.11.28.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Congressional Question</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>There seems to be no doubt that the Representatives elect from the Southern
                        States will be denied admission to their seats until after the House shall
                        have been organized, and there seems to be as little doubt that an effort,
                        at least, will be made by the Radicals to keep them out altogether.</p>
                    <p>McPherson, the clerk, has declared he will not place upon the list of members
                        of Congress elect from the Southern States, and Colfax, the Speaker, says
                        that he is right. McPherson says the next Speaker must appoint a committee
                        to report upon the eligibility of the gentlemen who claim to represent the
                        States lately in rebellion and if the aforesaid Colfax is elected Speaker of
                        the next House of Representatives, <emph rend="italics">he will appoint the
                            committee whose report will go very far to decide the fate of the
                            Southern members elect.</emph></p>
                    <p>Colfax, says the Richmond Times, having prejudged the whole question, and
                        announced his decision in advance of all Congressional discussion, the
                        character of the committee which he will appoint cannot be doubted. Thus, at
                        the moment when speedy peace and reconstruction seemed about to crown the
                        nation with a thousand blessing, the dark shadow of continued sectional
                        strife again casts a gloom like the sun "in dim eclipse" over the land. The
                        patriotic reconstruction policy of the president is endangered at the moment
                        when good men believed that he was about to receive the support of all
                        parties. Really, it would seem that so far as the South and her people are
                        concerned, no concessions, no sacrifices, no compromises, no pledge of
                        fealty to the Union, the laws and the Constitution will satisfy the Radical
                        element of the North. The Jacobin wolf has determined to invent some pretext
                        or excuse for devouring the lamb, and assigns the most unnatural, monstrous
                        and detestable reasons for his policy of sectional strife and
                        disintegration.</p>
                    <p>Whatever honorable men could do consistent with honor and self-respect, we
                        have done, or have expressed a willingness to do, and yet we are still told
                        that we have given insufficient proofs of our fitness for re-admission into
                        the great family of States.</p>
                    <p>We sincerely trust that the influence of President Johnson may be cast in our
                        favor, and that he may be able to defeat the machinations of the Radicals in
                        Congress; but if he cannot or does not do so, the South, we fear, is
                        destined to endure a long period of degrading probation to "taxation without
                        representation," and of the subordination of civil rule to martial law.</p>
                    <p>Such a rejection of Southern representatives would violate the fundamental
                        principle of republican institutions, for we should have taxation without
                        representation, and would be held amenable to laws in the framing of which
                        we had no voice.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that there is "little doubt" that the Radicals in Congress will
                    attempt to keep the newly elected Southern representatives from taking their
                    seats, but holds out hope that President Johnson "may be able to defeat the
                    machinations of the Radicals."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Negro Suffrage</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that "negro suffrage" has recently been voted down in Connecticut,
                    Wisconsin, Minnesota and Colorado.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Public Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>Bolivar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kenney</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harrison</ln>
                        <fn>Powell</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Preston</ln>
                        <fn>T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Latane</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echols</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>Archibald</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The proceedings of a meeting held at the Staunton Court House on November
                    27 for the purpose of raising an endowment for Washington College, during which
                    a letter by Robert E. Lee was read to the audience to encourage their
                    benevolence. The meeting resolved to appoint "three ladies from each Church
                    congregation in the county to solicit subscriptions" to what they titled the
                    "Lee Endowment."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Repository</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A new order of things has been established. henceforth we of the North are to
                        be untrammelled. We are to enjoy an independent press, a fearless pulpit and
                        an unquestioned right to agitate to our heart's content. Genuflection is to
                        be counted a deformity and not a graceful accomplishment. Officious
                        interference is to be rebuked and unmanly servility to be despised.--<emph
                            rend="italics">Franklin Repository, Chambersburg, Pa</emph>.</p>
                    <p>The <emph rend="italics">Repository</emph> is a Republican paper, and claims
                        all for the North and the denies all to the South. The "North are to be
                        untrammelled" -- the South to be shackled; the North to have an independent
                        press" -- the South a servile one; the North "an unquestioned right to
                        agitate to their heart's content" -- the South no right to agitate at all;
                        in the North "genuflection is to be counted a deformity" -- in the South, a
                        "graceful accomplishment;" on the part of the South, "officious interference
                        is to be rebuked" -- on the part of the North, commended; on the part of the
                        North, "unmanly servility is to be despised" -- on the part of the South, it
                        is to be required. We are part of the same people, in the same Union, under
                        the same flag and Government. "Oh liberty! how many crimes are committed in
                        thy name!"</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Quoting from the Franklin Repository, the Spectator asserts that the
                    Republicans intend to place the South under their heels.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>The Freedmen</head>
                <origin>Richmond Whig</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Richmond Whig says that the statistics, collected by a Northern
                        contemporary, show that the mortality among the freedmen of the South ranges
                        from thirty to fifty per cent., varying in different localities, and
                        according to the circumstances in which they are placed, and this with all
                        the aid extended by the Freedmen's Bureau. At this rate, it will not require
                        many years to put them all under the sod. There is, we believe, but one
                        thing that can arrest this fearful mortality, and that is the protection and
                        guardianship of the Southern whites. It is manifest to the whole country
                        that they must occupy the relation of wards. If they remain here they must
                        be wards of the whites. "God moves in a mysterious way," and it may be that
                        their sufferings in the past few months were inflicted to convince them and
                        out Northern countrymen that the negroes must have guardians, and to
                        reconcile them both to the guardianship and protection of those among whom
                        their lot is cast since other guardianship and protection of those among
                        whom their lot is cast, since other guardianship is, confessedly,
                        impossible.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Drawing on figures found in the Richmond Whig, the author contends that
                    "mortality among the freedmen of the South ranges from thirty to fifty percent"
                    and predicts that "it will not require many years to put them all under the
                    sod."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1865.11.28.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Immigrants Coming South</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Predicts that many of the "newly-arriving immigrants" will be headed South,
                    "where they should be warmly welcomed" to effect "the regeneration of the
                    South."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parker</ln>
                        <fn>Maurice</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dice</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carroll</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barley</ln>
                        <fn>Mollie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mollie Barley and John Carroll were married on November 22 by Rev. J. C.
                    Dice.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harlan</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Harlan died on October 28, a victim of typhoid fever.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hess</ln>
                        <fn>Chas. Edward</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hess</ln>
                        <fn>Erasmus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hess</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Charles Edward Hess, son of Erasmus and Margaret Hess, died of Diphtheria
                    in Greenville on October 20. He was two and a half years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beck</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beck</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Elizabeth Beck died on October 19 at the home of her son after a "brief
                    illness" that she faced with "great patience and christian resignation." She was
                    87.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1865.11.28.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Basis of Representation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lists the number of representatives for each Southern state in three
                    scenarios: if only whites are counted to determine representation, if "the
                    negroes are all counted," and on "the three-fifths negro basis." Points out that
                    "the South will have the inducement of an absolute gain of thirty-four members
                    in Congress to make voters of the freedmen."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
