<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1865/va.au.ss.1865.11.14">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>John Riedl</taggerName>
            <tagDate>11/24/99</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1865-11-14">
            <year>1865</year>
            <month norm="11">November</month>
            <day>12</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1865.11.14.01">
            <div type="l">
                <column>06</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Many citizens of Staunton are unwittingly, but certainly, doing a great
                        wrong, almost every day, to themselves and to the better class of colored
                        people.</p>
                    <p>The least worthy freedmen are flocking to town, to seek their living by their
                        wits. They desert the farms, and leave the fields uncultivated, and depend
                        on making a living by little jobs, for which they charge exhorbitant prices.
                        These high prices in town are reported in the country and render the
                        freedmen on the farms dissatisfied and disposed to leave.</p>
                    <p>The object of the loungers around town is, to live without work. If they do
                        anything, they charge double price, and are thus able to idle away the
                        greater part of their time. Every job of this kind to a freedmen, is a <emph
                            rend="italics">bounty to laziness</emph>, and an injury to the more
                        industrious classes in the country. It tends to injure the agricultural
                        interest, and thereby to increase the cost of living.</p>
                    <p>The remedy for this evil is of the people not to submit to extortion. The
                        fair price for cutting up a cord of wood, for an ordinary fireplace, is 50
                        cents -- why should any one, therefore, pay a lazy negro a dollar for it? A
                        good hand can easily cut three cords of wood per day, and therefore can earn
                        good wages at 50 cents a cord.</p>
                    <p>Town people, especially females, do not know the value of this kind of labor,
                        and are therefore constantly imposed on. This evil ought to be corrected. It
                        is injuring not only the parties concerned, but it is demoralizing the
                        colored population, sapping the foundation of the whole labor system. We
                        should pay what is right, and nothing more. If freedmen are not willing to
                        work for fair wages, let them take the consequences.--The creator has
                        ordained that man should his bread by the sweat of his brow. Those who will
                        not work must do without the bread. Freedmen are not freed from the laws of
                        God.</p>
                    <p>If we offer inducements to the negro to leave the farms, scarcity and high
                        prices of grain, hay, and meats must follow. People ought to think of these
                        things, and discourage negroes from coming to town. Unless they do, the
                        whole country will be over-run by an idle, vagrant population, who will live
                        by stealing. Let us be kind, but firm; just, but not weak and foolish. Let
                        freedmen understand that they must earn their living by steady industry and
                        not occasional jobs. If we pursue this course, the country will prosper.</p>
                    <p>Franklin</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Franklin</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Encourages citizens of Staunton to "discourage negroes from coming to town"
                    or face the prospect of being "over-run by an idle, vagrant population who will
                    live by stealing" as well as rising prices for agricultural products.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1865.11.14.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Endowment for Washington College</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Encourages "the people of Augusta" to contribute to the endowment of
                    Washington College, which is still severely damaged from the war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Contracts for Labor</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>As soon as the Legislature shall meet a law should be enacted in reference to
                        the contracts for labor, which may be entered into between the Freedmen and
                        their employers. This should be done before the Holidays, as that is the
                        time at which most of the contracts for the next year's labor will be made.
                        The law should be such as to ensure, on the one hand, the faithful
                        performance, by the Freedmen, of their part of the contracts, and, on the
                        other, to protect efficiently the Freedmen against the imposition of such
                        employers as would be base enough to attempt to take advantage of their
                        ignorance of dependent circumstances. The law should be rigid, and even and
                        exact justice should be meted out to both of the contracting parties. The
                        Freedmen should be required to work faithfully, and their employees should
                        be required to pay them punctually a just compensation.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article calls on the legislature to adopt rules for labor contracts as
                    soon as possible. The law should ensure both the "faithful performance" of the
                    Freedmen" and to protect them "against the imposition of such employers as would
                    be base enough to attempt to take advantage of their ignorance and dependent
                    circumstances."`</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1865.11.14.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Jno. Willis McCue</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>Jonathon W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>Jonathon H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that Jonathon Willis McCue, of Augusta, has been pardoned and
                    released from the penitentiary.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1865.11.14.04">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
