<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1869/va.au.rv.1869.04.23">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>10/12/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1869-04-23">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day norm="">23</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1869.04.23.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1869.04.23.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Some of our exchanges are urging with all their vim the necessity of
                        unanimity on the part of the conservatives of the State in the present
                        political crisis. This we have felt and urged at all times, and, especially
                        when the election on the adoption or rejection of the proposed constitution
                        seemed imminent. And we yield to none at present in warmth of desire for
                        unanimity on the part of our people in the approaching crisis. We think it
                        essential to the future welfare of the State that there should be
                        unanimity--but, not that attainable only by the sacrifice of principles and
                        long established and acknowledged rights. Not the unanimity of the man who,
                        while his storehouse is being invaded by a band of thieves, and the
                        sustenance of his family is being carried off, counsels the members thereof,
                        as they value peace and quiet and their lives, to remain quiet and let the
                        robbers do their worst. But the unanimity which assails the thief in his
                        midnight revels, recovers the purloined articles from his grasp and drives
                        him in ignominious and head-long flight from the premises. This was the
                        unanimity we had, until temporizing expedients were suggested with their
                        concomitant demoralization.</p>
                    <p>We anxiously await the action of the meeting called by the Conservative
                        Executive Committee on the 28 inst., in Richmond, but trust they will be
                        guided by superior wisdom. If they incline to a new State Ticket, although
                        the old one is good enough for us, let it be one that the people can be
                        united upon. Let it not be the Walker ticket, which under the guise of
                        conservatism, would sell us out to the Republican party. We warn them in
                        advance, as we warned those who advocated this ticket in its incipiency,
                        that persistence in the Walker movement can only result in the election of
                        the Wells Ticket.</p>
                    <p>All in the Valley long for peace and quiet, but they are not willing to
                        secure it at the price of a sacrifice of principles, honor or rights and we
                        caution those who assemble on the 28th that all the wisdom they can command
                        will be required to secure the sympathy and concurrence of the Whites of the
                        State.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Supports the assembly of the Conservative party but warns them not to act
                    like the Walkerites and sacrifice principle for expediency. Insists the whites
                    in the state want unanimity of action but only if principle and honor can be
                    saved as well.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>With the probability of an election on the 4th Thursday in May next, we again
                        appeal to all who have not registered to do so when the books are again
                        opened. This is an incumbent and imperative duty and must not--can not be
                        avoided.</p>
                    <p>Those registered must come forward when the polls are opened and cast their
                        votes.--In the absence of a knowledge of what clauses of the Underwood
                        Constitution will be submitted separately we can not speak specially, but
                        advise all, as the safest course to vote "no" on all propositions. Vote
                        against the Constitution as a whole and against every clause submitted
                        separately.</p>
                    <p>Do not let anything detain you at home, on election day, but come forward and
                        vote. The welfare of Virginia demands this at your hands and you will be
                        derelict in your duty if you fail to be present at the polls and cast your
                        votes.</p>
                    <p>Remember, safety lies alone in voting against the Constitution and every
                        separate clause submitted.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Again urges all voters to register for the coming election and vote against
                    the proposed constitution to secure the welfare of the state.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper warns against assuming that the Walker Party is very strong and
                    popular in Virginia. They caution the Conservative Convention that an
                    endorsement for the ticket may divide the white vote.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1869.04.23.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The annual meeting of the Superintendents of Virginia's Lunatic Asylums
                    will be held in Staunton on June 16th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Covell</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. C. Covell, principal of the Deaf, Dumb, and Blind Institution, warns
                    against trespassing on Institute grounds.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>A. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A. B. Cochran of Staunton was elected Worthy Grand Conductor of the Grand
                    Lodge of Odd Fellows.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Harman and Company have put in a new daily stage line between Staunton and
                    Harrisonburg, and offer connections to the Chesapeake and Ohio and Orange,
                    Alexandria, and Manassas Railroads.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Collector of Internal Revenue will be in Staunton on the 26th, 27th,
                    and 28th of April to collect taxes on licenses, incomes, watches, and plate.
                    "All who have been notified and all delinquents are notified to come forward and
                    pay."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ide</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Staunton Musical Association gave a concert before a large crowd at the
                    chapel of the Deaf, Dumb, and Blind Institute. Professor Ide played the new
                    Stieff piano and agraffe trible.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Drowned</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clayton</ln>
                        <fn>Willie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clayton</ln>
                        <fn>W. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newman</ln>
                        <fn>W. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Willie Clayton, six-year old son of W. K. Clayton, drowned while attempting
                    to wade the Calf Pasture River on his way to see his step-father, W. W. Newman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bledsoe</ln>
                        <fn>Mortimer P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mortimer P. Bledsoe has taken charge of Augusta's American Hotel.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Herndon</ln>
                        <fn>Lemuel F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Radford</ln>
                        <fn>Susan F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lemuel F. Herndon of Albemarle and Mrs. Susan F. Radford of Fluvanna were
                    married at West View, Augusta County, on April 7th by the Rev. C. King.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moore</ln>
                        <fn>William R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William R. Moore died at his residence in Fairfield on April 6th of heart
                    disease. He was 66 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walters</ln>
                        <fn>Benny P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walters</ln>
                        <fn>William L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walters</ln>
                        <fn>Hannah C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Benny P. Walters, infant son of Dr. William L. and Hannah C. Walters died
                    suddenly on April 1st. He was 7 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Piper</ln>
                        <fn>Florence M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Piper</ln>
                        <fn>James A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Piper</ln>
                        <fn>Ann E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Florence M. Piper, beloved daughter of James A. and Ann E. Piper of
                    Staunton, "passed into the spirit land" on the night of April 17th. "After four
                    months of intense suffering, her spirit now has heavenward taken its flight, and
                    left us o'er clouded with gloom and burdened with grief. The home circle has
                    lost its cherished treasure; the church and sabbath school a valued and beloved
                    worker, whose place cannot well be filled, and society, a brilliant gem, the
                    charm, admiration and delight of all."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1869.04.23.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
