<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1869/va.au.rv.1869.12.17">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>01/31/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1869-12-17">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="12`">December</month>
            <day>17</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1869.12.17.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1869.12.17.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Admission of Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that Republican members of the Virginia State Legislature
                    issued a protest to Congress against re-admitting the state to the Union under
                    its present form of government. They argue that all legislators should be
                    subject to the test-oath.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The people of this State are now looking out for the speediest manner of
                        building up the interests of each particular section and all have, as with
                        one accord, come to the conclusion that the solution of the problem lies in
                        the opening up of lines of communication. Especially do we in this section
                        look forward to great good from completion of the great line from Norfolk or
                        Newport News to the Ohio, which runs through this county, and the consequent
                        construction of two other railway lines up and down the Valley, to cross the
                        Chesapeake and Ohio in this county, and connect with the combined roads from
                        Norfolk and Memphis at or near Salem.</p>
                    <p>That the result of the completion of these roads must be most advantageous to
                        the people of this county and the Valley will not be gainsaid. But the
                        question suggests itself how can we derive the greatest benefit from it.
                        These roads can not run by every man's door, and, while they give ready
                        access, in all directions, to markets, unless all can readily and easily
                        reach the various depots with heavy loads, it were almost as well that the
                        roads were never constructed. To be ever near to market and yet not be able
                        to reach it with produce, would make our people another Tantalus chained to
                        a rock, with water surrounding him to his lips and yet dying with thirst.
                        The remedy in our case, however, is easy, if the proper steps be taken, and
                        consists in the construction of good country roads--not dirt roads, but good
                        McAdamized roads. Such roads can be made in every section of the county if
                        we only make the effort. Staunton must take the initiative and McAdamize her
                        un-McAdamized roads to the corporation limit. There the county court should
                        take the matter in hand, and McAdamize, say two, three, five or seven miles,
                        as it may deem best, on each of the main roads each year until they reach
                        the county limit. Then the cross roads should come in for their portion of
                        improvement. This would cause an additional tax of a small amount each year,
                        but we know of no object for which our people would more cheerfully bear a
                        tax. The increased amounts they would be able to transport, in all seasons,
                        and at times when they could no nothing on their farms and can not use the
                        present roads on account of their muddy condition, and the saving in wear
                        and tear of teams, wagons &amp;c., would more than four-fold compensate
                        them for the yearly cost of making good roads and keeping them in repair.</p>
                    <p>The New Constitution, on the subject of roads, has the following:</p>
                    <p>"ART. 7.--<emph rend="italic">Sec</emph>. 4.--Each Township shall be divided
                        into one or more road districts. In each road district there shall annually
                        be elected one overseer of roads, under whose direction the roads shall be
                        kept in repair <emph rend="italic">at public expense</emph>, in a mode
                        prescribed by law.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Sec</emph>. 5.--The General Assembly, at its first
                        session after the adoption of this constitution shall pass such laws as may
                        be necessary to give effect to the provisions of this article."</p>
                    <p>If the Legislature is to pass a law for keeping in repair county roads, at
                        public expense, it must do it by taxing. That it will make such a law there
                        is scarcely a doubt. Our object then is simply to encourage the idea of
                        first class county roads, to be built from a central point, on the score of
                        economy. If all the overseers provided for in the constitution were to
                        commence simply putting in repair our dirt roads, it would cost a large
                        amount yearly to keep them in repair. Whereas if we commence from a central
                        point to McAdamize and extend it yearly as far as can be done, in a few
                        years we have good roads over the county, with a necessity for only a
                        nominal tax to keep them in order. Is it not well for all of our people to
                        consider this subject, and especially our Legislators, who must, in all
                        probability, in a very short time, frame a law to carry into effect the new
                        road system?</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper stresses the importance of the construction of roads and
                    railroads to help bring prosperity to Virginia. The article also offers plans
                    for implementing taxation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ryan</ln>
                        <fn>J. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burnett</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hill</ln>
                        <fn>Reuben D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stribling</ln>
                        <fn>Francis T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fifer</ln>
                        <fn>B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickle</ln>
                        <fn>Robert G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGuffin</ln>
                        <fn>David C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A number of citizens from Augusta had their political disabilities removed
                    by an act of Congress.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1869.12.17.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>Ned</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mitchel</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>An African American child was found nearly frozen in the stable of Ned
                    Burke. It was the baby of Maggie Mitchel, who claimed that the gypsies had
                    stolen it.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn>Bob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fishburn</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Justice</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A black man being led to jail by Justice Fishburn escaped and ran before
                    reaching the building. A pursuit ensued and he was captured in the rear of Bob
                    Campbell's Bar Room.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Arbuckle</ln>
                        <fn>John D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vanlear</ln>
                        <fn>M. Lizzie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vanlear</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pinkerton</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John D. Arbuckle of West Virginia and Miss M. Lizzie Vanlear, daughter of
                    the late Rev. John A. Vanlear, were married near Mount Solon on December 8th by
                    the Rev. John Pinkerton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Matheney</ln>
                        <fn>Lafayette D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Demasters</ln>
                        <fn>Martha C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lockridge</ln>
                        <fn>John N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Capt. Lafayette D. Matheney and Miss Martha C. Demasters, both of Augusta,
                    were married at Wintergreen, near Sherando, on December 9th by the Rev. John N.
                    Lockridge.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Valentine</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Holman</ln>
                        <fn>Emma</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ervin</ln>
                        <fn>J. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel T. Valentine, formerly of Augusta, and Miss Emma Holman of Indiana
                    were married at the residence of the bride's mother on October 28th by the Rev.
                    J. E. Ervin.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wiseman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Wiseman, formerly of Augusta, died in West Virginia on November 24th.
                    He was 19 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitlock</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Robert Whitlock died at his Augusta residence on November 26th. He was 53
                    years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fauber</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fauber</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Fauber, son of Samuel C. Fauber of Augusta, died in Illinois at the
                    residence of his brother on November 12th. He was 35 years old and leaves a
                    young wife.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1869.12.17.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
