<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1869/va.au.rv.1869.12.24">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>01/31/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1869-12-24">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="12">December</month>
            <day>24</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1869.12.24.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1869.12.24.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The subject of Virginia Reconstruction still hangs fire in Congress. Virginia
                        has taken every step required by the Reconstruction Acts, but yet among some
                        of the out and out Radicals this is not considered sufficient, and other
                        guarantees are demanded. The case of Georgia, in regard to her expulsion of
                        the negro member of her Legislature, is taken as the ground for opposition
                        to the early reconstruction of Virginia. The Reconstruction Committee have
                        been harangued by a number of Carpet-baggers, who are opposed to the early
                        admission of the State, whose positions will be vacated by such course, and
                        who exhibit "the spoils" as the great reason of their opposition. Many of
                        those who came here after the war and who held offices and now hold offices,
                        are, however, earnest advocates of Virginia's early admission, without
                        further requirements or conditions. Some of these have appeared also before
                        the Reconstruction Committee and have successfully answered all the
                        objections raised by those opposed to early reconstruction, yet, from the
                        proceedings of the Reconstruction Committee on Saturday last it is certain
                        that any definite action will not be taken in the case of Virginia until
                        after the holidays.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper updates readers on Virginia's possible re-admission to the Union.
                    The article asserts that Georgia's expulsion of African American law-makers from
                    the legislature and a stream of "carpet baggers" speaking out against
                    readmission have hurt the state's chances.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Negro Exodus from Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The fact that the negroes in droves are leaving every part of Virginia at
                        this time for the inviting cotton fields, is attracting much attention at
                        the North, and many are the speculations in regard to it. The New York <emph
                            rend="italic">Herald</emph> says:</p>
                    <p>The negroes appear to be leaving Virginia in shoals for the cotton
                        plantations of Georgia, Alabama and Mississippi, where they are sure of
                        better wages and a warmer climate than they have in the "Old Dominion." In
                        Richmond, for instance, a labor agent advertises for negroes by thousands to
                        go South at from fifteen dollars to twenty-two dollars and fifty cents per
                        month. Before the war the sales of "Virginny niggers" for the cotton States
                        amounted in Richmond to about twenty millions of dollars a year. The present
                        demand from the cotton planters for these Virginia field hands is but the
                        revival of the old one in a new shape. Under the old slavery demand the
                        Virginia master sold to the trader "a few niggers?" from year to year to
                        make both ends meet. Under the new voluntary freedom and free labor system
                        whole families and colonies of these Virginia plantation blacks are moving
                        South. The end will probably be the disappearance of the black population
                        from the State and its replacement by white labor. This will involve the
                        cutting up of the large plantations into small farms for Germans, Danish,
                        Norwegian, English, Welsh, Irish, and Yankee settlers--a transformation
                        which will double the value of every acre of land in the State within the
                        next ten or fifteen years.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that large numbers of African Americans are leaving
                    Virginia for the South in search of better wages. The article asserts that this
                    will lead to the replacement of black labor with white labor on small farms.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1869.12.24.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCutchen</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>G. W. McCutchen, sheriff of Augusta county, paid $31,000 to the state
                    treasury. The treasury received a total of $60,000 on Saturday and is "being
                    replenished pretty rapidly."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sears</ln>
                        <fn>Ed H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper applauds the appointment of Ed H. Sears as Staunton Postmaster.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunter</ln>
                        <fn>C. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>C. W. Hunter, superintendent of the Methodist Sunday School of Staunton,
                    will oversee the annual Christmas tree exhibition in the church. The public is
                    invited to attend.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The ladies of New Hope are holding a fair to raise money for the erection
                    of a Temperance Hall. The councils of Augusta and Rockingham are invited to
                    attend.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crowder</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Thomas J. Crowder is now in charge of the Virginia Hotel Bar and Billiard
                    Saloon. "Those desiring a little of the oh-be-joyful, served in any style, or a
                    sociable game of Billiards, can be accommodated in the best manner by calling on
                    Tommy."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Masonic</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Staunton Lodge will meet on the 31st. Union Royal Arch Chapter will meet on
                    the 28th. Stevenson Commandry, Knights Templar, will meet on the 27th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>May</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>Kitty Lomax</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>William E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George W. May and Miss Kitty Lomax Waddell, daughter of Dr. Alexander
                    Waddell of Staunton, were married on December 21st at the residence of the
                    bride's father by the Rev. William E. Baker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Silling</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stover</ln>
                        <fn>Mary C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>R. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John A. Silling and Miss Mary C. Stover were married on December 16th by
                    the Rev. R. C. Walker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carson</ln>
                        <fn>Robert N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Meck</ln>
                        <fn>Amanda C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>William E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Robert N. Carson and Miss Amanda C. Meck, both of Augusta, were married in
                    Staunton at the Virginia Hotel on December 15th by the Rev. William E. Baker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>David P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>Cornelia M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richardson</ln>
                        <fn>W. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>David P. Bell and Miss Cornelia M. Patterson, daughter of John A.
                    Patterson, were married at Long Glade, Augusta County, on November 18th by the
                    Rev. W. T. Richardson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woodward</ln>
                        <fn>John P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>Lucy R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shreckhise</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John P. Woodward and Miss Lucy R. Wright of Augusta were married in
                    Staunton on December 15th by the Rev. J. M. Shreckhise.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Engleman</ln>
                        <fn>D. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>M. Kate</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bushong</ln>
                        <fn>A. A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>D. B. Engleman and Miss M. Kate Koiner, daughter of J. H. Koiner, were
                    married at the residence of the bride's father near Middlebrook on December 16th
                    by the Rev. A. A. J. Bushong. The paper sends warmest wishes to the "happy pair"
                    and thanks them for a piece of cake.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hogshead</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hogshead</ln>
                        <fn>Elijah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Margaret Hogshead, wife of Elijah Hogshead, died near Middlebrook,
                    Augusta County, on December 16th. She was 62 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John McClure, son of Andrew and Mary McClure, died in Staunton at the
                    residence of his parents on December 14th. He was 2 years old. "This little one
                    has left sad hearts behind, yet if its parents have one treasure less on earth,
                    they have one more in heaven, and 'they only can be said to possess a child
                    forever, who have lost one in infancy.'"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1869.12.24.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
