<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1869/va.au.rv.1869.06.25">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>01/18/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1869-06-25">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="06">June</month>
            <day norm="">25</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1869.06.25.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1869.06.25.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>With the present Candidates for Congress in the field in the district, it is
                        scarcely possible to prevent the election of a Radical. Some of the
                        Candidates can and some can not take the required oath. The two most
                        prominent ones, who are likely to receive the largest number of votes, will
                        be necessitated to have their disabilities removed before they can take
                        their seat if elected. In a contested election between either one and a
                        radical, (and we learn a radical is to be voted for,) no matter how few
                        votes he may receive, there can be little doubt as to the result. Congress,
                        with its radical majority would scarcely be likely to remove disabilities
                        from any one in order that he might take a seat, when one of their own party
                        is ready to their hand who can take the oath.</p>
                    <p>This is the case, as it stands at the present, but need not exist, had Mr.
                        Wm. Milnes, of Page, who is the choice of the people of this District
                        announced himself. This he has declined to do, though repeatedly called
                        upon, on the ground, as we learn, that being a stranger to the people,
                        except in his immediate proximity, he could not be their choice.</p>
                    <p> We have but a few words to say on this subject, but we hope sufficient to
                        induce him to place himself in nomination. Mr. Milnes, though personally a
                        stranger to the people of this and the more Southern Counties of the
                        District, is generally well known to all by reputation. They know that he
                        has large interests in our midst, a guarantee that can not be passed by with
                        impunity. They have heard time and again of his conservatism, sound sense
                        and worth as a man, which has been so long practically demonstrated in his
                        immediate neighborhood, until he has become really their choice. They know
                        that he came among us to build up, not to destroy, and they want his
                        services in a more enlarged field. They are not personally acquainted with
                        him, and on this account alone feel a reluctance in demanding his services.
                        But were he willing to serve them, he would receive the almost undivided
                        vote of Botetourt, Rockbridge and Augusta to start with. We speak what we
                        have the best reasons for believing true, when we say that Mr. Milnes, <emph
                            rend="italic">is the choice</emph> of the district, and that, if he
                        supposes the desire for his announcement as a Candidate for Congress is
                        confined to his neighbors, he is greatly mistaken. </p>
                    <p>The people of the District believe he can do a great deal of good for us, and
                        knowing that he can take his seat and that his interests are largely
                        identified with our own, prefer him to any man who can be nominated.</p>
                    <p>Satisfied that he is really and truly the choice of the people of the
                        district and that it is only necessary for a gentleman of Mr. Milnes'
                        enlarged views to be satisfied of the fact to allow his name to be used, we
                        take the liberty of placing his name forward as our Candidate for Congress.
                        We call upon our contemporaries in the Valley to run up his name at once and
                        gratify the wishes of the people.</p>
                    <p>No time is to be lost and we therefore, in the name of the people, call upon
                        Mr. Milnes to publicly express his willingness to serve them.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article calls upon William Milnes to announce his candidacy for
                    Congress. Although Milnes has publicly declined to run for the seat, suggesting
                    people do not know him well enough, the author says Milnes's reputation far
                    exceeds personal acquaintance among the citizenry. In the name of the people,
                    the article states, Milnes must "express his willingness to serve them."
                    Otherwise, a Radical will surely capture the seat.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>At the Convention held in the Court-house on Saturday last, in accordance
                        with the announcement made by the Superintendents of the county, the
                        following ticket for the Senate and House of Delegates was nominated:</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">For the Senate: </emph> Jos. A. Waddell. </p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">For the House of Delegates: </emph> H.M. Bell and
                        Marshall Hanger. </p>
                    <p>The ticket may not be in exact accordance with the wishes of each and every
                        voter, for that were impossible. It, is however, the one selected upon which
                        to concentrate the Conservative voters of the County. The gentlemen are all
                        well known and to the manor born. Their interests are identified with the
                        interests of the people of Augusta. Although some may have preferences for
                        others as representatives, yet it would be folly to vote our special
                        preferences and thereby increase the chances of, if not secure the election
                        of a Radical ticket from this county.</p>
                    <p>We therefore advise one and all to unite as one man on this ticket. The
                        Legislature we want and the Legislature we must have. Be wise then and vote
                        to secure it.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>Alex B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>H. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>Marshall</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>This article announces the nominations for Senate and House of Delegates.
                    While the author comments that they may not be the candidates that suited the
                    wishes of all voters, they nevertheless will represent the interests of
                    Conservatives.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Convention of Superintendents of Insane Asylums</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The 23rd annual meeting of the Association of Medical Superintendents of
                    American Institutions for the Insane was held in Staunton's Virginia Hotel
                    between June 15th and 18th. Delegates from around the country attended.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Colporteur Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J. I.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>G. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Covell</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ross</ln>
                        <fn>C. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Colporteur Convention of the American Tract Society met in Staunton.
                    Seven branches of the Christian Church were represented. The group thanked the
                    Rev. J. I. Miller of the Evangelical Lutheran Church for use of his office; Rev.
                    G. B. Taylor, hotel proprietors, and citizens of Staunton for hospitality; and
                    Maj. J. C. Covell, Principal of the Institute for the Deaf, Dumb, and Blind, for
                    an invitation to exercises held on the 16th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1869.06.25.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allen</ln>
                        <fn>Waldo M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Waldo M. Allen has been appointed mayor of Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Augusta Fire Company will take an excursion to Goshen on July 3rd.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Masons of Staunton Lodge No. 13, joined by local brethren, celebrated
                    St. John's Day on the 24th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that the conservatives of the Valley are "waking up."
                    "Their speakers are haranguing the sovereigns at every town, school-house and
                    cross-roads. The people are alive to the necessity of action and every
                    indication exists that there will be a very large vote polled in the Valley."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Friends of Temperance</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Staunton Council No. 47, Friends of Temperance, will meet tonight to close
                    the quarter.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Wesleyan Female Institute held their annual soiree in the Chapel of the
                    Deaf, Dumb, and Blind Institution. A large audience attended "who were generally
                    delighted with the progress and proficiency of the young ladies."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>H. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tams</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donaghe</ln>
                        <fn>B. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bayley</ln>
                        <fn>E. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Effinger</ln>
                        <fn>M. Harvey</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phillips</ln>
                        <fn>R. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>English</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wayt</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Stockholders of the Virginia Fire Insurance Company met and decided to
                    cease insuring against fire and begin operating as a life insurance company
                    only.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The following are the precincts at which votes will be cast, at the election
                        on July 6th.</p>
                    <p>Read carefully, that you may have trouble and delay in casting your votes on
                        election day.</p>
                    <p> 1st <emph rend="italic">Dist. </emph> Dividing line, Greenville road to
                        Beverly Street. Persons living West of Greenville road and South of Beverly
                        Street, will vote at the Court-house. Persons living East of Greenville road
                        and South of Beverly Street, will vote at Piper's new Building, near
                        Virginia Hotel, Staunton. </p>
                    <p> 2nd <emph rend="italic">Dist. </emph> Dividing line, Churchville road to
                        Augusta Street. Persons living North of Churchville road and East of Augusta
                        Street, will vote at Town Hall, Staunton. Persons living South of
                        Churchville road and West of Augusta Street, will vote at the old Market
                        House, Staunton. </p>
                    <p> 3rd <emph rend="italic">Dist. </emph> Middlebrook, Craigsville &amp;
                        Swoope's Mill, same boundaries as formerly except that persons living in the
                        Newport Precinct will vote at Middlebrook. </p>
                    <p> 4th <emph rend="italic">Dist </emph> Greenville and Midway same boundaries
                        as formerly. Except that persons living in the Stuart's Draft precinct will
                        vote at Greenville. </p>
                    <p> 5th <emph rend="italic">Dist </emph> Waynesboro, Fishersville and Sherando </p>
                    <p> 6th <emph rend="italic">Dist </emph> New Hope and Mount Meridian. </p>
                    <p> 7th <emph rend="italic">Dist </emph> Mount Sidney and Spring Hill. </p>
                    <p> 8th <emph rend="italic">Dist </emph> Mount Solon and Parnassus. </p>
                    <p> 9th <emph rend="italic">Dist </emph> Churchville and Deerfield. </p>
                    <p> The five last mentioned Dist's have same boundaries as formerly. Persons are
                            <emph rend="italic">required</emph> to vote in the precinct in which
                        they reside, but if they show to the Commissioners of Election that for want
                        of notice or other good reason they failed to vote at the proper precinct,
                        and make oath that they have not voted before at the election they may vote
                        at any precinct in their magisterial district. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article lists the voting places for the various districts in Augusta
                    county. The article states plainly that a voter is required to vote in the
                    precinct in which they reside. Excepted are those who can show that they were
                    either not informed of their voting place or who will swear an oath that have
                    not yet voted.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Rev. R. A. Holland of Trinity M. E. Church South Baltimore preached at
                    the commencement of the Wesleyan Female Institute. His subject was "Jesus of
                    Nazareth" and "I am not Ashamed of the Gospel of Christ."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Atkinson</ln>
                        <fn>John M. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>Francis P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>Alex H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Latane</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. John M. P. Atkinson, president of Hampden Sidney College, and Miss
                    Francis P. Stuart, daughter of Alex. H. H. Stuart, were married on June 16th at
                    the Staunton residence of the bride's father by the Rev. J. A. Latane.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Prufer</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Prufer</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Prufer</ln>
                        <fn>Caroline</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Joseph T. Prufer, son of Frank and Caroline Prufer, died in Staunton on
                    June 19th. He was 11 weeks old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ensor</ln>
                        <fn>Charles Elmore</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ensor</ln>
                        <fn>George B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ensor</ln>
                        <fn>Virginia H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Charles Elmore Ensor, infant son of George B. and Virginia H. Ensor, died
                    on June 11th of congestion of the brain. He was 1 year old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1869.06.25.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
