<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1869/va.au.rv.1869.09.03">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>01/22/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1869-09-03">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day norm="">3</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1869.09.03.01" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The widely heralded meeting of the officers, (U.S and Confederate,) who took
                        part in the battle of Gettysburg, to mark the operations of both armies on
                        the field, by enduring memorials of granite, has proven, as many expected a
                        great farce. But few of the prominent Northern officers were present and
                        only two Confederate officers of minor grades. The Hotel man did not make as
                        much as he expected, when he got up the idea.</p>
                    <p>Gen. Lee was invited and forwarded the following reply:</p>
                    <p>Lexington, VA., August 5, 1869.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Dear Sir</emph>--Absence from Lexington has prevented my
                        receiving until to-day your letter of the 26th ult., inclosing an invitation
                        from the Gettysburg Battle-field Memorial Association, to attend a meeting
                        of the officers engaged in that battle at Gettysburg, for the purpose of
                        marking upon the ground by enduring memorials of granite the positions and
                        movements of the armies on the field. My engagements will not permit me to
                        be present. I believe if there, I could not add anything material to the
                        information existing on the subject. I think it wiser, moreover, not to keep
                        open the sores of war but to follow the examples of those nations who
                        endeavored to obliterate the marks of civil strife, to commit to oblivion
                        the feelings engendered. Very respectfully,<lb/> Your obedient servant,<lb/>
                        R. E. Lee.</p>
                    <p>The New York <emph rend="italic">Herald</emph> and other Northern papers were
                        down on perpetuating the memory of Gettysburg. The Democratic Watchman,
                        (Pa.) expresses their sentiments in short, which for its succinctness and
                        pith, we copy below:</p>
                    <p>"Another big fuss at Gettysburg. A lot of officers are there for the purpose
                        of fixing definitely the positions occupied by the troops on the first day's
                        battle. Better take Gen. Lee's advise and let the darned thing die out of
                        remembrance."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper prints Robert E. Lee's note declining an invitation to join
                    officers on the battlefield of Gettysburg to mark troop positions for posterity.
                    Lee and a number of Democratic newspapers believe that the battle of Gettysburg
                    and the strife accompanying the Civil War are best left forgotten.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We observe as rather remarkable that the Radical papers do not chronicle the
                        recent horrible crimes perpetrated in different parts of the Southern
                        country, upon white woman, by depraved and wicked blacks, as "rebel
                        outrages" at all. They leave out the word "rebel!"--<emph rend="italic"
                            >Norfolk Journal</emph></p>
                    <p>We suggest to our brethren of the Conservative Press, that we call all such
                        outrages "Radical outrages," as we have, clearly, the same right to call
                        them "Radical outrages," as Radicals have to style acts of white men in the
                        South "Rebel outrages." Besides, Conservative colored men are of the better
                        class of colored people, are well behaved, and disdain the commission of
                        such heinous crimes, while Radical negroes are notoriously the guilty
                        perpetrators of such crimes. Then let us give the devil his due--fight him
                        with his own fire and call these crimes by their right names--"Radical
                        outrages."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper asserts that crime allegedly committed by African Americans
                    should be termed "Radical outrages."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1869.09.03.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turner</ln>
                        <fn>Charles W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turner</ln>
                        <fn>A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Charles W. Turner, son of Prof. A. J. Turner of Staunton, was elected
                    assessor of a territory in Montana.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Canby</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Towne</ln>
                        <fn>F. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Gen. Canby appointed Lt. F. B. Towne Military Commissioner in Augusta,
                    Albemarle, and Fluvanna counties.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>Robert W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Burglars entered the store of Robert W. Burke and took $30 cash and a dozen
                    bottles of whiskey.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Rain fell in Augusta County for the first time in eleven weeks. It was not
                    enough to save the corn crop, but it will help the pasturage and aid the
                    farmers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper remarks on the large number of new buildings in town that have
                    just been completed or are under construction. The article estimates that the
                    town will be 1/6 larger than last year. Despite this fast expansion, all the
                    buildings are occupied.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sears</ln>
                        <fn>Edward</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Postmaster Edward Sears is offering a number of locked post-office boxes
                    for rent.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Munsey</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. Munsey delivered an oration on "Man" at the Methodist Church on Friday.
                    The paper praises the presentation. The event raised $78 for Mr. Munsey.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper stresses the importance of insuring property. The many uninsured
                    barns and dwellings that have burned stand as testimony to that point.
                    Interested readers are directed toward the Southern Mutual Fire Insurance
                    Company.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Augusta County Court</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">August Term.</emph>--Lt. T. E. Towne qualified as
                        Commissioner in Chancery for Augusta county, <emph rend="italic">vice</emph>
                        Joseph A. Waddell.</p>
                    <p>Robt. G. Byers, Wm. A. Reed and Wm. H. Bull qualified as deputy Sheriffs.</p>
                    <p>S. Travers Phillips qualified as Attorney at Law.</p>
                    <p>Joel S. Wallace and Geo. W. Sutler severally renewed their bonds as Notaries
                        Public.</p>
                    <p>The Grand Jury brought in nine indictments for misdemeanors, and one against
                        Jno. M. Stanley, for murder.</p>
                    <p>Rev. Jno. N. Lockridge and Rev. Rufus H. Wilson, Ministers of the M. E.
                        Church South, were severally appointed and authorized to celebrate the
                        rights of matrimony.</p>
                    <p>Geo. W. Greiner, Jno. R. Johnson and Saml. Hunt were appointed a committee to
                        superintend the rebuilding of the bridge across South River, at Waynesboro,
                        in place of the committee appointed at June term.</p>
                    <p>The election on the proposed county subscription to the Valley Railroad was
                        postponed until the 4th Thursday in October next.</p>
                    <p>A large number of cases were disposed of on the Issue and Misdemeanor
                        dockets.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Towne</ln>
                        <fn>T. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Byers</ln>
                        <fn>Robert G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bull</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phillips</ln>
                        <fn>S. Travers</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wallace</ln>
                        <fn>Joel S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sutler</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stanley</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lockridge</ln>
                        <fn>John N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>Rufus H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greiner</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>John R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunt</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Proceedings of the August Term of the County Court.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bishop</ln>
                        <fn>Robert E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bishop</ln>
                        <fn>Mary J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Robert E. Bishop, son of Robert E. and Mary J. Bishop, died in Staunton on
                    August 28th. He was 13 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1869.09.03.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
