<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1869/va.au.rv.1869.03.05">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>10/10/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1869-03-05">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day norm="">5</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1869.03.05.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1869.03.05.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Expediency has been the curse of all ages, times and peoples. It has been the
                        peculiar rock on which this country has split. Its history has been
                        interlined here and there for years with temporizing induced by the specious
                        argument of expediency, the fruits of which are the extraordinary condition
                        of affairs we now witness. Opinions have and will be diverse and the effort
                        has been to assimilate and harmonize this contrariety of political opinion
                        for the sake of peace.--Principle was sacrificed for seeming policy and the
                        result was a temporary solution of the difficulties. Opinions were not
                        changed--not even harmonized, but merely suppressed, temporarily, to break
                        forth again with renewed vigor and exhibit their results with a tenfold
                        damaging effect. Looking back through the past this will be clearly seen by
                        the unprejudiced mind and acknowledged to be the natural result of bartering
                        principle for expediency.</p>
                    <p>This seems destined also to be the curse of the future. A powerful party
                        based solely on the fanaticism of the age holds the reins of power. For four
                        years more it is firmly seated in the control of affairs. It wields an
                        immense patronage while in power and is disposed to oppress all who oppose
                        its edicts or even differ with it in opinion--Thousands, whose convictions
                        for a life-time have been in direct opposition to the fanaticism which has
                        engendered it, still maintain the old time principles of our forefathers and
                        are the chosen subjects for its malicious persecutions, as witnessed on all
                        sides. On this account, when the last lease of power was obtained by this
                        party, the cry of expediency was raised. The cry was "let us accept its
                        theories for the sake of peace."--Barter principle for expediency. With the
                        lights of the past before them it is wonderful that so many of the learned
                        and gifted in the land were carried away by this insidious plea. It is less
                        wonderful that some, tired of these persecutions, should actually sacrifice
                        principle for expediency. The fruits of the former rigidly adhered to are
                        necessarily postponed to the future--the fruits of the latter are to be
                        found in the emoluments and "spoils" of the present. It is alike expediency
                        that induces temporizing or yielding and its direful results are to be
                        reaped in the bitter future. It needs no prophetic mind to predict the
                        results in the near future of temporizing or yielding to the cry of
                        expediency in the present. Beware, then, ye, who to escape the persecutions
                        or share in the spoils of the present, barter away principles, which erected
                        out of a savage wild a Republic, the model government of the world, a strict
                        adherence to which can alone preserve it and the liberties of your children
                        and your children's children in all time to come.</p>
                    <p>Expediency nailed the Savior to the cross--principle produced a Redeemer for
                        a sin-polluted world.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Opinion column condemning Southerners who submit to Republican policies,
                    thereby giving up principle for the sake of expediency. Believes all Southerners
                    should stick to principle regardless of the sacrifice.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The managing committee of the Inaugural ceremonies, have been very much
                        troubled at the question of admitting or refusing to admit colored persons
                        to the Inauguration Ball. They have, at last, nerved themselves to decide
                        the question and authorize the announcement "that colored persons will not
                        be present, the high-toned colored population having too much self-respect
                        to force themselves into society where they are not welcome, and those who
                        have not any self-respect will not be admitted anyhow."</p>
                    <p>One would think that those who proclaimed themselves the <emph rend="italic"
                            >especial</emph> and <emph rend="italic">peculiar</emph> friends of the
                        colored people, sitting with them in their meetings &amp;c., should
                        welcome them everywhere. It seems, however, that they are not <emph
                            rend="italic">welcome</emph>, even to a participation in all the
                        inauguration ceremonies of the first President they have helped to elect;
                        nay, are refused permission to participate in a portion of the pleasures of
                        the occasion. This is a singular act for boasted friends, but,
                        nevertheless--"the colored troops fought nobly."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Pokes fun at Republicans, supposed friends of blacks, who recently decided
                    not to allow blacks to attend the inaugural ball of President Grant.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1869.03.05.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shelton</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shelton</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper corrects their mistaken report that Henry Shelton, who is under
                    sentence for theft, served as vice-president of the county Republican meeting.
                    It was actually Robert Shelton who served in that position.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reynolds</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Isaac Brown, "an old and highly respected colored man," died in Staunton of
                    pneumonia. "He was for many years the faithful slave of Dr. Reynolds, and
                    retained, to his last moments, a fond attachment to his old master and his
                    memory. As a freedman he was equally faithful, upright and honest, and his death
                    was regretted alike by white and colored. His funeral was attended by a number
                    of his white friends. In his death this community has lost one of the most
                    correct and trustworthy colored men we ever knew."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Another Pow-Wow</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On Saturday night last the Republicans held a meeting in the M. E. colored
                        Church in this place. No whites save those invited knew of the meeting, and
                        but few of them attended. We learn that speeches were made by Maj. Jno. A.
                        Harman, Rev. Mr. Phelps, A.T. Maupin, Geo. A. Smith, Wm. L. Herr, and Rev.
                        Bowser (colored) and ---Black (colored.)--Wright Bolen, (colored) presided.</p>
                    <p>We are unable to give a detailed account of the meeting, but are informed
                        that Rev. Bowser, (colored) grew eloquent in speaking of the conversion of
                        Maj. Harman, liking him when opposed to the Republican party to Saul of
                        Tarsus, but when converted, to Paul, whom, with open arms, the colored
                        people welcomed, as the Rock of their salvation in this section.</p>
                    <p>Our apology for this meagre statement is that we were not an invited guest
                        and heard of the meeting only after it was over.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phelps</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maupin</ln>
                        <fn>A. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>George A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Herr</ln>
                        <fn>William L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowser</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bolen</ln>
                        <fn>Wright</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Gives a brief account of a Republican meeting held in the M.E. colored
                    Church, naming those who gave speeches. Few details because editor did not have
                    a correspondent there.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garber</ln>
                        <fn>William B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn>Nancy Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garber</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William B. Garber and Miss Nancy Jane Grove, both of Augusta, were married
                    on February 18th by the Rev. Martin Garber.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Butler</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Thomas Butler died at his Staunton residence on February 26th. He was 66
                    years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>Ann E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Ann E. Walker died at her residence on Middle River near New Hope,
                    Augusta County, on February 6th. She was 53 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCreary</ln>
                        <fn>John L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John L. McCreary, died at his father's residence near Kindig's school house
                    on February 15th of consumption. He was 36 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robertson</ln>
                        <fn>Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>John J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Ann Robertson died in Waynesboro at the residence of her son-in-law,
                    John J. Bell, on February 17th. She was 74 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barrett</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Thomas Barrett died in Staunton on February 28th after a very short
                    illness.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1869.03.05.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
