<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1869/va.au.rv.1869.03.19">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>10/10/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1869-03-19">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day norm="">19</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1869.03.19.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1869.03.19.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Republican Convention, which assembled in Petersburg last week, after a
                        noisy contention between the Wells and anti-Wells members, and after much
                        labor and travail, brought forth the following ticket.</p>
                    <p>For Governor, H.H. Wells</p>
                    <p>Lieut-Governor, Dr. J. D. Harris, (colored.)</p>
                    <p>For Attorney General, Thomas R. Bowden.</p>
                    <p>For Congressman at large, A. M. Crane.</p>
                    <p>There are various rumors as to how Wells secured the nomination, one
                        correspondent stating that negro members, who had not enough money to pay
                        for meals and lodging, were suddenly darting around asking every one to
                        change $20 Greenbacks for them. Whether this is true or not, the anti-Wells
                        men certainly <sic>euchered</sic> the Wells men, though they held a full
                        hand. They brought forward a negro and, by warming up the sympathies of his
                        colored brethren, nominated him by an overwhelming vote for the office of
                        Lieut. Governor. This piece of strategy of the anti-Wells men, who had been
                        beaten in the effort to secure the nomination of Clements for Governor,
                        fully accomplished the purpose intended and destroys all chance of the
                        success of the ticket. The more moderate Republicans, those who can not
                        swallow the negro, "wool, heels and hide," are kicking up a row over it, and
                        have issued the following address:</p>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">To the Republican Party of Virginia:</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>We, the undersigned members of the Republican party, and some of us delegates
                        to the late Convention held in the city of Petersburg, dissenting from the
                        action taken and nominations made by that body, express the following cause
                        of incurable dissatisfaction:</p>
                    <p>That the nominations there made are of such a character as to render it
                        utterly impossible to make the party successful in the State and thereby
                        secure the best interest of the country.</p>
                    <p>Now, with a view to the very best interests of the Republican party and of
                        our Commonwealth, and to the more permanent establishment of this political
                        organization in the State of Virginia upon the broad principles of true
                        Republicanism, and with a further view to the reconstruction of our State
                        and its restoration to the Federal Union upon the terms prescribed by the
                        reconstruction acts of Congress, and in the solemn belief that the existing
                        dissensions which have resulted from the action of the Petersburg Convention
                        will militate fatally against all these objects, impair the efficiency of
                        the existing administration of the National Government, and finally
                        culminate in the disintegration of the Republican party in the State of
                        Virginia we do hereby most earnestly invoke your presence at a Convention to
                        be held in the city of Richmond on the 15th day of April next. And the Hon.
                        George Rye, Franklin Stearns and W. Henry Read, Esq., of Richmond, Va. are
                        hereby appointed a committee for the furtherance of such a Convention. They
                        are authorized to associate with them any gentleman from each Congressional
                        district of the State. The whole to act as an Executive Committee.</p>
                    <p>The Wells party, report says, are also sick of the ticket, with the name of
                        Harris on it, and have made overtures to the bolters to reconcile the matter
                        by removing the name of Harris from the ticket. This, we learn, was
                        respectfully declined, and that the bolters have prepared the following
                        ticket: General Gilbert C. Walker, of Norfolk, for Governor; John F. Lewis,
                        of Rockingham, for Lieutenant-Governor, and James C. Taylor, of Montgomery,
                        for Attorney General.</p>
                    <p>There is evidently a positive split in the Republican party of this State,
                        which is likely to widen more and more every day, and we should make the
                        most of it.</p>
                    <p>Some of our "Conservative" exchanges speak of the ticket made out by the
                        bolters as a "respectable" ticket. Do not be deluded by this idea, men of
                        Virginia. Both of the Republican tickets carry with them the odious
                        Underwood Constitution, which will be none the less onerous and odious,
                        whether enforced by the "black-and-tans," or the "respectables." Stick to
                        the ticket which brings nought of shame or dishonor to you or our beloved
                        old Virginia. Stand by the men who battled for your rights when all looked
                        darker than the present. Remember the noble canvass made by our bold
                        standard-bearers, and "rally round" the flag which they bore, inscribed with
                        such names as Col. Robt. E. Withers, Gen. Jas. Walker, and Col. Marmaduke
                        Johnson, and emblazoned with the motto "down with the Underwood
                        Constitution." You will thus be true to principles and preserve your honor
                        and your self-respect intact, and Virginia's bright escutcheon will remain
                            <sic>untarnshed</sic> by a single stain. It may be said that such a
                        course will continue military domination in this State. In reply we say,
                        better that, a thousand times better, than the odious Underwood
                        Constitution, sapping the very life blood of the proud old State and
                        beggaring her citizens. Better, a thousand times better that, than ruin
                        under the rule of either "respectables" or "black-and-tans."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on the state Republican convention, which nominated men for top
                    state offices. Notes with glee the split in the Republican ranks over the
                    nominee for governor and the placement of a black man on the ticket for
                    Lieutenant Governor. Also warns Virginians not to endorse either faction because
                    they both support the Underwood Constitution.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper denounces Dr. George K. Gilmer who had signed a petition asking
                    for the removal of Gen. Stoneman for declaring he would not appoint African
                    Americans to office.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Last "New Movement"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The following address signed by 151 persons and placing in nomination another
                        Republican State ticket, was published in the Richmond papers, of Tuesday
                        last:</p>
                    <p>The undersigned citizens of Virginia, and earnest friends of the restoration
                        of our State to the Union, under the reconstruction acts of Congress,
                        believe that the time has fully come when a determined and zealous effort,
                        should be made to rescue the Republican party of Virginia from the
                        management and control of designing and selfish politicians.</p>
                    <p>We are satisfied that the Convention which assembled at Petersburg on the 9th
                        instant, did not reflect the feelings and wishes of the Republicans of the
                        State, and that the means used to secure the nomination of the persons who
                        are placed upon the State ticket were such as cannot secure the sanction or
                        approval of those who desire to promote the welfare our people. We feel that
                        there has never been a period in her history when the counsel and direction
                        of wise, experienced and patriotic men, whose unselfish regard for the
                        public weal commend them to the confidence and support of the people, were
                        more eminently needed. The men who are put forward for the highest honors of
                        our restored Commonwealth are not sufficiently identified with our people to
                        secure that confidence, and we fear that defeat awaits the party, because
                        many of the best of our citizens who are now identified with it anticipate
                        the worst consequence to our material interests in the event of their
                        election, and are disposed to resent and resist the dictation of the
                        arrogant and presumptuous clique of political adventurers by whom the late
                        Convention was controlled.</p>
                    <p>We believe that a large majority of the intelligent and reflecting people of
                        Virginia who have a permanent interest in the prosperity of the State are
                        becoming convinced that wisdom and sound policy alike demand that they shall
                        accept and carry out, in good faith, the measures proposed by Congress for
                        the reconstruction of the Southern States, and are earnestly desirous of
                            <sic>adoptigg</sic> the great principles enunciated by the Republican
                        Party of the country. We believe that they will cheerfully support true and
                        well-known Republicans for State officers; and to afford them an opportunity
                        to do this we respectfully recommend.</p>
                    <p>For Governor--G.C. Walker, of Norfolk city.</p>
                    <p>For Lieutenant Governor--John F. Lewis, of Rockingham county.</p>
                    <p>For Attorney General--J.C. Taylor, of Montgomery county.</p>
                    <p>Among the signers we find the names of the following persons well known here:
                        W. J. Dews, A. B. Arthur, W. R. Morris, Geo. A. Smith, Jno. B. Engleman,
                        Reuben D. Hill, Henry H. Peck, Benjamin T. Bagby, Robt. G. Bickle, David
                        Fultz, and N.K. Trout. These gentlemen endorse the Reconstruction acts of
                        Congress, which secure to the negro all and more than the Petersburg
                        convention gave, but they can't stand the fire of a negro on the
                        ticket.---Surely these <emph rend="italic">are</emph> model Republicans, or
                        rather as they delight to call themselves <emph rend="italic"
                        >"respectable"</emph> Republicans.</p>
                    <p>And how magnanimously does W. J. Dews and Co. step forth to "rescue the
                        Republican party of Va, from the management and control of designing and
                        selfish men." This we could applaud had we only known that all these
                        gentleman had all along been such zealous Republicans. We knew that Dews and
                        a portion of his company were, but the majority of them have been secreting
                        their Republican lights in a Conservative bushel. Perhaps they were only
                        waiting until the "respectables" arose--only waiting <sic>o jine</sic> Capt.
                        Dews' company.</p>
                    <p>To those who purpose <sic>jining</sic> the "respectables" we say, cease to
                        hide your lights and then lay claim to so much, but send along your names
                        that we may give publicity to them, that all may know exactly where you
                        stand, and that you may also, at once, be entered on Capt. Dews' <emph
                            rend="italic">pay</emph> roll.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prints a statement given by the "respectables" faction of the state
                    Republican party, citing their troubles with the other faction and naming their
                    own slate of candidates. Editor again stresses that though they may appear
                    respectable, they are still Republicans and so true Virginians should avoid them
                    like the plague.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that many northerners are alarmed at the prominence of
                    military officers in Grant's administration. It raises the prospect of "military
                    despotism."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1869.03.19.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clark</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Rev. J. L. Clark, longtime pastor of Staunton's Methodist Episcopal
                    Church, will relocate next year to West Virginia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The ladies of the Bethel Church Congregation in Greenville are planning to
                    hold a dinner to raise money for the construction of a parsonage.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCorkle</ln>
                        <fn>John Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hogshead</ln>
                        <fn>Elijah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoge</ln>
                        <fn>P. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Samuel McCorkle and Mrs. Mary Jane White were married near Middlebrook
                    at the residence of Elijah Hogshead by the Rev. P. C. Hoge.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>Lyttleton</fn>
                        <sf>Sr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>L.</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lyttleton Waddell, Sr., died in Augusta on March 12th at the house of his
                    son, L. Waddell, Jr. He was 79 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClung</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Elizabeth McClung died in Staunton on March 9th of pneumonia. She was
                    86 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>Betsy Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>Chesley</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Betsy Ann Kinney, wife of Chesley Kinney, died at Stribling Springs,
                    Augusta County, on March 3rd. She was 48 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eubank</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoge</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Elizabeth Eubank died in Staunton at the residence of Mr. John B. Hoge
                    on March 10th. She was 76 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. William Cochran died on February 15th at his residence near Greenville.
                    He was 71 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wheat</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Almira</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wheat</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Mary Almira Wheat, daughter of the Rev. J. C. Wheat, died in Staunton
                    on March 12th. She was 28 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craver</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Sarah Craver died at Barterbrook on February 28th at age 63. "She was
                    a member of Hebron Presbyterian Church and died as a christian."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turk</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Elizabeth Turk died on the Long Meadows on March 2nd. She was 61 years
                    old. "She was a consistent member of Tinkling Spring Church and died in peace."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1869.03.19.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
