<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1869/va.au.rv.1869.03.26">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>10/11/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1869-03-26">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day norm="">26</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1869.03.26.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1869.03.26.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Executive committee of the latest "New Movement" have issued an address
                        to the people of Virginia, calling upon them to support the Walker ticket
                        which we published in our last.</p>
                    <p>The committee then deal in great praise of Messrs Walker, Lewis and Taylor.
                        Now this is extremely absurd to say the least of it. What care the people of
                        Virginia concerning the respectability of this ticket? It is principles not
                        mere men we want. This is then the merest effort to sugar coat a very bitter
                        pill, and we can tell the advocates of the Walker ticket that it will not be
                        swallowed by the majority of the anti-Republicans of the State, though it be
                        intensely sugar coated, and that those who do swallow it will find it to be
                        a most nauseating emetic.</p>
                    <p>The committee then herald their platform. We give it for the amusement of our
                        readers</p>
                    <p>"Peace and good will among men."</p>
                    <p>The prosperity and happiness of all the people.</p>
                    <p>Unity of purpose and combination of strength to build up our State and
                        develop her inexhaustible resources.</p>
                    <p>Consolidation and concentration.</p>
                    <p>The removal of political disabilities.</p>
                    <p>The striking from the Constitution the test oath and the county organization.</p>
                    <p>The unity of the States and the glory of the Union.</p>
                    <p>The equality of all men before the law, and the equal protection of all of
                        whatever color or previous condition in life.</p>
                    <p>True allegiance and loyalty to the Government.</p>
                    <p>And such a platform. Made up, in the main, as it is, of vague generalities,
                        how could it excite anything but laughter. It must be a trick of their
                        Republican Chairman to carry the Petersburg ticket and platform. The first
                        four planks really mean nothing. The fifth and sixth trench on subjects
                        which are of interest to our people, but pray what can the Walkerites do on
                        the subject. It is true they may aid the Conservatives in defeating the
                        disqualifying clauses in the Underwood constitution, but how do they propose
                        to effect the county organization clause. The only thing proposed in
                        Congress in reference to getting rid of the onerous features of the
                        Underwood Constitution was concerning the disability and test-oath clauses.
                        The constitution as a whole to be voted upon and the disqualifying clauses
                        to be voted upon separately. If a majority vote "against disqualification"
                        then that onerous feature of the Constitution fails to become a part of it,
                        but this does not effect the county organization clause nor any of the other
                        onerous features of that odious document. It is plain, therefore, that the
                        Walkerites, nor even the Wells party, have any power in the world to rid the
                        people of those onerous clauses save by voting down the whole constitution.</p>
                    <p>The seventh plank is rich. Messrs. Grant, Colfax, Blaine &amp; Co. come
                        down from yon high pedestals, the Walkerites are going to take care of
                            "<emph rend="italic">the unity of the States and the glory of the
                        Union.</emph>" Ha! ha!" unity of the States and glory of the Union."</p>
                    <p>The eighth plank goes back on the old "new movement" and the negro. The
                        former said grant the negro suffrage and eligibility to office "to boot."
                        Congress says the negro shall have suffrage and office, but the Walkerites
                        say they shall have only "equality before the law and equal protection." But
                        then you know the Walkerites are all powerful, for have they not taken in
                        charge "the unity of the States and the glory of the Union."</p>
                    <p>The ninth plank beats all. "Allegiance, and loyalty to the <emph
                            rend="italic">Government</emph>." In the good old days of the Republic
                        this idea was scouted. The allegiance of the fathers was acknowledged due
                        only to the Constitution. That and that only they swore to support and
                        defend. With the Walkerites, however, loyalty to the Government is the
                        thing.</p>
                    <p>This is the platform of the party which solicits the votes of the
                        Conservatives of Virginia. Let us examine into the probable results of the
                        Walker movement. From the eighth plank mentioned it is plain that it can
                        obtain but few recruits from the Wells party. The negroes will all stand by
                        that party, since it does not cut them off from suffrage and office, but
                        gives them the second place on the ticket. The ninety-two thousand negro
                        voters will be a fine nucleus around which to rally and comparatively few
                        whites, now allied with them, can afford to leave so strong a party. This
                        seems to be in the mind's eye of the Walkerites, or part and parcel of the
                        plan of Dr. Gilmer, and hence their high sounding but meaningless platitudes
                        to catch conservative voters. Whether this is the intention or not, the
                        result is the same. The Walkerites can only draw strength from the
                        conservatives. Some conservatives will be caught, others will go with the
                        hope of "loaves and fishes." What then will be the consequence? The Withers
                        party will be the only one weakened and will fail to defeat the Constitution
                        which they could do but for the weakening of their ranks by the Walkerites.
                        The Wellsites and Walkerites will carry the Constitution. The Withers party
                        and Walker party will vote to strike out the disqualifying clauses and the
                        Wells party will elect their ticket. The Underwood Constitution, freed only
                        of one objectionable clause, with all its other onerous and odious clauses
                        untouched, will be the Constitution of Virginia. Wells is known to be an
                        ardent aspirant for the U.S. Senatorship. The negro Legislature will elect
                        him, and Harris, negro, become the Governor of Virginia. Picture to
                        yourselves the Underwood Constitution, freed only of the disability and
                        test-oath clauses, and enforced by a negro Governor. Reflect upon it and you
                        are bound to conclude that this is destined to be the ultimate and only
                        result of the Walker movement. Then we say to one and all, stand aloof from
                        the latter as you did from the former "new movement," for its results are
                        far more pernicious to Virginia. You, who have been inveigled into the
                        Walker movement, leave it at once, ere you help to bring upon the State the
                        dire calamity which we have predicted and which your reasoning faculties
                        must force you to conclude is the only result which the Walker party can
                        attain.</p>
                    <p>The only safety to Virginia and Virginians is to vote down the odious
                        Underwood Constitution with all its onerous conditions. Then stand firm ye
                        Conservatives. Let the Walker and Wells faction split the Republican party
                        if they will. This will only add greater strength to the Conservative ranks.
                        You will the easier be enabled to defeat the Constitution. This will
                        continue military domination, but who will say that that is not better, far,
                        then the inevitable result we have foreshadowed above?</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Steps up the attack against the Walkerites. Claims that if Conservative
                    voters support the movement, the hated Underwood Constitution will be passed and
                    blacks will ultimately control the state. Denounces each section of the
                    Walkerite platform, urges all Virginians to vote down the Underwood Constitution
                    to save the dignity of the state.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Walker party press are insinuating that if the Conservatives do not unite
                        with them, that the onus of the terrible result in this State must fall upon
                        us. We beg leave to differ with these gentlemen. The Conservative party as
                        organized under their accepted leaders is a large and powerful party, able,
                        unless from defection, due to the Walker movement, to defeat not only the
                        nominees of the Petersburg Convention but to vote down the Underwood
                        Constitution, and thus save the State from the dire results all fear. The
                        Walker faction place their hopes on the respectability of their ticket and
                        take the Underwood Constitution modified slightly. They call upon the
                        Conservative to renounce their life-time opinions--their maintenance of
                        time-honored rights and leave a large organization to unite with a few
                        disaffected Republicans for a supposed expediency.</p>
                    <p>No gentlemen, you cry in vain for the mountain to come to you, and when it is
                        so easy to go to the mountain and thus save yourselves from the flood which
                        must otherwise <sic>engulph</sic> you, and you fail to do it, let the onus
                        rest on your own shoulders and don't presume to shift it on others. Be
                        warned in time and save yourselves from the threatening doom, while yet you
                        may.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Denounces Walkerite Republican insinuations that conservative hopes lay
                    solely with the Walker movement. Counters that the Conservative party has enough
                    power to defeat the Wells faction if only defectors didn't join the Walkerites.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>As we mentioned the name of N. K. Trout among the signers of the Walker
                        address published in our last, we, <emph rend="italic">unsolicited</emph>,
                        give place to his card published in the last Spectator.</p>
                    <p>We disagree entirely with Mayor Trout that we should all be of <emph
                            rend="italic">no</emph> party and should support men and measures for
                        the sake of expediency alone, and we admonish the prominent Conservatives he
                        speaks of that the course he indicates, instead of "lifting our bleeding
                        country from the dust," will certainly and surely place it under the heel of
                        cuffee.</p>
                    <p>In regard to his signing the address, in justice to ourselves, we merely say
                        that the address appeared here (in the Richmond papers) several days before
                        the <emph rend="italic">Vindicator</emph> was issued and that not one of the
                        signers, to us, or to our knowledge, asserted that he had signed it with a
                        qualification, and hence we could but take it as we found it and treat it
                        accordingly.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Disagrees with one N.K. Trout, who proposes supporting those who would do
                    the least damage to the state. Insists Virginia conservatives must stick to
                    principle or their state would end up in the hands of blacks.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The "respectables" assert as one of their objects, "the rescue of the
                        Republican party of the State from the control of designing and selfish
                        politicians" and thereby prevent its inevitable defeat. We can not see what
                        possible business the Conservatives can have in assisting the Republicans in
                        this matter. What we want is the defeat of this same Republican party. Stand
                        aloof then fellow conservatives and have nothing to do with rescuing the
                        Republicans from designing or selfish men or from defeat. Stand as one man
                        and secure their defeat.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Again urges all conservative Virginians to work to defeat any Republican
                    movement in the upcoming elections.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1869.03.26.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Benedict</ln>
                        <fn>Ira</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The citizens of Staunton were in great excitement over the appearance of a
                    velocipede in town. Ira Benedict constructed and rode the vehicle.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that an unnamed unionist "since war time" and a current
                    Republican is looking to "sell" his stock in the party which he believes to be
                    rapidly "dropping."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper remarks sarcastically that an African American woman in town
                    asserted that "since so many white folks are joining the colored people's party,
                    it is a difficult matter for the colored people to distinguish them and suggests
                    that they procure and wear wooly wigs to secure easy recognition."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper complains that General Stoneman ordered all Augusta clerks
                    removed, making it impossible to hold March court. "This was an anomaly in the
                    history of Augusta county and exhibits one phase of the beauties of
                    reconstruction."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Valley Railroad Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tate</ln>
                        <fn>William M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hotchkiss</ln>
                        <fn>Jed</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>Bolivar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fultz</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echols</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>A. H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>J. Marshall</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickle</ln>
                        <fn>Robert G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gallaher</ln>
                        <fn>H. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>C. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hogshead</ln>
                        <fn>M. W. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grattan</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mauzy</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lynn</ln>
                        <fn>W. H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crockwell</ln>
                        <fn>J. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>Marshall</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>W. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hansberger</ln>
                        <fn>R. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>William F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bruce</ln>
                        <fn>G. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>Chesley</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guy</ln>
                        <fn>R. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craig</ln>
                        <fn>J. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parkins</ln>
                        <fn>I. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The citizens of Augusta met in the Court House on Monday to appoint a
                    delegation to travel to Baltimore to lobby for a $1,000,000 subscription to the
                    stock of the Valley Railroad. Maj. William M. Tate chaired the meeting with Jed
                    Hotchkiss acting as secretary.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Judges</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fultz</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn>H. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turner</ln>
                        <fn>Zeph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>John T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pendleton</ln>
                        <fn>Edmund</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parker</ln>
                        <fn>Richard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shackelford</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Watson</ln>
                        <fn>Egbert R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>General Stoneman has appointed the following judges in the section
                    including Augusta: David Fultz replaces H. W. Sheffey on the 11th circuit; Zeph
                    Turner replaces John T. Harris on the 12th circuit; Edmund Pendleton replaces
                    Richard Parker on the 13th circuit; Henry Shackelford replaces Egbert R. Watson
                    on the 10th circuit.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Gen. Stoneman has made the following appointments in this county:</p>
                    <p>CLERK OF COUNTY COURT--Samuel A. East, vice Wm. A. Burnett removed.</p>
                    <p>CLERK OF CIRCUIT COURT--R.D. Sears, vice Joseph N. Ryan removed.</p>
                    <p>MAGISTRATES.--Wm. Armstrong, vice Jas. Wilson, Wm. Link, vice Theophilus
                        Gamble, David Alexander, vice Thos. J. Burke, W. W. Clinedinst, vice Geo. A.
                        Bruce, F.M. Finley, vice Absalom Koiner, John H. Dalhouse, vice Jno. S.
                        Ellis John Silor, vice A. A. McPheeters, Wm. W. Thomas, vice W.F. Smith, Wm.
                        Gibson, jr., vice Lewis Bumgardner, Geo. Reubush, vice Wm T. Rush, Jos. A.
                        Miller, vice Jas. F. Hite, Henry Mish, vice B. O. Ferguson, Wm. Morgan, vice
                        B.F. Hailman, Jos. T. Mitchell, vice B.F. Points.</p>
                    <p>COMMISSIONERS OF THE REVENUE--Erasmus L. Houff, vice Jno. G. Stover, Henry B.
                        Jones, vice Thos. M. Donoho.</p>
                    <p>CONSTABLES.--J.J.B. Shultz, vice Geo. M. Apple, Geo. L. Arehart, vice Adam
                        Rusmisel; Jno K. Kayser, vice Wm. M. Bush, Jacob Ewing vice A. T. Grooms,
                        Jas. F. Davis, vice E.J. Bell, Wm. A. Reed, vice Jno. H. Heizer.</p>
                    <p>OVERSEERS OF THE POOR.--Jos. A. Miller, vice Jas. E. Beard, Benj. M. Lines,
                        vice Fred. Burns.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>East</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burnett</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sears</ln>
                        <fn>R. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ryan</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armstrong</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Link</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gamble</ln>
                        <fn>Theophilus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Alexander</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clinedinst</ln>
                        <fn>W. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bruce</ln>
                        <fn>George A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Finley</ln>
                        <fn>F. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>Absalom</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dalhouse</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ellis</ln>
                        <fn>John S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Silor</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McPheeters</ln>
                        <fn>A. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thomas</ln>
                        <fn>William W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>W. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gibson</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reubush</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rush</ln>
                        <fn>William T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hite</ln>
                        <fn>James F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mish</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ferguson</ln>
                        <fn>B. O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Morgan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hailman</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mitchell</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Points</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houff</ln>
                        <fn>Erasmus L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stover</ln>
                        <fn>John G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>Henry B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donoho</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shultz</ln>
                        <fn>J. H. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Apple</ln>
                        <fn>George M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Arehart</ln>
                        <fn>George L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rusmisel</ln>
                        <fn>Adam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kayser</ln>
                        <fn>John K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bush</ln>
                        <fn>William M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ewing</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grooms</ln>
                        <fn>A. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>James F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>E. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heizer</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>James E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lines</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burns</ln>
                        <fn>Fred</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Names all the people appointed by General Stoneman for local offices in
                    Augusta county.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>From the Spectator</p>
                    <p>MESSRS. EDITORS:--</p>
                    <p>Give me a space in which to put myself right upon the record. I am published
                        as having signed myself a member of a political party and a disciple of its
                        creed. My name was by an unintentional mistake (of the telegraph) attached
                        to the document.</p>
                    <p>Believing that in this dark hour of our affair, we should be of <emph
                            rend="italic">no party</emph>--should discard abstract political
                        principles, and support such <emph rend="italic">men</emph> and <emph
                            rend="italic">measures</emph>, and adopt such practical expedients for
                        the evils of the day as will restore as honorably and speedily as may be,
                        our oppressed Commonwealth to the Union--and to peace and prosperity, and
                        having knowledge that the persons named in the new ticket are high-toned
                            gentlemen--<emph rend="italic">conservative</emph> in their
                        politics--opposed to the Underwood Constitution with its present obnoxious
                        features--in favor of removal of political disabilities--devoted to the
                        advancement of the material interests of the State for which they are
                        selected, I say, honestly entertaining these views, that when applied to, I
                        most cordially and sincerely <emph rend="italic">endorsed</emph>, above my
                        name that the Gilbert C. Walker ticket met my approbation, and should have
                        my support, but I declined to sign the document referred to.</p>
                    <p>If the people generally, after "a second sober thought," and as I know
                        prominent Conservatives design doing, will put their shoulders to the work,
                        we can elect the trustworthy and patriotic gentlemen on that ticket to the
                        government and lift "our bleeding country from the dust."</p>
                    <p>NICHOLAS K. TROUT</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prints a reply from N.K. Trout, who admits he supports men from any party
                    whom he feels will get Virginia through Reconstruction the quickest, but denies
                    signing a document which states he is a firm adherent to the Republican cause.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crousehorn</ln>
                        <fn>William F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Switzer</ln>
                        <fn>Mary C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William F. Crousehorn and Miss Mary C. Switzer, both of Augusta, were
                    married at the residence of the bride's father near Mt. Sidney by the Rev. C.
                    Beard.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roots</ln>
                        <fn>Junius F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Croft</ln>
                        <fn>Mary A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>See</ln>
                        <fn>C. S. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Junius F. Roots and Mrs. Mary A. Croft, both of Augusta, were married near
                    Christian's Creek on March 16th by the Rev. C. S. M. See.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bolen</ln>
                        <fn>J. Edwin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hopewell</ln>
                        <fn>Sallie T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carson</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. Edwin Bolen and Sallie T. Hopewell were married in Mt. Solon on March
                    21st by the Rev. Thomas C. Carson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swoope</ln>
                        <fn>Washington</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Washington Swoope died at his residence at Swoope's Depot on March 11th. He
                    was 73 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eidson</ln>
                        <fn>Bettie J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eidson</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Bettie J. Eidson, daughter of Henry Eidson of Augusta, died suddenly
                    in Baltimore on March 19th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huffner</ln>
                        <fn>Anna Maria</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huffner</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Anna Maria Huffner, "maiden daughter" of the late Michael Huffner, died in
                    North River near Mt. Solon on March 15th. She was 67 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Litten</ln>
                        <fn>Abram</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Abram Litten died on Middle River below Spring Hill on March 10th. He was
                    87 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1869.03.26.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
