<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1869/va.au.rv.1869.09.24">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>01/22/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1869-09-24">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day norm="">24</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1869.09.24.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1869.09.24.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The report that Messrs. Butler and Boutwell are bestirring themselves to
                        prevent the restoration of Virginia to the Union and profer funds to get up
                        a strong case against Virginia's admission, obtains credence just now.</p>
                    <p>We should not be surprised if it were true and that these gentlemen would
                        exert themselves to prevent a consummation greatly desired by the whole
                        country, save New England. President Grant gave his public assurance not
                        only to the country but to the world, that there <emph rend="italic"
                        >should</emph> be a reconstructed--united country within a year and he
                        stands committed to the fulfillment of that promise. Some have accused him
                        of a want of "back bone" in trying times, when the policy of his party was
                        plainly in the face of right and against his convictions. Will he lack nerve
                        in this instance and yield to the demands of Butler, Boutwell, &amp; Co?
                        We can scarcely think so. We remember that he "bottled up" the hero of Big
                        Bethel and, although the "bottled-imp" squirmed and twisted--gnashed his
                        teeth and struck the stopper with his head, yet Grant kept his thumb <emph
                            rend="italic">firmly</emph> on the cork, and, as far as he is concerned,
                        to this day the valiant knight of New Orleans remains bottled. He had
                        bottled him in the face of the world and per force he could not allow his
                        escape. He has, in this instance, given his word, and pledged his faith to
                        the world, that the States shall be restored to the union, in the speediest
                        manner, and he can not afford to be thwarted by Butler, Boutwell or any one
                        else.</p>
                    <p>He can accomplish the restoration of the still, so-called, unreconstructed
                        States, if he will, against all opposition, and he must. He stands pledged
                        to this course and we therefore look for another pressure on the cork and
                        more squirming on the part of the imp.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper ridicules Butler and Boutwell for attempting to prevent the
                    re-admission of Virginia to the Union and hopes Grant will oppose them in
                    pursuing his goals of a united nation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Many of our exchanges are discussing the question of the Legislature electing
                        U. S. Senators. While we would like to see Virginia represented in the
                        United States Senate, yet as our Legislature, as elected, is allowed to
                        meet, in deference to the opinion of Attorney General Hoar, and as that
                        opinion must therefore, be the authority for the construction of the acts
                        under which the Legislature convenes, it would seem beyond their power to
                        elect U. S. Senators. He expressly states in his opinion, that the
                        Legislature can only meet and ratify the fifteenth amendment. To do aught
                        else would subject each and every member to subscribe to the test-oath.</p>
                    <p>We are, as one of our valued exchanges aptly says, just a pinch of the hill
                        and we cannot proceed too carefully. Enemies are on the look out for any
                        misstep. Frauds in the Tennessee election, even, have been presented as a
                        ground for refusing to restore Virginia to the Union. The election of
                        Senators might be taken as an assumption of authority and the restoration be
                        deferred. Then let us rather bear the deprivation of non-representation in
                        the Senate, than risk the chances of success at this stage of the game.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper expresses the opinion that the Virginia Legislature cannot elect
                    Senators under General Hoar's decision. Legislators may meet without taking the
                    test-oath, but only to ratify the fifteenth amendment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that Gilbert C. Walker, Governor-elect of Virginia, has
                    been installed in Richmond. "Virginia, after four years of appointed rulers, has
                    at last a Governor, for whom a majority of her citizens cast their suffrages."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1869.09.24.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Farmers have begun bringing large quantities of flour to market in
                    Staunton, and the town is "again assuming that busy appearance which
                    characterized it during the past four years."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper states ticket policy for the county fair. Stockholders can get a
                    three-day pass for $1. After the first day, two-day passes at 75 cents. Tickets
                    on the last day are 50 cents.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Frazier</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sales</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scheffer</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Frazier and W. H. Sales, longtime managers of the Rockbridge Alum
                    Springs, have leased Staunton's Virginia Hotel for $3,000 per year. The paper
                    welcomes the new proprietors while bidding a fond farewell to F. Scheffer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shea</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coiner</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trippe</ln>
                        <fn>E. T. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Shea and Miss Rebecca Jane Coiner, both of Augusta, were married on
                    September 15th by the Rev. E. T. R. Trippe.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cox</ln>
                        <fn>Lucretia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Lucretia Cox died at the Staunton residence of her husband on
                    September 14th. She was 43 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1869.09.24.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
