<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1870/pa.fr.vs.1870.09.28">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>11/07/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1870-09-28">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day norm="">28</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.09.28.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.09.28.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The People are "Ignoramuses"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>So says John Cessna. In his speech in the Court House last week, he made the
                        extraordinary statement that any person who expected to have the question of
                        negro suffrage submitted to the people, was certainly an "ignoramus." To
                        sustain this position he explained the provision of the Federal Constitution
                        for its own amendment, claiming that the most ignorant man could see that
                        any proposed amendment must be submitted to the State Legislatures or to
                        conventions called by the people of the States, and that whenever
                        three-fourths of either of these ratify it, it becomes a part of the
                        Constitution. But the people of Franklin County know that this was not the
                        position which the radical leaders, including Cessna, took two years ago.
                        When the Democrats charged that it was the intention of the Radicals to
                        force negro suffrage upon the people without allowing them to vote upon the
                        question, these same Radicals denounced the charge as a lie gotten up for
                        electioneering purposes. They pointed to the State Constitution and the
                        election laws with the word <emph rend="italic">white</emph> in them, and to
                        the provisions of our State Constitution with reference to its amendment.
                        They said it was utterly impossible to force negro suffrage upon the people
                        because the State Constitution provides that <emph rend="italic">two</emph>
                        Legislatures must endorse the proposition and <emph rend="italic">then it
                            must be submitted to the people</emph>. Our readers will remember how
                        distinctly the issue was made in 1868 when Capt. John Walker was the
                        candidate of the Radical party in this County for the Assembly. He was
                        elected, not alone on account of his high personal character, but because
                        his neighbors and friends believed him to be inexorably opposed to the
                        Fifteenth Amendment. He went to Harrisburg, and when it was discovered that
                        the Radical leaders were about to cheat the people on this question--when
                        the question of the ratification of the Fifteenth Amendment was being
                        agitated at Harrisburg--from Metal township (Capt. Walker's own election
                        district) went an earnest protest signed by many of his prominent brethren
                        of the Radical party against its adoption. They began to see the infidelity
                        of the men who had made cheap promises. But this protest could not hold
                        Capt. Walker to his pledge. The party discipline was too rigid--the lash was
                        applied with too much severity--for Capt. Walker to carry out the wishes of
                        his constituents, he yielded to the influences brought to bear upon him and
                        voted to ratify the Fifteenth Amendment.</p>
                    <p>So great was the indignation in his own party at this vote, that when the
                        Radical County Convention met in 1869, it was deemed advisable to leave his
                        name off the ticket. <emph rend="italic">Captain Walker was not considered a
                            safe candidate for the party because of his vote to ratify the Fifteenth
                            Amendment</emph>.</p>
                    <p>And although an able and worthy gentleman was put in nomination by the
                        Radical Convention, such was the indignation at Walker's betrayal of his
                        constituents that the Democratic majority on the State ticket ran up to 308
                        and the majority for the Democratic candidate for Assembly exceeded that
                        figure. The people resented the conduct of the Radical representative on
                        this very question. <emph rend="italic">Let them do it again</emph>.</p>
                    <p>It is in very bad taste for Cessna to come to Franklin County and talk about
                        her people being "ignoramuses" for expecting an opportunity to vote on this
                        question, when all their expectations were the result of Radical teachings.</p>
                    <p>Not only did the speakers of the party take this position, but the organ of
                        the party, the <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph>, sought to impress the
                        same views upon its readers. As far back as 1865, Col. McClure endeavored to
                        allay the apprehensions of the people on this subject by entering into an
                        elaborate explanation of the provisions of the State Constitution. He was
                        sagacious enough to see what would be proposed by the agitators of his
                        party, and he knew that negro suffrage would not be palatable to the people
                        of Franklin County. Accordingly, he sounded the first false notes and
                        persuaded his readers that their right to vote upon this question could not
                        be interfered with.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Now, Cessna says that the people were "ignoramuses" for
                            believing Col. McClure</emph>--that they ought to have had sense enough
                        to know that McClure was deceiving them.</p>
                    <p>Perhaps this position might be a good one, if Cessna had not committed
                        himself in the same way. In his joint discussion with Judge Kimmell at
                        Waynesboro', he took this same position, as those who were present will
                        remember. He hooted at the idea of negro suffrage being forced upon the
                        people without them having an opportunity to vote on the question. On the
                        contrary, Judge Kimmell endeavored to warn the people that day of what was
                        surely in store for them. He told them that the Radicals meant to give the
                        negro the ballot by packing the State Legislatures. But Democrats were not
                        believed then. This horde of loyal scoundrels who are robbing the government
                        and the tax payers, possessed the confidence of a majority of the people of
                        this Congressional District, and they elected this double faced individual
                        who blows hot and cold in the same breath and thinks that the people of
                        Franklin County are such "ignoramuses" as not to know the difference.</p>
                    <p>What say you, voters of Franklin County? Are your memories so shallow that
                        you can not recollect the promises which Cessna made two years ago? He has
                        betrayed you, and now seeks to make you believe that he never made any
                        promises at all. Defeat him for his bare-faced falsehoods.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Accuses Cessna of lying to his constituents and forcing black suffrage on
                    them. Claims he said people would have a chance to vote on the issue but now
                    says anyone who thought that is an "ignoramus". Calls on voters to oust this
                    deceiver.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>That Bill for Services</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A fit of desperation has seized the Editor of the <emph rend="italic"
                            >Repository</emph>. He hears from all quarters the terrible complaints
                        which are coming up from the people against Cessna for his indifference to
                        the interests of the people. Not only complaints greet his ear, but curses
                        loud and deep. Thereupon, he becomes frenzied, for are not his hopes of a
                        protracted term as Assistant Assessor hanging on Cessna's re-election? He
                        resolves, therefore, that Cessna must be re-elected even if the hopes of the
                        people for payment of losses must be completely wrecked in order to do it.
                        Accordingly, he shows that Cessna went to Harrisburg and <emph rend="italic"
                            >paid his own expenses</emph> (about one dollar and fifty cents for
                        supper and lodging, his passes having carried him free over the railroads)
                        in order to put Skinner on the Committee of Ways and Means. Five prominent
                        gentlemen spoke to Speaker Strang in favor of Skinner's appointment and it
                        seems to us that it was putting it a little strong under those circumstances
                        for Cessna to say that <emph rend="italic">he</emph> did the work himself.
                        But Cessna never was suspected of having any modesty.</p>
                    <p>But failing to make a respectable defence for Cessna, the Editor of the <emph
                            rend="italic">Repository</emph> thinks it wise not only to belittle Mr.
                        Meyers' services but also to impugn his motives in relation to the Border
                        Claim bill. In the last issue of his paper he uses this language:</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">We say then that, in addition to the promise of support
                            from the leaders of the Franklin county Democracy for his nomination for
                            Congress, Mr. Meyers presented his bill to the Franklin County Border
                            Damage Committee, for the services of the Patriot in urging the payment
                            of the border damages, and demanded payment of it.</emph>" The italics
                        are his own. Now the Editor of the <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph>
                        willfully and deliberately misrepresented Mr. Meyers in this matter. He knew
                        very well (at least, being a member of the Border Claim Committee, he ought
                        to have known) that the bill rendered by the <emph rend="italic"
                        >Patriot</emph> office was not for "the services" of that paper, <emph
                            rend="italic">but for copies of the Patriot furnished to the
                        Committee</emph>. Here is the bill that was presented by the <emph
                            rend="italic">Patriot</emph> office:</p>
                    <p>HARRISBURG, May 12th, 1870.</p>
                    <p>MR. J. W. DOUGLAS:</p>
                    <p>1870. To <emph rend="italic">Patriot</emph>, Dr.</p>
                    <p>Feb. 24. To 800 copies <emph rend="italic">Weekly Patriot</emph> at 5
                        cts.....$40.00</p>
                    <p>And here is the letter which accompanied the bill:</p>
                    <p>HARRISBURG, PA., May 12, 1870.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Dear Sir:</emph> Enclosed find bill for copies of Weekly
                            <emph rend="italic">Patriot:</emph> said copies were ordered by Col.
                        Stumbaugh, and contained an article on the "Border Claim Bill." It has been
                        suggested that you were the proper person to send the bill to. We sent the
                        bill to Col. Stumbaugh but suppose he has overlooked the matter. Col.
                        Stumbaugh will certify to the bill, as to its correctness. Please give it
                        the proper attention.</p>
                    <p>Yours very truly,</p>
                    <p>B.F. MEYERS &amp; Col.,</p>
                    <p>To J.W. Douglas, Esq. per K.</p>
                    <p>This bill was sent to Mr. Douglas because that gentlemen is the Treasurer of
                        the Border Claim Committee, and the suggestion referred to in the letter as
                        to the proper person to whom the bill should be sent, was made by gentlemen
                        who were members of that Committee.</p>
                    <p>Now it certainly was enough to ask the <emph rend="italic">Patriot</emph> to
                        give us the influence of its editorial columns <emph rend="italic"
                        >gratis</emph> without expecting that office to furnish us 800 copies of the
                        paper for nothing. The Editor of the <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph>
                        did excellent service with the pen in the same cause, and for this it does
                        not expect pay, we presume. But for its job work done for the Committee, it
                        has a bill in excess of that of the <emph rend="italic">Patriot</emph>. For
                        that it has been partly paid and will demand payment of the balance, and it
                        deserves to be paid. The <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> asks nothing for
                        its editorial articles, for it was its duty to do its utmost to procure
                        payment for the Border Claims if possible. But it has a bill for job work in
                        excess of the bill presented by the <emph rend="italic">Patriot</emph>. A
                        portion of this bill has been paid, and we expect payment of the balance.</p>
                    <p>It seems to us that the Editor of the <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph>
                        has gotten himself into a very indefensible position by making this impudent
                        and unfounded charge. His hot zeal for the little fellow who feeds him on
                        Government "pap" has outrun his discretion.--When next he endeavors to get
                        up a sensation, let him confine himself to the truth.</p>
                    <p>We can not wonder at his departure from the truth in this campaign, however,
                        after that "whopper" which Cessna threw out at McConnellsburg the other
                        evening. Cessna was accounting for his infamous conduct in favor of Wallace,
                        in the case of Wallace vs. Simpson in South Carolina. He said that one of
                        the chief reasons for his astounding action, was that on the day of the
                        election <emph rend="italic">nineteen hundred loyal men had been slaughtered
                            at the polls</emph>. The news of this massacre was only furnished to
                        John Cessna.</p>
                    <p>It looks as if the Editor of the <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph> had
                        slept in the same bed with Cessna.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Criticizes the local Republican paper for supporting Cessna and appearing
                    to back out on its previous support of the Border Claims. Gives examples of the
                    paper's recent conduct and more of Cessna's devious dealings.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Land Grabbers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper criticizes the Republican controlled Congress for giving large
                    tracts of public land to corporations and railroads.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Brag Game</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper ridicules Cessna for habitually overestimating his support in
                    Franklin County. The small majority he enjoyed in the last election can be
                    easily wiped out with a little effort. "The white men who have been deceived by
                    his base deception and who have been grievously disappointed by his failure to
                    keep his promises, can easily defeat this little political trickster."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Not for Mahon</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper asserts that their praise for Republican Thaddeus Mahon's work as
                    Clerk of the Courts does not imply support for the political principles he
                    represents. The editors endorse Capt. George W. Skinner in his race against
                    Mahon for Assembly.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Why Taxes are High--Radical Corruption and Extravagance--Government
                    Expenditures Under Grant Compared with Democratic Administration</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper argues that Republican administrations cost the tax payers
                    significantly more money than Democratic ones.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.09.28.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Democratic Meetings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Democrats and Conservatives will hold a meeting at Mercersburg on October
                    1st and in the Chambersburg Court House on October 10th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gable</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Democrats of Hamilton will meet at the Public House of Michael Gable to
                    form a township ticket.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column/>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Capt. George W. Skinner will take the place of Col. Pyfer who was scheduled
                    to address the reunion of the 77th Pennsylvania Volunteers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cathell</ln>
                        <fn>Everist</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Everist Cathell will conduct services in the Episcopal Church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Fine Pictures</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>H. R. Hershberger will exhibit several paintings at the Franklin County
                    Fair. The following number among his subjects: Wyland's Mill on Dennis Creek,
                    said to be the oldest in the county; the farmhouse of Frederick Mish on Back
                    Creek in Hamilton; "A Scene in Bay's Cove;" "The Dragoon's Stampede;" and
                    "Winter Scene."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The County Fair</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilbert</ln>
                        <fn>Calvin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Franklin County Agricultural Society will hold its third annual
                    exhibition near Chambersburg beginning on October 5th. Entries can be made
                    through the secretary, Calvin Gilbert. Single tickets are 25 cents.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>Club Organized</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Noble</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Alexander</ln>
                        <fn>R. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McAllen</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Noonan</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyd</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keggereis</ln>
                        <fn>Michael R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Democrats of Metal township organized a political club.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Census Reports</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>By the census papers of Capt. E.D. Reid, Assistant Marshal for the North Ward
                        of this Borough, and Hamilton township, we find the following statistics: In
                        the North Ward, the number of white males is 1273, number of white females
                        1548, colored males 72, colored females 84. Whole number of males 1345,
                        whole number of females 1632 making the population of the North Ward 2977.
                        Deaths in this ward during the year from June 1st, 1869 to June 1st 1870,
                        were 35. There are 47 houses of productive industry in the ward. The value
                        of the real estate owned by the inhabitants is $2,257,909. Value of personal
                        property is $1,757,445; total value of real and personal property,
                        $4,015,354.</p>
                    <p>In Hamilton township we find the following: Number of acres of improved land
                        14,982, of wood-land 4259, total number of acres 18,241. The present cash
                        value of farms is $958,605. The whole amount of wages paid in that township
                        during the year, including the value of board, is $26,689. Number of horses,
                        650; mules 6; Milch cows 626; other cattle 598; Sheep 352; Swine 1123. Value
                        of all livestock $108,114. Number of bushels of winter Wheat raised during
                        the year is 35,466; of Rye 3216; of Indian corn 46,577; of Oats 38,769; of
                        Barley 1769; of Buckwheat 115. Number of pounds of wool raised 417; bushels
                        of Irish potatoes 9372; bushels of sweet potatoes 313; value of orchard
                        products $2789; gallons of wine made 220; value of produce of market gardens
                        $2662; pounds of butter made 55,995; tons of hay 3266; bushels of clover
                        seed 946; gallons of molasses made 1578; pounds of honey 215; value of
                        animals slaughtered, or sold for slaughter $22,227; estimated value of all
                        farm production, including betterments and additions to stock $222,640.</p>
                    <p>The number of inhabitants in Hamilton township is 1635; dwelling houses 306;
                        families 306; houses of productive industry 5; farms 173; number of deaths
                        during the year 15.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Provides census data for the North Ward and Hamilton. Includes statistics
                    on agriculture, populations, and industry.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>How Scarlet Fever is Spread</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Since Chambersburg has experienced a number of scarlet fever cases, the
                    paper publishes an article about how it is spread. According to the author, "it
                    is spread through personal carelessness, by neglect, and by recklessness of
                    individuals to the public safety."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Radical Meeting at Shady Grove</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>GREENCASTLE, September 24, 1870.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Messrs. Editors:</emph> The Radical meeting last night in
                        Shady Grove, was attended by a considerable number of the neighbors without
                        respect to party. Greencastle was also slightly represented. Curiosity no
                        doubt led most of those present to the spot. The Greencastle band was in
                        attendance and performed well. The Radical bills announce about two dozen
                        meetings to be held at different places between this and the election by the
                        party. These meetings are intended principally to drum in the "disaffected"
                        of the party, as the speakers themselves last night called the "weakkneed"
                        Republicans (another of their expressions) by diverting their minds as much
                        as possible from the issue of their disaffection to other <del/> very
                        interesting to the people, entire absence of any cheering, except <del/>
                        called upon, evidently manifested at night, for even these calls were
                        <del/>feebly responded to.</p>
                    <p>If the leaders of the party only persuade the rank and file <del/> the
                        outrageous imposition of the <del/> amendment, they would hug the idea
                        <del/> by victory this fall; but from some <del/> or other, they seem to be
                        in great<del/> to how a large number of their fervent supporters are biting
                        at the black <del/> such means as coaxing, or <del/> or appeals to the baser
                        passions <del/> or false swearing, or bribery <del/> required to bring them
                        under the <del/> they will all be brought into <del/> as some of them are
                        now. The speech <del/> night resorted to the foulest slander <del/> to our
                        account all kinds of <del/> with the rebellion. If there is, or <del/> any
                        other foundation than the <del/> imaginations or the most malicious <del/>
                        of Radical politicians for these <del/> insinuations against the whole
                        Democratic party, every one would be <del/> perfect amazement at the success
                        <del/> Radicals in conquering the rebellion. <del/> men appear to be unable
                        to distinguish between an honest difference from their <del/> and sympathy
                        for the rebels. <del/> hearted professions that the men <del/> the
                        Democratic party are honest or <del/> is only another way of calling us
                        <del/> ignorant, since they allow us no <del/> but "rebel sympathizers!" It
                        would <del/> to call every Democrat a "rebel sympathizer." That would be too
                        bare-faced. <del/> stabs at the Democratic masses <del/> the shoulders of
                        our leaders, have <del/> answered to arouse the prejudices <del/>
                        "weak-kneed" Republicans sufficient to overcome the many shortcomings of the
                        party in the past as it is hoped their prejudices can in the same way be
                        worked <del/> high that the unnameable meanness <del/> passage of the negro
                        amendment itself <del/> be overlooked by them at the coming <del/> Many of
                        these men say, and <del/> we, if the negro amendment had been <del/> a vote
                        of the people of the States and <del/> by them, instead of being almost
                        <del/> forced on us, the impropriety of <del/> measure at best could be
                        endured with <del/> degree of patience, but as it is it will <del/> long
                        time before the ring of the <del/> will cease to sound in Radical ears, no
                        <del/> under what name they may be known hereafter. We call upon all
                        Conservatives not to be deceived by the Radical leaders any longer. Try the
                        "White Man's" party. Its leaders cannot deceive you more nor as much.
                        OBSERVER.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prints a letter from an anonymous author describing a recent Republican
                    gathering. Takes great offense at the Republican charges that Democrats are
                    rebel sympathizers and despises Republican efforts to pass the 15th amendment.
                    Urges all Conservatives to join the "White Man's Party" to defeat the Radicals.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Radical Meeting at Upton</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>GREENCASTLE, Sept. 26, 1870.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Messrs. Editors:</emph>--We attended a meeting on
                        Saturday night at Upton, of that party which inasmuch as it "saved the
                        country" is so desirous of ruling it. It had been heralded forth for the
                        past week that there was to be a grand rally of the <emph rend="italic"
                            >loyal</emph> men on that occasion, and "Frank" Meyer's prospect for
                        Congress was to be darkened terribly. Urgent appeals were sent out to
                        individuals, but alas! loyalty was not forthcoming; and the meeting held
                        there proved to be a burlesque on the Radical party. By an actual count
                        there were but seventeen Republican voters there. Every other man was a
                        Democrat. And yet this is the place that used to turn out its hundreds to a
                        Republican meeting.</p>
                    <p>The orators were Fred Foreman, W. U. Brewer, Jere. Cook and John Stewart. We
                        can pass by the speeches of Foreman and Brewer for they contained nothing;
                        also the speech of Cook who spoke of the beauties of the income tax and,
                        being a good mathematician, showed very conclusively (to himself) that there
                        had been a reduction of expenditures during the Grant regime. But Stewart!
                        Oh how loyal he was! He became so enraged at the audacity of Meyers for
                        daring to run for Congress, that he imagined that he was in the army again
                        "and thrice he fought his battles o'er and thrice he slew the slain." He
                        declared that Meyers was a <emph rend="italic">Copperhead</emph>, and at
                        this juncture his voice was drowned <emph rend="italic">by three hearty
                            cheers for Meyers</emph>. Somewhat disconcerted he pounced on Skinner
                        comparing him to Benedict Arnold and here again <emph rend="italic">his
                            voice was drowned by cheers for Skinner</emph>. He next proceeded to
                        inform his seventeen voters that the political skies never looked brighter
                        for the Radicals. But the seventeen were sad, for they thought of
                        Connecticut, New York, North Carolina and Oregon. He said that no
                        Republicans would leave the ranks on account of negro suffrage; and yet by
                        his side, within four feet of him, stood a man who declared as for him and
                        his sons they intended in the future as <emph rend="italic">not</emph> in
                        the past to vote the full Democratic ticket. And we can tell Mr. Stewart
                        that if he is desirous of seeing more such men let him visit this community;
                        find out the temper of those who have heretofore been identified with his
                        party and he will go home a sadder and wiser man. In the meantime let them
                        have another "grand rally" at Upton.</p>
                    <p>Yours, MONTGOMERY.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prints another letter from an anonymous source describing a Republican
                    rally in Upton. Gleefully reports that more Democrats than Republicans attended
                    and drowned out the speakers on several occasions. Says Republicans are
                    disheartened by reversals in the past and certain defeat in the future.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Haefner</ln>
                        <fn>Casles A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Haefner</ln>
                        <fn>M. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Haefner</ln>
                        <fn>Kate</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Casles A. Haefner, son of M. A. and Kate Haefner, died on September 24th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shank</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Shank died near Waynesboro on September 23rd. He was 67 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.09.28.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
