<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1870/pa.fr.vs.1870.05.25">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>10/24/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1870-05-25">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day norm="">25</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.05.25.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.05.25.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The New York Elections. Victory for White Men.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper hails Democratic electoral victories across the state of New York
                    as a blow to Radicals and a "victory for white men." "Although some fifteen
                    thousand negroes were clothed with the right of suffrage and exercised it in
                    support of the Radical candidates, twice that number of white men came out from
                    the ranks of the Radical organization, and, enlisting under the banner of the
                    White Men's Party, fought the good fight with courage and unswerving zeal, and
                    won a most glorious victory. White men have made up their minds to rule this
                    country."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>A Bill to Imprison White Men so as to Let Negroes Vote</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>So obnoxious is the Fifteenth Amendment to the white people of the country,
                        that Congress finds it necessary to pass the most stringent bill for its
                        enforcement. The pains and penalties prescribed by the Act that recently
                        passed the Senate are terrible. These "wards of the nation" are to be
                        protected in the exercise of the right of suffrage in every State,
                        territory, district, municipality, or other territorial sub-division, no
                        matter what may be contained in any constitution, law, custom, usage or
                        regulation of any State of Territory to the contrary. Congress, at one
                        sweep, wipes out the power of any State to regulate the elective franchise
                        within its limits for any purpose. If this is not a centralization of power
                        in the General Government equal to any demand ever made by the original
                        advocates of that theory, we fail to understand the effect of this new
                        measure. Why it is almost as much as a white man's liberty is worth for him
                        to attempt to <emph rend="italic">challenge</emph> a negro's vote, for he
                        may be construed to be <emph rend="italic">hindering</emph> him in the
                        exercise of the right of suffrage. White men, the only privilege you have
                        left, and the Lord only knows how long this may be left to you, is <emph
                            rend="italic">to vote against the party that forces such a monstrosity
                            upon you</emph>. Your necks are under the heels of these Radical
                        fanatics. They do not stop to reason. They are hurried on by passion from
                        one outrage to another. And, if allowed to go on unchecked they will
                        undertake ere long to disfranchise those who dare to vote against their
                        nefarious schemes. New York has led off gloriously. Conservative men of
                        Franklin County, cast in your lot with us and help us to crush the Radical
                        demagogues who pretend to represent Pennsylvania in Congress. Let us teach
                        them that the white men of the old Keystone State have rights which they are
                        determined shall be respected. Join with us in the cry, <emph rend="italic"
                            >White men must rule America.</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Denounces laws passed in Congress for enforcing the 15th amendment, claims
                    its an assault on state sovereignty. Claims the only way to reverse the
                    situation and save white rights is to vote for the Democrats.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Grant's Insult to Hancock</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper criticizes Grant for refusing to award General Winfield Scott
                    Hancock command of a division. Grant based his decision on political
                    differences. In the opinion of the editor, the move dishonors a war hero and
                    "reflects disgrace upon the nation."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper asserts that the Republicans are ignoring the needs of German and
                    Irish voters in their pursuit of African American voters. "White
                    men--naturalized citizens and Americans born--let us join hands to defeat these
                    negro-worshipers. Let white men rule America."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.05.25.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George Eyster, Assistant Treasurer at Philadelphia, visited Chambersburg
                    last week.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Resigned</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Callender</ln>
                        <fn>S. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Rev. S. N. Callender has resigned as pastor of the Reformed Church at
                    Greencastle. His health is not good.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Sensible</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper applauds the decision to extend cemetery closing hours until
                    7:00.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bender</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George Bender, Justice of the Peace at Waynesboro, died on May 12th after
                    being "attacked by apoplexy." "He was a worthy citizen and a very useful man."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Franklin County Cases</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barncord</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Emerson</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parker</ln>
                        <fn>Maria</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dixon</ln>
                        <fn>W. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bitner</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Supreme Court heard the following Franklin County cases: Jacob Barncord
                    and E. Emerson vs. Maria Parker, judgement affirmed; Gillan's Executors vs. W.
                    D. Dixon and wife and John Walker and wife, judgement affirmed; Bitner vs.
                    Bitner, judgement affirmed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Beautiful!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An exhibition of art and photography will be held in Repository Hall this
                    week. The Silver Cornet Band will perform. A Saturday afternoon exhibition will
                    be held for children and those who cannot attend at night.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Old Citizens Gone</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mohler</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel Mohler died in Orrstown on May 8th. He was 80 years old. "He was an
                    upright man, a consistent Christian, having been a member of the Lutheran Church
                    for upwards of sixty years." Ex-sheriff Jacob S. Brown died in Chambersburg last
                    week. "Mr. Brown was elected Sheriff of this County in 1856 and served three
                    years. On the election of Sheriff Fletcher in 1868, Mr. Brown was appointed
                    Deputy Sheriff and served in that capacity up to the beginning of his recent
                    illness."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"Public Opinion" asserts that the mechanics of Franklin County have not
                    been paying for their papers. "We are happy to say that there is no class of men
                    who pay for the Spirit more promptly than the mechanics. If any of them do not
                    pay for the Opinion, there are likely two reasons for it. One is because their
                    names have been put upon its subscription lists without their orders, and the
                    other is because they do not consider it worth paying for."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>After the Negro Vote</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Some weeks ago we stated that immediately upon the issuing of the
                        proclamation announcing the ratification of the Fifteenth Amendment, John
                        Cessna began a correspondence with the colored men of Chambersburg with a
                        view to procuring their votes. We now have the pleasure of laying before our
                        readers one of the letters since addressed to a colored man in this Borough,
                        by the Honorable John's Secretary. It seems that the member from the 16th
                        Congressional District is able to keep a clerk for the simple purpose of
                        conducting his correspondence with the negroes and "sending them all the
                        speeches and documents he may have." Cessna wants a list of these voters for
                        the purpose of calculating his chances for re-election. We tell him now that
                        if he gets 800 negro votes in this Congressional District, it will not save
                        him. He ought to strain his ear and listen to the mutterings of discontent
                        that are coming up from the throats of white men who voted for him before,
                        but who have now joined the "white men's party," and, of course, intend to
                        tomahawk him next time. Let him get 500 negro votes in Franklin County, if
                        he can, and we will still beat him 800 here without any trouble. Every day
                        white men are declaring their purpose to quit the rotten hulk of Radicalism.
                        These men will vote the straight Democratic ticket. But these are not all
                        that will strike at John Cessna. Go where you will in this County you can
                        hardly meet a man who speaks well of him. He is as deeply despised as any
                        man within the range of our acquaintance. How well he will run among the
                        Republicans can be predicted from this state of facts. But here is the
                        letter:</p>
                    <p>WASHINGTON,<lb/> May 2, 1870.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Dear Sir:</emph> This package of speeches is from the
                        Hon. Jno. Cessna, who desires that you distribute them among the colored
                        voters in Chambersburg. They are the speeches of Hon. Mr. Revels the U.S.
                        Senator from Miss., the colored man who has held that very high and exalted
                        position.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Cessna requested that you have a list of all the colored voters in
                        Chambersburg made out and sent to him, as he wants to send them all the
                        speeches and documents he may have. Please attend to this at once and send
                        on as many names as possible and direct your letters to Hon. Jno. Cessna,
                        Washington D.C.<lb/> H.E. WEAVER.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cessna</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Prints a letter from Cessna to the black voters in Chambersburg, clamoring
                    for their support. Claims that will not help him because whites are flocking to
                    the Democratic party to protest the 15th amendment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Habeas Corpus Case</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rohrer</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mackey</ln>
                        <fn>Harriet</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rowe</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kimmell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reilly</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel Rohrer, charged with assault and battery and attempt to commit rape
                    upon Miss Harriet Mackey, was brought before Judge Rowe on a writ of habeas
                    corpus. He was committed to jail in default of $1000 bail. Kimmell and Reilly
                    handled the defense.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Sharp</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Mr. John Doebler was elected last Fall as the Assessor of this
                        Borough.--Owing to private reasons, he resigned his position recently. It
                        became the duty of the Commissioners to appoint an Assessor. They appointed
                        Mr. George Foreman. A Board having a <emph rend="italic">Democratic</emph>
                        majority selects an extreme <emph rend="italic">Radical</emph> as Assessor.
                        Here was the opportunity to insure an honest registration of the voters of
                        this Borough by the appointment of some faithful and competent <emph
                            rend="italic">Democrat</emph>, and especially was it important because
                        of the addition to the registry of the names of the colored voters. A
                        Democrat would have prevented the registration of those negroes who, we
                        understand, are to be imported from Maryland to help to beat white men.</p>
                    <p>When Democrats elect men to office they expect them to carry out the
                        principles of the party, or at least to do nothing that will tend to the
                        defeat of those principles.</p>
                    <p>Contrast with this the action of a Republican Board a few years ago. Mr. Wm.
                        Flory had been elected Assessor of this Borough. He died, and a Republican
                        Board appointed Mr. John Rhodes, dec'd., a thorough Republican. That party
                        never does such foolish things as a matter of personal favor.</p>
                    <p>We are heartily sick of, and disgusted at this kind of Democracy. We regret
                        that we obliged to write thus, on account of our personal relations with the
                        Democratic Commissioners, but it has become a <emph rend="italic"
                        >necessity</emph>. The Democracy can not overlook such a want of fidelity to
                        their interests.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doebler</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foreman</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flory</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rhodes</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Expresses disappointment and disgust at a Democratic Board of Commissioners
                    selecting a Republican as Assessor. Counted on Democrats following Democratic
                    principles, sees this recent action as a failure of that mission.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Decoration Day</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>At a meeting, on Monday evening last, of the Committee appointed by the
                        soldiers to make arrangements for the ceremonies attending the decoration of
                        the soldiers' graves in this place, on Monday next, the following committees
                        were appointed:</p>
                    <p>Committee to mark the graves of soldiers and place flags over the same--John
                        A. Selders, T. M. Mahon, Harry Strickler, Geo. Wampler.</p>
                    <p>Committee on Invitations and Music--S. W. Hays, D. F. Lesher, J.L.P.
                        Deitrich, Dr. G.F. Platt.</p>
                    <p>Committee to see to the tolling of the bells--Daniel Glass, D. W. Houser,
                        Solomon Swert, Jere. Donovan, John Shinefield.</p>
                    <p>Committee to secure an orator for the occasion--Dr. S.G. Lane, G. W. Welsh,
                        W. Clugston, S. G. Barnes.</p>
                    <p>The different secret societies and the citizens generally are cordially
                        invited to appear in the procession, and to take part in the ceremonies of
                        the day.</p>
                    <p>The following circular has been addressed especially to the ladies: <lb/>
                        "Strew Garlands of Flowers around each sleeping Hero's Grave."<lb/> IN
                        MEMORIAM.</p>
                    <p>CHAMBERSBURG, May 23, 1870.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">To the Ladies of Chambersburg:</emph>--At a meeting of
                        the Soldiers of the Borough of Chambersburg, held Monday evening May 16th,
                        the undersigned were appointed a Committee to invite the Ladies to join with
                        them in procuring flowers for the purpose of strewing the graves of those of
                        our Soldiers who sleep in our midst. The Committee remember with gratitude
                        and pleasure your noble response on former occasions, and take this method
                        of reminding you of the return of the Annual Decoration Day, believing that
                        this alone will be necessary to insure a liberal donation of choice flowers
                        and boquets. The living comrades of our gallant dead desire to make the
                        coming occasion one of peculiar interest. They realize that one after
                        another the years are setting down over their passionless mounds and over
                        the events which called so many of them from life to death, hence they
                        believe that on each successive occasion redoubled efforts should be made to
                        keep alive the memory of their invaluable services.</p>
                    <p>"A debt of gratitude we owe<lb/> To them--is justly due--<lb/> And till our
                        nation's latest day,<lb/> Our children's children still shall say,<lb/> They
                        died for me and you."<lb/> T. J. Grimison,<lb/> Geo. W. Skinner,<lb/> Thad.
                        M. Mahon,<lb/> Committee.</p>
                    <p>Contributions of Flowers will be left in Repository Hall between the hours of
                        8 and 12 A. M., on Monday next.</p>
                    <p>Col. Theodore McGowan, Chief Marshall, has appointed as his aid Capt Geo. W.
                        Skinner, Sergt. John A. Selders, Lieut. G. F. Platt, Lieut. Geo. W. Welsh.</p>
                    <p>The procession will form in front of the Court House, at 3 o'clock on Monday
                        afternoon next, and move off in two detachments, one to decorate all graves
                        South of Market street, and the other all North of Market street, when they
                        will join in the Diamond and proceed to the cemetery, where the oration will
                        be delivered.</p>
                    <p>The procession will then countermarch to the Court House and be
                    dismissed.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Selders</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mahon</ln>
                        <fn>T. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strickler</ln>
                        <fn>Harry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wampler</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>S. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lesher</ln>
                        <fn>D. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deitrich</ln>
                        <fn>J. L. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Platt</ln>
                        <fn>G. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Glass</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houser</ln>
                        <fn>H. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swert</ln>
                        <fn>Solomon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donavan</ln>
                        <fn>Jere</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shinefield</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lane</ln>
                        <fn>S. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Welsh</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clugston</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnes</ln>
                        <fn>S. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grimison</ln>
                        <fn>T. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mahon</ln>
                        <fn>Thad M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGowan</ln>
                        <fn>Theodore</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Selders</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Platt</ln>
                        <fn>G. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Welsh</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports on the preparations for Decoration Day. Prints the names of the men
                    involved, their requests for local men and women to contribute flowers and flags
                    for the graves, and the schedule of events to take place.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Orrstown Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>ORRSTOWN, May 20, 1870.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Editors Spirit:</emph>--The local editor of the <emph
                            rend="italic">Repository</emph> last week took advantage of a little
                        progressive movement in our Borough and styled it a <emph rend="italic"
                            >Radical victory</emph>, desiring to convey the impression that because
                            <emph rend="italic">two</emph> Radicals had been elected, "Orrstown, the
                        former stronghold of Democracy, ratifies the fifteenth amendment." This is
                        an impression far from being correct, and I think a mere statement of the
                        facts will at once set the matter in its proper light.</p>
                    <p>A regular ticket was nominated by the Democrats at their convention, but as
                        this ticket was composed entirely of men opposed to certain improvements, on
                        the following day a ticket was formed of men favoring these improvements,
                        made up in part of the regularly nominated ticket and besides containing the
                        two Radicals elected. As but little interest is manifested in our Borough
                        elections, it was no matter of surprise to those who got afloat the new
                        ticket to know that it was elected by a small majority. But it was a matter
                        of <emph rend="italic">much</emph> surprise to those of us who supported
                        this ticket to have it heralded about as a Radical victory and every
                        Democrat who voted for it, most severely condemns this unkind act of our
                        Radical neighbors. Not a half dozen Radical votes were polled, yet they cry
                        because of a mere local success, "Radical victory." The truth is, were an
                        election to be held in our Borough to-day both of these men would meet with
                        a most inglorious defeat. There is no complaint of them as public officers,
                        but it certainly is a question of honesty whether they did right in
                        proclaiming themselves victorious champions of the Radical party because a
                        mere local matter without any regard to politics, was the sole reason for
                        their selection.</p>
                    <p>Neither Mr. Dehart or Mr. Kniseley, the successful Radicals, owe their
                        election to their personal popularity or any superior qualification they
                        possess over their defeated opponents (as the <emph rend="italic"
                        >Repository</emph> would have its readers belive) but <emph rend="italic"
                            >only</emph> because they were supporters of this new measure. It is but
                        justice to the Democrats who supported this ticket to have these facts made
                        known, that it may be plainly understood that they voted for no Radical for
                        political reasons, and that they consider it unmanly and unjust in the
                        successful Radicals to have so attempted to construe it before the public.
                        Probably the astute correspondent of the <emph rend="italic"
                        >Repository</emph> will find Orrstown not as entirely given up to the
                        reprobateness of Radicalism, when he comes before its people again for their
                        suffrages.</p>
                    <p>Hoping this may fully explain away "the ratification victory," I am truly
                        yours,<lb/> A Supporter of the <lb/> IMPROVEMENT TICKET.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Takes offense at Radical declarations of a recent victory for their party
                    in the Orrstown elections. Insists the Radical members were only elected because
                    they supported certain improvement measures with Democrats and not because they
                    carried any weight with the local voters.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doran</ln>
                        <fn>George S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Appleby</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George S. Doran and Miss Elizabeth M. Appleby, both of Burnt Cabins, were
                    married on May 19th by the Rev. J. A. Crawford.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kegerreis</ln>
                        <fn>J. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kunesman</ln>
                        <fn>Nannie J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>West</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. D. Kegerreis and Miss Nannie J. Kunesman, both of Spring Run, were
                    married on May 12th by the Rev. William A. West.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lehman</ln>
                        <fn>David H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Frey</ln>
                        <fn>Maria</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneck</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>David H. Lehman and Miss Maria Frey, both of Chambersburg, were married on
                    May 19th by the Rev. Dr. Schneck.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dubbs</ln>
                        <fn>A. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Aller</ln>
                        <fn>Lizzie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Townsend</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A. M. Dubbs and Miss Lizzie Aller, both of Burnt Cabins, Fulton County,
                    were married in Chambersburg at the National Hotel on May 19th by the Rev. David
                    Townsend of the Church of God.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stock</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foutz</ln>
                        <fn>Catherine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Felker</ln>
                        <fn>A. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel Strock and Mrs. Catherine Foutz, both of Hamilton, were married on
                    May 19th at the Parsonage of the Grindstone Hill Pastorate by the Rev. A. C.
                    Felker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Groover</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Felker</ln>
                        <fn>A. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>B. F. Groover and Miss Maggie Snyder, both of Hamilton, were married on May
                    19th at the Parsonage of the Grindstone Hill Pastorate by the Rev. A. C. Felker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brandt</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>David Brandt died at his residence in St. Thomas on May 13th. He was 71
                    years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCartney</ln>
                        <fn>Isabella</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Isabella McCartney died near Spring Run on May 9th. She was 79 years
                    old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharper</ln>
                        <fn>Hannah E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Hannah E. Sharper died at the residence of her father on May 18th. She
                    was 18 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.05.25.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
