<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1870/pa.fr.vs.1870.06.29">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>10/25/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1870-06-29">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="06">June</month>
            <day norm="">29</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.06.29.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.06.29.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Dismiss Him at Once</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper calls for the dismissal of Government Pension Agent for Invalids.
                    He has allegedly defrauded the government of a large sum of money.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Cheek By Jowl</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>JOHN CESSNA was one of the twenty-four who voted to admit the carpet-bagger,
                        cadetship-broker, Whittemore, to a seat in the House of Representatives.
                        This fellow is confessedly guilty of a crime which would consign him to the
                        Penitentiary, if he were prosecuted for it. The House refused very properly
                        to admit him to a seat.</p>
                    <p>Our able contemporary, the Harrisburg <emph rend="italic">Morning
                        Patriot</emph>, regards the action of the House as a gross outrage upon the
                        right of representation, but we cannot look at it in that light. It looks to
                        us as though the constitutional clause, giving each House the right to judge
                        of the qualifications of its members, covers this case. Our forefathers,
                        doubtless, would have hedged that power about with limitations, if they had
                        foreseen or even suspected the degeneration of these times. But they did
                        not. They left it very broad, and while we believe that in the majority of
                        cases it has worked to the detriment of the people, in this particular case,
                        we think it has operated for their benefit.</p>
                    <p>The re-election of this man Whittemore by an ignorant negro population, ought
                        to fill the people of this Union with disgust at this infamous
                        reconstruction policy. The disfranchisement of the intelligent men of the
                        South has rendered it possible for such scalawags to be elected to prominent
                        positions. And when elected, they can not represent the sentiment of the
                        majority of the people of their districts. <emph rend="italic">Is it not
                            time for amnesty--an amnesty so broad and sweeping as to remove
                            political disabilities from every man, in every State of the Union, who
                            engaged in the rebellion</emph>? The article which we print in another
                        column from the Philadelphia <emph rend="italic">Inquirer</emph> reflects
                        immense credit upon that paper.</p>
                    <p>Then, too, the vote which Cessna cast on the question of Whittemore's
                        admission ought to fill the people of the Sixteenth Congressional District
                        with disgust at their representative. He labored for months to put out that
                        upright gentleman Henry D. Foster and put into his place the "humbuggedest"
                        Covode, and he succeeded in the effort. He voted with the extremists of his
                        party on the contested election cases from Louisiana--giving seats to men
                        who had been defeated by majorities running into the thousands. But the act
                        evincing the most reckless disregard of common decency was the vote to which
                        we have referred, by which he sought to admit a man to a seat who would be
                        serving a term in a penitentiary cell, if the leaders of this "party of
                        great moral ideas" had prosecuted him as he deserved to be.</p>
                    <p>But there were only twenty-three men in the House as indifferent to their own
                        reputation and the National honor as Cessna was, and for this there is some
                        cause for thanks.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes with disgust how Cessna, one of only 24 men to do so, voted to admit
                    a man to Congress who apparently had committed a crime. Cites this act as
                    typical of Cessna, who has a record of ruling in favor of all Republicans.
                    Editor is glad Cessna was in the minority on this one.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Hallelujah!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper applauds the House of Representatives for voting to strike from
                    the tariff bill a provision continuing the income tax. "Let this odious,
                    inquisitorial tax die, never to be resurrected in republican America."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.06.29.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Medical Society of Franklin County will meet in Chambersburg on July
                    6th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDowell</ln>
                        <fn>Craig</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDowell</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Craig McDowell, son of John M. McDowell of Chambersburg, has been appointed
                    cadet to the U. S. Naval Academy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Trial Sermon</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kieffer</ln>
                        <fn>Moses</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Rev. Dr. Moses Kieffer preached a trial sermon at the Greencastle
                    Reformed Church. He is hoping to receive a position there.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Mr. Beardslee, Singer Sewing Machine agent, will hold a public sale at the
                    Montgomery House.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Resigned</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKibbin</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Captain Robert McKibbin, U. S. Army, resigned his commission and was in
                    Chambersburg visiting his parents. He had been stationed at Fort Laramie.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>On a Visit</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Hon. Jeremiah S. Black visited Chambersburg last week as a guest of
                    Judge Kimmell. He then rode to his farm near Mercersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Wilson Female College</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>I. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Lellan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>T. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>William G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLanahan</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Small</ln>
                        <fn>Albert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The board of trustees of the Wilson Female College met last week. They
                    discussed construction of a new building on campus. It will be made of brick and
                    cost around $10,000.They also discussed selecting a president.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Laying of the Corner Stone of Trinity Church</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paddock</ln>
                        <fn>Wilbur F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Watson</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Howe</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lamberton</ln>
                        <fn>R. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clerc</ln>
                        <fn>Francis J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Marsden</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moore</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hare</ln>
                        <fn>William Hobart</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heaton</ln>
                        <fn>William S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Douglass</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orrick</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kellogg</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The services for laying the Corner Stone of Trinity Church, Chambersburg,
                    will be held on July 6th. A number of clergymen will deliver addresses on the
                    occasion.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Scarcity of Beef Cattle</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article reports that beef cattle has never been so scarce in the
                    Cumberland Valley. Butchers are facing hard times and must charge high prices.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Prisoner Escaped</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sites</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Sites was convicted of malicious mischief and assault and battery and
                    sentenced to the County jail. He escaped in April and stole some clothing from
                    the vicinity of Quincy. The sheriff captured him, but he escaped again. "This
                    man should have been confined so that there would have been no chance for
                    escape. We fear that our Sheriff is entirely too humane and allows prisoners to
                    have too many privileges. As reckless and devilish a scapegrace as this man was
                    shown to be on trial, ought to have received no extra favors at the hands of the
                    Sheriff."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Census Appointments</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>General Gregory has at last made his appointments for this county. Mr. D.F.
                        Lesher has been appointed to the district composed of the North Ward and
                        Hamilton township; Capt. E.D. Reid has received the appointment for the
                        South Ward. This must be a mistake on the part of the Marshal. Mr. Lesher is
                        a resident of the South Ward and Capt. Reid of the North Ward, and yet
                        neither resides in the district to which he has been appointed. The Act of
                        May, 1850, provides that the Marshal shall make sub-divisions or districts,
                        but his appointees must be residents of the districts to which they are
                        appointed.</p>
                    <p>W.T. Graham, Esq., is commissioned to take the census of St. Thomas and
                        Peters townships; Mr. J. P. Study for Guilford and Quincy townships; Mr.
                        J.F. Kurtz for Waynesboro' and Washington township; Mr. Henry P. Prather for
                        Greencastle borough and Antrim township; Mr. W. Lackens for Montgomery and
                        Warren townships; Mr. Jacob Kendig for Lurgan, Fannett and Metal townships,
                        and Mr. W. K. Widener for Southampton, Letterkenny and Green townships.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gregory</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lesher</ln>
                        <fn>D. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reid</ln>
                        <fn>E. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Graham</ln>
                        <fn>W. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Study</ln>
                        <fn>J. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kurtz</ln>
                        <fn>J. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Prather</ln>
                        <fn>Henry P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lackens</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kendig</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Widener</ln>
                        <fn>W. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lists the people appointed to take the census in different towns in
                    Franklin County. Points out how two of them should not be eligible because they
                    don't reside in the districts they were appointed to.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Chambersburg Academy Exhibition</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Case</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snively</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nevin</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Loose</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Suesserrott</ln>
                        <fn>C. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stover</ln>
                        <fn>William E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>D. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Russell</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ludwig</ln>
                        <fn>C. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Black</ln>
                        <fn>J. Harper</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hull</ln>
                        <fn>George S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duffield</ln>
                        <fn>M. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Lanahan</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sears</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ferguson</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mendenhall</ln>
                        <fn>H. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vanderbilt</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shumaker</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Principal</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zeller</ln>
                        <fn>H. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nevin</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Linn</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dixon</ln>
                        <fn>W. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wallace</ln>
                        <fn>T. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shook</ln>
                        <fn>D. Z.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kreps</ln>
                        <fn>W. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyd</ln>
                        <fn>W. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The students of the Chambersburg Academy gave an exhibition in Repository
                    Hall on Friday. 400 people attended. The evening consisted of readings and
                    speeches. The select readings were well-delivered, but the original orations
                    were not, even if they were well-written. The paper took issue with the content
                    of Mr. Mendenhall's well-written, well-delivered speech that attacked the
                    doctrines of the Catholic Church. "This might have been in place in a Protestant
                    pulpit, but it was decidedly out of place at an Academy exhibition. Just as
                    appropriate to the occasion, would have been a stump speech."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolf</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McAfee</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kirby</ln>
                        <fn>E. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George Wolf and Miss Mary E. McAfee, both of Mercersburg, were married in
                    Chambersburg at the M. E. Parsonage on June 4th by the Rev. E. W. Kirby.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doyle</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doyle</ln>
                        <fn>B. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doyle</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Margaret Doyle, daughter of B. J. and Elizabeth Doyle, was married in
                    Fannett township on June 19th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Edward Shriver</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>G. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Emeline</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Riley</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Edward Shriver Miller, son of G. A. and Mary Emeline Miller of
                    Chambersburg, died in Baltimore at the home of his Uncle, Dr. William Riley. He
                    was 21 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.06.29.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
