<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1870/pa.fr.vs.1870.08.24">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>10/28/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1870-08-24">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="08">August</month>
            <day norm="">24</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.08.24.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.08.24.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>That "Unavoidable and Logical" Growth</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph> has been terribly worried at the
                        resolutions passed by the late Democratic County Convention. It inflicts
                        almost two whole columns upon its readers on the subject, and if it has not
                        "insulted their intelligence," the fault certainly does not lie with the
                        author of the article. In his anxiety to give Mr. M'Lellan a slap for
                        leaving the Radical party, he confesses to the perpetration of the most
                        gigantic fraud upon the conservative portion of that organization. This
                        confession is contained in these words, "for the Fifteenth Amendment and the
                        right of suffrage unavoidably and logically grew out of the abolition of
                        slavery, of which Mr. M'Lellan was a part." Waiving, for the present, the
                        vagueness and doubtful grammatical correctness of the concluding clause, we
                        pass to the consideration of the main allegation in the sentence.</p>
                    <p>We deny emphatically that the Fifteenth Amendment and the right of suffrage
                        grow either <emph rend="italic">unavoidably, or logically</emph> out of the
                        abolition of slavery. There was no unavoidable necessity for the
                        introduction of the Fifteenth Amendment. The overwhelming sentiment of the
                        people of the country was against it. There is no Radical so bigoted and
                        blind as to assert that it met the approval of a majority of the people of
                        Pennsylvania. Then, why was it "unavoidable"? Because a few fanatical
                        leaders saw in it an element of supposed strength for the Radical party, and
                        as that party was beginning to lose its hold on white men they recognized
                        the necessity of investing the black man with the right of suffrage. The
                        waning fortunes of the Radical party made negro suffrage an "unavoidable
                        necessity." It did not grow unavoidably out of the abolition of slavery.
                        From the effrontery with which this declaration is made, one ignorant of the
                        facts would suppose that there was one spontaneous outburst of popular
                        feeling all over the Union in favor of negro suffrage, and that the
                        Fifteenth Amendment was made part of the National Constitution in obedience
                        to the command of an overwhelming majority of the people. Instead of that,
                        however, the intelligent observer of events shows how carefully the people
                        were kept from expressing an opinion at the ballot box on this question. The
                        opportunity was never afforded them to vote on the subject. State
                        Legislatures were packed and the party lash was applied with terrible fury
                        to the backs of refractory members. In Indiana, the amendment was declared
                        ratified when there was not a quorum of members there to do business. This
                        was under the pressure of the "unavoidable necessity." The assent of Ohio
                        and New York <del/> before the requisite number of States was procured, and
                        yet those States were counted as having ratified the amendment. This was
                        under the pressure of the "unavoidable necessity." The very complaint which
                        comes to-day from the mouths of conservative citizens brands this
                        declaration as false. It runs in this way: "We were in favor of the
                        abolition of slavery, but now we find the negro entitled to vote without
                        that opportunity being afforded us. Nay, more, the Radical leaders
                        notwithstanding their promises to us as to this matter, dared to construe
                        our support of the Radical candidates as a declaration in favor of negro
                        suffrage. Now we find ourselves deceived." This is the "unavoidable"
                        necessity that forced negro suffrage on the country.</p>
                    <p>The <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph> lent itself after the close of the
                        war to the work of adroitly keeping the people in the dark on this subject.
                        It did more. It deliberately sought to deceive its readers. According to its
                        own confession made at this late day, <emph rend="italic">it knew that the
                            Fifteenth Amendment and negro suffrage would grow unavoidably and
                            logically out of the abolition of slavery</emph>, and yet it labored to
                        convince its patrons that no such result would necessarily follow. It
                        distinctly stated that the general government had no power over the question
                        at all, and that in our own State the amendment could not be offered until
                        1869 and would require the ratification of two Legislatures and <emph
                            rend="italic">then be submitted to a vote of the people</emph>. And yet,
                        the right of suffrage grew out of the abolition of slavery so "unavoidably
                        and so logically" that the forms of law, as the <emph rend="italic"
                            >Repository</emph> had stated them, were disregarded in order to give
                        the people the supreme luxury of seeing black men voting and holding office
                        without their consent.</p>
                    <p>We fail to see also the <emph rend="italic">logical</emph> connection between
                        the abolition of slavery and negro suffrage. This subject would bear
                        amplification on the part of the <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph>, for
                        the people want to know, why, when the Democracy charged that it was the
                        Radical purpose to force negro suffrage upon the country, it was denounced
                        by the Radicals as "a Copperhead lie gotten up for electioneering purposes,"
                        if it was true that they then knew that negro suffrage would grow
                        "unavoidably and logically out of the abolition of slavery." The Editor of
                        the <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph> no doubt claims his share of the
                        honor which attaches to the Radical party for the abolition of slavery. Does
                        he mean to say that when he was engaged in the work of abolishing slavery,
                        he knew that his party intended to make the negro a voter? If he did, why
                        did he deceive the public on the subject? If he did not, by what rule does
                        he desire to make Mr. M'Lellan responsible for the Fifteenth Amendment and
                        negro suffrage, on the ground simply that he labored for the abolition of
                        slavery? The truth is that neither Mr. M'Lellan, nor any other honest man,
                        knew of any purpose to force negro equality upon the country when he was
                        laboring to strike the shackles from the slave. And it was when he
                        discovered the iniquitous purpose of the reckless Radical leaders to force
                        negro equality at all hazards, that he refused to be identified with them
                        any longer and joined the "White Man's Party."</p>
                    <p>And now, the cry is coming up from all quarters, "<emph rend="italic">we have
                            been deceived</emph>." All the elections that have recently taken place
                        attest the healthy feeling that exists on this question. It gives promise of
                        better times. It has thrown the Radical party on the defensive. They are
                        compelled to defend themselves and yet they have no defence to offer. They
                        now glory in the ratification of the Fifteenth Amendment so as to obtain the
                        entire negro vote, whilst they thus openly advertise their shame to the
                        white men who have been deluded by their false statements. And they actually
                        think that their white readers are too dumb to see the point. Such
                        presumption is unparalleled. The white men of the State will demand a
                        hearing on the second Tuesday of October, and announce their condemnation of
                        the atrocious Radical fraud called the Fifteenth Amendment, by electing
                        white men on a white man's platform.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Defends the Democratic platform from attacks from the Republican press.
                    Ridicules the Republican argument that black suffrage grew inevitably out of
                    abolition, and uses past statements as evidence of their deception and
                    treachery. Feels confident whites are up to the task of ousting Radicals and
                    electing Democrats, the "White Man's Party."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.08.24.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Strasburg has a yearly quit-rent of $150.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Waynesboro' Population</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kurtz</ln>
                        <fn>J. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. F. Kurtz reports that the population of Waynesboro is 1340. It was 1233
                    in 1860.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Widner</ln>
                        <fn>W. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>W. K. Widner has completed his census of Metal and is almost done with
                    Letterkenny.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Camp Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fetterhoff</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The United Brethren will hold a camp meeting on the land of George
                    Fetterhoff.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Church of God Camp Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clippinger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Churches of God of Shippensburg, Orrstown, Fayetteville, Newville,
                    Plainfield, Chambersburg, and Green Spring will hold a camp meeting on Mr.
                    Clippinger's farm near Mowersville.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letterkenny has laid a tax of 3 1/2 mills for road purposes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>A Relic of Booth</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Dr. John Peddicord allegedly has a lock of hair from the head of John
                    Wilkes Booth. He served in the navy and stood guard over Booth's corpse while it
                    lay on board a ship on the Potomac. Peddicord took the hair then.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Franklin County Horticultural Society</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hazelet</ln>
                        <fn>R. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deckelmayer</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The society met on Tuesday evening. R. P. Hazelet read the minutes and was
                    appointed to collect membership fees. Several pear specimens from Joseph
                    Deckelmayer's garden were exhibited. The fall exhibition will be held September
                    23rd and 24th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Van Amburgh's Menagerie</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Van Amburgh and Company's Golden Menagerie will visit Chambersburg. It is
                    reputed to have many wild and rare animals, and should provide high
                    entertainment for Chambersburg's citizens.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Wilson College</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wightman</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Plympton</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Ms.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robinson</ln>
                        <fn>Virginia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smead</ln>
                        <fn>Lizzie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robbins</ln>
                        <fn>Julia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCarty</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Rev. J. W. Wightman, Pastor of the Presbyterian Church at Greencastle,
                    has been elected vice president and resident professor of Wilson College. The
                    following will teach at the college: Miss Plympton, Miss Virginia Robinson, Miss
                    Lizzie Smead, Miss Julia Robbins, and Mrs. McCarty. The brick-work on the new
                    building is finished. The school will be able to accommodate between 80 and 100
                    boarders.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Reunion of the 77th Pa. Vet. Vol.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The second annual reunion of the survivors of this gallant regiment will, we
                        learn, occur in this place on the 13th day of next October. General F.S.
                        Stumbaugh, who was chosen President of the organization at its meeting in
                        Pittsburg a year ago, aided by such of its members as reside in this
                        vicinity, is making all necessary arrangements for the meeting. It is
                        expected that over a hundred members of the regiment, residing in other
                        sections of the State, will be present besides a number of distinguished
                        officers of other organizations, who have been, or will be invited. At the
                        last reunion Col. Fred. S. Pyfer, of Lancaster City, was chosen to deliver
                        the Annual Address and Capt. Geo. W. Skinner, of this place, the Address of
                        Welcome. This regiment was one of the first to enter the service and we
                        believe the last from this State to leave it, having been mustered in on the
                        11th of October, 1861, and mustered out on the 17th day of January, 1866. No
                        other regiment saw more real hard service. It was the only Pennsylvania
                        regiment engaged in the battle of Shiloh and participated in almost every
                        subsequent battle in the West down to the close of the war, after which it
                        served almost a year in Texas. The 77th was organized in our county. The
                        remains of Col. Housum and many other of its gallant dead sleep in our
                        midst. The heroic services of each member are held in lively remembrance
                        among our citizens, and we bespeak for those who attend a generous welcome
                        at their hands.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>F. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pyfer</ln>
                        <fn>Fred. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces a reunion of the 77th Pa. Vol. to be held in Chambersburg in
                    October. Gives a brief history of the regiment and its accomplishments, and
                    extends its welcome to the veterans who will come.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Calmore</ln>
                        <fn>Martha A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Russell</ln>
                        <fn>D. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. H. Patterson and Miss Martha A. Calmore, both of Franklin, were married
                    in Bowden's Hotel, Waynesboro, on July 28th by D. B. Russell.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Murphy</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Potts</ln>
                        <fn>Jemima</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>West</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John A. Murphy of Metal and Miss Jemima Potts of Huntingdon County were
                    married on August 4th by the Rev. William A. West.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shaffer</ln>
                        <fn>William V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>West</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William V. Shaffer of Fannettsburg and Margaret Jane Wilson of Spring
                    Garden Mills were married on August 11th by the Rev. William West.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snowberger</ln>
                        <fn>Barbara</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Barbara Snowberger died at Snow Hill on August 13th. She was 86 years
                    old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Small</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Small</ln>
                        <fn>E. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Henry Small died in Funkstown at the residence of his son E. J. Small on
                    August 6th. He was 84 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoke</ln>
                        <fn>W. H. Harrison</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>W. H. Harrison Hoke died in Montgomery on August 9th. He was 30 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mackey</ln>
                        <fn>Isabel P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Isabel P. Mackey died in Spring Hill on August 3rd. She was 25 years
                    old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rodenhaver</ln>
                        <fn>Annie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rodenhaver</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rodenhaver</ln>
                        <fn>Anne M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Annie Rodenhaver, daughter of Henry and Anne M. Rodenhaver, died in
                    Chambersburg on August 13th. She was 5 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.08.24.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
