<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1870/pa.fr.vs.1870.07.13">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>10/26/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1870-07-13">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day norm="">13</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.07.13.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.07.13.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Income Tax</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Another effort was made to abolish the Income Tax last week. Senator Conkling
                        moved a resolution to restrain the Internal Revenue officers from collecting
                        this tax.--The point was raised, that such a resolution was not in order
                        after the former definite action of the Senate. By a vote of 27 yeas to 21
                        nays, the Senate decided to allow the resolution to be introduced. A
                        discussion then followed upon the merits of the proposition, during which
                        Senator Cameron, who had voted to admit the resolution, left the Senate
                        Chamber. A vote was reached about half past eleven o'clock at night, and the
                        resolution was lost by a tie vote, the yeas being 26 and the nays 26. Had
                        Senator Cameron been at his post, the resolution would have carried, and
                        this odious impost would have been swept away. The defeat of Senator
                        Conkling's resolution may be justly attributed to the Winnebago Chief, who
                        is suspected of having made an agreement with Senator Sherman, by which the
                        tax on gross receipts was to be stricken out, in case he allowed the Income
                        Tax to be continued. Senator Cameron is largely interested in a certain
                        railroad company, and the tax on gross receipts consequently troubled him
                        far more than the tax against which the people have uniformly set their
                        faces. What gives color to this rumored bargain, is the fact that on the
                        night the Income Tax was continued, the tax on gross receipts was abolished.</p>
                    <p>Another remarkable feature about the vote on the Income Tax is that all the
                        respectable and intellectual Senators were found arrayed against it, while
                        the carpet-baggers were rallied in solid column in its favor. The votes of
                        such men as Conkling, Fenton, Trumbull, and Sumner were set off by the votes
                        of a set of stupid carpet-baggers whose very names are not known to the
                        people of the United States. By the way, let him who reads this, set himself
                        to the work of recalling from memory the names of the Senators from the
                        Southern States, and he will discover that he cannot get far.</p>
                    <p>Perhaps there is some justice in this result so far as these leading Radical
                        Senators are concerned. They labored to impose these foreign fellows upon
                        the Southern States, and there is a certain degree of just retribution in
                        the defeat which they have met at their hands. But it is greatly to be
                        regretted that the people at large should be subjected to the oppression to
                        which the action of reckless, irresponsible, corrupt carpet-baggers subjects
                        them.</p>
                    <p>We notice with pleasure that the leading men of Philadelphia, having lost all
                        hope of relief from Congress, have recently formed an association for the
                        purpose of testing the constitutionality of the act continuing this unequal
                        and unjust tax. It is to be hoped that this movement will be pushed
                        vigorously. It is high time that this matter should be decided. The people
                        bore this tax patiently during the war, under the belief that it was a
                        military necessity, and in hope of the fulfillment of the promise that it
                        should not continue longer than 1870. It has now expired by its own
                        limitation. If it is to be reimposed, the people ought to demand the
                        authority by which it is to be done.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports with outrage the recent defeat of another effort to abolish the
                    income tax. Blames carpet-baggers and hopes the Republicans who want the tax
                    repealed now realize the mistake of putting carpet-baggers in place. Hopes the
                    tax will be found unconstitutional in the near future.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>At His Old Tricks</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Cessna appeared in all his glory again in the House on Thursday last. Of
                        course there was another contested election case on hand. Cessna never
                        speaks except on a contested election case and there is no contested
                        election case up for discussion that Cessna does not speak. His whole time
                        in Congress is devoted to the manipulation of contested election cases. If a
                        Radical finds that his case is desperate and that the Democrat is likely to
                        succeed in ousting him from or keeping him out of the seat, as a last
                        resort, he is referred to Cessna, who has acquired a national celebrity as a
                        jobber in contested election cases. The usual remark is, "if Cessna can't
                        save you, the devil himself can't."</p>
                    <p>The case of Thursday was a Missouri contest between Suitzler and Dyer. Dyer
                        was the sitting member and is a Radical. The majority of the Committee on
                        Elections reported in favor of Suitzler who was shown to have been legally
                        and fairly elected. But Cessna, who never votes to admit a Democrat, made a
                        minority report declaring Dyer elected. The majority, with a reckless
                        disregard of facts, right, justice, their own consciences and their
                        accountability to God, sustained Cessna's infamous report, and the
                        smuggler-in of John Covode, and the defender of the cadetship-broker
                        Whittemore, achieved another of the victories which have given him the
                        reputation of a dexterous political prestidigitator.</p>
                    <p>He then offered a resolution to pay Mr. Suitzler five thousand dollars of the
                        people's money for contesting a seat to which the House decided he had no
                        right. Will the people of the Sixteenth Congressional District re-elect this
                        man, who, by almost every vote that he has cast, has brought disgrace upon
                        his constituency?</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Ridicules Cessna's work on contested elections, and gives another recent
                    example as proof of his corrupt behavior. Asks voters if they would stand to
                    re-elect this man given his sordid reputation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Crazy About the Negro</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper criticizes Senator Sumner for striking the word "white" from
                    naturalization laws. After panic ensued about the prospect of Chinese
                    citizenship, lawmakers restored "white" to the text. They made an exception for
                    persons of African decent, however, extending them full opportunity to become
                    citizens.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>No Prejudice Against White People</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper praises Charles Dickens' reported comments that Harriet Beecher
                    Stowe did not give white men "fair play" in her novel Uncle Tom's Cabin.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Candidate for Congress</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"Observer" suggests William M'Lellan as the perfect candidate to beat John
                    Cessna for Congress.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.07.13.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Democratic County Committee Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn>John R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnhart</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armstrong</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shillito</ln>
                        <fn>J. Newton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Worley</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Holliday</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Holland</ln>
                        <fn>Alonso</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clugston</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Diehl</ln>
                        <fn>Jeremiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reisher</ln>
                        <fn>B. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilmore</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCurdy</ln>
                        <fn>Robert I.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>DeHaven</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyd</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McAllen</ln>
                        <fn>William S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blair</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hauck</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Logue</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamsher</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillan</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stake</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phenicte</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sibbett</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Laughlin</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>H. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A meeting of the Democratic County Committee will be held at the office of
                    John R. Orr on July 16th. They will discuss reapportioning local districts. A
                    list of the committee members is included.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Bank Stock Sold</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stock</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jacob Stock of Antrim bought 150 shares of the capital stock of the
                    National Bank of Chambersburg. He paid $73 per share.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Probable Homicide</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cummings</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hasson</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kean</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>An altercation involving Peter Cummings, John Hasson, Jr., and Frank Kean
                    occurred in the yard of the Indian Queen Hotel on Friday afternoon. Hasson threw
                    a brick at Cummings that struck him in the back of the head. He is lying in
                    critical condition at Boyd's Hotel. Hasson and Kean are being held in jail.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Meeting of the County Committee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reminder that the Democratic County Committee will meet on Saturday. The
                    participants will set a date for the county convention and decide each
                    district's representation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Disgraceful Occurrence</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A dozen "rowdies" broke up the society singing held at Keller's
                    schoolhouse. They then proceeded to attack a few boys from New Guilford with
                    clubs and stones. "Such conduct is a disgrace to the community."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Waynesboro Mutual Fire Insurance Company</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The company has done a large amount of business in the last month. "Funds
                    have been secured sufficient for all emergencies, and losses will be promptly
                    paid." The editors endorse the company's board of directors.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Franklin County Cases</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Supreme Court has entered the following judgments in cases taken up from
                        this county:</p>
                    <p>Oller vs. Bonebrake. Judgment affirmed.</p>
                    <p>Fabruey vs. Holsinger. Judgment affirmed.</p>
                    <p>Greenawalt vs. M'Dowell. Judgment affirmed.</p>
                    <p>Dr. Max Kennedy, Committee of Sally Mahon, vs. George Johnson. Judgment
                        affirmed.</p>
                    <p>Thompson et al. vs. Kyner. Judgment affirmed.</p>
                    <p>Fleming's Appeal. Decree affirmed.</p>
                    <p>Eyster vs. Sprecher et al. Decree affirmed.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Oller</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bonebrake</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fahrney</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Holsinger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greenawalt</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Dowell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>Max</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mahon</ln>
                        <fn>Sally</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kyner</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fleming</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sprecher</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports on judgments handed down by the State Supreme Court on county
                    cases, all of which were affirmed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Trinity Church</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Howe</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lamberton</ln>
                        <fn>Robert A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hawkins</ln>
                        <fn>W. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The cornerstone of Trinity Episcopal Church was laid on Wednesday.
                    Ceremonies marked the occasion. Addresses were delivered in the Methodist Church
                    Building, including an account of the financial condition of the Trinity
                    congregation. The church is doing well, but still must raise some money.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Viewers to Assess Damages Appointed</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rowe</ln>
                        <fn>D. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armstrong</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stewart</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Lellan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharpe</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGowan</ln>
                        <fn>Theodore</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clark</ln>
                        <fn>Lyman S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stenger</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snively</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingert</ln>
                        <fn>Adam B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bossert</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Amberson</ln>
                        <fn>William S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Austin</ln>
                        <fn>James C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Britton</ln>
                        <fn>W. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilmore</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Teeter</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Hon. D. W. Rowe and the Hon. John Armstrong appointed commissioners to
                    assess damage claims along the line of the Southern Pennsylvania Railroad. The
                    viewers are: Benjamin Snively and Adam B. Wingert of Antrim, William Bossert of
                    Hamilton, William S. Amberson of Waynesboro, James C. Austin of Chambersburg,
                    and W. W. Britton and Joseph Gilmore of Letterkenny. Kennedy and Stewart and
                    William M'Lellan represented the company and J. M. Sharpe, Theodore McGowan,
                    Lyman S. Clark, and W. S. Stenger represented the aggrieved parties. The
                    commission will begin with inspection of the property of David Teeter of Peters.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Wilson Female College</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Edwards</ln>
                        <fn>Tryon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>J. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wightman</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Creigh</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>I. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Rev. Tryon Edwards was elected President of the Wilson Female College.
                    Professors were also chosen. The board also decided to erect the new building
                    immediately. It will be 105 feet long, 40 feet wide, have a French attic, and be
                    supplied with gas, water, and "all the latest conveniences" on every floor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Meeting of the Medical Society</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lane</ln>
                        <fn>S. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Suesserott</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richards</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davidson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLanahan</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Montgomery</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyle</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flickinger</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cleary</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Franklin County Medical Society met on July 5th in the hall of Columbus
                    Lodge. Dr. S. G. Lane, delegate to the State Medical Society, read a paper on
                    the late meeting in Philadelphia. "The everlasting 'Women' and 'Negro'
                    questions, as our readers have no doubt noticed by the papers, were needlessly
                    obtruded on the State Association and suffered to disturb the harmony of its
                    proceedings, excluding other and more important business. This action of the
                    Society was severely criticised by the Dr. in his able report, and the position
                    assumed denounced in strong terms."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Incendiaries About</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickley</ln>
                        <fn>Augustus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Opinion reports that an attempt was made to set fire to the house of
                    Augustus Bickley. Unknown persons placed a burning newspaper in the house that
                    would have burned it down had not Mrs. Bickley discovered it in time.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>A Gold Swindle</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We take the following account of a bold operation from the Philadelphia <emph
                            rend="italic">Morning Post</emph> of Monday. Mr. Early, as our readers
                        are all, doubtless, aware, hails from Chambersburg. We are glad that he
                        caught the one scoundrel and hope that he may be successful in apprehending
                        the others. The account is as follows: "Several instances of bold attempts
                        to swindle merchants and banks in this and other cities of the Union have
                        transpired recently, but in a majority of the cases the operators have been
                        unsuccessful and fallen into the hands of the police. But on Saturday,
                        Assistant Treasurer Barnet Early, of this city, was swindled out of over
                        $2500 in gold in the following bold manner. A party appeared in the upper
                        office of the Custom House building, and presented three coupons to the
                        clerk, Mr. Noble. After calculating the interest thereon, Mr. Noble issued
                        three checks for three dollars each, in gold. The fellow then left, and by
                        some process erased the figure 3 and where the amount was written in full,
                        and filled in one check for the sum of $1200, in another $1320, and in
                        another $1230.</p>
                    <p>"The checks were then presented by different individuals-- the two former
                        following each other in a short space of time. These were paid by the paying
                        clerk. The book-keeper, in checking off discovered the fraud, and notified
                        Mr. Early, who took the position of the paying teller. Shortly after doing
                        that the third check was presented. Mr. Early, being satisfied that it was a
                        forgery, seized the one who presented it by the coat and held him until
                        assistance arrived. Chief Kelley was notified, and he took the fellow into
                        custody. He is an Englishman, and gave the name of Daniel M. Johnson. He had
                        a hearing, subsequently, before United States Commissioner Biddle, who
                        committed him in default of $10,000 bail for a further hearing on Thursday
                        next."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes a daring attempt of forging gold banknotes in Philadelphia, and
                    the man who nearly foiled the crime.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Appointed to Take the Social Statistics</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gregory</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Marshal</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wertz</ln>
                        <fn>David A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Marshal Gregory has appointed David A. Wertz of Chambersburg to take the
                    social statistics of several counties including Franklin. The statistics
                    include: valuation of real and personal property, amount of the public debt,
                    taxation levels, extent of pauperism, crime statistics, library information,
                    average wages, number of newspapers, college, academy, and school enrollment,
                    membership of religious organizations.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Appointments</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schaff</ln>
                        <fn>J. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. G. Schaff announces he will preach at Marion Station and at Chambersburg
                    on Sunday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilbert</ln>
                        <fn>Michael A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hogens</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wood</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Michael A. Gilbert and Miss Sarah S. Hogens, both of Upton, were married in
                    Greencastle on June 23rd by the Rev. J. A. Wood.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brine</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Quigley</ln>
                        <fn>J. X.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Brine and Catharine Reed, both of Greencastle, were married on June
                    26th by the Rev. J. X. Quigley.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hutton</ln>
                        <fn>Minnie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hutton</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hutton</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Minnie Hutton, daughter of William and Mary Hutton, died on July 11th. She
                    was 4 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheets</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Sheets died in Chambersburg on July 3rd. He was 47 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunter</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. Joseph Hunter of Strasburg died at his residence on June 27th. He was
                    85 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Evits</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Elizabeth Evits died near Spring Run on June 15th. She was 86 years
                    old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scott</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Scott died in Greencastle on July 2nd. He was 74 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.07.13.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
