<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1870/pa.fr.vs.1870.08.10">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>10/27/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1870-08-10">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="08">August</month>
            <day norm="">10</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.08.10.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.08.10.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Our Candidates</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The proceedings of the Democratic County Convention will be found in another
                        column. It is not too much to say that it has presented a ticket in every
                        way worthy of the suffrages of the people of Franklin county. Its
                        deliberations were characterised by the greatest harmony and good feeling.
                        There was no wrangling and not the slightest bitterness exhibited by one
                        member towards another. All seemed to be animated by a common purpose, to
                        nominate a ticket that would be strong before the people, and, if elected,
                        that would reflect credit upon the Democratic organization.--The candidates
                        are such as every Democrat can vote and labor for with pleasure.</p>
                    <p>For Assembly, the Convention renominated Captain George W. Skinner, by
                        acclamation. It is hardly necessary for us to say anything about this
                        nomination. Capt. Skinner, although young in years is so well known to the
                        people of the county that no words of ours are needed to acquaint our
                        readers with his merits and his services. Entering the Union army when a
                        mere boy as a private, he served his country faithfully until the close of
                        the war, distinguishing himself by his coolness and gallantry, and winning
                        (although a strong Democrat) from a Radical administration a Captain's
                        commission.</p>
                    <p>In 1867, he was nominated as the Democratic candidate for County Treasurer,
                        and although his competitor was one of the most popular men in the county,
                        Capt. Skinner was elected by a majority of 251.--Last year, just as his term
                        of office as Treasurer was expiring, he was nominated for the Legislature.
                        His opponent was a gentleman of high respectability and acknowledged
                        integrity and ability, but such was Capt. Skinner's popularity that his
                        majority over the Radical candidate from Franklin was 415. In the
                        Legislature he was faithful and efficient. Whilst the majority of the
                        members were at all times willing to sell their votes for the highest price
                        offered, no one dared to impugn the integrity of the member from Franklin.
                        His hands were not soiled with bribes. He was honest in the discharge of his
                        duties, voting on all questions according to his best judgment as to what
                        the interests of his constituents demanded. He labored most assiduously for
                        the Border Claims Bill. We had opportunities for judging, having been on the
                        ground the greater portion of the Winter, and we feel it our duty to add our
                        testimony to the unselfish devotion manifested by our representative. He
                        labored with commendable zeal for the advancement <del/>. Had Governor Geary
                        not arrayed himself in deadly hostility to the bill, there is no doubt
                        whatever that the energies of Capt. Skinner and Senator
                        <unclear>Durham</unclear> would have ensured its passage.</p>
                    <p>We believe that notwithstanding the hostility of Governor Geary to the Border
                        Claims Bill, it will pass during the coming session, and pass over the
                        Governor's veto. The Governor seems to be a constitutional
                        <unclear>tool</unclear>, incapable of looking upon the people of the border
                        counties in any other light than that of "thieves and robbers." But in our
                        judgment, the prospect is good that, with proper management, the members of
                        the Legislature will recognize the justice of our claims, and make haste to
                        discharge the obligations of the State. To insure this result, it becomes
                        our people to return to the legislature one who has rendered us such signal
                        service and who now understands our trials and is possessed of the knowledge
                        and experience at Harrisburg that will enable him to do far more for us than
                        any new man could possibly do.</p>
                    <p>For Commissioner, the choice of the Convention is to be commended. In view of
                        <del/> recent transactions, it was demanded by the people that a man of
                        unimpeachable integrity should be nominated for this office. There was a
                        general cry for an upright and honorable man, one who would not disgrace the
                        party by suspicious complicity with paying jobs. This Borough presented
                        Samuel M. Worley and the nomination was conceded and given to the town. Mr.
                        Worley is an honest mechanic, one who has earned his bread by the sweat of
                        his face, and who is held in high esteem by his friends and acquaintances.
                        He is a man of excellent business capacity and sound judgment. His
                        mechanical skill will be of great service to the people if he should be
                        successful at the polls. In the giving out of bridge contracts for instance,
                        it is very desirable that at least <emph rend="italic">our</emph> member of
                        the Board of Commissioners should have some scientific and practical
                        knowledge of the work that is to be done. He is honest and he is capable.</p>
                    <p>He has a strong claim upon all Democrats for their support. He has never been
                        found untrue to Democratic principles. Whilst others have wavered he has
                        been staunch and true. He is one of the hardest workers on election day to
                        be found in the county. He labors from the opening to the closing of the
                        polls for the success of the Democratic ticket. The Democracy can,
                        therefore, rest satisfied that for this office they have a candidate who is
                        indefatigable and who will do everything in his power to secure his own
                        election. Let his efforts be seconded by every Democrat and victory is
                        certain.</p>
                    <p>Peter McFerren, of Guilford township is the nominee for Director of the Poor.
                        He is a man who is respected wherever he is known. By his excellent judgment
                        and practical knowledge of business affairs, he is admirably fitted for the
                        position of Director of the Poor. He is a man, too, who favors rigid economy
                        in the management of public affairs as well as individual matters. The
                        people can therefore expect of him that not a dollar will be uselessly
                        spent, and that every dollar spent must be accounted for.</p>
                    <p>No better selection could have been made than that which has been made for
                        Jury Commissioner. The present Democratic incumbent of that office is a
                        gentleman in every way capable of performing its duties. And Mr. Elias
                        Patton, the nominee, is no less capable. He is an exceedingly careful man.
                        He will not consent to put any man into the jury box whom he does not regard
                        as a safe person to decide upon the rights of life, liberty, and property.
                        He is not one of those who will put a man's name into the wheel just because
                        he is asked to do so as a personal favor to some fellow who is over anxious
                        to serve his country in that capacity, on account of the little notoriety it
                        gives him in his township, or perhaps simply to see his name in the
                        newspapers. Mr. Patton will select men who are competent to sit in judgment
                        upon the great issues which are constantly being presented in our courts
                        wherein the rights of our citizens are to be determined.</p>
                    <p>For Auditor, we have Mr. John A. Selers who is known to everybody in St.
                        Thomas township and to many in the county as a skillful accountant, a
                        correct and honest business man, a gentleman of admirable social qualities,
                        and a Democrat of unswerving fidelity.</p>
                    <p>Such, Democrats, is your ticket. It commends itself to your support. It is
                        composed of good men and true. Besides it is a white man's ticket, and
                        stands on a white man's platform. The principles announced by the Convention
                        which nominated this ticket have the true Democratic ring. They are the
                        principles which are taking hold of the Conservative minds of the country.
                        Everywhere there are dissensions in the Radical ranks. The moderate men of
                        that party refuse to go further with the extremists, and a general alarm has
                        been signaled. The Radical party is disintegrating. It has lost its cohesive
                        power. The people have become disgusted, amazed and horrified at the
                        terrible extent to which they have been plundered. The cry for reform is
                        going up and politicians must heed the cry or go down to defeat. We have
                        faith in the glorious triumph of the Democracy.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on the nominees picked at the County Convention. Has especially
                    high praise for George Skinner, nominated for the Legislature, and Samuel
                    Worley, nominated for Commissioner. Ends by declaring Democrats the white man's
                    party, and predicts overwhelming defeat for Radicals.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.08.10.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>County Fair</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Franklin County Agricultural Society will hold their fair on the 5th,
                    6th, and 7th of October.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Light</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Silver Cornet Band of Chambersburg played in Shippensburg during John
                    A. Light's ascension in a balloon.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>An Interesting Lecture</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McElwain</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A. McElwain will deliver a lecture on capital punishment in the Court
                    House. The editors do not know what side of the question he will take, but, no
                    matter what, the evening promises to be interesting. The proceeds will go to pay
                    the debt of the Bethel Church of God.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>County Executive Committee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duncan</ln>
                        <fn>Auge.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitmore</ln>
                        <fn>C. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharpe</ln>
                        <fn>J. McDowell</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Speer</ln>
                        <fn>John D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hollsworth</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fagan</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shatzer</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reber</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dysert</ln>
                        <fn>H. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillan</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunter</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCurdy</ln>
                        <fn>R. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilbert</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Noble</ln>
                        <fn>Fletcher</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Black</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn>James B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brauthafer</ln>
                        <fn>W. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Plasterer</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gelwicks</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Culbertson</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phenicle</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lacrone</ln>
                        <fn>Simon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elliott</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper lists the members of the County Executive Committee.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Radical Ticket</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cessna</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mahon</ln>
                        <fn>Thad. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huber</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strickler</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cressler</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mackey</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The following were nominated at the Republican County Convention: John
                    Cessna for Congress; Thad. M. Mahon for assembly; John Huber for commissioner;
                    Jacob Strickler for director of the poor; John Cressler for auditor; William H.
                    Mackey for Jury Commissioner.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Court Proceedings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Court began on Monday morning, His Honor, Judge King presiding. The forenoon
                        was taken up with hearing the motions of counsel. In the afternoon the case
                        of the Com. vs. Wiley A. Himes charged with breaking into the store of Isaac
                        Clugston at Doylesburg, was taken up and Defendant pleaded guilty. He was
                        sentenced to three years imprisonment in the Eastern Penitentiary.</p>
                    <p>The next case was that of the Com. vs. Wm. Williams, John Anderson and Nelson
                        Bird. Charge, Riot. Chan. H. Cressler, Prosecutor. The offence was committed
                        on the 17th day of June last in front of Mr. Cressler's Drug Store. Two of
                        the darkies got into a fight that morning and raised considerable
                        disturbance among the negroes that usually congregate in that neighborhood.
                        Mr. Cressler considered it an intolerable nuisance and went after the
                        "larkies" in the Quarter Sessions. Verdict, Guilty.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. David Gelwicks--Assault and Battery.--Rufus K. McClellan,
                        Prosecutor. Verdict not guilty and costs equally divided between Prosecutor
                        and Defendant.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Samuel Rhores--Assault and Battery with intent to commit
                        rape.--Harriet A. Mackey, Prosecutrix. On trial.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Himes</ln>
                        <fn>Wiley A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clugston</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Williams</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bird</ln>
                        <fn>Nelson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cressler</ln>
                        <fn>Charles B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gelwicks</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClellan</ln>
                        <fn>Rufus K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rohrer</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mackey</ln>
                        <fn>Harriet A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Covers cases in the county court and the verdicts rendered. Most appear to
                    be assault and battery cases and rioting.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Democratic County Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Democratic County Convention met in the Court House in this place at 11
                        o'clock, A.M., last Thursday. H.M. White, Chairman, Democratic County
                        Committee, called Convention to order.</p>
                    <p>On motion of W.S. Stenger, Esq., Col. B. F. Winger was chosen President, who
                        returned his thanks to the Convention in a few appropriate remarks.</p>
                    <p>On motion of Jno. R. Orr, Esq., Wm. Logue of Quincy twp., and Jno. C. Tritle
                        of Hamilton were chosen Vice Presidents, John Russell of Washington and
                        Andrew Burgess of Peters Secretaries.</p>
                    <p>The following named gentlemen presented their credentials and were admitted
                        as delegates to the Convention:</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Antrim</emph>.--Michael L. Stine, Jacob Statler,
                        Christian Whitmore, Milton A. Emblek, B.F. Winger, Jacob R. Smith and E.C.
                        Betrick.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Chambersburg--North Ward</emph>.--Wm. McLellan, John R.
                        Orr, Martin Ludwig, P. Henry Peiffer, and Thomas Cook. <emph rend="italic"
                            >South Ward</emph>.--W.S. Stenges, J. Newton Shillito, Alexander Martin,
                        Christian Frederick and H.C. Koontz.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Dry Run</emph>.--David H. Skinner, George Rinesmith and
                        William Shetter.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Fayetteville</emph>.--Jesse Kean, John Cook, Henry Snider
                        and Peter McFerren.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Greenvillage</emph>.--Josiah McDowell, Charles Ditzler
                        and Jacob Etter.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Guilford</emph>.--Cadwalader Kisecker, Henry Dyssert,
                        Alex. Clugston and Jere Overcash.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Hamilton</emph>.--Samuel Gillan, John C. Tritle, Wm.
                        Bossert, and Samuel Reisher.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Letterkenny</emph>.--George Heller, Wm. Forbis, Jonathan
                        A. West and J.V.S. Leedy.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Lurgan</emph>.--John Gilbert, J. Shuman, D. Cover and
                        J.C. Breckinridge.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Loudon</emph>.--George M. Stenger, Andrew Burgess and
                        John Smith.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Metal</emph>.--W.S. McAllen, Fletcher Noble and Samuel
                        Noonan.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Montgomery</emph>.--A.R. Sohnebry, Henry Black, Leonard
                        Leidy and John McLaughlin.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Orrstown</emph>.--James B. Orr, J. Houston McCullough and
                        Charles Mahon.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Peters</emph>.--Jacob Hauck, J.W. Hays and Jacob
                        Hawbecker.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Quincy</emph>.--James A. Cook, Wm. Logue, George W.
                        McCleary, Daniel Thompson and John Heller.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Southampton</emph>.--Joseph Boaz, Benjamin Johnston and
                        Jacob Hamsher.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">St. Thomas</emph>.--John A. Sellers, Frederick Gelwicks,
                        Albertus Hicks and Jacob Hockersmith.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Washington</emph>.--W.F. Horner, Jacob J. Miller, John B.
                        Russel, Michael Houstine and John Zody.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Welsh Run</emph>.--John W. Kuhn, Lewis C. Hinkle and Wm.
                        Reed.</p>
                    <p>On motion of W.S. Stenger, the Reporters of the Press in the county were
                        invited to seats in the Convention.</p>
                    <p>On motion of Wm. McLellan, a Committee on Resolutions, consisting of Wm.
                        McLellan, Col. James B. Orr and Henry Black, was appointed by the Chair.</p>
                    <p>On motion of Milton A. Embick, the Convention adjourned to meet again at 1
                        o'clock P.M.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>H. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stenger</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Winger</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn>John R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Logue</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tritle</ln>
                        <fn>John C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Russell</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burgess</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stine</ln>
                        <fn>Michael L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Statler</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitmore</ln>
                        <fn>Christian</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Embick</ln>
                        <fn>Milton A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Winger</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Detrick</ln>
                        <fn>E. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLellan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn>John R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ludwig</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peiffer</ln>
                        <fn>P. Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stenger</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shillito</ln>
                        <fn>J. Newton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Frederick</ln>
                        <fn>Christian</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koontz</ln>
                        <fn>H. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>David H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rinesmith</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shetter</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kean</ln>
                        <fn>Jesse</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snider</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McFerren</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDowell</ln>
                        <fn>Josiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ditzler</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Etter</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Klecker</ln>
                        <fn>Cadwalader</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dysert</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clugston</ln>
                        <fn>Alex</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Overcash</ln>
                        <fn>Jere</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillan</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tritle</ln>
                        <fn>John C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bossert</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reisher</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heller</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Forbis</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>West</ln>
                        <fn>Jonathan A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Leedy</ln>
                        <fn>J. V. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilbert</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shuman</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cover</ln>
                        <fn>D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Breckinridge</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stenger</ln>
                        <fn>George M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burgess</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McAllen</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Noble</ln>
                        <fn>Fletcher</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Noonan</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sohnebry</ln>
                        <fn>A. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Black</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Leidy</ln>
                        <fn>Leonard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLaughlin</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn>James B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCullough</ln>
                        <fn>J. Houston</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mahon</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hauck</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hawbecker</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>James A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Logue</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCleary</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heller</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Booz</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnston</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamsher</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sellers</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gelwicks</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hicks</ln>
                        <fn>Albertina</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hockersmith</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Horner</ln>
                        <fn>W. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Russel</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Honstine</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zody</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kuhn</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hinkle</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stenger</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLellan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lists the delegates from each town who attended the county convention. Also
                    reports on motions carried in the early part of the day, mainly concerning
                    committees and resolutions.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Afternoon Session</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Convention reassembled at the hour named. Mr. Stenger moved that John A.
                        McAllen be substituted as a delegate from Metal township in place of
                        Fletcher Noble, who was compelled to leave by the 1 o'clock train.</p>
                    <p>On motion of J.M. Shillito, Capt. Geo. W. Skinner was renominated for
                        Assembly by acclamation. Being called upon, Capt. Skinner returned his
                        thanks to the Convention coupled with a few pertinent remarks upon the
                        Border Claims Bill. He spoke as follows:</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Mr. President and Gentlemen of the Convention:</emph> I
                        thank you heartily for the mark of approbation which you have seen fit to
                        bestow upon me. This is the third time I have been honored at your hands. I
                        have ever tried to show myself worthy of your trust. Errors may have been
                        made, but they were errors of the head and not of the heart. My last
                        position was a trying one, and had I been less unselfish I might have acted
                        differently, but I thought it was my duty to do anything and everything for
                        my county. Our border bill failed on political grounds. Its friends were
                        found on the Democratic side and its enemies among the Radicals.--The vote
                        on the bill shows this. 15 out of the 16 votes in favor of it were
                        Democratic. To such matters, however, so it stood. But I think the time has
                        come for action. Better that the interests of the Democratic party should
                        suffer to a certain extent than that our bill should fail to pass entirely.</p>
                    <p>I believe these claims ought to be paid and I think they <emph rend="italic"
                            >will</emph> be paid. In no other county was the loss of life and
                        property so great as in this, and none other responded more promptly and
                        willingly to the call for men. We have a right to demand relief.</p>
                    <p>Had the men who went from here remained to protect their homes, we would not
                        now be asking relief, but Chambersburg would be standing to-day with its
                        ancient houses--time-honored and hallowed by old associations--monuments of
                        our fathers childhood.</p>
                    <p>One day these claims, I repeat, will be paid. I have too much faith in the
                        State of Pennsylvania, and I have too much faith in the inconsistency of
                        Governor Geary to believe otherwise. For although in the presence of a
                        reliable witness I heard Governor Geary declare that the people of the
                        border counties ought to be ashamed to ask the payment of their claims, yet
                        I think like most politicians he can be made to feel the force of a <emph
                            rend="italic">change of front</emph>.</p>
                    <p>In conclusion, I thank you for the privilege I have had of speaking to you,
                        and again for the honor which you have conferred upon men.</p>
                    <p>On motion, Convention proceeded to nominate a candidate for Commissioner
                        which the following named gentlemen were placed in nomination: Samuel M.
                        Worley, Dr. John Montgomery, B. Frank Nead, Jacob S. Brand and Martin L.
                        Hammond. By request of Mr. Hammond his name was withdrawn as a candidate.
                        The Convention then proceeded to a ballot with the following result:</p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>1st ballot.</cell>
                            <cell>2d ballot.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Worley</cell>
                            <cell>33</cell>
                            <cell>50</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Montgomery</cell>
                            <cell>19</cell>
                            <cell>1</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Nead</cell>
                            <cell>20</cell>
                            <cell>24</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Brand</cell>
                            <cell>7</cell>
                            <cell>4</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <p>Samuel M. Worley, of Chambersburg, having received a majority of all the
                        votes cast, was declared the nominee for Commissioner. On motion his
                        nomination was made unanimous.</p>
                    <p>The Convention next proceeded to nominate a candidate for Director of the
                        Poor, when the following named gentlemen were put in nomination: Jacob J.
                        Miller, Wm. Brand, Jacob Hefflefinger, Solomon Brake, Peter McFerren and
                        Peter Brindle.</p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>1st Ballot.</cell>
                            <cell>2d Ballot.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Miller</cell>
                            <cell>21</cell>
                            <cell>20</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Brand</cell>
                            <cell>11</cell>
                            <cell>4</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Hefflefinger</cell>
                            <cell>4</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Brake</cell>
                            <cell>8</cell>
                            <cell>3</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>McFerren</cell>
                            <cell>35</cell>
                            <cell>49</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Brindle</cell>
                            <cell>2 a</cell>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>a withdrawn</cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <p>Peter McFerren of Guilford Twp. having received the majority of all the votes
                        cast was declared the nominee for Director of the Poor. The nomination was
                        then made unanimous.</p>
                    <p>The Convention next proceeded to nominate a candidate for Jury Commissioner,
                        when Elias Patton, Wm. Boyd, Thomas Hollar, John Gilbert and Joseph Gilmore
                        were put in nomination and balloted for with the following result:</p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>1st ballot.</cell>
                            <cell>2nd ballot.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Patton</cell>
                            <cell>23</cell>
                            <cell>40</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Boyd</cell>
                            <cell>4 a</cell>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Hollar</cell>
                            <cell>7 a</cell>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Gilbert</cell>
                            <cell>17</cell>
                            <cell>21</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Gilmore</cell>
                            <cell>22</cell>
                            <cell>17</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>a withdrawn</cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <p>Elias Patton, of Peters, having received a majority of the votes cast on this
                        ballot was declared the nominee, and his nomination made unanimous.</p>
                    <p>Jacob Hambright, John A. Sellers and Charles Ditslear were then put in
                        nomination for Auditor, and balloted for with the annexed result.</p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>1st ballot.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Hambright</cell>
                            <cell>30</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Sellers</cell>
                            <cell>45</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Ditslear</cell>
                            <cell>4</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <p>John A. Sellers, of St. Thomas having received a majority of all the votes
                        cast, was declared the nominee. The nomination was made unanimous.</p>
                    <p>On motion of Milton A. Embick, the Convention proceeded to ballot for
                        Congressional Conferees. The ballot resulted in the choice of Col. B.F.
                        Winger, W.S. Stenger and John R. Orr, Esq.</p>
                    <p>On motion of Henry Black, J. Logan Kennedy and Martin Ludwig were appointed
                        Legislative Conferees.</p>
                    <p>On motion of Geo. M. Stenger, Esq., the following resolution was adopted:</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That each Delegation from the Rural
                        Districts shall name one person, and the Delegations from the North and
                        South wards of Chambersburg shall each name two persons who shall constitute
                        the County Executive Committee, with Augustus Duncan as Chairman.</p>
                    <p>Mr. M'Lellan, as Chairman of the Committee on Resolutions, reported the
                        following:</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That the Democracy of Franklin County in
                        Convention assembled, appeal to their Conservative fellow-citizens, whatever
                        may have been their party affiliation heretofore, to unite with them at the
                        approaching election and rally under the banner on which is
                        inscribed--OPPOSITION TO RADICALISM.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That the use of the power of the General
                        Government, and the high-handed outrages of the Radical leaders to force
                        negro suffrage upon the States, against the will of the people, as shown in
                        the means employed to procure the fraudulent ratification of the Fifteenth
                        Amendment, have made manifest the deliberate purpose of the Radical leaders
                        "to put all the States of the Union (all of them more or less, and some of
                        them entirely) under the domination of negroes, to Africanize a large
                        portion of the country, and degrade the white race, morally and socially, as
                        well as politically, to the low level of the black." To this scheme, so
                        discreditable to white men and so dangerous to the republic, we are
                        unalterably opposed and, therefore, present today for the suffrages of the
                        people, a white man's ticket on a white man's platform.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That the reconstruction policy adopted
                        by the Radical majority in Congress has been the fruitful source of woe to
                        the country. It has presented the amazing spectacle of States unrepresented
                        in Congress five years after the termination of the war. It has afforded an
                        opportunity for obscure Northern adventures to settle in the South and, by
                        pandering to, and associating with negroes, to procure their votes to
                        elevate them to offices of trust and honor. It has enabled negroes to be
                        elected to seats in State Legislatures and has elevated one to the high
                        position of United States Senator. Under its baneful influence, anarchy
                        reigns in North Carolina and peaceable citizens have been arrested without
                        warrant. Military officers defy the processes of the Courts, and the Radical
                        Governor of that Commonwealth approves of their conduct. President Grant
                        gives his sanction to these outrageous proceedings. All this has been done
                        to overawe the Conservative people and keep them from the polls, so as to
                        insure a victory for the Radical ticket at the election being held this day.
                        Such infamous conduct deserves the severest condemnation of all who love
                        liberty.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That the true greatness and glory of
                        this nation is promoted largely by the prosperity and progress of its
                        laboring classes, and therefore we must deprecate the introduction of the
                        Chinaman as a competitor in our varied industrial pursuits, for the reason
                        that he is never likely to become an American citizen, and for the
                        additional and more important consideration that his cheap labor will tend
                        to the degradation of our own laboring man and his posterity.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That we demand as a matter of right and
                        justice, redress from the State for losses and damages sustained by the
                        citizens of the border during the progress of the late rebellion. And we
                        would urge our candidate this day selected for the Legislature, (if elected)
                        to bend all his energies, as he has done heretofore, to secure this result.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That we condemn the course of the Hon.
                        John Cessna, our present Representative in Congress, for this reason--among
                        many others--that he has done or attempted nothing during his Congressional
                        career looking to the reimbursement of the State or payment of our citizens
                        for losses and damages sustained during the late rebellion.</p>
                    <p>On motion the following resolution was adopted:</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That the thanks of this Convention are
                        due to Col. B.F. Winger for the able and impartial manner with which he has
                        discharged the duties of the Chair.</p>
                    <p>On the motion to adopt the resolutions Mr. M'Lellan made a forcible address.
                        He was followed by W.S. Stenger, Esq., in a brief speech. The resolutions
                        were then unanimously adopted and the Convention adjourned.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McAllen</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shillito</ln>
                        <fn>J. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Worley</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Montgomery</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nead</ln>
                        <fn>B. Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brand</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hammond</ln>
                        <fn>Martin L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brand</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hefflefinger</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brake</ln>
                        <fn>Solomon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McFerren</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brindle</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patton</ln>
                        <fn>Elias</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyd</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hollar</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilbert</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilmore</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hambright</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sellers</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ditslear</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Embick</ln>
                        <fn>Milton A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Winger</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stenger</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn>John R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>J. Logan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ludwig</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Continues its coverage of the county convention. Prints a speech made by
                    George Skinner, lists the votes taken for different positions and the results of
                    those votes, and lists the resolutions passed. Most of the resolutions denounce
                    Republican policies, favor the border claims bill, attack John Cessna, and
                    oppose the introduction of Chinese labor into the state.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Snubs his Colored Constituents</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The <emph rend="italic">Bedford Gazette</emph> of the 4th inst. gives the
                        following account of a compliment tendered to Hon. John Cessna which he
                        failed to appreciate. He seems to have been afraid to "face the music." He
                        likes begs that they will not ask him to "speak in public on the stage" to a
                        colored assembly. The <emph rend="italic">Gazette</emph> says: "Last Friday
                        evening the colored 'battalion' of waiters at the Springs, reinforced by
                        Bedford darkies, came to town, in brilliant procession, with torch and
                        transparencies, and marched and counter-marched through our principal
                        streets. Passing along Jullanna street the procession left-flanked and
                        right-flanked, then halted in front of the residence of the Hon. John
                        Cessna. The Colonel commanding the "colored troops" then, in
                            <unclear>stentorian</unclear> voice, called out, "Attention! Battalion!
                        Three cheers for de 'onorable John Cessnah!" The three cheers were given
                        with a breadth and depth of yell such as the throats of Fifteenths only can
                        produce. Now comes a dead silence--a painful waiting for "de 'onarable" to
                        make his appearance. But the manipulator of the contested Congressional
                        elections, and the writer--by proxy--of the famous letters to Franklin
                        County Africans in perfect keeping with his character as an artful dodger,
                        failed to present himself to his noble brethren, and thank them for the
                        honor conferred upon him by their "cheering" presence. Full five minutes
                        waited they, but no John came, when the commandant of the forces gave the
                        order: "Attention! Battalion! About face, forward march!" and the whole
                        party turned away in disgust at the manner in which they had been treated by
                        "our member." The majority swear they will not vote for John this fall, and
                        we should not be surprised if they kept their word. They were shamefully
                        snubbed, and "de 'onerable" had better fix it up the best way he can."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates a story of Cessna snubbing his black supporters by not appearing in
                    front of a crowd of them to speak and accept their thanks. Sees it as another
                    example of Cessna's duplicity and speculates he may not even get the black vote
                    in the election.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fahnestock</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fleshour</ln>
                        <fn>Maria</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>I. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Charles Fahnestock and Miss Maria Fleshour, both of Chambersburg, were
                    married on July 5th by the Rev. I. N. Hays.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sprecher</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Givler</ln>
                        <fn>Caroline I.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>I. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jacob L. Sprecher and Miss Caroline I. Givler, both of Stoufferstown,
                    Franklin County, were married on August 4th by the Rev. I. N. Hays.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamilton</ln>
                        <fn>Robert A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lloyd</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Robert A. Hamilton and Miss Maggie Reed, both of Franklin, were married on
                    July 28th at the M. E. Parsonage in Orrstown by the Rev. John Lloyd.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Briggs</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cover</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>P. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Joseph Briggs and Miss Sarah E. Cover, both of Mercersburg, were married on
                    August 2nd by the Rev. P. S. Davis.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>S. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wagner</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anthony</ln>
                        <fn>J. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>S. T. Miller and Miss Catharine Wagner, both from near Newburg, were
                    married on August 4th by the Rev. J. P. Anthony at his residence in Orrstown.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harney</ln>
                        <fn>John E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deardoff</ln>
                        <fn>Anna G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anthony</ln>
                        <fn>J. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John E. Harney of Newburg and Miss Anna G. Deardoff of Roxbury were married
                    on August 4th by the Rev. J. P. Anthony at his residence in Orrstown.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miley</ln>
                        <fn>Franklin Skinner</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miley</ln>
                        <fn>Reuben</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miley</ln>
                        <fn>Ella</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Franklin Skinner Miley, son of Reuben and Ella Miley, died in Chambersburg
                    on August 2nd. He was 1 year old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lindsay</ln>
                        <fn>Ida H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lindsay</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lindsay</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Ida H. Lindsay, daughter of Benjamin and Catharine Lindsay, died in Horse
                    Valley on August 2nd. She was 5 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shearer</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Susan Shearer died in Strasburg on August 3rd. She was 85 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clippinger</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Daniel Clippinger died near Mowersville on August 3rd.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kohler</ln>
                        <fn>Charles Cary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kohler</ln>
                        <fn>A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kohler</ln>
                        <fn>Eliza J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Charles Cary Kohler, son of A. J. and Eliza J. Kohler, died in Fayetteville
                    on August 6th. He was ten months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.08.10.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
