<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1870/pa.fr.vs.1870.08.17">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>10/28/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1870-08-17">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="08">August</month>
            <day norm="">17</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.08.17.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.08.17.02" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.08.17.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Festival</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Lutheran Congregation of Loudon is holding a festival this weekend.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Valentine</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. M. Valentine, President of Pennsylvania College, preached in the
                    Lutheran Church of Chambersburg last Sunday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schaff</ln>
                        <fn>J. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bishop</ln>
                        <fn>J. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snively</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. G. Schaff and J. P. Bishop will preach near Greencastle in the grove of
                    Samuel Snively on August 21st. The subject will be "the Judgement and the
                    afternoon Hell."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Wilson College</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The work on Wilson College's new building is progressing rapidly. It should
                    be ready for the opening of the school in the fall.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Grasshoppers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Grasshoppers have been destroying crops in Franklin County for the past
                    five weeks. Jeremiah Zollinger and Jacob Kauffman each lost an entire field of
                    oats. They are now attacking the clover crop and doing much damage.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Licenses</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Detrich</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McNulty</ln>
                        <fn>William C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rice</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolff</ln>
                        <fn>Scott</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The following received licenses: Jacob L. Detrich to keep a restaurant in
                    Greencastle; William C. McNulty to keep a wholesale liquor store in
                    Chambersburg; Rice and Gordon to keep a restaurant in Chambersburg. The
                    following applications were refused: James Snyder to wholesale liquor, and Scott
                    Wolff for a restaurant in Mercersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Census</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lesher</ln>
                        <fn>David H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reid</ln>
                        <fn>E. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>David H. Lesher completed a census of the South Ward and E. D. Reid is
                    close to completing a census of the North Ward and Hamilton. The paper believes
                    the results will show that Chambersburg residents have overestimated the
                    population of the town. "The whole population, white and black, will not in our
                    judgement exceed six thousand five hundred."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Post-Office Salaries</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The salary for the Chambersburg Postmaster is fixed at $2400.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Admitted to the Bar</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Detrich</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duncan</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGowan</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Douglas</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lewis W. Detrich, who studied law with Duncan and McGowan, has been
                    admitted to the Chambersburg Bar on motion of J. W. Douglas.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Death From Lockjaw</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Logan</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Logan</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyle</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Senseny</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lane</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George Logan, son of Thomas Logan, died of lockjaw after stepping on a
                    nail. Dr. Boyle, Dr. Senseney, and Dr. Lane attempted to treat him but were
                    unsuccessful.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Pennsylvania College</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Probst</ln>
                        <fn>J. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Rev. J. F. Probst, financial agent for the collection of funds for
                    Pennsylvania College, is now in Chambersburg soliciting contributions. The
                    appeal is made directly to the Lutheran Church for which the college is the main
                    institution in the east. Money will go to paying debts that funded new building
                    construction.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Report of the Grand Jury</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Opinion of the Poor House and the Jail</emph>.--The
                        following is the report of the Grand Jury which visited the Alms House and
                        Jail last week:</p>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">The Grand Inquest of the County would make the following
                            presentment:</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>They examined the Poor House property, which at present is under the
                        immediate charge of Samuel Brandt and his efficient lady and they desire to
                        express their highest approval of the condition of things there; the house
                        is in most excellent order, the paupers are well cared for and under
                        admirable treatment, and the farm is productive and in every way we find the
                        institution all that it was intended to be.</p>
                    <p>We also examined the County Jail, and we regret to say that we can not record
                        our approval of the administration of things there. The Jail itself is not
                        calculated for the condition of things existing in our county; its
                        construction and arrangement are very bad, and it may be that it is
                        impossible for the turnkey, with the great number of persons confined, of
                        both sexes, to administer the affairs with that judgment and prudence that
                        is required in such an institution. We find the persons confined, of all
                        sorts, mingling together, the baser with those that still have some remains
                        of virtue, and the County Jail a den of evil. The Jail yard has been turned
                        into a pigsty, and is consequently in a most filthy condition. The internal
                        management of the Jail is considerably better, according to the means at
                        hand, and we believe it is scarcely possible for the officer in charge, as
                        matters stand, to do much better. One of the great evils that we find is the
                        constant idleness of the inmates--many of them large, able men and women
                        accustomed to labor, who have been there for months, and during that time
                        have had no employment whatever. They have done nothing towards paying the
                        expenses of the Jail and their own keeping, and if we are to judge from the
                        general result of idleness, among the class confined, the Jail of the County
                        would be the worst place in it.</p>
                    <p>In our judgment a new jail is imperatively necessary, and we recommend to the
                        County Commissioners to build a new one as speedily as possible, adapted to
                        the wants of the County, with the modern improvements--one that will enable
                        the Court to confine persons in comfortable quarters, with the sexes
                        separate, and give employment to all--containing cells, if it be deemed
                        proper, for the punishment of prisoners by solitary confinement.<lb/> DANIEL
                        TOLHELM, Foreman.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prints a report on conditions of the local poor house and jail. Finds the
                    poor house in good shape but says the jail is in desperate need of repair and
                    upkeep.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Result of the exploration of Chambersburg by Rev. F. Dyson, the Agent of
                        the Franklin County Bible Society, is as follows:</p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Number of families visited, white</cell>
                            <cell>1131</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Number of families visited, colored</cell>
                            <cell>202</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>-----1333</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Number of families destitute of a bible, white</cell>
                            <cell>38</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Number of families destitute of a bible colored</cell>
                            <cell>80</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>------118</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Church members, white</cell>
                            <cell>2263</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Church members, colored</cell>
                            <cell>234</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>-----2437</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Sabbath school children and teachers, white</cell>
                            <cell>1952</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Sabbath school children and teachers, colored</cell>
                            <cell>180</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>-----2132</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Families none of which are members of any church, white</cell>
                            <cell>175</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Families none of which are members of any church, colored</cell>
                            <cell>59</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>--------234</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Bibles donated to Boyd's Hotel</cell>
                            <cell>15</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Bibles donated to Keefers Hotel</cell>
                            <cell>12</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Bibles donated to Jail</cell>
                            <cell>12</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>To destitute families, white</cell>
                            <cell>35</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>To destitute families, colored</cell>
                            <cell>64</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>To destitute individuals</cell>
                            <cell>6</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Amount received on Bibles</cell>
                            <cell>$3.50</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Amount received as donations</cell>
                            <cell>$42.95</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <p>The population of Chambersburg, as taken by the Agent in his work, is
                        <sic>a</sic> follows:</p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>White</cell>
                            <cell>5254</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Colored</cell>
                            <cell>738</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>------5992</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <p>The average to the family is as follows: white 4.65 hundredths; colored 3.65
                        hundredths.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prints the results of a study done by a reverend to calculate the number of
                    bibles people in Chambersburg have and how many were donated by local
                    organizations. Divides the results between the white and black populations.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>A Centenarian</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDade</ln>
                        <fn>Mary M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Everett</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDade</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Mary M. McDade died at Greencastle after reaching the age of 102. The
                    Rev. Thomas T. Everett gave the funeral address. "She was by common consent
                    respected and beloved as a christian, and in all her relations as a woman, a
                    wife, a mother, a neighbor, and a friend." Her father fought in the war for
                    Independence, and Mary was allegedly once spoke to George Washington as he
                    passed through the area. She had five children with her husband John McDade, who
                    passed away in 1804. Only one child survives--John McDade, age 70.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The County Fair</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper announces plans for the Franklin County Fair to be held in
                    October. Improvements have been made to the grounds and a large number of prizes
                    will be awarded.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Court Proceedings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The whole week was taken up with the trial of criminal cases. There were one
                        hundred cases on the calendar. The following were disposed of.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Samuel Rohrer--Assault and Battery with intent to ravish. Harriet A.
                        Mackey, Prosecutrix. Verdict guilty. Sentenced to three years imprisonment
                        in the Eastern Penitentiary.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Mordecai McMahon--Charge of stealing the horse of Daniel Palmer on
                        the night of the 25th of June last. We gave an account of this case in our
                        columns at the time of its occurrence. The horse was taken from the yard of
                        the Indian Queen Hotel in this borough. It was found in possession of the
                        defendant at Fairfield, Adams County, Pa. The defence was that the man was
                        laboring under the influence of <emph rend="italic">mania a pota</emph>. He
                        is a blacksmith from Altoona who is in the habit of getting on periodical
                        sprees. The horse was taken on a Saturday night. On the Tuesday previous he
                        had come to this borough and on Tuesday night he was in a raving delirium at
                        the National hotel. On Wednesday morning he left the hotel, and was about
                        the town tolerably "soggy" until Saturday evening when he left, taking Mr.
                        Palmer's horse with him. He was arrested on the next day (Sunday) and taken
                        to the Gettysburg jail from whence he was brought to this jail on the
                        Tuesday following. On Tuesday night he had an attack of <emph rend="italic"
                            >mania a pota</emph> which continued four or five days. The defence
                        contended that he was under the influence of <emph rend="italic">mania a
                            pota</emph> all the time that he had been in Chambersburg. The Jury
                        thought so too, and rendered a verdict of not guilty.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. John Swingler--Surety of the Peace. Harry Jones, Prosecutor. Case
                        dismissed and the costs divided equally between prosecutor and defendant.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Samuel Stumbaugh--Surety of the Peace. Henry Cordell, Prosecutor.
                        Complaint dismissed, defendant to pay costs.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Peter Lenhart--Assault on Frederick Lenhart. Verdict guilty. Before
                        sentence could be passed, the defendant quietly left the Court room and his
                        recognizance and that of his bail were forfeited.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. George Brown--Surety of the Peace. Charlotte Stoner, Prosecutrix.
                        Dismissed at the cost of the Prosecutrix.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Harry Jones--Fornication. Verdict guilty. Sentenced to pay $1 and
                        costs.</p>
                    <p>Same vs. Same--Fornication. Verdict guilty. Sentenced to pay a fine of $10
                        and costs.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Mary Ellen Swingler--Adultery committed with Harry Jones. The
                        testimony was that the parties were caught in the act by the husband and two
                        other persons, and the husband was with difficulty restrained from shooting
                        Jones. He did chastize his wife severely, and out of that fact grew the case
                        of the</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. John Swingler for Assault and Battery on his wife. To this charge
                        defendant pleaded guilty, and was fined $1 and the costs.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Rebecca Lane, Com. vs. Sarah Ramsey, Com. vs. Ida Carroll and Com.
                        vs. Charles Stevenson, were four cases of Surety of the Peace brought by Ann
                        Williams, and all were dismissed at her costs.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Mary Jane Lotsbaugh--Procuring goods by false pretences. About the
                        20th of June last this Defendant went to the Dry Goods Store of J.P. Keefer
                        &amp; Co., and to the Shoe Store of H.E. Spellman and procured goods to
                        the amount of about twelve dollars, by means of two orders purporting to
                        have been signed by the wife of Rev. I.N. Hays. There were two bills of
                        indictment to which she pleaded guilty.--She was sentenced to the County
                        jail for three months.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. John Kimple--Charge of forging the orders passed by Mary J.
                        Lotsbaugh to J.P. Keefer &amp; Co., and H.E. Spellman. Mary J. Lotsbaugh
                        was the Prosecutrix.--She swore that Kimple had written them, giving the
                        time and place. A letter was produced which she admitted she had written
                        which was very similar to the handwriting in the orders. From this fact, and
                        the additional fact conclusively established by the defence that the
                        Defendant <emph rend="italic">could not write at all</emph>, the District
                        Attorney abandoned the case and a verdict of not guilty was at once
                        rendered.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Samuel Stokes--Larceny. This was a charge of stealing a $20 U.S.
                        Government bill from a letter. It turned out that the bill was a counterfeit
                        and therefore valueless, and a verdict of not guilty was rendered.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Hugh Larman--Assault and Battery on George Dingler. Defendant
                        pleaded guilty, and was fined one dollar and costs.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Abraham Seldenstricker--Surety of the Peace. Horace Little
                        Prosecutor. Defendant sentenced to pay costs.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. David B. Little--Surety of the Peace. A. Seldenstricker, Prosecutor.
                        Case dismissed at the cost of the Prosecutor.</p>
                    <p>Com.vs. Mrs. David B. Little--Surety of the Peace. A. Seldenstricker,
                        Prosecutor. Case dismissed at the cost of the Prosecutor.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Horace Little--Surety of the Peace. A. Seldenstricker, Prosecutor.
                        Case dismissed at the cost of Prosecutor.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Emanuel Hess--Assault and Battery. Michael Fallon, Prosecutor.
                        Defendant pleaded guilty, and was fined $10 and costs.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Joseph Knepper--Fornication and Bastardy. Defendant pleaded guilty.
                        Sentenced to pay $15 lying in expenses and 75 cts. per week for seven years.</p>
                    <p>Com.vs. Robert Palmer--Surety of the Peace. Charles Weitzell, Prosecutor.
                        Defendant held in $100 to keep the peace and sentenced to pay costs.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. John Smith--Larceny. H. Forrest, Prosecutor. Sentenced to 3 months
                        imprisonment in County jail.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. George Coldsmith--Cutting timber, trees. Wm. McNeal, Prosecutor.
                        Verdict not guilty, but defendant to pay costs.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Wm. Davis--Rape. This defendant was charged with having violated the
                        person of a little girl named Mary Snider about the month of January, 1866.
                        The girl is a sister of the prisoner's wife and was at that time nine years
                        of age. The prisoner was living in Montgomery township and was out in the
                        woods cutting timber. The little girl went out on an errand having been sent
                        by the prisoner's wife, and when she arrived there was seized by this
                        ruffian and outraged. She went home and told her sister and in about three
                        weeks after, when taken to her mother's house, who lived in Maryland,
                        communicated the intelligence to her mother. The criminal was a perfect
                        desperado, and the whole family as well as the community, were in constant
                        terror on account of him. Davis left this State soon after this occurrence
                        and assisted in robbing the Express Office at Cherry Run, Maryland, for
                        which he was obliged to leave that State. He has been swinging backward and
                        forward between Virginia, Maryland and Pennsylvania ever since. Last fall,
                        his brother Henry attacked Dr. John L. Blair, of Mercersburg, on some public
                        road at night and robbed him. The Dr. got on the track of the scoundrel,
                        followed him to Juniata county, arrested him, and took him to Haggerstown
                        where he was tried for some grave offence and sentenced to six years
                        imprisonment in the Penitentiary. William Davis then swore vengeance on the
                        Doctor. Knowing his character well, the Doctor determined to arrest him also
                        and bring him to justice. He made the effort and succeeded. He took him to
                        Haggerstown also, but the Grand Jury ignored the bill which was sent in
                        against him. He was then brought here on a requisition for trial for the
                        offence of rape. The result was a verdict of guilty, and the Court sentenced
                        him to <emph rend="italic">twelve</emph> years imprisonment in the Eastern
                        Penitentiary.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Michael Miller--convicted at April Sessions of selling liquor on
                        Sunday. Sentenced to pay a fine of $10 and costs, and to imprisonment in
                        county jail for ten days.</p>
                    <p>Cases in which a <emph rend="italic">nolle prosequi</emph> was entered with
                        leave of Court.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. John King et. al. Riot; same vs. John Murphy, Malicious Mischief;
                        same vs. Albert McDonough two cases of Larceny; same vs. Wm Huber, Surety of
                        the Peace; same vs. Frank Elliott, selling at auction without license; Same
                        vs. Clayton Philips, Perjury; same vs. James Nuce Malicious Mischief; same
                        vs. Francis Helman, Fornication and Bastardy; same vs. C.B. McCune,
                        Fornication and Bastardy; same vs. Susanah Moaty, Assault and Battery; same
                        vs Catharine Baker, Surety of the Peace; same vs. Jackson Wolfkill,
                        Fornication and Bastardy; same vs. Samuel Hartman, Fornication and Bastardy;
                        same vs Ann Tarman, Surety of the Peace; same vs. David Unger; same vs D. B.
                        Hade; same vs. George Burger; same vs. Peter Dorty, Huckstering without
                        license.</p>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">Bills Ignored</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Joseph Arbegast; same vs. S.R. Boyd and Jacob Spoonhour; same vs
                        Crawford Kauffman and Henry Kauffman; same vs. Daniel Barnhart: same vs.
                        Daniel Row; same vs. Samuel Brooks; same vs. Eli Little; same vs. Rebecca
                        Lane et al.; same vs. Abram Saylor; same vs. Daniel Row et al.; same vs.
                        W.C. Corbett; same vs. M.S. Minters, Larceny; same vs. Daniel Baker,
                        Larceny; same vs. George Brook Assault and Battery; same vs. M.G. Minters,
                        Selling Liquors to Minors; same vs. Wm. Parker, Larceny; same vs Frank
                        Yeager, Larceny; same vs. John Anderson Assault and Battery, same vs. George
                        Loudensinger, Assault and Battery; same vs. Samuel Wingerd et al. Malicious
                        Mischief; same vs Hugh Armstrong, Assault and Battery; same vs. James
                        Laferty, Fornication and Bastardy; same vs. Emanuel Kuhn, Assault and
                        Battery: same vs. Alexander Lewis, Assault and Battery; same vs. Mary
                        Naugle, Larceny; same vs. H.A. Gisher, Assault and Battery; same vs. same.
                        Assault and Battery; same vs. John Embly et al., Assault and Battery; same
                        vs. Thos. Shearer et al., Riot and Assault and Battery; same vs. same, Riot
                        and Assault and Battery; same vs. Annie Weisgarber and Philip Florich,
                        Conspiracy; same vs. Emanuel Staver, Surety of the Peace; Same vs. Geo F.
                        Embly, Assault and Battery; same vs. Jerusha Williams, Assault same vs.
                        Daniel Ward, Surety of the Peace, Conrad Gubler Prosecutor; same vs. Conrad
                        Gubler, Surety of the Peace, Daniel Ward, Prosecutor. The last two were
                        cross actions, and as neither of the defendants appeared, the recognizances
                        of both and their bail were forfeited.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rohrer</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mackey</ln>
                        <fn>Harriet A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McMahon</ln>
                        <fn>Mordecai</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palmer</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swingler</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>Harry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cordell</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lenhart</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>Harry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swingler</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Ellen</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swingler</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lane</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ramsey</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carroll</ln>
                        <fn>Ida</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stevenson</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Williams</ln>
                        <fn>Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lotsbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spellman</ln>
                        <fn>H. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>I. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kimple</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stokes</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Larman</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dingler</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seldenstricker</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Little</ln>
                        <fn>Horace</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Little</ln>
                        <fn>David B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hess</ln>
                        <fn>Emanuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fallon</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Knepper</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weitzell</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Forrest</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coldsmith</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McNeal</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snider</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blair</ln>
                        <fn>John L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Murphy</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDonough</ln>
                        <fn>Albert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huber</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elliott</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Philips</ln>
                        <fn>Clayton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nuce</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Helman</ln>
                        <fn>Francis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCune</ln>
                        <fn>C. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moaty</ln>
                        <fn>Susanah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolfkill</ln>
                        <fn>Jackson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hartman</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tarman</ln>
                        <fn>Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Unger</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hade</ln>
                        <fn>D. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burger</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dorty</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Arbegast</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyd</ln>
                        <fn>S. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spoonhour</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kauffman</ln>
                        <fn>Crawford</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kauffman</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnhart</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Row</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brooks</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Little</ln>
                        <fn>Eli</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lane</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Saylor</ln>
                        <fn>Abram</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Row</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Corbett</ln>
                        <fn>W. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Minters</ln>
                        <fn>M. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brook</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parker</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yeager</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Londenslager</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingerd</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armstrong</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Laferty</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kuhn</ln>
                        <fn>Emanuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lewis</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Naugle</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>H. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Embly</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shearer</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weisgarber</ln>
                        <fn>Annie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Florich</ln>
                        <fn>Philip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Staver</ln>
                        <fn>Emanuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Embly</ln>
                        <fn>George F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Williams</ln>
                        <fn>Jerusha</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ward</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gubler</ln>
                        <fn>Conrad</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Covers the county court cases and verdicts. Most of the cases were criminal
                    cases, including larceny, rape, Surety of the Peace, etc.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keefer</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keefer</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keefer</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary Catharine Keefer, daughter of John and Mary Keefer, died in
                    Chambersburg on August 13th. He was 8 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ritter</ln>
                        <fn>Ira Tripner</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ritter</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ritter</ln>
                        <fn>Annie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Ira Tripner Ritter, son of John and Annie Ritter, died on August 6th. He
                    was ten months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davison</ln>
                        <fn>Annie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Annie Davison died of dyptheria on August 13th. She was 5 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.08.17.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
