<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1870/pa.fr.vs.1870.07.20">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>10/26/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1870-07-20">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day norm="">20</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.07.20.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.07.20.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Dawn of the Financial Millennium</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The great Radical statesmen in Congress who have for the last two or three
                        years been tinkering at a bill to fund the debt of the United States at a
                        reduced rate of interest, have succeeded in passing a funding bill at last.
                        They got it through on the 13th, a couple of days before the adjournment of
                        Congress. We can imagine the broad grin that overspread the faces of the
                        leading financiers of the country as they read the bill. It must have been
                        impossible for the greatest among them to repress a smile as he surveyed
                        this Congressional bantling.</p>
                    <p>The bill provides for the issue of two hundred million dollars of bonds,
                        bearing five per cent interest and redeemable in coin at the pleasure of the
                        government after ten years; for three hundred million bearing four and a
                        half per cent interest and redeemable in coin after fifteen years; and for
                        one thousand million bearing four per cent interest and redeemable in coin
                        after thirty years.--These bonds are to be sold at not less than par, for
                        coin, and the proceeds of such sale are to be applied to the redemption of
                        outstanding five-twenty bonds at their par value, or they may be exchanged
                        for such five-twenty bonds at par for par.</p>
                    <p>This bill is not worth the paper it was written on. The youngest Banker's
                        Clerk in the country could have drawn a better.--No capitalist will buy the
                        new bonds and no holder of five-twenties will exchange for them. Congress
                        might have made it obligatory upon the National Banks to take the new bonds
                        and substitute them for those now deposited in the Treasury Department as
                        security for their circulation, but there is no such requirement in the
                        bill. There is nothing to induce or compel the taking of the new bonds, and
                        they will not be taken. The Radical wiseacres who rule our destinies in
                        Congress seem to be incapable of achieving financial successes, except in
                        the matter of selling cadetships. They can make money for themselves, but
                        they can devise no practicable plan to make or save money for the people.
                        Things worked differently in Congress in the good old times when that body
                        was composed of Whigs and Democrats. The Radical party is a stupendous
                        failure. The honest men who have clung to it in hopes that it would do
                        something for the good of the country ought now to abandon it, seeing as
                        they must that all its measures are either impotent or mischievous.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Explains the details of a new funding bill recently passed by Congress.
                    Claims it will never work because nothing in the bill forces current holders of
                    bonds to exchange for the new ones. Ends by calling the Radicals a total failure
                    as a party.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Accessions to the Democracy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper celebrates rumors that Gov. Fenton, United States Senator from
                    New York, plans a defection to the Democratic Party. "It is a time when honest
                    white men of all parties should join to take the government of their country out
                    of the hands of malignant and incompetent Radicals and ignorant negroes."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.07.20.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Proceeding of the Democratic County Committee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Pursuant to notice, the Democratic County Committee met at the office of John
                        R. Orr. Esq., in the Borough of Chambersburg, on the 18th day of July, 1870.
                        On motion, the following resolutions were unanimously adopted, vis:</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That in accordance with the wishes of
                        the last Democratic County Convention, the representation of the several
                        districts in the County Convention shall be governed by the vote cast for
                        Asa Packer, the Democratic candidate for Governor at the last October
                        election, as follows: Each Election District shall have two (2) Delegates
                        and one (1) additional Delegate for each hundred (100) and each fraction
                        above fifty (50) Democratic votes cast at said election. Provided, That no
                        District shall have less than three (3) Delegates, which will give the
                        following result:</p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>Packer.</cell>
                            <cell>Delegates.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Antrim,</cell>
                            <cell>485</cell>
                            <cell>7</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Chambersb'g, N.W.,</cell>
                            <cell>253</cell>
                            <cell>5</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Chambersb'g, S.W.,</cell>
                            <cell>271</cell>
                            <cell>5</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Concord,</cell>
                            <cell>99</cell>
                            <cell>3</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Dry Run,</cell>
                            <cell>103</cell>
                            <cell>3</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Fayetteville,</cell>
                            <cell>210</cell>
                            <cell>4</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Greenvillage,</cell>
                            <cell>114</cell>
                            <cell>3</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Guilford,</cell>
                            <cell>210</cell>
                            <cell>4</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Hamilton,</cell>
                            <cell>156</cell>
                            <cell>4</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Letterkenny,</cell>
                            <cell>223</cell>
                            <cell>4</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Lurgan,</cell>
                            <cell>153</cell>
                            <cell>4</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Loudon,</cell>
                            <cell>119</cell>
                            <cell>3</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Metal,</cell>
                            <cell>96</cell>
                            <cell>3</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Montgomery,</cell>
                            <cell>172</cell>
                            <cell>4</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Orrstown,</cell>
                            <cell>140</cell>
                            <cell>3</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Peters,</cell>
                            <cell>69</cell>
                            <cell>3</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Quincy,</cell>
                            <cell>299</cell>
                            <cell>5</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Southampton,</cell>
                            <cell>73</cell>
                            <cell>3</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Sulphur Spring,</cell>
                            <cell>46</cell>
                            <cell>3</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>St. Thomas,</cell>
                            <cell>221</cell>
                            <cell>4</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Washington</cell>
                            <cell>297</cell>
                            <cell>5</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Warren</cell>
                            <cell>58</cell>
                            <cell>3</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Welsh Run,</cell>
                            <cell>139</cell>
                            <cell>3</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Total</cell>
                            <cell>4006</cell>
                            <cell>88</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That the Democratic voters of the
                        several election districts hold their election for Delegates to the County
                        Convention at the usual times and places, on Saturday, July 30, 1870, and
                        that the Convention assemble in the Court House, in Chambersburg, on the
                        following Thursday, August 4, at 11 o'clock A.M., to nominate a ticket.<lb/>
                        J.N. SHILLITO, Secretary and H.M. WHITE, Chairman.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces plans to hold elections for delegates to the Democratic County
                    Convention and the number of delegates allotted to each township, based on the
                    votes for Packer in the last election.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Committee Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn>John R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Democratic County Committee met in the office of John R. Orr on
                    Saturday. 18 members attended. The committee apportioned districts based on the
                    recommendations of last year's convention. This year's County Convention will
                    meet on August 4th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Balloon Ascension</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Light</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John A. Light, "champion balloonist," will take off from Chambersburg on
                    Saturday. "His last ascension here was one of the most beautiful spectacles
                    imaginable. Of course all the town and half the country will turn out to see
                    him. Harvest will be over, and the men who are gathering it, as well as the
                    'women folks' who are sweating over their increased labors inside the house,
                    will need a day's recreation."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Unpaid Taxes</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Persons who have not yet paid taxes can do so before August 10th. After
                    that, there will be a 5% penalty added.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Wilson Female College</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Workers are making rapid progress on the North wing of Wilson Female
                    College. The foundation has been laid, and the brickwork begun. It now seems
                    certain it will be ready to open in the fall. "It looks like 'a big thing' to
                    put up this building in the short time set apart for its construction, but those
                    who have the work on hand have 'got their blood up,' and it is an old and well
                    established proverb that 'blood will tell.'"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Sudden Death</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Steinke</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A German named Steinke was found in the street in a state of exhaustion. He
                    was carried to Boyd's Hotel where he passed away. He is a stranger in
                    Chambersburg and had just come form harvest work in Cumberland County. "His
                    appearance was not that of a dissipated man, and it is supposed that he died
                    from exhaustion occasioned by his labors in the harvest field and by the intense
                    heat of the weather."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dechert</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>W. W. Beardsline, Travelling Agent of the Singer Manufacturing Company,
                    advertises his presence in Chambersburg. He has appointed J. L. Dechert company
                    agent for Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Roxbury Bridge</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Proposals were received at the office of the County Commissioners, in this
                        borough, on Saturday last, for building a new Bridge over the Conodoguinet
                        at Roxbury. The Bridge is to be 110 feet long, of iron, with stone
                        abutments--the stone work to be finished by the 15th of September and the
                        iron work by the 1st of October. There was a wide range in the bids for the
                        stone work, as will be seen by the following:</p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>S. Filckinger</cell>
                            <cell>bid, per perch,</cell>
                            <cell>$5.40</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>W. Forbes</cell>
                            <cell>bid, per perch,</cell>
                            <cell>4.79</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Henry Kurts</cell>
                            <cell>bid, per perch,</cell>
                            <cell>4.50</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Grousy and Quincy</cell>
                            <cell>bid, per perch,</cell>
                            <cell>4.49 1/2</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>F.M. Shoemaker,</cell>
                            <cell>bid, per perch,</cell>
                            <cell>3.19</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Henry Shearer</cell>
                            <cell>" " "</cell>
                            <cell>2.65</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>John Agle</cell>
                            <cell>bid, per perch,</cell>
                            <cell>2.57 1/2</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <p>There was likewise considerable difference in the bidding for the iron work.
                        The following were the bids received:</p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>T.B. Wood and Co., per foot,</cell>
                            <cell>$19.50</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Gilbert and Co., per foot,</cell>
                            <cell>19.40</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>King and Son, Cleveland, Ohio, per ft.,</cell>
                            <cell>16.00</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <p>The contract for the stone work was awarded to John Agle--that for the iron
                        work to Gilbert &amp; Co. The contractor for the stone work is to remove
                        the old Bridge. The bid of King &amp; Son for the iron work, if
                        accepted, would have saved the county $374. We have not heard the reason for
                        its rejection.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces the building of a new bridge at Roxbury and the bids placed by
                    different companies for the stone and iron work.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Camp Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The United Brethren will hold a camp meeting in Wilson's woods, two miles
                    south of Orrstown, on August 18th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Street Preaching</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Rev. J.G. Schaff, whose peculiar doctrines have excited some interest in this
                        community, preached according to previous announcement in the Diamond,
                        nearly in front of the <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> office, on Sunday
                        evening about five o'clock. At the appointed hour the Reverend gentleman
                        mounted a chair and opened the exercises by singing a hymn. A small crowd
                        soon collected under the shadow of the buildings on the north-west side of
                        the Diamond and disposed themselves as comfortably as the limited
                        accommodations would permit.--The first comers were rewarded with seats on
                        the curbstones, whilst the more tardy drank their share of the discourse
                        standing. Several of the occupants of front seats on the curbstones
                        composedly smoked segars, and perhaps inwardly congratulated themselves that
                        if the doctrines of the speaker were correct "Old Nick" would get no chance
                        to "make them smoke" in the world to come. The weather was rather favorable
                        to the enforcement of the speaker's views. With the mercury at 100, and the
                        perspiration streaming out of every pore, most men would be willing to be
                        convinced, if they could, that they would never be subjected to a great
                        degree of heat.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Schaff is a very good speaker, with a full, clear voice and an earnest
                        manner; but with all that we think he might preach a lifetime without
                        converting any great number of people to his way of thinking.</p>
                    <p>We are not quite sure that we understand his doctrine exactly. The popular
                        impression is that he "does not believe in hell,"--does not believe that the
                        wicked will be resurrected after death and cast into everlasting fire. But
                        on Sunday evening he said, "That the wicked will be cast into everlasting
                        fire I do not doubt, but (he inquired) what will be the effect of that
                        fire?" He answered this inquiry by saying that fire makes a speedy end of
                        all that it acts upon. We understood him to say that "when the son of man
                        shall come in his glory, the <emph rend="italic">living</emph> wicked will
                        be cast into fire which will consume them," that is to say, they will be
                        utterly burnt up, soul and body, and there will be nothing more of them.
                        What will become of the wicked dead? Will they escape the fire altogether?
                        If the speaker said anything on this point, we failed to catch it. If only
                        the "living wicked" are to be cast into fire at the last day, the wicked who
                        die before that time possess an advantage we never before heard accorded to
                        them.</p>
                    <p>He took ground against the immortality of the soul and said it was not a
                        doctrine of the Bible and had only been made an article of faith by a
                        Catholic Council held under Pope Leo about three hundred years ago. The
                        Bible, he said, "affirms, that the soul that sinneth shall <emph
                            rend="italic">die:</emph> and such a phrase as immortal soul, or
                        deathless spirit, though often found in hymns, prayers and sermons, never
                        once occurs in the Bible." In conclusion he said the gospel is simply an
                        offer of life to a dying world. Those who accept it are given life evermore
                        in God's Kingdom--in other words, their souls are made immortal by their
                        acceptance--whilst those who reject it go down to irretrievable death, and
                        their souls perish with their bodies.</p>
                    <p>We have stated the Reverend gentleman's views as we understood him to express
                        them. Of course we leave our readers to think of them what they please.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schaff</ln>
                        <fn>J. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports on Rev. Schaff's recent preaching in town on his unorthodox
                    doctrines concerning hell, the afterlife, and souls. Editor doesn't think Schaff
                    will gain many converts to his views.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Grove Meetings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bishop</ln>
                        <fn>J. Philip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schaff</ln>
                        <fn>J. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snively</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. Philip Bishop and J. G. Schaff will hold meetings "for worship and for
                    preaching Jesus and the Resurrection" in the grove of Samuel Snively near
                    Greencastle on August 7th. The public is invited.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wraverling</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Elizabeth Wraverling died at Fannettsburg on July 1st. She was 82
                    years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGinley</ln>
                        <fn>Eliza Bell</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Eliza Bell McGinley, died in Waynesboro on July 6th. She was 65 years
                    old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.07.20.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
