<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1870/pa.fr.vs.1870.09.07">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>10/31/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1870-09-07">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day norm="">7</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.09.07.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.09.07.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Howl Against Free Trade from Free Traders</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph> seeks to hold the Pennsylvania
                        Democracy responsible for some of the vagaries of the Southern people on the
                        negro suffrage question. Will it apply the same rule to the Pennsylvania
                        Radicals on the tariff question? It keeps writing vigorously in favor of a
                        protective tariff, and yet its Editor knows that the Radicals of the great
                        West are all arrayed in deadly hostility to the doctrines which he
                        advocates. A large majority of the present Congress are Radicals and yet the
                        free-traders nearly had a majority. Why does he attack Democrats, therefore,
                        on account of free-trade notions? Why does he not apply his whip to the
                        backs of his own political friends?--Even General Walbridge, in nominating
                        Grant for another term, intimates that there must only be a temporary
                        postponement of the tariff questions, and that it will soon be expedient and
                        practicable to strike for free trade.</p>
                    <p>And so demoralizing, on this subject, means the atmosphere at Washington that
                            <emph rend="italic">John Cessna voted at the last session to reduce the
                            duty on pig iron from nine to seven dollars per ton</emph>. The fact is
                        that some of the strongest free traders are in the ranks of the Radical
                        party, and that ere long they will demand the fullest recognition of their
                        principles in the administration of the government. These long professions
                        on the tariff issue are only intended to cheat the people, just as the
                        solemn promises made by the Radical leaders that the people should have an
                        opportunity to vote on the negro suffrage issue were only intended to
                        deceive.</p>
                    <p>Considering the ugly complications in which the Radical party is involved on
                        the tariff question, and the fact that they have had control of the
                        government for ten years and have not <emph rend="italic">satisfied
                            themselves</emph> in all that time in the way of protection, it
                        certainly requires a considerable amount of brass for Radical journals to
                        keep hammering away at Democratic candidates for anticipated action. The
                        sins of omission and commission in regard to this very subject, chargeable
                        upon Radical members of Congress, are allowed to pass by unnoticed, whilst
                        the people are asked to condemn Democratic candidates in advance for what
                        Radicals apprehend they may do. But especially should the organ of John
                        Cessna keep quiet <emph rend="italic">after that vote to reduce the duty on
                            pig iron from nine to sever dollars per ton</emph>.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Asks how the Radical press can condemn Democrats on the tariff issue when
                    so many Republicans are in favor of free trade. Gives the example of Cessna's
                    votes in Congress as proof.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>What has Cessna Done for the Border Claimants?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph>, some weeks ago, promised us a
                        little light on this subject, but we have watched and waited in vain. We
                        have reviewed the honorable member's record, and, if there was any motion
                        made, or resolution read by him in Congress on this subject, it has escaped
                        our notice altogether. We are boiling over with anxiety to do him justice
                        and, if the <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph> can give us a line
                        written, or a word spoken, by Cessna in Congress, which squints at an effort
                        on his part to procure payment for the losses of our people, we will be glad
                        to lay it before our readers. It is asserted by Radical journals that he is
                        one of the most influential members of Congress. Indeed, so popular is he
                        alleged to be, that one of the arguments used for procuring votes for him is
                        that he will be elected Speaker of the next Congress. There is no doubt but
                        that Cessna dreams of attaining to that position. Some few of his political
                        friends are, doubtless, sanguine enough to believe that he may be successful
                        in carrying off this prize. Why is it then, we ask, that a man so extremely
                        popular, so wonderfully useful and about to be so signally honored, has
                        never opened his mouth in Congress in behalf of his constituents upon whom
                        the horrors of war fell with such terrible force? Why is it that he was
                        always occupied about other people's business, tinkering at an infamous
                        reconstruction policy, or playing sleight-of-hand tricks in contested
                        election cases? A man of such marvelous influence and prodigious popularity
                        might at least have had the courage, even "solitary and alone," to "put this
                        ball in motion." As this matter is getting to be "serious," we would like
                        the <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph> to "give it all the consideration
                        it merits."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Criticizes Cessna for not doing more to drum up support for border claims
                    payments. Asks why if he's so popular in Congress, he did not do anything to
                    help his own constituents on this issue.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.09.07.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that scarlet fever is lingering in Chambersburg. The
                    disease has caused several deaths.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ludwig</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Martin Ludwig took possession of the Washabaugh Brewery on September 1st.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shoemaker</ln>
                        <fn>P. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>P. M. Shoemaker has resumed his career as a teacher by taking charge of
                    Strasburg High School.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Appointments</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schaff</ln>
                        <fn>J. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bishop</ln>
                        <fn>J. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Revs. J. G. Schaff and J. P. Bishop will preach at Pinefield School
                    House on September 10th and at Foreman's Mill on September 11th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Festival at St. Thomas</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The German Reformed Festival held in St. Thomas was a complete success. The
                    event raised $153.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Death of Mr. Richards</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richards</ln>
                        <fn>T. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>T. M. Richards died in Shippensburg on Wednesday after a brief illness. He
                    used to be a school teacher and was widely known as a "christian gentleman." He
                    has recently acted as a book sale agent.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Death of Judge Orr</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Hon. John Orr died in Orrstown on Sunday. He was 75 years old. He had
                    suffered from a "protracted illness." "Mr. Orr was one of the best citizens of
                    our county. He was a man of unblemished integrity and possessed of a remarkably
                    sound judgement. His social qualities won the friendship of all with whom he
                    came in contact. In 1866 he was elected by the Democracy to the position of
                    Associate Judge. He served his term of office to the satisfaction of everybody
                    and retired from the bench universally esteemed. His son, Rev. Thomas X. Orr, is
                    pastor of a Philadelphia Church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Directory of Strasburg</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Justices of the Peace, Daniel Gelwix and W.W. Briton; Constable, Joseph
                        Gabler; County Superintendent, Samuel Gelwix; Physicians, W.A. Huster and
                        James M. Gelwix; Merchants, Philip Karper and Lehman &amp; Zullinger;
                        Tanners, M.D. Miller and Wm. McClellans; Cabinet Makers, George Foreman and
                        Joseph Gabler; Blacksmiths, Daniel Gelwix, and Joseph Bowan; Carpenter,
                        Robert Worthington; Tailors, Geo. Heller and John Newton; Weavers, Adam
                        Carbaugh and Daniel Shouman; Wagonmaker, Samuel Frost; Fence-makers, Jacob
                        Martin, Geo. Byers and Philip Byers; Chair-makers, J. &amp; M. Eyer;
                        Wheelwright, Rudolph Eyer; Butcher, W. W. Britton; Masons, Joseph Gipe, Levi
                        Myers and Samuel Breneman; Tinner, D. E. Stavick; Saddler, Samuel Phreaner;
                        Confectioner, Geo. Heller; Veterinary Surgeon, Solomon Neff; Shoe-makers,
                        J.V.B. Leedy, and Geo. Flora; Minister, A.H. Shirts; Public House, Issac
                        Quigley.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gelwix</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Britton</ln>
                        <fn>W. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gabler</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gelwix</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunter</ln>
                        <fn>W. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gelwix</ln>
                        <fn>James M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Karper</ln>
                        <fn>Philip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lehman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zollinger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>M. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClellans</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foreman</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gabler</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowen</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Worthington</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heller</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newton</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Adam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shonman</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Freet</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Byers</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Byers</ln>
                        <fn>Philip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyer</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyer</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyer</ln>
                        <fn>Rudolph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Britton</ln>
                        <fn>W. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gipe</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Levi</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Breneman</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stavick</ln>
                        <fn>D. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phresner</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heller</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Naff</ln>
                        <fn>Solomon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Leedy</ln>
                        <fn>J. V. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flora</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shirts</ln>
                        <fn>A. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Quigley</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lists the names and professions of people in Strasburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Menagerie</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Van Amburgh and Company's Menagerie exhibited in Chambersburg on Wednesday.
                    The paper called it "the finest collection of animals that we have ever seen."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Base Ball</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCleary</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Haefner</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kreichbaum</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burnett</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henninger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flack</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brisisch</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hutton</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mateer</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hendricks</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stewart</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gish</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elsrode</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolf</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Criswell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Adams</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gribbie</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Printer's Nine of Chambersburg and the Picked Nine of Shippensburg
                    played a game of baseball in Chambersburg. The Printer defeated the
                    recently-established Shippensburg club.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wood</ln>
                        <fn>George E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spangler</ln>
                        <fn>Katie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>P. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George E. Wood and Miss Katie Spangler, both of Chambersburg, were married
                    in the first Reformed Church in Chambersburg on September 1st by the Rev. P. S.
                    Davis.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Potts</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robison</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Creigh</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George W. Potts and Miss Margaret Robison, both of Franklin, were married
                    on August 30th by the Rev. Thomas Creigh.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sellers</ln>
                        <fn>Calvin G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Unger</ln>
                        <fn>Susan E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Callendar</ln>
                        <fn>S. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Calvin G. Sellers and Miss Susan E. Unger, both of Franklin, were married
                    on June 4th by the Rev. S. N. Callendar.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strite</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mann</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitmore</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lesher</ln>
                        <fn>H. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John A. Strite of Leitersburg and Miss Catharine Mann of Antrim were
                    married near Greencastle at the residence of Jacob Whitmore on August 25th by H.
                    C. Lesher.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKee</ln>
                        <fn>David R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swanger</ln>
                        <fn>Ann E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sherts</ln>
                        <fn>A. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>David R. McKee and Miss Ann E. Swanger, both of Letterkenny, Franklin
                    County, were married at the Lutheran Parsonage on August 30th by the Rev. A. H.
                    Sherts.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harry</ln>
                        <fn>Albert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harry</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Albert Harry, son of Jacob K. Harry, died in Greencastle on September 17th.
                    He was 29 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Meade</ln>
                        <fn>Josiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Josiah Meade died in Chambersburg on August 20th. He was 67 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craig</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Craig of Welsh Run died on August 26th. He was 73 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Dowell</ln>
                        <fn>James Dunlap</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Dowell</ln>
                        <fn>A. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James Dunlap M'Dowell, son of A. B. M'Dowell of Peters, died on August
                    30th. He was 9 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swank</ln>
                        <fn>Effie Louisa</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swank</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swank</ln>
                        <fn>Anna M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Effie Louisa Swank, daughter of Jacob and Anna M. Swank, died in
                    Chambersburg on September 4th. She was 8 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.09.07.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
