<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1870/pa.fr.vs.1870.03.09">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>10/19/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1870-03-09">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day norm="">9</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.03.09.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.03.09.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Border Claims</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>From the information in our possession, we believe there is a majority, a
                        very decided majority, in each branch of the Legislature in favor of paying
                        the border claims. The present Legislature has a larger number of men of
                        intelligence, honesty, and independence, than any one that has assembled for
                        many years. Many of them are young men who have been for the first time
                        entrusted with political power. But they are young men of mark in their
                        respective districts. They have gone to Harrisburg to do what they believe
                        to be right. When, therefore, a claim, so manifestly just as that of the
                        people of the border, is presented to their consideration, they can not help
                        but acknowledge its justice and, believing it to be right, can not fail to
                        give it their support. Many of them come from districts where the armed
                        legions of the enemy never trod. They were not forced to witness the
                        footprints of blood which the invader left behind him. And now, when they
                        listen to the recital, or read the story of the sufferings of our people,
                        all the sympathies of their hearts must go out towards us, and
                        notwithstanding the unprincipled attacks of enemies who are influenced by
                        sordid motives, their sense of justice, and sympathy for our condition, and
                        lofty independence constrain them to come cheerfully to our help.</p>
                    <p>There are others of more mature years and enlarged experience who have been,
                        for a long time, our steadfast friends. Some of these men were enrolled in
                        the ranks of the Union army and served the nation faithfully in the hour of
                        her need. They were willing to lay down their lives as so many sacrifices
                        upon the altar of patriotism. They know what war is, not from hearsay, not
                        from the pen of history, but from their own actual observation. And with the
                        recollection of events that made the blood curdle in their veins fresh in
                        their memory, they can not fail to realize how deeply the people of the
                        border suffered at the hands of an insolent foe. They are ready to aid us
                        with their votes, trusting to time and sober reflection to justify their
                        action. To such men, the gross misrepresentations and wilful and deliberate
                        falsehoods that have been put afloat, are but as the idle wind. They are not
                        to be moved by the tongue of calumny, or the pen of the hired libeler. They
                        well know that the majority of their constituents are men of philanthropic
                        natures, and that when the real facts are made known to them, they will
                        approve their conduct.</p>
                    <p>In those classes of men we put our trust. We care nothing for the support of
                        a man who trembles at the faintest whisper of disapprobation that comes from
                        the lips of some hard-hearted miser who prizes his money bags above his own
                        soul. The poor, weak-kneed representative who is afraid to take the
                        responsibility of doing right, through fear that some lynx-eyed sharper may
                        denounce him for the act, deserves our pity more than we deserve his aid. We
                        want the votes of men who know their duty, and knowing, dare to perform it.
                        Such men are always appreciated. It is the man who is bold in the
                        performance of his duty that shapes and gives tone to the sentiment of his
                        community. Men come to rely upon his judgment. Instead of being led, he
                        becomes a leader. He needs not to proffer his counsel. It is sought for
                        continually and consistently. Chance has nothing to do with his success. He
                        carves out his own fortune. Greatness is not thrust upon him. He achieves it
                        because he deserves it. Such men there are who take a lively interest in the
                        success of the movement to pay those who have been impoverished by the war.
                        And when these claims shall have been liquidated, as we do not doubt they
                        will be at some day not far distant, they will be honored as those who have
                        preserved the escutcheon of our State pride from the dishonor with which it
                        is now sought to tarnish it by refusing to pay the just obligations of the
                        State. That distinguished statesman and lawyer, Hon. J. S. Black, has well
                        said that he can see no reason why payment of these claims should be
                        refused, unless upon the principle announced by Richard Brinsley Sheridan,
                        that "<emph rend="italic">he did not intend to fritter away his money in
                            paying his debts.</emph>"</p>
                    <p>And if this bill should pass both branches of the Legislature, will it meet
                        with opposition in the Executive Chamber? We hope, we believe not. Governor
                        Geary has been a soldier. He served in the war with Mexico. He moved in the
                        midst of the horrors of "bleeding Kansas." He unsheathed his sword in the
                        gigantic conflict which ended the suppression of the late rebellion. He was
                        an eye witness of the desolation which marked the path of large armies. He
                        saw the horrors of war in all their startling and painful reality. He knows
                        the destruction of property which was occasioned even by the hurried tramp
                        of raiding parties. And the far greater devastation which was caused by the
                        march of a large invading army he was perfectly familiar with. His was a
                        soldier's life and a soldier's experience. All the manufactured stories of
                        the ridiculous insignificance of the losses of the people of the border
                        counties do not find a believer in him. Besides, he appointed some of the
                        Commissioners who adjudicated these claims. They were men in whom he had
                        confidence, and he knows that they stand high in the estimation of their
                        fellow-citizens. They have filed at Harrisburg the result of their best
                        judgment as to the value of the property destroyed and taken, and he, no
                        doubt, is satisfied that they discharged their duty in a conscientious
                        manner.</p>
                    <p>And again, Governor Geary has visited our people. He has seen the portion of
                        our town that was swept by the devouring flames. He has been informed of the
                        terrible anxiety of mind, the horrible suspense, and the far more horrid
                        realities to which our citizens were subjected. And he has expressed the
                        utmost sympathy for those who were plundered by the enemy and those whose
                        homes were fired by rebel torches. In a speech made at Mercersburg in the
                        fall of 1868, he expressed, unreservedly, his opinion that these claims
                        ought to be paid. Surely there can be no difficulty in the mind of the
                        Governor as to the expediency and justice of affording the relief now prayed
                        for. Let but the Legislature pass the bill that will be presented to it, and
                        the Governor will have an opportunity to do a nobler act of justice and
                        humanity than has ever fallen to the lot of any Chief Magistrate of
                        Pennsylvania. And he certainly will not fail to seize it. We, of course,
                        cannot write from personal knowledge, but we base our judgement on his great
                        experience, his full information of the real facts of the case, his never
                        suppressed, but openly expressed sympathy for our people, and his
                        determination to have the State discharge its just obligations, so that it
                        may not be said that his administration ever cast disgrace upon the fair
                        name and fame of our grand old Commonwealth.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Senses victory in the border claims fight and urges all legislators
                    favorable to the measure to back down in the face of possible criticism. Also
                    has commendable comments for Governor Geary, hoping to secure his support for
                    the measure as well. Stresses his war record and knowledge of what war can do to
                    a community.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Still More Reconstruction. The States to be Attacked.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Not satisfied with the monstrous usurpation of power that Congress has
                        already resorted to in the reconstruction of the rebel States, the infamous
                        Ben Butler is now preparing a bill for the reconstruction of Tennessee. The
                        papers inform us that "a Tennessee delegation of republicans had a meeting
                        at Butler's house, where they compared notes, and Maynard presented the
                        draft of a bill which he had prepared. Butler said he was thoroughly
                        satisfied of the necessity of reconstructing Tennessee, and had no doubt of
                        the power of Congress over the subject. He said he would take Mr. Maynard's
                        bill and merge it into his own."</p>
                    <p>Where is this thing to stop? Are the people to sit quiet and allow the rights
                        of States to be violated, and State Governments to be overthrown, by such
                        fanatical scoundrels as the plunderer of New Orleans? Tennessee went
                        regularly through the reconstruction mill. She has her representatives and
                        Senators in Congress. She is a sovereign State. Upon what plea is she to be
                        thrown back under the rule of a military despot? If the Committee on
                        Reconstruction, and Congress under their lead, can undertake to do this,
                        they may do the same thing with any State of the Union. There will be no
                        limit to their power, and, of course, no limit to its exercise.</p>
                    <p>The reason for this proposed conduct is the fact that Tennessee defeated the
                        Radical Stokes for Governor and elected the Conservative Senter. It grieves
                        Butler that he did not so hamper her people and restrict them to such a
                        degree, as that she could not be entitled to representation unless she would
                        elect Radicals to all the offices. He now intends to supply this omission.
                        The State is to be thrown back to the <emph rend="italic">protection</emph>
                        of the military power, and then things are to be done according to the
                        notions of the epaulleted gentlemen who will be selected to do the dirty
                        work. And, when Brownlow "shuffles off this mortal coil," as he is expected
                        to do very soon, one of these booted and spurred individuals will be
                        elected, as Ames was in Mississippi, to fill his place. Of course this will
                        be a spontaneous tribute of the people to the worth of the fellow who has
                        lorded it over them with the bayonet. What a farce this whole business is in
                        a republic! Why not turn Congress into a Parliament, and the President into
                        a King?</p>
                    <p>There is a bill now before the House of Representatives which proposes to
                        reconstruct Georgia. The Radical leaders are well assured that Georgia will
                        go Democratic. Hence Bulter's proposition is to continue Governor Bullock in
                        office for an indefinite period. The villainy of this scheme was well
                        exposed in a speech by Mr. Farnsworth on Saturday, from which we clip the
                        following extract.</p>
                    <p>There is an easier way of maintaining our ascendency in the nation than by
                        holding elections--that way, by act of Congress. That is the way to do it.
                        The gentleman from Massachusetts (Mr. Butler) had yesterday raised the cry
                        of murder in the House. Whenever he wanted to pass one of these
                        reconstruction bills he got up in the House, and, with flaming nostrils and
                        raised hands, bawled out, "Murder! murder!!" and by a hue and cry of that
                        sort got his bill passed.</p>
                    <p>Whenever one of these bills was to be passed the Washington <emph
                            rend="italic">Chronicle</emph> published accounts of so great outrages
                        that immediately the Reconstruction Committee was called together and a bill
                        reported to the House. He remembered that last year a gentleman, a
                            <sic>verry</sic> clever fellow, but whose politics were always those of
                        the reigning dynasty, who had sold arms to the people of Georgia in the
                        winter of 1860-61 with which to shoot down Union soldiers, went down to
                        Georgia, and with the assistance of Governor Bullock, manipulated the
                        Legislature, and got a commission appointed to examine his claim for payment
                        for these arms. The commission was manipulated so as to make a favorable
                        report, but the Legislature refused to adopt or to pay the claim. There upon
                        that man came on to Washington full of sorrow, his heart wrung to its very
                        depths, with tears in his eyes over the terrible persecutions of the negroes
                        and loyal men of Georgia. That man was in favor of the reconstruction of
                        Georgia at once. What was his touchstone? It was that he could get his
                        $25,000 and interest for the arms that he had sold in the State of Georgia.</p>
                    <p>He (Mr. Farnsworth) felt that the passage of this bill, and the prolonging of
                        the terms of office of the men who now controlled the State of Georgia,
                        authorizing Governor Bullock to commence <emph rend="italic">de novo</emph>,
                        and putting the power of the State into his hands, would be a most infernal
                        outrage on the taxpayers of the State. He believed that this bill was in the
                        interest of a few people, who desired to perpetuate their reign so that they
                        might put money in their purses.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports with outrage General Butler's plans to institute reconstruction
                    again in Tennessee and Georgia. Claims he is doing it solely for political
                    reasons, since those two states went Democratic recently. Also charges the
                    architects of the scheme with fraud and corruption, gives an example of an arms
                    dealer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Massacre of the Indians</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper criticizes the Grant administration for a massacre of western
                    Native Americans. The editors argue that Grant has violated his campaign slogan
                    "let us have peace" with his actions toward both the South and the western
                    Indian tribes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.03.09.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Rev. S. J. Milligan of Academia, Pa., will preach in the Falling Spring
                    Presbyterian Church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>"Peculiar People"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gough</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John B. Gough will lecture on "Peculiar People" at Repository Hall on March
                    31st. Tickets are 75 cents.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Sudden Death</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Linn</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Linn</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel Linn, son of John Linn, died suddenly on Tuesday evening. He had
                    been to school all day and was 15 years old. John Linn recently suffered losses
                    in a fire at his home and is now doubly afflicted. The community extends its
                    sympathy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Town Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Culloh</ln>
                        <fn>A. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyle</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McNulty</ln>
                        <fn>William C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elliot</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bishop</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gardon</ln>
                        <fn>C. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burkhart</ln>
                        <fn>Christian</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duncan</ln>
                        <fn>Auge</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greenawalt</ln>
                        <fn>S. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Etter</ln>
                        <fn>E. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jeffries</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gelwicks</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heafner</ln>
                        <fn>P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Border Claimants will meet at the Court House tomorrow.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Concert</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A concert for the benefit of the poor was held in Repository Hall on Monday
                    night. The Chambersburg Cornet Band "entertained the visitors with excellent
                    music." The event raised $125.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Robbery and Attempted Incendiarism</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>Frank H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Starliper</ln>
                        <fn>James P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Another incident involving robbery and attempted incendiarism occurred in
                    Mercersburg. The paper attributes the crime to "the villains who infest that
                    portion of our County." Thieves entered Frank H. Johnson's gunsmith shop, broke
                    into a chest, took $21 in money, and stole a number of valuable tools. Johnson
                    estimates his loss at $100. They then entered James P. Starliper's saddler shop
                    and set fire to it using powder from the gun shop. It is not known if they stole
                    anything from the saddler shop. The fire alarm sounded between 10 and 11 and the
                    flames were extinguished after destroying two sets of harness and most of
                    Starliper's tools.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Franklin Co. Horticultural Society</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>P. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Franklin County Horticultural Society met and fixed the date of their
                    spring exhibition for the 10th and 11th of June. The Rev. P. S. Davis and Mr.
                    Reed spoke on flower cultivation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Atwell</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jarrett</ln>
                        <fn>Mattie E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnes</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel M. Atwell and Miss Mattie E. Jarrett, both of Chambersburg, were
                    married at the Methodist Parsonage on March 1st by the Rev. S. Barnes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wood</ln>
                        <fn>James T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McFerrin</ln>
                        <fn>Mandie A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnes</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James T. Wood and Miss Mandie A. McFerrin, both of Chambersburg, were
                    married at the Methodist Parsonage by the Rev. S. Barnes on January 20th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reynolds</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dovenberger</ln>
                        <fn>Mary S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Felker</ln>
                        <fn>A. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Reynolds and Miss Mary S. Dovenberger, both of Maryland, were
                    married at the Washington House in Chambersburg on March 1st by the Rev. A. C.
                    Felker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pence</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Winnfield</ln>
                        <fn>Kate C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kreps</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Penepacker</ln>
                        <fn>G. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>G. W. Pence and Miss Kate C. Winnfield, both of Greencastle, were married
                    at the residence of William Kreps on February 27th by the Rev. G. D. Penepacker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Liner</ln>
                        <fn>Jeremiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hartman</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnhart</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jeremiah Liner and Miss Susan Hartman, both of Middleburg, were married on
                    February 22nd by David Barnhart, the Justice of the Peace.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deal</ln>
                        <fn>Louisa</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deal</ln>
                        <fn>J. Wesley</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Louisa Deal, wife of J. Wesley Deal, died in Chambersburg on February
                    28th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pool</ln>
                        <fn>Rosanna</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pool</ln>
                        <fn>Levi</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Rosanna Pool, wife of Levi Pool, died near Greencastle on February
                    23rd. She was 37 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Frantz</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Frantz died near Greencastle on February 24th. He was 79 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Read</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Read died in Middleburg on February 27th. He was 57 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Springer</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Catharine Springer died near Waynesboro on March 1st.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.03.09.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
