<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1870/pa.fr.vs.1870.07.06">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>10/25/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1870-07-06">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day norm="">6</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.07.06.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.07.06.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Income Tax</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Taking advantage of a slim attendance in the Senate, on Friday night last
                        Senator Wilson procured a reconsideration of the vote by which the sections
                        of the tax-tariff bill relating to the Income Tax were stricken out. The
                        Senate then by a vote of 27 to 21 agreed to continue this tax, against which
                        the whole country has loudly protested, until 1872. This action has excited
                        a storm of indignation. The press of the country had just congratulated the
                        people on the abolition of this tax by the action of the Senate of the 24th
                        ult. Radicals and Democrats alike shouted their approvals. It is difficult
                        to understand how, at the moment when the people were saying "well done,"
                        grave Senators should deliberately resolve to run counter to the people's
                        wishes and thus draw down their denunciations. Mr. Conkling, a most
                        determined opponent of this tax, was absent, confined to his room by
                        sickness. Telegraphic dispatches state that he intended to bring the matter
                        up in the Senate on Monday again with the confident expectation that the
                        Senate, when full, will again wipe out this unpopular tax. Senator Cameron
                        seems to have been absent also.</p>
                    <p>The tax is revived at the rate of 2 1/2 per cent on all incomes exceeding two
                        thousand dollars. The Philadelphia <emph rend="italic">Morning Post</emph>
                        (Radical) says of this fraud:--"This is one of the most deliberate acts of
                        injustice ever practiced by a legislative body, and those Senators who were
                        instrumental in thus outraging a unanimous public sentiment must prepare
                        themselves for the responsibility imposed by their action. The people will
                        receive this action of the Senate with surprise and indignation, the more
                        profound, because they had scarcely ceased rejoicing at the prospect of the
                        discontinuance of this oppressive system. Had all the Senators who voted to
                        strike it out been in their seats last night, it could not have been again
                        inserted. If the House agrees with the Senate the country will look with
                        hope to the President."</p>
                    <p>But there is no hope to be entertained in that quarter; the President has put
                        himself on the record in favor of this measure. In his annual message of
                        December last, he said:--"I also suggest the renewal of the tax on incomes
                        but at a reduced rate--say of three per cent and this tax to expire in three
                        years."</p>
                    <p>He <emph rend="italic">suggests</emph> it, and of course when Congress
                        imposes the tax, he will approve it.</p>
                    <p>The Philadelphia <emph rend="italic">Inquirer</emph> (Radical), which has
                        dealt some very damaging blows at this tax, thus gives vent to its views in
                        its issue of Monday:--"The revival of the Income Tax in the Senate on Friday
                        was in admirable keeping with the discreditable jugglery which has been part
                        and parcel of this unpopular levy ever since Messrs. Boutwell and Delano
                        have had it in charge. Its history is that of a bad law, passed under the
                        protest of its authors, but which they were obliged to pass owing to the
                        extreme exigencies of one of the costliest wars which a country ever bore.
                        In that view it was allowable; but when the war was over, and the expenses
                        of the Government were no longer a million a day, the tax was no longer
                        allowable and Congress so considering, on the second of June, 1867, solemnly
                        decreed that it should last until the year 1870, "<emph rend="italic">and
                            now longer</emph>."</p>
                    <p>That compact has now been broken, and Congress stands toward the Nation as a
                        violator of the pledged faith. Unpopular and <unclear>odious</unclear> as it
                        was in itself, the unjust, absurd and arbitrary decisions of Commissioner
                        Delano, from which there was no appeal permissible, made the law taxing
                        incomes <unclear>unendurable</unclear>, and consequently from one end of the
                        country to the other Congress has been petitioned and solicited to keep its
                        faith with the people, and let the law expire under the limitation placed
                        upon it."</p>
                    <p>The <emph rend="italic">Age</emph> (Democratic) says:--"The infamous Income
                        Tax has been endorsed by the Senate with a change from five to two and a
                        half per cent. This is the manner in which the Radicals respond to the
                        petition of the people for redress. The masses ask for a fish, the Radicals
                        give them a stone."</p>
                    <p>We might quote from other leading papers of both parties to the same effect.
                        And yet, in spite of almost universal opposition to the continuance of this
                        tax on the part of the people, the Senate persists in forcing it upon the
                        Country. When will Senators learn wisdom? The remedy for all this defiance
                        of the will of the people is to defeat the Radicals at the polls. Let men be
                        elected to Congress who will regard the wishes of those who sent them there.
                        Let us teach our representatives that they must obey--that they were not
                        elected to rule the country with a rod of iron.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports with indignation the Senate's recent action to extend the life of
                    the Income Tax against the will of the people. Quotes from both Democratic and
                    Republican newspapers denouncing the move. Says the only way to reverse this
                    state of affairs is to elect Democrats who will follow the voters' wishes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Chinese Labor</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Chinese question has opened upon us suddenly, and loomed up with
                        tremendous front in the Eastern States. Hitherto its discussion has been
                        confined to the Pacific coast, but a shoemaker in North Adams,
                        Massachusetts, has recently imported a lot of these coolie laborers and thus
                        thrown them into competition with the white working-men of that town. The
                        intelligence has spread like wildfire and the working-men are moving
                        everywhere. Monster mass meetings have been held to protest against any
                        further importation and to join hands against this scheme to reduce the
                        wages of labor to a mere nominal figure.</p>
                    <p>The Chinese, who feed on rats, mice, dogs, cats and other equally cheap, as
                        well as luxurious articles of diet, can easily afford to work for less money
                        than white men whose stomachs revolt at such food, and who require more
                        expensive provisions.--Hence the danger that the Radical capitalists of New
                        England, who care nothing for anybody but themselves, and who will engage
                        the laborer who will work for the least amount of money, may import these
                        Chinese in large numbers, thus throwing white men out of employment and
                        reducing many of them to want and, perhaps, starvation.</p>
                    <p>It was the Radical newspapers that first advocated the importation of these
                        laborers in order to make labor cheap. The <emph rend="italic">Press</emph>
                        and the <emph rend="italic">Inquirer</emph> both endorsed the plan months
                        ago, and the Democracy of California and Oregon were denounced without
                        stint, on account of their opposition to it.--But now, the workingmen of the
                        North are adopting the platform of the Democracy, and are expressing their
                        dissatisfaction in no feeble terms. They have seen with perfect disgust the
                        negro elevated to political and social equality with them, and have balked
                        at this effort to degrade white labor. But they recognize in this new
                        movement, a still stronger invasion of their rights, and they are moving
                        solidly now to brand it with the condemnation that it deserves. The only
                        hope of the workingmen is in the success of the Democratic party. Let him
                        learn this at once and act upon it.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Denounces the importation of Chinese labor to the Eastern States. Claims
                    Republicans are in favor of it and urges all white workingmen to support the
                    Democrats in order to avoid unemployment and starvation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>The Fourth of July</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"Katrina Fielding Riddles Jasper" writes the paper to complain about the
                    midnight revelry on the Fourth of July. A man drove a wagon through town while
                    ringing a cow-bell to announce the arrival of the 4th. Many "urchins" of the
                    town then awoke and began celebrating and ringing more bells, making it
                    impossible for upstanding citizens to sleep.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Cleanliness Next to Godliness</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"W." writes to complain about the foul odors stemming from the town's dirty
                    gutters and hog pens. These conditions, the writer asserts, adversely affect the
                    health of the town. If water-works cannot be built, the town should at least
                    supply enough water to clean offensive areas daily.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.07.06.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Democratic County Committee Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn>John R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnhart</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armstrong</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shillito</ln>
                        <fn>J. Newton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Worley</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Holliday</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Holland</ln>
                        <fn>Alonso</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clugston</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Diehl</ln>
                        <fn>Jeremiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reisher</ln>
                        <fn>B. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilmore</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCurdy</ln>
                        <fn>Robert I.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>DeHaven</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyd</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McAllen</ln>
                        <fn>William S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blair</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanck</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Logue</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamsher</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillan</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stake</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phenicle</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sibbett</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Laughlin</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>H. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Democratic County Committee will meet on July 16th in the office of
                    John R. Orr. A full attendance is requested as they will discuss reapportioning
                    districts. The article includes a list of the committee members.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Greencastle Band played in Chambersburg on the Fourth of July to rave
                    reviews.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hess</ln>
                        <fn>Frank W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Major Frank W. Hess, an "old friend of before the war," visited
                    Chambersburg. He is enjoying his position in the regular army and expects duty
                    in Texas.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Calls Extended</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The congregations of the Presbyterian Church, Shippensburg, issued a call
                    to serve as pastor to Rev. John Edgar of Philadelphia. The vote was 74 in favor,
                    34 against.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Sale of Bank Stock</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robinson</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pym</ln>
                        <fn>E. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John A. Robinson will sell 150 shares of capital stock in the National Bank
                    of Chambersburg. He is acting on behalf of the estate of the late Mrs. E. M. Pym
                    of McConnellsburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Begun Work</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Laborers have broken ground on a new building at the Wilson Female College.
                    It should be completed so the school can open in the fall.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Death of a Well-Known Citizen</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunter</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. John Hunter, a "well-known resident" of Franklin County and resident of
                    Upper Strasburg, died at the home of his son at Burnt Cabins after suffering a
                    "lingering and painful illness." Dr. Hunter, a native of Ireland, lived in
                    Strasburg for more than forty years. He passed away at age 84. "He was a man of
                    exemplary character and respected by all who knew him."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Fourth in Town</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Our National holiday was excessively dull in town. There was no public
                        meeting, no Fourth of July oration, no reading of the Declaration of
                        Independence. The boys indulged in fire crackers, torpedoes and sky rockets
                        to their hearts' content, but the men and women seemed to be oppressed with
                        a horrible dullness.</p>
                    <p>The Sunday Schools wisely got out of town, and, we are informed, enjoyed
                        themselves hugely. The United Brethren School went to Oyler's woods on the
                        Waynesboro road, the Lutheran to Messersmith's (formerly Shetter's) woods on
                        the Gettysburg turnpike, the First Methodist to a grove not far distant form
                        the last mentioned place, the Second Methodist to Grossman's School House on
                        the Greencastle road, and the German Lutheran to Hege's woods near Marion.</p>
                    <p>All places of business were closed, and the town wore a Sunday aspect.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes the lack of enthusiastic fervor and amusement in Chambersburg during
                    the 4th of July. Says church groups went to various other places and had a lot
                    more fun.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Appointments Revised</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Just before going to press, we received the sub-divisions of this county made
                        by Marshal Gregory with the names of the persons appointed in each as they
                        stand since correction. As we intimated last week, the appointments have
                        been changed to suit the places of residence of the appointees. The first
                        and second subdivisions have also been changed, Southampton being thrown
                        into the First, and Metal into the Second District. The list now stands as
                        given below, the Borough of Mercersburg not being included in any of the
                        subdivisions. It will be given either to Mr. Lackens or Mr. Graham.</p>
                    <p>1st. Southampton, Lurgan and Fannet, Jacob Kendig.</p>
                    <p>2nd. Letterkenny, Metal and Greene, W. K. Widener.</p>
                    <p>3d. Northward and Hamilton, E. D. Reid.</p>
                    <p>4th. St. Thomas and Peters, W. T. Graham.</p>
                    <p>5th. Montgomery and Warren, Wm. Lackens.</p>
                    <p>6th. Southward, D.F. Leisher.</p>
                    <p>7th. Guilford and Quincy, J.P. Study.</p>
                    <p>8th. Greencastle and Antrim, H. P. Prather.</p>
                    <p>9th. Waynesboro and Washington, J. F. Kurtz.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gregory</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Marshal</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kendig</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Widener</ln>
                        <fn>W. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reid</ln>
                        <fn>E. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Graham</ln>
                        <fn>W. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lackens</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Leisher</ln>
                        <fn>D. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Study</ln>
                        <fn>J. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Prather</ln>
                        <fn>H. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kurtz</ln>
                        <fn>J. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Prints the revisions made to census appointments.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Sudden Death</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Louderbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Cornelius</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Mercersburg Journal reports the sudden death of Mr. Cornelius
                    Louderbaugh. Louderbaugh appeared to be in good health, but was found dead after
                    he took a short break from cutting wheat. The doctors suspect apoplexy due to
                    extreme heat. "Mr. L. was a worthy and estimable citizen, and his long business
                    connections at this place, (that of Coach Manufacturer), has made him many
                    acquaintances not only in this, but adjoining counties, who will deplore his
                    sudden demise."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>A Long Time Blind</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fyock</ln>
                        <fn>Susana</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Susana Fyock died at Snow Hill on June 29th. She was 84 years old and
                    had lost her sight after suffering smallpox at age 7. She lived most of her life
                    at the nunnery.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Agents are canvassing Franklin County selling a work entitled "A Sketch of
                    the 126 Pennsylvania Volunteers." The proceeds will go to erect a monument to
                    the memory of the dead soldiers of Franklin County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Winger</ln>
                        <fn>B. Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beyer</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Callender</ln>
                        <fn>S. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heck</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Col. B. Frank Winger and Miss Maggie K. Beyer, both of Greencastle, were
                    married at the residence of Mrs. Heck on June 9th by the Rev. S. N. Callender.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snider</ln>
                        <fn>Henry C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hafer</ln>
                        <fn>Emma J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anthony</ln>
                        <fn>J. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Henry C. Snider of St. Thomas and Miss Emma J. Hafer of Orrstown were
                    married on June 25th by the Rev. J. P. Anthony at his residence in Orrstown.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>J. Snyder</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Forn</ln>
                        <fn>Lizzie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Linn</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. J. Snyder Trout and Miss Lizzie Forn, both of McConnellsburg, were
                    married on June 29th at the residence of the bride's parents by the Rev. H.
                    Linn.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Williams</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James Williams died in Warren on June 19th. He was 58 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>Nancy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Nancy Reed died in Orrstown on June 25th. She was 66 years old.
                    Funeral services will be held at Pleasant Hall.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Breckenridge</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel Breckenridge died near Fayetteville, Franklin County, on June 17th.
                    He was 60 years old. "The deceased had many warm friends who knew his worth.
                    Naturally kind and amiable in disposition, he was always ready to assist the
                    needy and support the weak. The community in which he lived has lost by his
                    death a most important member, for he was ever ready with a helping hand where
                    he could render assistance. In his family he was the kindest of parents, holding
                    the reins of parental government in the most generous and loving manner. Deeply
                    will they feel their loss, and great is the void left by his departure."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.07.06.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
