<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1870/pa.fr.vs.1870.11.23">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>11/09/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1870-11-23">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="11">November</month>
            <day norm="">23</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.11.23.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.11.23.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Let Us Beat the Trickster</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Conservatives and Democrats: John Cessna is making an effort to nullify your
                        votes. Repudiated by his constituency, he now seeks, by political
                        legerdemain, to render invalid their judgment of condemnation. Unexpectedly
                        rebuked and rejected by the men whom he had deceived and betrayed, he now
                        strives to hold his place by hook or by crook. He, last week, served a
                        notice upon Mr. Meyers that he intends to contest his seat in the
                        Forty-Second Congress.</p>
                    <p>Now, look at the "run" which the contemptible little fellow made. In 1868 he
                        was elected by a majority of 144. By the adoption of the Fifteenth
                        Amendment, more than one thousand negroes were enfranchised in the district,
                        who actually voted for Cessna almost without exception. If his party friends
                        who voted for him before had supported him at the late election, he should
                        have had a majority of 1150. <emph rend="italic">Instead of that, he is
                            beaten by fifteen votes</emph>.</p>
                    <p>Whilst the campaign was in progress, Cessna was confident of being elected.
                        He did not anticipate defeat. He would not believe in the defection of his
                        party friends on account of negro suffrage, and he thought that the party
                        lash would whip into the traces all the refractory members whom he had
                        treated without any show of decency and who were threatening to "cut" him at
                        the polls. While thus confident and defiant, he said in Mercersburg, when
                        the possibility of defeat was suggested to him, that if Mr. Meyers would get
                        the certificate from the Return Judges, <emph rend="italic">he would not
                            trouble him with a contest</emph>. Why doesn't he stick to this
                        declaration?</p>
                    <p>Well, as Cessna has not sufficient honor left to acknowledge and submit to
                        his defeat and thus make his declaration good, it becomes the people who
                        defeated him, to see to it that they are not cheated out of their votes and
                        thus deprived of the fruits of their victory. It becomes their duty to aid,
                        as far as in them lies, in defeating this last effort of the little
                        political thimble-rigger to represent a people who have positively declared
                        that they will not have him to represent them.</p>
                    <p>The Conservatives and Democrats of other Counties are all wide awake and hard
                        at work. They are a unit in the determination not to allow Cessna to succeed
                        in this disgraceful undertaking. They know his skill in the manipulation of
                        contested election cases by which he perpetrated the infamous fraud of
                        turning out men who had been elected by majorities running into the
                        thousands, just because they were Democrats, and putting in their defeated
                        competitors just because they were Radicals. They believe that a man who is
                        guilty of such conduct has no conscience left, and they do not intend to be
                        represented by such an one in Congress.</p>
                    <p>The Conservatives and Democrats of Franklin County will not fall behind their
                        brethren of the other counties. <emph rend="italic">Franklin County defeated
                            John Cessna</emph>. Here is the place where his duplicity was chiefly
                        practiced and most widely known. Here is the place where he made his
                        promises only to break them. And for this it was that pure, honest men in
                        the Radical ranks would not bow the knee to Cessna, or wear the collar which
                        he sought to put about their necks. Here, too, is the place where the
                        Democracy despise John Cessna. They hate him with a most intense hatred.
                        They know his disposition--they know his character. They remember the
                        bitterness with which he assailed Democrats when he turned traitor to the
                        party which had nurtured and fed and honored him. They recall the abusive
                        epithets which he applied to men who were far better patriots than himself.
                        For all this they had treasured up their wrath knowing that</p>
                    <p>"Time at last sets all things even,<lb/> And if we do but wait the hour,<lb/>
                        There never yet was human power<lb/> That could evade, if unforgiven,<lb/>
                        The patient search and vigil long<lb/> Of him who treasures up a wrong."</p>
                    <p>And when the opportunity came, they made haste to seize it. With alacrity
                        they went to the polls, declaring that no ordinary engagements should keep
                        them from voting against John Cessna. They all seemed to be animated by a
                        common determination to defeat him. This accounts for the splendid vote
                        polled by the Democracy, enabling them to carry Franklin County by a
                        majority of 186, notwithstanding the large number of negroes who voted the
                        Radical ticket. We have no fear that these same Democrats will be
                        indifferent to the contest now, or negligent of the duty which this contest
                        imposes upon them.</p>
                    <p>What is this duty? John Cessna attacks the vote in several election districts
                        on account of irregularities and informalities which, in his judgment, would
                        have been of no account, if he had only been elected.--He alleges that
                        certain illegal votes were cast for Meyers and he hopes thus to overcome the
                        majority for Meyers. Now there are, doubtless, irregularities and
                        informalities which will weigh against Cessna. There were illegal votes cast
                        for Cessna. It is the duty of Democrats throughout the County to inquire and
                        make diligent search for these irregularities, informalities and illegal
                        votes and report them at once. Let every Democrat who reads this article
                        resolve himself into a committee of one to furnish all the information of
                        this kind that he can gather. Inasmuch as Cessna insists upon a contest, let
                        us make it a battle along the whole line. Let us show him that his own
                        adherents are the men who polled the illegal votes. The truth is that this
                        cry about illegal voting in the rural districts is not of much account.--It
                        is only in large towns and cities that unscrupulous men resort to wholesale
                        frauds. But there are <emph rend="italic">some</emph> illegal votes, and we
                        venture the prediction that it will be discovered that there are three
                        illegal Radical votes for every illegal Democratic vote.--There was a large
                        illegal negro vote polled as we hope to be able to show. Let our friends
                        turn their attention to it, and they will find that many blacks were voted
                        who had not arrived at the age of twenty-one years. Send us the names of all
                        such.--Many of them paid no taxes. Find out all such who voted.</p>
                    <p>A portion of Cessna's $100,000 was floating around through Franklin county.
                        Ascertain whether any votes were obtained for him by the payment of money,
                        or by threats or intimidation of any kind. Look well to the payment of
                        taxes. Ascertain whether persons just above <emph rend="italic">twenty-two
                            years of age</emph> who voted for Cessna, were assessed and paid taxes.
                        Learn, also, whether the person who received the taxes were authorized by
                        law to do so. Ascertain when the polls were opened and when closed, and
                        whether during the progress of the election or the counting of the votes,
                        persons not sworn were present in the room in which the election was held.
                            <emph rend="italic">Ascertain every vote of doubtful propriety cast at
                            your respective polls, and report at once the name of the person who
                            cast it and the reason why you deem it illegal, or informal</emph>.
                        Wherever election-boards acted illegally and improperly, their conduct
                        should be noted, and the names of all persons who offered to vote the
                        Democratic ticket whose names were rejected, should be reported.</p>
                    <p>It is necessary that this should be attended to <emph rend="italic">at
                        once</emph>, inasmuch as Mr. Meyers must file his answer within thirty days
                        from the time of service of the notice. Let there be no delay therefore. The
                        Bedford <emph rend="italic">Gazette</emph> says, "the skunk has been caught
                        and is now to be skinned." Send in your data as quickly as possible
                        addressed to W. S. Stenger, Esq., or John R. Orr, Esq.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cessna</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Meyers</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stenger</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn>John R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Expresses outrage that Cessna is set to contest his recent defeat at the
                    polls. Lists the untrustworthy actions Cessna has done in the past and sees this
                    as just another example. Calls on all Conservatives to steal a march on Cessna
                    by reporting all illegal Radical votes cast in the election.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Contrast their Conduct</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper criticizes John Cessna for making preparations to challenge the
                    outcome of his failed bid for election as representative of the 16th District.
                    He lost by 15 votes, and had promised ahead of time not to challenge the
                    results.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.11.23.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Scarlet fever is rampant in St. Thomas.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prof. Kidd will lecture tonight at the Court House.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Dancing</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ridgely</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Charles Ridgely's hotel in St. Thomas hosted "a large and brilliant ball."
                    A number of ladies and gentlemen from Chambersburg attended.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Fatal Result of an Accident</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spidle</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bushman</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Spidle was accidently shot by Frederick Bushman while "out gunning."
                    He passed away last Saturday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Appointment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Townsend</ln>
                        <fn>D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Rev. D. Townsend of Chambersburg has been appointed by the Grand Lodge
                    of the I. O. G. T. to travel through Pennsylvania and make speeches in favor of
                    the temperance cause.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Teachers' Institute</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gelwicks</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Enterline</ln>
                        <fn>T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hockenberry</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn>Lyman S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shillito</ln>
                        <fn>S. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClelland</ln>
                        <fn>W. Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eckert</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kidd</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McElwain</ln>
                        <fn>A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shumaker</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolfe</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McFadden</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McFadden</ln>
                        <fn>D. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bender</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foust</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Franklin County Teacher's Institute met in the Court House. They
                    attended prayer sessions and addresses by prominent teachers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn>Fannie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneck</ln>
                        <fn>B. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jacob A. Martin and Miss Fannie Martin, daughter of Joseph R. Martin of
                    Green, were married on November 17th by the Rev. B. S. Schneck.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maloy</ln>
                        <fn>Calvin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Speck</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Townsend</ln>
                        <fn>D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Calvin Maloy of Fayetteville and Miss Mary Catharine Speck of Shippensburg
                    were married on November 17th by the Rev. D. Townsend.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dice</ln>
                        <fn>Hannah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Hannah Dice died near Greenvillage on November 5th of bronchitis.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewbaker</ln>
                        <fn>Christian</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Christian Brewbaker died suddenly near Welsh Run on November 16th. He was
                    64 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.11.23.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
