<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1870/pa.fr.vs.1870.11.02">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>11/08/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1870-11-02">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="11">November</month>
            <day norm="">2</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.11.02.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.11.02.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Centralization</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Conservative people of the country are looking with alarm upon the
                        strides which the present Administration is making towards despotism. It is
                        high time that they should do so. The first encroachments were made under
                        the guise of patriotism and military necessity and the masses willingly
                        acquiesced in them. The "war power" was used unscrupulously to batter down,
                        one by one, the reserved rights of the States.--The attack upon our
                        republican form of government was the more insidious, because it seemed to
                        be directed solely against the States that were in rebellion. In this way
                        the Radicals accomplished their purpose and received the endorsement of the
                        blatant loyalists of the North, who, unthinkingly, applauded everything that
                        was done to humiliate and insult rebels.</p>
                    <p>But "usurped powers grow like avalanches." The march of despotism is ever
                        onward. It never rests satisfied. It goes from one aggression to another.
                        The exercise of unlimited authority in the South intensified the arbitrary
                        disposition of those who were wielding that power there, and they turned
                        their eyes Northward for other fields to conquer. They were not content with
                        subjugating the States that had been in rebellion. They could not rest
                        satisfied with the disfranchisement by military power, of white men who had
                        been dressed in Confederate uniforms. They marched their soldiers to the
                        polls in North Carolina and attempted to intimidate the men who were opposed
                        to the Radical ticket, and saw their infamous scheme fail to accomplish the
                        end designed. Mortified, maddened, these Radical leaders resorted to the
                        same means to carry the election in Pennsylvania. In Philadelphia the United
                        States Marshal appointed a large number of Deputy Marshals and held a force
                        of United States troops in readiness to back them if they got into any
                        trouble.</p>
                    <p>And now, as the election is approaching in the great State of New York, which
                        is to tell more plainly than any election that has preceded it, the story of
                        the utter disorganization and disintegration of the Radical party, troops
                        are being sent rapidly to New York city to overawe voters, and failing to do
                        that, to incite the citizens of the metropolis to riot and bloodshed, so
                        that the Democratic vote can not be fully polled.</p>
                    <p>On last Thursday night, the Democrats of that city turned out in procession
                        and organized huge mass meetings to protest against this infamous act of
                        tyranny. The <emph rend="italic">Sun</emph> says there were <emph
                            rend="italic">one hundred acres</emph> of Democrats. The <emph
                            rend="italic">World</emph> says there were one hundred thousand
                        Democrats in procession. Speeches were delivered by many eminent men and all
                        counselled moderation and peace on election day, so that this Radical scheme
                        may be completely foiled.</p>
                    <p>But what is to be said of the Administration which permits such things to be
                        done by virtue of the authority of the United States? The Philadelphia <emph
                            rend="italic">Post</emph> (Radical) says:</p>
                    <p>We would have the President enforce the laws when they are broken, not
                        before. It is his duty to see that the laws are executed, and he is given
                        the right to employ the military in these special cases. If necessary,
                        troops should be sent to New York.</p>
                    <p>But the question is, is it necessary? We remember the riots of 1863, and the
                        riots here in 1844, and we have heard of St. Bartholomew's massacre. But a
                        riot past does not prove there is danger of riot now. <emph rend="italic">We
                            have not yet heard upon what information of immediate danger three
                            thousand troops have been ordered to a Northern city in time of
                        peace</emph>.</p>
                    <p>We do not see the wisdom of sending troops to New York, because we already
                        see that the mere announcement has exasperated the worst classes in New
                        York, offended many of the better classes, and that it is itself an
                        incitement of the election troubles it was intended to prevent."</p>
                    <p>Hon. James Brooks was one of the speakers on Thursday night, and used the
                        following language with reference to this action of the President:</p>
                    <p>I have come mainly as a member of Congress to protest most solemnly, to
                        protest here before all my countrymen, as well as before the people of this
                        city, against the introduction, for the first time in our history of the
                        army of the United States into the election of the State of New York. It is
                        known to you that a considerable body of troops, in numbers not contemptible
                        when under the authority of the President of the United States, is
                        approaching us, for what purpose is not known, but in my judgment that of
                        intimidation, but as it is alleged for the enforcement of the laws of the
                        United States. Now there is no disposition upon the part of any of us,
                        although we believe those laws to be wicked and unconstitutional and enacted
                        solely for the purpose of introducing the army of the United States into our
                        elections--there is no intention, I say, on the part of any member of the
                        Democratic party to resist the authorities of the United States. Supervisors
                        are admitted to our boards of registration--the laws enforcing the fifteenth
                        amendment and the naturalization laws will be obeyed by the people and
                        authorities of New York just as though they were constitutional laws and
                        good laws, and we propose to obey them in good faith. There is ample power
                        too on the part of the United States, through the United States marshals and
                        their deputies; the civil authority is full and ample to execute all the
                        laws of the United States, and yet, with this civil posse before them, armed
                        with all the authority of those two statutes, two weeks prior to the
                        election the President concentrates here a considerable army of the United
                        States, and, as if to degrade and insult us, he marches here a regiment
                        lately used in the elections of North Carolina, before that used in the
                        elections of Tennessee, recently used in the elections of South Carolina to
                        elect four negro or mulatto members of Congress to represent the white as
                        well as the black people of South Carolina. He uses that regiment, fresh
                        from those scenes of action and lands them in our harbor to threaten us, the
                        white people of New York, with the use of that regiment in our elections.
                        Without entering into any language that may be calculated to exasperate or
                        excite our people, for I pray for peace and order on the day of election,
                        for they are essential not only to our salvation, but for the security of
                        our ballot-box and the polling of the full vote--without entering into any
                        further denunciation of that proceeding on the part of the President of the
                        United States and the Secretary of War. I protest, as a member of Congress,
                        and may I not also for my colleague here present and my other colleagues,
                        that we pronounce this act of the President unwise, unnecessary, tyrannical
                        and in utter hostility to the genius and to every principle of our form of
                        government. (Applause.) I call upon him if he is a republican and not a
                        monarchist, I call upon him if he is President of the United States and not
                        merely the general of the army, and I invoke him, in the name of our
                        Constitution and of the spirit of American liberty, I invoke him to withdraw
                        our armies and leave us to the marshals, to the laws of the United States
                        and the laws of the State of New York, amply powerful to enforce a just
                        election.--(Applause, long continued.)</p>
                    <p>May not the citizen pause in view of events like these and ask, whither are
                        we drifting? Why is this change being wrought in the Administration of the
                        Government?--Whence comes the authority for the exercise of such a fearful
                        power? The Government of our fathers is hardly recognizable any more. Mr.
                        Madison said of Hamilton:--"He <emph rend="italic">administrationized</emph>
                        the government into a thing totally different from what he and I both knew
                        perfectly well had been understood and intended by the people in adopting
                        it." And John Quincy Adams "hit the nail on the head" the other night in
                        Faneuil Hall, Boston, when he said: "So the Democracy say to-day that the
                        Republican party has '<emph rend="italic">reconstructed</emph>' the
                        government into something not only totally different from anything the
                        people ever intended, but so utterly unlike the work of the fathers that Mr.
                        Madison himself would not know it for his offspring, and old Patrick Henry
                        would justly vociferate again: 'It has an awful squinting, sir; it squints,
                        towards monarchy.'"</p>
                    <p>The condemnation of the whole people should be passed upon President
                        Grant.--Against him the same indictment might be drawn as was contained in
                        the Declaration which our forefathers leveled at King George when they said:</p>
                    <p>"He has kept among us, in times of peace, standing armies, without the
                        consent of our Legislature."</p>
                    <p>"He has affected to render the military independent of, and superior to, the
                        civil power."</p>
                    <p>That Declaration was no less pointed in its denunciation of the King for
                        "combining with others," and "giving his assent to their acts of pretended
                        legislation, for quartering large bodies of armed troops among us." And the
                        same denunciation applies to President Grant, for he, too, has given "his
                        assent to acts of pretended legislation for quartering large bodies of armed
                        troops among" the people of the different States for the purpose of
                        controlling elections to suit his own partisan views.</p>
                    <p>From this despotism, may the good Lord soon deliver us!</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Denounces the government's recent policy of sending soldiers to northern
                    cities during elections. Quotes from Republican papers and speakers who are also
                    upset with this turn of events. Claims Grant is only doing it to cow Democratic
                    voters and ensure Republican victories at the polls.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.11.02.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Religious</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The U. B. Congregation of St. Thomas concluded on October 24th a revival
                    they had been holding.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>New Lime Kiln</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guthrie</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Speer</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Guthrie, Speer, and Co. have just completed construction of two large lime
                    kilns, greatly enhancing the company's productive capacity.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Educational</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillan</ln>
                        <fn>U. Rush</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGarvey</ln>
                        <fn>Sue</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sackman</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coble</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Detrick</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The schools of St. Thomas opened on October 18th under the direction of U.
                    Rush Gillan and Miss Sue McGarvey. The Teachers District Institute met and
                    elected the following officers: Jacob Sackman, president; J. W. Coble, vice
                    president; J. C. Detrick, Secretary.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Franklin County Horticultural Society</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ryder</ln>
                        <fn>B. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The society will meet on November 1st. Dr. B. L. Ryder will deliver an
                    address on Horticultural Education.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>A White Girl Kissed in the Street by a Negro</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On Tuesday night of last week, about half-past nine o'clock, as the three
                        young ladies of this Borough were passing up Front street, near the clothing
                        store of Mr. Frank Elliott, they were met by three negroes. One of the
                        negroes threw both his arms around the neck of one of the girls and kissed
                        her. She struggled and got loose, and the negro ran. By this time the alarm
                        was given and the persons in the immediate neighborhood began to run after
                        him. The excitement spread; the crowd swelled in size as the pursuit
                        continued until the Diamond was thronged with people. The negro ran down to
                        Trostle's hotel, through the front building, back into the dining room, and
                        made his escape by leaping through a window into the yard of Miss Susan
                        Chambers. The indignation of the crowd was intense and if the offender had
                        been caught he would no doubt have been dealt with very summarily.</p>
                    <p>Soon after the occurrence, a negro approached a knot of negroes in front of
                        the Montgomery House, and asked the cause of the excitement. He was informed
                        of what had taken place. "Well," said he, "dat darkey must hab been might
                        hard up to kiss a <emph rend="italic">white</emph> girl."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elliott</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Relates an incident where a black man, probably in a drunken state, kissed
                    a white lady in public, and was subsequently chased by a white mob.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Festival</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Methodist Church of St. Thomas raised $130 at their recent festival.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Personal</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palsgrove</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shields</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nelson</ln>
                        <fn>A. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. John B. Palsgrove, formerly of St. Thomas, is visiting Franklin this
                    week. Mrs. Elizabeth Shields, sister of Sarah Wilson, is also visiting relatives
                    in St. Thomas. "She is 92 years of age and seems to enjoy good health. On the
                    16th ult. she attended church at St. Thomas and received Holy Communion at the
                    hands of Rev. A. K. Nelson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Arrest of an Escaped Convict</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sites</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foltz</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Deputy Sheriff</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Sites, who had been convicted of malicious mischief and assault and
                    battery, was captured after escaping from jail. He allegedly committed larceny
                    while free of jail. Deputy Sheriff Foltz made the arrest.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Reunion of the 126th Penna. Vols.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The soldiers of the 126th will hold their first reunion in Repository Hall,
                        Chambersburg, on Tuesday, the 13th day of December next, at which time it is
                        intended to effect a permanent organization. The Regiment was made up
                        chiefly from Franklin, Fulton, and Juniata counties, much the largest number
                        being from Franklin. Chambersburg has therefore been selected as the place
                        for holding the first meeting.</p>
                    <p>The exercises will be of a most important character, and a large and
                        interesting meeting is confidently expected. The committee of arrangements
                        have authorized us to say that so far as it can be done special invitations
                        will be sent to every survivor of the regiment, but that owing to removals
                        and other causes it will be impossible to get reliable information as to the
                        address of every one. Any soldier who belonged to this organization and may
                        learn of the reunion from newspaper notices, or in any other way, will not
                        abstain from attending for want of other invitation.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces a reunion of the 126th Pennsylvania Volunteers in Chambersburg in
                    December and invites all surviving veterans to attend.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Court Proceedings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The following cases were tried during the session of the Court last week, His
                        Honor Judge King presiding:</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. John Hasson and Frank Kean. Assault and Battery on Peter Cummings,
                        with intent to kill. The indictment contained two additional counts, one for
                            <emph rend="italic">aggravated</emph> Assault and Battery and the other
                        for Assault and Battery.</p>
                    <p>The evidence showed that Cummings, Hasson and Kean had been drinking freely
                        together and Cummings rode Kean's horse up to the Indian Queen Hotel and put
                        him in the stable. They then went into the barroom and Kean and Cummings got
                        into a quarrel about the horse and adjourned to the back yard to fight it
                        out. Hasson went out also. After the three had sparred together for awhile,
                        Cummings made a savage assault upon Hasson and struck him twice. Hasson
                        stepped back, picked up a brick bat and hurled it at Cummings. It struck him
                        on the head and he fell senseless. He was taken to Boyd's Hotel, where he
                        lay unconscious for eight or ten days.</p>
                    <p>Cummings was called upon the stand but could not recollect anything about the
                        difficulty. The jury found the Defendants guilty on the third count for
                        Assault and Battery. Kean was sentenced to pay costs, and Hasson to pay
                        costs and undergo imprisonment in county jail for ten days.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Samuel Stokes. Forgery. This was a charge of having forged the name
                        of David Smith to a note dated Nov. 27, 1867, for $50. Mr. Smith is dead.
                        Verdict Not Guilty, but Deft. to pay costs.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Hugh Dugan and George Brown.</p>
                    <p>The Defts. were charged with stealing six dollars from the person of William
                        Bell in August last. Bell was drunk and had laid down to sleep in the jail
                        yard. He asked Dugan to take his money and go for some whiskey. Dugan
                        refused to go, but after Bell fell asleep, he took the money and went, not
                        returning, however, until the officer brought him back with a commitment for
                        larceny. When the case was called for trial, Bell was among the missing,
                        having most probably gone to his "cups" again. Verdict, Not Guilty.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Daniel Row. Assault and Battery on Abram R. Saylor. Verdict, Guilty.
                        Sentenced to pay $5 and costs.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Leonard Nave. Fornication and Bastardy. Sarah Ann Porter,
                        Prosecutrix. Verdict, Guilty. Sentenced to pay $15 lying in expenses and 75
                        cents per week for seven years.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. George Kell, Sr. Assault and Battery on Frank Myers. Verdict, Not
                        Guilty, and costs equally divided between Pros'r and Deft.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. George Kell, Jr., and Joseph Kell. Deft. Geo. Kell pleaded guilty
                        and was sentenced to pay costs and a <emph rend="italic">nolle
                        prosequi</emph> was entered as to Joseph.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Samuol Myers, David Bergenstock and Henry Bergenstock.</p>
                    <p>These were three Surety of the Peace cases in which John C. Gilbert was the
                        Prosecutor. The Defendants were all sentenced to pay costs.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. George Goettman.</p>
                    <p>This was a charge of stealing four bottles of wine from the restaurant of
                        Lantz &amp; Unger about four weeks ago. The Deft. had been drinking very
                        hard for some time and to allay his thirst entered the restaurant through a
                        window and took the wine. Verdict, Guilty. The Court took into consideration
                        the circumstances under which the offence was committed, and imposed the
                        light sentence of two months in the county jail.</p>
                    <p>Com.vs. Jane Gilbert. Surety of the Peace. Case dismissed at the costs of the
                        Prosecutrix, Mary Myers.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Frances Leasure. Assault and Battery on Miss Catharine Gans.</p>
                    <p>The Prosecutrix owns a house in Waynesboro' and rented a portion of it to the
                        Deft. and her husband. It seems they did not get along well together, and
                        one day as the Prosecutrix, who is a lady advanced in years and a cripple,
                        closed and locked the door of her room and turned towards the Defendant, who
                        was sweeping the stairway, the Defendant swept "the sweepings" right smack
                        into the face of the Prosecutrix. This was the assault and battery. The jury
                        "settled the dust" of the case, by returning a verdict of Not Guilty, and
                        making the Deft. pay 2/3 and the Pros'x 1/3 of the costs.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Frank Myers. Surety of the Peace. Thomas Gardner Prosecutor.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. John Thomas and William Thomas. Horse Stealing.</p>
                    <p>Same vs. Same. Larceny of a Buggy.</p>
                    <p>The facts in regard to these two cases are these: On Friday night, the 21st
                        ult., the stable of Mr. John S. Hunsecker, in Hamilton township, was entered
                        and a dark brown horse was stolen therefrom, together with a set of single
                        harness.</p>
                    <p>On the same night a good buggy was stolen from the premises of Mr. George
                        Palmer, also in Hamilton township. Mr. Henry W. Ramsey, of Newville, had
                        hired the buggy from Mr. Wm. C. Sharp, in Newville, Cumberland county, Pa.,
                        and was spending the night with Mr. Palmer, who is his brother-in-law. When
                        they got up on Saturday morning, the buggy was gone. Telegrams were sent in
                        every direction and bills describing the stolen property. On Saturday
                        morning, however, before intelligence of the stealing of the property had
                        reached Hagerstown, Mr. George Albert and his sons arrested two negroes in
                        that place on suspicion of having stolen a horse and buggy which they had in
                        their possession. The horse proved to be Mr. Hunsecker's and the buggy the
                        one which Mr. Ramsey had hired. The negroes were removed to this place and
                        lodged in prison on Monday of last week. They gave the names of John Thomas
                        and Wm. Thomas. Bills were sent to and found by the Grand Jury on the same
                        day. On Tuesday, they were arraigned, tried and found guilty, and on
                        Thursday, were each sentenced by His Honor Judge King--on the bill for Horse
                        Stealing six years and on the other bill two years--to the Eastern
                        Penitentiary, making the term of service for each, eight years. The offences
                        were committed on Friday night and on the following Thursday, they were
                        sentenced. Just before their sentence, information was received from the
                        District Attorney of Dauphin county stating that he had two indictments
                        against each of them for Burglary, committed in Harrisburg. Their real names
                        are Joseph Jones and Jacklin Ellis. This summary mode of dealing with the
                        men ought to be a wholesome lesson to this class of offenders.</p>
                    <p>Cases in which a <emph rend="italic">nolle prosequi</emph> was entered:</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. P. Henry Peiffer; com. vs. David D. Fahrney; com. vs. Susan Shock;
                        com. vs. Joseph Shaffer; com. vs. Henry H. Miller; com. vs. Wm. Wyncoop;
                        com. vs. Catharine Dine; com. vs. Michael Gable; com. vs. Margaret Johnson;
                        com. vs. John W. Kuhn; com. vs. Jerome Ferguson; com. vs. Frederick Myers;
                        com. vs. John Disert et al.; com. vs. James Powell; com. vs. James Martin;
                        com. vs. Obed Gaell.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Bills Ignored</emph>.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Edward Harman et al. County to pay costs.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Henry Clensinger. Pros'r, Robert Harman, to pay costs.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Samuel Little. Pros'x Elizabeth Little to pay costs.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. John Hart, colored. Pros'r, Frank Myers, to pay costs.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Emanuel Whisler and Jacob Wagner. Pros'x Susan Little, to pay costs.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. George Long.</p>
                    <p>Same vs. Same.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Alfred Nelson.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. J.W. Hannan.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Susan Scott. Pros'r, Marion Scott, to pay costs.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Wm. Sly. Pros'x, Martha Craig, to pay costs.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Byers Wingert and Frank Shively. Pros'r, Obed Goell, to pay costs.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Margaret Wolfe. Prose'x, Margaret Winters, to pay costs.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Jacob R. Kreps. County to pay costs.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Samuel Brooks. Pros'r, Henry Meads, to pay costs.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. "Bish" Meads and others.--Pros'r, Samuel Brooks, to pay costs.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. George Long. Two bills.--County to pay costs.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. David Henderson et al. County to pay costs.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Civil Causes disposed of</emph>.</p>
                    <p>D.F. Wilson vs. H.S. Gilbert &amp; Col. Case in Assumpsit founded on book
                        acc't. Verdict for $329.11.</p>
                    <p>Alex. E. McDowell vs. Brough &amp; Foltz. Summons in Assumpsit. Deft's
                        confess judgment for $456.53.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hasson</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kean</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cummings</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stokes</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dugan</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Row</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Saylor</ln>
                        <fn>Abram R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nave</ln>
                        <fn>Leonard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Porter</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kell</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kell</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bergenstock</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bergenstock</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilbert</ln>
                        <fn>John C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Goettman</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilbert</ln>
                        <fn>Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Leasure</ln>
                        <fn>Frances</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gaps</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gardner</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thomas</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunsecker</ln>
                        <fn>John S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palmer</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ramsey</ln>
                        <fn>Henry W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharp</ln>
                        <fn>William C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Albert</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ellis</ln>
                        <fn>Jacklin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peiffer</ln>
                        <fn>P. Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fahrney</ln>
                        <fn>David D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shook</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shaffer</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Henry H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wyncoop</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dine</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gable</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kuhn</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ferguson</ln>
                        <fn>Jerome</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Disert</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Powell</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gsell</ln>
                        <fn>Obed</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>Edward</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clensinger</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Little</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Little</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hart</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whisler</ln>
                        <fn>Emanuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wagner</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Little</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wagner</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Long</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nelson</ln>
                        <fn>Alfred</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hannan</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scott</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scott</ln>
                        <fn>Marion</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sly</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craig</ln>
                        <fn>Martha</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingert</ln>
                        <fn>Byers</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shively</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolfe</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Winters</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kreps</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brooks</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Meade</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Meade</ln>
                        <fn>"Bish"</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brooks</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Long</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henderson</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>D. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilbert</ln>
                        <fn>H. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDowell</ln>
                        <fn>Alex E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brough</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foltz</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Covers a session of the county court, announcing cases and verdicts. Cases
                    include theft, forgery, assault and battery, etc.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Lanahan</ln>
                        <fn>T. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Austin</ln>
                        <fn>Beckie A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>I. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. T. J. M'Lanahan and Miss Beckie A. Austin, both of Chambersburg, were
                    married at the residence of the bride's father on October 27th by the Rev. I. N.
                    Hays, assisted by the Rev. James Kennedy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peifer</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hassler</ln>
                        <fn>Sophie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roth</ln>
                        <fn>G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Henry Peifer and Miss Sophie Hassler, both of Franklin, were married on
                    October 27th by the Rev. G. Roth.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cormany</ln>
                        <fn>Jennie A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jennie A. Cormany, formerly of Franklin, died in Ohio on October 19th of
                    pulmonary consumption.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.11.02.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
