<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1860/va.au.ss.1860.06.26">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Jeff McClurken</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/22/95</tagDate>
            <tagNote>2nd Pass; Josh Rothman did first pass.</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1860-06-26">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="06">June</month>
            <day>26</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1860.06.26.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Singular Affair</head>
                <origin>Lewisburg (Greenbrier County) Chronicle</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Some six years ago, a man came to this place, or rather its vicinity, calling
                        himself Heriff, and has since then worked for numerous gentlemen in the
                        county, as a day laborer. Although of rather dark complexion, no one ever
                        supposed him to be akin to the descendents of Ham. After living here
                        sometime, he won the affections of a pretty white girl whom he married.
                        Things went on 's quite prosperously for some time, two children gladening
                        the happy father's heart, when, alas! his felicitous existance was
                        unexpectedly terminated. A negro man, in town, seems to have conceived the
                        idea that all was not right with Heriff, and that he bore the indications of
                        being more closely connected with the sons of Afric's burning sands, than is
                        countenanced on Southern soil, and communicated this idea to a gentleman,
                        who upon seeing him, immediately recognized him as the same individual once
                        belonging to a gentleman at or near the Hot Springs in Bath county, and from
                        whom he had run off. The gentleman was informed of the fact, and on the 2nd
                        inst. he arrived here, in company with someone who could substantiate his
                        claims. He met Heriff in one of our stores, and informed him that he had
                        come for him and claimed him as his servant. He seemed rather indignant,
                        upon receiving this unpleasant piece of information, but after a few words,
                        he acknowledged his true character, and accompanied his master home.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Story of an escaped slave "passing" as white in Greenbrier County, where he
                    managed to establish a family before being recognized years later and reclaimed
                    by his former master.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/ssjune60.html#6.26a</note>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>"L.L."</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Polmer</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Author recounts tale of bravery and fine horsemanship by Captain Polmer.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1860.06.26.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Proceedings at Baltimore</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Brief summary of the proceedings of the Democratic National Convention now
                    meeting in Baltimore.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Democratic Nominees</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Laments the breakup of the Democratic party and the need for it to nominate
                    two separate tickets (a Douglas ticket and a Breckenridge ticket). Predicts that
                    the party's division will lead to victory for neither Democratic ticket.
                    Spectator asserts that the country's only hope is that the Constitutional Union
                    party will be able to accrue enough electoral votes to win the election. They
                    exhort Democratic voters to break from party labels and give a patriotic vote
                    for Bell and Everett.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Car Coupling</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Esq.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>W.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announcement that John D. Imboden has bought a five year interest in the
                    railroad car coupling recently invented by L. and W.H. Waddell of Staunton,
                    which allows for self-coupling of cars and for uncoupling at the flip of a
                    lever.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>New Book</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Spectator has received from New York the second volume of children's
                    "Oakland Stories," written by Rev. George B. Taylor of Staunton. This volume is
                    entitled "Cousin Guy," and the Spectator approves of the work.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Population of Staunton</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Watts</ln>
                        <fn>J.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Major</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>According to the totals of Major J.B. Watts, local census marshall, the
                    population of Staunton is 3,716, not including students in the Augusta Female
                    Seminary, the Virginia Female Institute, the Wesleyan Female Institute, or the
                    Staunton Male Academy. Including these institutions, the population is over
                    4,000.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Railroad Difficulty</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The difficulty between the Central and the Orange and Alexandria Railroads
                    has been resolved and mail and passengers now come through on time.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Junior Blues</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lilley</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A juvenile military company calling itself the Junior Blues held a public
                    parade led by Captain Lilley.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Mossy Creek Academy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>"Pendleton"</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mohler</ln>
                        <fn>J.L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roler</ln>
                        <fn>A.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Report of closing exercises held at Mossy Creek Academy, at which J.L.
                    Mohler of Augusta County delivered an introductory speech, A.B. Roler of Augusta
                    County received a medal from the Literary Society as Best Debater, and Hugh W.
                    Sheffey of Staunton delivered the annual address.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Military Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>F.C. Roberts, Chairman; J. Olin Hobbs, Sec'y</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roberts</ln>
                        <fn>F.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hobbs</ln>
                        <fn>J. Olin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>At a military meeting of a volunteer company to be formed at West View,
                    F.C. Roberts was named Chair and J. Olin Hobbs was named Secretary.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Loch Willow Exhibition</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>"A Virginian"</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hotchkiss</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grinnan</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hotchkiss</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Report of proceedings at the Loch Willow school exhibition, under the
                    management of J. Hotchkiss and Mr. Grinnan in the male department and Mrs.
                    Hotchkiss in the female.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Continuation and a much extended version of the proceedings of the National
                Democratic convention at Baltimore, discussed in column 1, printed in columns 3-4.
                Proceedings of "Seceders' Convention," column 4. Proceedings of Congress, column 4.
                Print at bottom of columns 3-5 is too faint to read.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1860.06.26.03">
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>W.E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lange</ln>
                        <fn>W.D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Marple</ln>
                        <fn>Louisa</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>W.D. Lange married Louisa Marple on June 7 at the Virginia Hotel.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wheeler</ln>
                        <fn>J.R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Freed</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barger</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George W. Freed married Margaret H. Barger, both of Augusta County, on June
                    7.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wheeler</ln>
                        <fn>J.R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gollady</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Williams</ln>
                        <fn>Martha</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George Gollady married Martha A.A. Williams, both of Augusta County, on
                    June 14.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>"E."</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCheeney</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blair</ln>
                        <fn>John Taylor</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blair</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Taylor Blair, son of James A.R. Blair, died at the house of his
                    grandfather, Dr. John McCheeney, in Augusta County at age 17.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Article on the congeniality of the press at the Democratic convention despite
                the bitterness of the convention's events, taken from the Philadelphia Press, column
                1. Most of page is advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1860.06.26.04">
            <pageNote>Advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
