<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1860/va.au.ss.1860.11.13">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Jeff McClurken</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/22/95</tagDate>
            <tagNote>2nd Pass; Josh Rothman did first pass.</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1860-11-13">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="11">November</month>
            <day>13</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1860.11.13.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Kate Yale's Marriage</head>
                <origin>Cornhill Monthly</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Story about a young woman who first seeks a man to marry who has money,
                    only to discover that love is more important in choosing a spouse.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>6-7</column>
                <head>Way-Side Jottings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>See</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McFarland</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letter to editor from a person who had visited Augusta County and wishes to
                    give his opinions of the county.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Blue Eyes</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Short piece claiming that blue eyes have been predominant among the great
                    men of the world.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Page has a number of short stories/poetry, as well as one or two sentence
                morality quips.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1860.11.13.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Union in Danger! Mass Meeting of the People of Augusta</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilkeson</ln>
                        <fn>A.G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Points</ln>
                        <fn>B.F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>L.</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woodward</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cowan</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wayt</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yost</ln>
                        <fn>S.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hansel</ln>
                        <fn>B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woods</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donaghe</ln>
                        <fn>W.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>Alex.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gregory</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>G.M.</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bruce</ln>
                        <fn>A.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doyle</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mauzy</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>N.K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>Lee</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn>H.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>H.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>Breeze</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Golladay</ln>
                        <fn>Jonathan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hendron</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Churchman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Templeton</ln>
                        <fn>S.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Haas</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn>G.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Marshall</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kayser</ln>
                        <fn>W.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>Edwin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>W.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Finley</ln>
                        <fn>S.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Durhoran</ln>
                        <fn>T.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>C.T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bledsoe</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Petition signed by a number of prominent Augusta citizens calling for a
                    mass meeting of county residents of all parties to be held on November 17 to
                    discuss the necessary steps for saving the Union in light of the election
                    results.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Though Lincoln is Elected, There is no Danger</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The success of the Republicans in the Presidential election is but a
                    barren victory, and its fruits, like the apples of the Dead Sea, will turn to
                    ashes upon their lips."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It is with deep pain that we announce the triumph of a Northern Sectional
                        party. We have labored earnestly to prevent that result, and supported the
                        only ticket which carried the flag around which all the conservative
                        strength of the country could rally without sacrifice of principle. The
                        ticket we supported bore aloft a <emph rend="italic">national</emph> banner
                        around which conservatives North and South should have rallied with the view
                        of preventing the success of sectionalism North or South. Our efforts were
                        unsuccessful, though applied in the right direction, and sectionalism has
                        triumphed over nationality.--Though we are mortified at the success of the
                        Black Republicans in the Presidential election, yet we are rejoiced to know
                        that the elections for Congressmen have resulted in giving us a very safe
                        and decided majority against the Republicans in Congress. The success of the
                        Republicans in the Presidential election is but a barren victory, and its
                        fruits, like the apples of the Dead Sea, will turn to ashes upon their lips.
                        They will have the Executive, but no other branch of the Government, and
                        will, consequently, be impotent for mischief--they will not have the power
                        to do any harm, however much disposed they may be to do so. We have the
                        Senate, the House of Representatives and the Supreme Court in our favor,
                        either one of which would of itself be a sufficient protection to our
                        rights. As we have all three there can, by no possibility, be any danger
                        that our rights can be violated. No law can reach the President for his
                        signature without first having passed <emph rend="italic">both</emph> Houses
                        of Congress, and we know that as at present composed no bill violative of
                        our rights can pass <emph rend="italic">either House</emph>. So that we are
                        perfectly safe. The President cannot even make an appointment without the
                        consent of the Senate, so that we have nothing to dread in that respect. If
                        we remain united we have nothing to fear from the Black Republicans,
                        because, as before stated, we have both Houses of Congress and the Supreme
                        Court in our favor. The danger is in secession. If several of the Southern
                        States secede, they will leave us in a minority in Congress, where we now
                        have a safe majority. This may be the reason why some of the Southern States
                        are in such a hurry to secede. They think that if they secede and leave us
                        at the mercy of a Black Republican majority in Congress, that we will secede
                        likewise. This is the way in which they expect to drag us into a like
                        destiny with them. They will secede when we have a safe majority and there
                        can be no danger, that we may be left in a minority where danger will
                        threaten, in the confident belief that we will then secede and unite our
                        fortunes with theirs. To secede when there can be no danger would be adding
                        cowardice to treason. To give up when we have the game in our own hands
                        would be cowardly, foolish and criminal. South Carolina, and other States
                        disposed to secede, should remember that comity due to neighboring States
                        should restrain them from taking action without consulting the wishes and
                        interests of other States, particularly such as Virginia which is more
                        deeply interested than all the Cotton States combined. As no man has a right
                        to destroy even his own property when by so doing he will endanger that of
                        his neighbor, so no State has the right to secede when that act will involve
                        other States in the common ruin. Virginia has interests independent of the
                        Cotton States, and she should take care of them in spite of the action of
                        those States. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Spectator regrets to inform its readers that the forces of sectionalism
                    triumphed in the election with Lincoln's victory, but feels confident that the
                    South can protect its own interests through the other branches of government,
                    which it still controls. It counsels against secession, which would place the
                    South in unnecessary danger by effectively turning all power over to the
                    Republicans.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/ssnov60.html#11.13a</note>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Union Democrats</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Spectator praises those patriotic Democratic voters who had the courage to
                    break ranks with their party and vote for Bell.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Augusta County, by District</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>
                        <table>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Districts</cell>
                                <cell>Bell</cell>
                                <cell>Douglas</cell>
                                <cell>Breckinridge</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Staunton, Precinct No. 1</cell>
                                <cell>509</cell>
                                <cell>300</cell>
                                <cell>48</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Staunton, Precinct No. 2</cell>
                                <cell>171</cell>
                                <cell>104</cell>
                                <cell>31</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Waynesboro</cell>
                                <cell>168</cell>
                                <cell>102</cell>
                                <cell>13</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Churchville</cell>
                                <cell>155</cell>
                                <cell>20</cell>
                                <cell>5</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Mt. Sidney</cell>
                                <cell>206</cell>
                                <cell>121</cell>
                                <cell>8</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Spring Hill</cell>
                                <cell>56</cell>
                                <cell>37</cell>
                                <cell>1</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Middlebrook</cell>
                                <cell>166</cell>
                                <cell>28</cell>
                                <cell>31</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Greenville</cell>
                                <cell>198</cell>
                                <cell>49</cell>
                                <cell>9</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Fishersville</cell>
                                <cell>82</cell>
                                <cell>24</cell>
                                <cell>3</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>New Hope</cell>
                                <cell>178</cell>
                                <cell>61</cell>
                                <cell>5</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Mt. Meridian</cell>
                                <cell>52</cell>
                                <cell>20</cell>
                                <cell>6</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Mt. Solon</cell>
                                <cell>176</cell>
                                <cell>90</cell>
                                <cell>10</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Deerfield</cell>
                                <cell>82</cell>
                                <cell>7</cell>
                                <cell>2</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Craigsville</cell>
                                <cell>71</cell>
                                <cell>11</cell>
                                <cell>3</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Newport</cell>
                                <cell>86</cell>
                                <cell>12</cell>
                                <cell>6</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Stuart's Draft</cell>
                                <cell>50</cell>
                                <cell>13</cell>
                                <cell>16</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Midway</cell>
                                <cell>36</cell>
                                <cell>13</cell>
                                <cell>2</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Swoope's</cell>
                                <cell>27</cell>
                                <cell>10</cell>
                                <cell>3</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Sherando</cell>
                                <cell>50</cell>
                                <cell>18</cell>
                                <cell>12</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Parnassus</cell>
                                <cell>34</cell>
                                <cell>54</cell>
                                <cell>4</cell>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <cell>Total</cell>
                                <cell>2553</cell>
                                <cell>1094</cell>
                                <cell>218</cell>
                            </row>
                        </table>
                    </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Spectator prints election returns by precinct for Augusta and claims that
                    Augusta's strong Bell vote allows it to be very proud despite national defeat.
                    Final vote tally for the county is 2553 for Bell, 1094 for Douglas, 218 for
                    Beckinridge.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/ssnov60.html#11.13b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Disunionism in Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Spectator criticizes those newspapers, such as the Clarke Journal, that are
                    now waving the "black flag of Disunion." The paper hopes that Union men will
                    unite to save Virginia from falling into the hands of Disunionists.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"I love the South--but I love the Union more."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>"R"</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter to the editor claiming that, while states such as South Carolina
                    move toward secession, Virginia remains conservative and unwilling to break away
                    from its national government. Author praises Virginia as an example for the
                    entire South and calls for a convention of the entire state to express the
                    sentiments of Virginia in this crisis.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Bottom of column 1 is illegible. Vote totals for other counties in Virginia,
                column 3. Electoral vote count by state, column 4. Editorial from the Richmond Whig
                on the election of Lincoln, column 4. Ads and land sales, columns 5-7.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1860.11.13.03">
            <div type="s">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fultz</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lathrop</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fultz</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Lathrop married Miss Fultz on October 30.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baskin</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henry</ln>
                        <fn>Amanda</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on November 8.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Buck</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Humston</ln>
                        <fn>N.Q.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on November 7 in Louisa County. Dr. Humston is from Augusta.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Travis</ln>
                        <fn>J.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanna</ln>
                        <fn>V. Carrie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dunlap</ln>
                        <fn>Madison</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on October 30 at the bride's father's home. Miss Hanna is from
                    Monroe County, Missouri, and Mr. Dunlap is from Augusta.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Willson</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Willson</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Margaret Willson, wife of William Willson, died on October 30 at age 65.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Mostly ads, land sales/auctions, etc. Bottom right is illegible.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1860.11.13.04">
            <pageNote>Advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
