<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1860/va.au.ss.1860.08.21">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Jeff McClurken</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/22/95</tagDate>
            <tagNote>2nd Pass; Josh Rothman did first pass.</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1860-08-21">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="08">August</month>
            <day>21</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1860.08.21.01">
            <pageNote>Page is mostly poetry, literature, moral suggestions, etc. Speech of John J.
                Crittenden of August 2 on the Presidential election, columns 6-7.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1860.08.21.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Douglas Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Douglas Convention which met in this place on Thursday last, was attended
                        by a <emph rend="italic">large</emph> number of delegates. The personel
                        [sic] of the body was very good indeed, much better than Democratic
                        Conventions generally. It was composed of fine-looking and intelligent
                        gentlemen, and the proceedings were not marked by that disorder and
                        "confusion worse confounded" which generally characterize the proceedings of
                        Democratic Conventions. The members did not drink as much mean whiskey as
                        the members in other Democratic Conventions, and consequently were in a
                        better condition to behave themselves. </p>
                    <p>The members of the Douglas Convention were men of spirit and backbone. They
                        seemed to be conscious of their rights as Democrats, and were determined to
                        maintain them at all hazards and to the last extremity. The large majority
                        of them <emph rend="italic">scorned</emph> the idea of affiliating with the
                        Breckinridge party which they denounced as a party of disorganizers and
                        disunionists. The considered the Breckinridge men as mutineers in the ship
                        of Democracy who should be thrown overboard. They were determined to nail
                        the Douglas flag to the mast and, sink or swim, to fight under that flag and
                        no other. The Breckinridge men, feeling that they were about to be driven to
                        the wall, were anxious to unite with the Douglas party, but the latter were
                        resolved to repudiate all propositions of compromise or affiliation. </p>
                    <p>The Convention contained much more talent than we had expected, and conducted
                        its proceedings with order, regularity and propriety.--Every member seemed
                        to be actuated by a firm determination to preserve the regular organization
                        of his party, and to oppose its seceding disorganizers to the bitter end. It
                        was truly gratifying to us to witness such a spirit of devotion to the Union
                        as was manifested by the members of the Convention. They made such good,
                        eloquent and Union-loving speeches that we thought they ought to be members
                        of the great, national, conservative, Constitutional Union Party. That they
                        are patriots we have not a doubt. There was not a member of that body who
                        harbored in the most secret recesses of his heart a single sentiment hostile
                        to the preservation of our Union and the perpetuation of our glorious free
                        institutions. To all they said so eloquently in behalf of the Union, and in
                        execration of treasonable disunionists, our heart responded. It always does
                        our very soul good to heart sound, patriotic, Union-loving sentiments, even
                        when lisped by a faltering and stammering tongue, and when uttered by
                        eloquent lips we can scarcely refrain from shouting aloud in an ecstasy of
                        joy.</p>
                    <p>The speeches were so much in the character of those delivered by the members
                        of the Constitutional Union party, that we sometimes almost forgot that we
                        were in a <emph rend="italic">Democratic</emph> Convention. The Convention
                        was spirited and enthusiastic, and the proceedings were transacted with
                        concord and harmony. In this respect, too, it resembles the Conventions of
                        the Union party more than those of the Democratic party. It contrasted, not
                        only well, but gloriously, with past Democratic Conventions. Were all the
                        disorder and disgraceful scenes which have heretofore characterized
                        Democratic Conventions caused by those who have seceded from the regular
                        organization? The Convention transacted its business in good order; and when
                        it adjourned, after being favored with stirring speeches by several of the
                        members, and the side-shaking anecdotes of Dr. Stovall, each and every
                        member was in a state of joyous exhilaration. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Spectator praises the gathering of Douglas Democrats as "men of spirit and
                    backbone' who scorned the idea of affiliating with Breckinridge Democrats in any
                    way. The paper is proud to have its town be host to a convention of such
                    Union-loving patriotic men.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/ssaug60.html#8.21a</note>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Charlottesville Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Report on the convention of Breckinridge Democrats held in Charlottesville.
                    The Spectator reports that the attempt to fuse the two wings of the Democratic
                    party failed completely as the Charlottesville Democrats approved the course of
                    the Southern Democrats who seceded from the regular Democratic convention.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garber</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Thank-you note from the "Staunton Artillery" to Capt Koiner of the Augusta
                    Rifles, to his entire Company, and to the citizens of Fishersville for the
                    picnic of August 4.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. George Taylor of the Baptist Church is temporarily away raising money
                    for Alleghany College. His brother, Rev. James B. Taylor, Jr., is substituting
                    for him while he is gone.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3-6</column>
                <head>Douglas Convention at Staunton</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yost</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>J.A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M.G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Report of proceedings of the State Democratic Convention of Douglas
                    Democrats, held on August 16-18 in the Staunton Armory near the American Hotel.
                    George Baylor was named temporary chairman. Samuel Yost of the Staunton
                    Vindicator and George M. Cochran, among others, were named Secretaries. Benjamin
                    Crawford was named a permanent Vice-President of the convention. J.A. Harman was
                    placed on a committee to answer well-wishes from the Kentucky state convention.
                    S.M. Yost was placed on the Committee on Resolutions. M.G. Harman was placed on
                    the Executive Committee.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clark</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roper</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James D. Clark married Susan Roper on August 15 at the Virginia Hotel.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1860.08.21.03">
            <pageNote>Advertisements, land sales, auctions, etc. Parts of columns 1-2 have ink
                blotches obscuring some text.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1860.08.21.04">
            <pageNote>Advertisements. Bottom left is blurry. Columns 6-7 have a few ink
            blotches.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
