<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1860/va.au.ss.1860.01.24">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Jeff McClurken</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/22/95</tagDate>
            <tagNote>2nd Pass; Josh Rothman did first pass.</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1860-01-24">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day>24</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1860.01.24.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Mr. Nelson, of Tennessee, on Dissolution</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Excerpted speech of Nelson, an American party member of Congress, at
                    Baltimore, in which he condemned the idea of disunion.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>A Letter from Dr. Livingstone</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Quoted letter from Dr. Livingstone about his travels in Africa, read at a
                    meeting of the Geographical and Statistical Society.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1860.01.24.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Abolitionists and the NY Herald</head>
                <origin>Mobile Register</origin>
                <commentary>Editorial picks up on Mobile Register criticism of New York Herald for
                    secretly collaborating in authorship of Hinton Helper's "Impending Crisis of the
                    South."</commentary>
                <excerpt>"The Herald is the most incendiary sheet published in the country. No one
                    need be surprised to see it supporting Seward in the next Presidential canvass."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Criticizes New York Herald for collaborating with abolitionists.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>South Carolina and the Union</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Praises some South Carolina legislators, such as Wade Hampton and B.F.
                    Perry, for their pro-Union speeches and expresses gratitude to South Carolina
                    for not rushing to disunion.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Mr. Stuart's Speech</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Criticizes the "Vindicator" for misinterpreting the comments of Senator
                    Stuart. The Spectator argues that Stuart praised the local militia for the speed
                    and selflessness with which it rushed to Charlestown, rather than criticized it
                    as the Vindicator claimed.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Death of Macaulay</head>
                <origin>London Globe</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article from London Globe about the death of British author Thomas
                    Salington Macaulay.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Civil, Not Sectional War</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"No one who knows anything of the Northern people believes that they are
                    united in the aggressive anti-slavery movement, or that they even agree in their
                    views of slavery in the abstract."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article summarizing the position of a Rev. Dr. Lord, who argues that the
                    slavery debate will produce a civil war in the North among Northerners rather
                    than an intersectional war. Cites divisions among Northerners on the slavery
                    issue, such as the battles between the New York Herald and the New York Tribune.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Trial of Conspirators</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Virginia State Legislature authorizes a special term for the Circuit
                    Court of Jefferson County in order to try Stephens and Hazlet, two of John
                    Brown's henchmen.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Letter of Dr. Breckenridge</head>
                <origin>Baltimore American</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We have read with deep interest a letter published in the Louisville Journal,
                        by Rev. Robert J. Breckenridge, addressed to his nephew, Vice President
                        Breckenridge. It is one of the most remarkable letters that the present
                        excitement has drawn out. His free criticism of the bad blunder made by the
                        South in the repeal of the Missouri Compromise would hardly be tolerated in
                        anyone else than a clergyman. So too his bold avowal that secession is a
                        revolutionary right--that the election of no man according to the forms of
                        the Constitution would justify any attempt to interfere with the stability
                        of the Union. So too his comment on parties--the absurdity of the South
                        claiming that slavery is carried into the Territories by the Constitution
                        are vividly presented. He maintains that the parties really having cause to
                        complain are the citizens of Maryland, Virginia, Kentucky and Missouri, that
                        the cotton States have no excuse for their disunion threats. He appeals to
                        Pennsylvania, Ohio, Indiana and Illinois, to rally to the Union, that these
                        central States, on either side of the supposed line of separation cannot and
                        will not tolerate a dissolution of the Union. <emph rend="italic">Balt.
                            Amer.</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Baltimore American</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Summarizes letter of Rev. Robert J. Breckenridge to his nephew, Vice
                    President John C. Breckenridge, in which he rejects the right to secession and
                    any contribution of the South to the instability of the Union. He calls on the
                    border states to rally to the Union.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/ssjan60.html#1.24a</note>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Giddings and Others Summoned</head>
                <origin>Cleveland Plain Dealer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Plain Dealer reports that Joshua Giddings, Ralph Plumb and John Brown,
                    Jr., have been subpoenaed to appear before the Harper's Ferry Investigating
                    Committee to tell what they know about the "Sons of Liberty" and any other
                    organization connected with John Brown's activities in Kansas. The Sons of
                    Liberty at West Andover and Oberlin, Ohio, have both refused to obey any
                    summons.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>New York Evening Post</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Post denies the statement of the New York Herald that Southern travel
                    to New York hotels has dropped off as a result of the slavery agitation.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schreckhise</ln>
                        <fn>J.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chittum</ln>
                        <fn>William Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ludwick</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on January 5th. All are from Rockbridge.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strayer</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moore</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moore</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Givens</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Colonel</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on January 12.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shry</ln>
                        <fn>Julia Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shry</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shry</ln>
                        <fn>Annie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Julia Shry died January 5, age 1 year.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>bottom left is blurry. Column 3 has political gossip under title of
                "Washington Facts and Speculations." Weekly proceedings of State Legislature, column
                4; Congress, column 5.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1860.01.24.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Coming Horror</head>
                <origin>Cincinnati Enquirer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Editorial quoted from the Cincinnati Enquirer regarding the possibility of
                    Ohio and other states following the lead of Arkansas in excluding free blacks
                    from their territories to avoid being "overrun by this swarm of the destitute
                    and improvident."</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Political announcements of people running for county offices printed in column
                2, as usual. Ordinance concerning damage to lampposts and other public property
                printed in column 1.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1860.01.24.04">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
