<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1860/va.au.ss.1860.07.24">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Jeff McClurken</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/22/95</tagDate>
            <tagNote>2nd Pass; Josh Rothman did first pass.</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1860-07-24">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day>24</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1860.07.24.01">
            <pageNote>Column 5 has a story entitled "The Sight of a Beautiful Blind Girl Restored by
                Marriage." Most of the page is full of literary stories, poetry, and morality tales.
                Columns 6 and 7 contain letters to the editor, but none with local names or
                relevance to local events. Bottom half of column 7 is illegible.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1860.07.24.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1-2</column>
                <head>Will You Assist the Election of Lincoln?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Spectator argues that the split of the Democratic party, especially the
                    nomination of a particularly Southern ticket, can only assist in Lincoln's
                    election by dividing the Democratic vote. Douglas was the only candidate with a
                    chance at victory, but even he probably would be unsuccessful. Calls on voters
                    to elect Bell and Everett to avert Lincoln's election.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Steamship Burnt</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>P.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Story about the burning of the Steamship Pennsylvania off of Jamestown.
                    People were killed, and the local firm of P.H. Trout &amp; Co. lost $500
                    worth of merchandise.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Wesleyan Institute</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Arbogast</ln>
                        <fn>B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCaulay</ln>
                        <fn>J.A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announcement that Rev. J.A. McCauley has been elected to replace Rev. B.
                    Arbogast as head of the Wesleyan Female Institute.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Waynesboro' Hotel</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bruce</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announcement that George A. Bruce has opened a hotel at Waynesboro.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Democratic Meetings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In pursuance of the published announcements of last week, both wings of the
                        divided Democracy held meetings at the Court House on yesterday. The one
                        endorsing the secession nominee, and appointing delegates to the
                        Charlottesville Convention, and the other endorsing the regular nominees and
                        appointing delegates to the Staunton Convention, both of which conventions
                        will meet on the same day, August 16th. They both adopted the same
                        resolution in reference to uniting the party upon a single electoral
                        ticket--the vote to be given to whichever ticket would carry most electoral
                        votes in the States other than Virginia--thus giving Virginia no voice in
                        the election, but to echo that of the other States--transferring the Douglas
                        votes to Breckinridge, or the Breckinridge votes to Douglas as the votes of
                        other States may determine -- trampling upon States Rights, especially the
                        rights of Virginia.</p>
                    <p>The Douglas meeting was first held, and then gave way for the Secessionists.
                        After both meetings had adjourned, the people assembled were addressed by
                        Ex-Gov. Wm. Smith, Ex-Lieut. Gov. Shelton F. Leake, Dr. Saml. Moffett, of
                        Rockingham, Gen. Harman, Jas. H. Skinner, Esq., Jno. A. Harman, Esq., and
                        the Castor and Pollux of Democracy, Jacob and George Baylor, Esqs.</p>
                    <p>As our form was nearly made up when these meetings adjourned, we have been
                        prevented for want of time and space, from commenting upon the proceedings
                        and speeches as we otherwise would have done. It was the universal
                        expectation that Messrs. Smith and Leake would boldly attempt to</p>
                    <p>"Beard the lion in his den <lb/>And the Douglas in his hall." </p>
                    <p>but the people were sadly disappointed, for they "roared him as gently as a
                        sucking dove."</p>
                    <p>Dr. Moffett's manner showed very clearly that he was prepared and was anxious
                        to meet the celebrated champions of the secessionists if they were disposed
                        to enter the lists; but as they refrained from discussing the issues between
                        the two wings of the party, and as the olive branch was tendered and
                        accepted in the resolution to which we have referred, he was prevented from
                        making a vigorous onslaught upon the secessionists, as he would have dome
                        under other circumstances.</p>
                    <p>Without any purpose to disparage the efforts of the other speakers, we must
                        say that there was more good sense and patriotism in one sentence of the
                        speech of John A. Harman, Esq., than in all the other speeches together. He
                        said that he would take back all he had ever said against the Union--that he
                        was now a Union man up to the hub, and was in favor of throwing all the
                        disunion democrats over-board. He said, too, that he did not want any more
                        "silk-stocking, hifalutin swell-heads"--that they had too many of them now.</p>
                    <p>The Union doctrines are beginning to take hold upon the hearts of the people.
                        The Union men supporting the Union ticket have great encouragement to
                        prosecute vigorously their good work. "Look with hope for to-morrow," for a
                        glorious victory is beckoning to you its embrace. She will not slight you
                        and "kick" you, as the girl did Extra-Billy who gave him the "rule" and the
                        "mitten," but not her heart and hand. Work in the good cause and "look with
                        hope for to- morrow."</p>
                    <p>At the close of the meeting, Jacob Baylor, Esq., stepped upon the rostrum,
                        and swinging his hat over his head, shouted, "Three cheers for the United
                        Democracy." But the cheers were not forthcoming--like the "spirits of the
                        vasty deep" they were called for, but would not appear. The Democrats were
                        dumb, and the assembled Whigs burst into laughter at the very ridiculous
                        spectacle presented.</p>
                    <p>Want of space prevents us from publishing the resolutions of the two meetings
                        in this issue.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Esq.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Esq.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Esq.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Esq.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Report of meetings held by both wings of the Democratic party at the
                    Staunton Court House, one endorsing the secessionists and nominating delegates
                    to the convention to be held at Charlottesville, the other endorsing the regular
                    Democrats and nominating delegates to the convention to be held in Staunton.
                    After both meetings, the people were addressed by a number of individuals,
                    including Gen. Harman, James H. Skinner, John A. Harman, Jacob Baylor and George
                    Baylor.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/ssjuly60.html#7.24a</note>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Two Conventions</head>
                <origin>Valley Democrat</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Excerpted article from the "Valley Democrat" which calls on Virginians to
                    reject the secessionist Democrats and unite at the convention to be held at
                    Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. George Walker of Augusta County married Margaret M. Huston of
                    Rockingham at the home of A.M. Effinger in Harrisonburg.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>"R"</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Matheny</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Matheny</ln>
                        <fn>Peachy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary Ann Matheny died on May 31, 1860 at age 28. She was the daughter of
                    the late Peachy Matheny of Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>"J"</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn>Eliza</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Points</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Eliza C. Grove, wife of John Grove and daughter of the late David Points,
                    died on June 28 at age 32. John David Grove, her infant son, died as well, aged
                    3 weeks.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>In column 1, Spectator offers subscriptions at low rates until the
                Presidential election and urges people to circulate copies of the paper at political
                clubs. Page is scattered with bits of political news and rumors, especially about
                and in support of the Bell/Everett ticket.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1860.07.24.03">
            <pageNote>Page is mostly advertisements, land sales, etc.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1860.07.24.04">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
