<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1860/va.au.ss.1860.02.14">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Jeff McClurken</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/22/95</tagDate>
            <tagNote>2nd Pass; Josh Rothman did first pass.</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1860-02-14">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day>14</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1860.02.14.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Letter from Hon. A.H.H. Stuart</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reprint of a letter from State Senator Stuart to the Committee of
                    Invitation for the Bailie Peyton Festival in Philadelphia. Stuart regrets that
                    he cannot attend, but uses the opportunity to expound on the mutually beneficial
                    relations between the sections and on the need to avoid intersectional
                    animosity. He severely criticizes both national parties for being sectional in
                    nature and contributing to intersectional hostility. He calls for the creation
                    and support of a National Union party to dedicate itself to the preservation of
                    the Union and to intersectional peace.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Nelson</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fultz</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Writer criticizes David Fultz for his claim that Judge Thompson has failed
                    to clear court dockets and produces documentation from the County Clerk of
                    Nelson County that shows that Judge Thompson is an extremely efficient judge and
                    a learned man.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Bottom right is blotchy and hard to read.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1860.02.14.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Report on the Harper's Ferry Outrages--Hon. Alex H.H. Stuart</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Editorial on the State Legislature's report on the Harper's Ferry raid,
                    written by Augusta State Senator Stuart. The report details the planning and
                    execution of the raid as well as a history of the slavery controversy and an
                    account of Republican party activities. It recommends action for preparing
                    Virginia for its own defense. Spectator has much praise for Senator Stuart's
                    service as head of the Joint Committee on Harper's Ferry as well as for his
                    service in the Legislature in general, and suggests he would be a fine choice as
                    an Opposition party candidate for President.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Fair</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The ladies of Staunton will hold a Fair at Union Hall this week to raise
                    money for ornamenting the grounds of Thornrose Cemetary.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Extension of the Town Limits</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>T.L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shumate</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Discusses the bill for the extension of the boundaries of Staunton. Argues
                    that the Vindicator printed a copy of the bill hoping to gain approval of the
                    voters. The Town Council approves of the extension, but the Spectator believes
                    that the proposed legislation would have an adverse impact on the town. It will
                    require the building of new roads and the extension of new facilities to the new
                    residents of the town. The taxes brought in by the new residents will not be
                    enough to counter these expenditures and the tax burden will thus increase for
                    all.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Adventures of an Augusta Convict</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parrott</ln>
                        <fn>Harrison</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Summarizes the "adventures" of Harrison Parrott, a convict who escaped from
                    custody and hid in the mountains near Covington with another convict before
                    being captured.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Homespun</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fultz</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The author writes to express his resentment toward the Spectator's policy
                    of printing letters that criticize or support candidates for office written by
                    random citizens. The author writes that he is entitled to make up his own mind
                    without the interference of other's opinions. He especially resents the
                    criticisms of David Fultz by supporters of Judge Thompson.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Culpeper Lands</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>D.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wise</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Spectator is happy that Messrs. Kennedy and Wise were able to purchase such
                    a fine farm in Culpeper, but regrets losing valuable citizens. Prints the farm's
                    previous production as well as a description of the land by the Culpeper
                    Observer.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>The People</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Author is critical of Judge Thompson and his supporters and argues that the
                    Circuit Court's docket still has 1,995 cases on it. Suggests that as the judge
                    gets older, he will only get slower and further behind.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Staunton Vindicator</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>Bolivar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Item from the Vindicator indicating that Bolivar Christian, Staunton
                    Representative, voted for the appropriation of funds for the volunteers who
                    served at Charlestown.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Acknowledgements</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>Polmer "is now after the Sheriffalty 'with a long pole,' and if as
                    successful with the people as he has been with the ladies he will get it."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Polmer</ln>
                        <fn>P.O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notice of the wedding celebration of P.O. Polmer, candidate for Sheriff.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>P.G. Seele</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seele</ln>
                        <fn>P.G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>P.G. Seele responds to "Long Glade and Mossy Creek" and writes that he has
                    made no agreements or deals concerning the election for Sheriff.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Stevens and Hazlett</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Report of the proceedings of the Circuit Court in Charlestown, where
                    Stevens and Hazlett were both convicted of their crimes in association with John
                    Brown's raid.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Rockbridge</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letter writer takes authors of previous letters to the Spectator (R.L.J.
                    and "Z." in particular) to task for fudging figures in order to support the
                    efficiency of Judge Thompson. In reality, the author argues, Thompson's
                    supporters have neither explained the 1,995 cases still on the court's docket
                    nor how Thompson's reelection would make him proceed more quickly with the
                    court's business.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Inhuman Murder</head>
                <origin>Petersburg Express</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Report of the murder of Dr. William S. Croxton, of Essex County, by two of
                    his female slaves. The slaves killed Croxton with a grubbing hoe and an axe and
                    then burned the body. An item from the Petersburg Express gives details of the
                    plot.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Weekly proceedings of State Legislature, column 4; of Congress, column
            5.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1860.02.14.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Union Counsels</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prints a letter of William C. Rives, in which he argues that Virginia and
                    the South would be ill-served by secession. Secession incorrectly assumes that
                    all the southern states have the same interests. Virginia, for example, with its
                    emphasis on tobacco production, has different interests than the cotton states.
                    This being the case, working out problems within the structure of the Union is
                    wisest.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Attempted Arrest of Coppic</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Report of the attempt and failure in Des Moines, Iowa, to arrest the
                    younger brother of Edwin Coppic, who was executed for his participation in John
                    Brown's Raid.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Latane</ln>
                        <fn>J.A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foster</ln>
                        <fn>R.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Esq.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stribling</ln>
                        <fn>Fannie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stribling</ln>
                        <fn>F.T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on February 9. Miss Stribling is from Augusta and Mr. Foster is
                    from Richmond.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brooke</ln>
                        <fn>G.G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Markwood</ln>
                        <fn>Ben</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Williams</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on February 7.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bear</ln>
                        <fn>Noah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pullins</ln>
                        <fn>M.E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Noah Bear of Rockingham married M.E. Pullins on February 9 at the American
                    Hotel, Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements, land sales, etc.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1860.02.14.04">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
