<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1860/va.au.ss.1860.02.07">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Jeff McClurken</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/22/95</tagDate>
            <tagNote>2nd Pass; Josh Rothman did first pass.</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1860-02-07">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day norm="07">7</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1860.02.07.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>A Lynchburg Darkey in High Life</head>
                <origin>Lynchburg Virginian</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Story of a slave who "passed" for white in Pittsburgh. The slave, named Bob
                    Burwell, had been a bar-tender in Lynchburg until his purchase by a celebrated
                    forger named Cross. Cross had always treated Burwell as his equal, so no one in
                    Pittsburgh realized that Burwell was actually his slave. After Cross was
                    arrested, Burwell voluntarily went back to Lynchburg to mortgage himself and
                    raise money for Cross's aid.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Letter of Rev. Dr. Breckinridge to the Hon. John C. Breckinridge</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lengthy letter from Rev. Breckinridge to his nephew, the Vice President.
                    This is the letter that the editorial in the January 31 issue discussed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1860.02.07.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Democracy and Slavery</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>John Brown embarked in his insane enterprise against Virginia under the
                        mistaken notion that he would find sympathizers in the State, who would
                        gather around his standard at the first sound of a bugle. He did not
                        anticipate accessions to his small band of desperate and determined men from
                        the negro population alone, but confidently believed that many of the free
                        white citizens of the Commonwealth, who he imagined to be anti-slavery in
                        sentiment, were ready and anxious to rally under the banner of a bold leader
                        and strike for the liberty of the slaves. It is an admitted fact that such
                        was the impression of the deluded man in regard to the state of sentiment in
                        Virginia, and although the delusion may seem strange at first blush, we are
                        constrained to admit when looking back upon the political struggles of the
                        past in this State, that John Brown was in some degree justified in the
                        belief that Virginia was ripe for the "irrepressible conflict." The leader
                        of the army of invasion was the old <emph rend="italic">old</emph> John
                        Brown,--a man well up in years--who had watched with the keen eye of
                        fanaticism the progress of political events in this country for the last
                        twenty years, and marked their bearings upon the great idea of his life--the
                        one grand object of his aspirations and efforts--the liberation of the
                        slaves from their bondage. It is not reasonable to suppose that he was an
                        indifferent spectator to the fierce conflicts of parties in Virginia. On the
                        contrary, the last steps of his career upon the soil of our State, as the
                        avowed leader of a crusade against slavery and slaveholders, even to
                        bloodshed and death, is of itself sufficient to establish the fact that he
                        had been watching the course of affairs in the State of Virginia with
                        special and peculiar interest. And what had he learned from the conflicts of
                        the last twenty years, and heard with exultation from the lips of
                        politicians and papers of the Democratic party? To those who are familiar
                        with the political history of the State it is scarcely necessary to say that
                        from them he heard, probably for the first time, of a difference of
                        sentiment among the people of Virginia on the subject of negro slavery. From
                        them he learned, not that a few of the people, but that a large and imposing
                        party, led on by men of acknowledged talents and ability, were regarded with
                        distrust by their fellow citizens and denounced as unsound and unworthy to
                        be trusted by the South with the power of either the Federal or State
                        government. He heard it as far back as 1836 when the "great Commoner" of
                        Kentucky, a Southern man and slave owner, was denounced as unworthy of
                        Southern confidence and support, and those who sustained him were charged
                        with disloyalty to their section and its "peculiar institution." He heard of
                        it again in 1840, and 1848, and 1852, when the same groundless and unjust
                        charges were proffered against Harrison and Taylor and Scott, together with
                        all who sustained those true and loyal sons of the South in those memorable
                        contests. He heard it in still louder tones in the gubernatorial election of
                        1851, when Geo. W. Summers, the gallant standard bearer of the Whigs, was
                        held up for his inspection and admiration as an abolitionist "to the manner
                        born," and the thousands who gathered around the banner which he bore so
                        gallantly, were denounced and defamed as affiliating with and lending aid
                        and comfort to the enemies of the South. </p>
                    <p>But not only during the political campaigns had John Brown heard this
                        cheering intelligence of the progress of anti-slavery opinions in the State
                        of Virginia.--Pending the discussion of every measure bearing upon the
                        question of slavery, he had heard the same charge ringing from the hustings
                        and the press against many of the greatest and best of Virginia's sons. The
                        sound had been listened to so long that it grew familiar, and it is not
                        surprising that it received credit. When so many concurred in the statement
                        that a vast number of the people of Virginia, were "doughfaces" and
                        "submissionists," and thousands of other sympathisers with the anti-slavery
                        sentiment of the North, is it to be wondered at that John Brown believed the
                        thing to be true, and addressed himself to the consummation of his grand
                        project with the confident expectation of finding all things ready for the
                        crisis? Like many others who have put faith in the Democracy, however, he
                        was most egregiously deceived.</p>
                    <p>Without holding the Democratic party directly responsible for the bloody
                        scenes at Harper's Ferry, we are fully persuaded that it is responsible to a
                        certain extent for that delusion in regard to the sentiments of Virginia,
                        which lured old Brown to his doom. We had hoped that the men of that party
                        would have seen the civil consequences of such a mode of warfare,
                        counterbalancing in our opinion all the advantages to be derived from a mere
                        party success, and that the scenes of the bloody drama on our borders, to
                        which men of all parties rushed for the defense of a common soil, would have
                        put an end to all aspersions upon the soundness of Virginia on this question
                        of slavery. But we have been disappointed. We find the Democratic papers
                        still virulent in the abuse of all who do not square up to their ideas of
                        what a Southern man should be. We find them setting up an "armory bill" in
                        the Legislature of the State as a test of soundness on the slavery question,
                        and holding up those who resist it as an unnecessary and extravagant
                        measure, as recreant to the State that gave them birth; and especially are
                        they violent against those who are most likely to be in their way in the
                        effort to perpetuate the power of the Democratic party. Thus do they
                        endeavor to perpetuate a "reign of terror" under which so many destitute of
                        "back-bone" have been dragooned into their ranks. We are mistaken, however,
                        if such treatment will do any good either to the Democratic party or the
                        South. Men of sense will not be driven into all sorts of folly because John
                        Brown invaded Virginia, nor frightened from their propriety by charges of
                        unsoundness that have been rung against them all their lives.--The Democracy
                        may turn the Harper's Ferry affair to their advantage, as they have
                        generally managed everything connected with slavery for the furtherance of
                        their party schemes; but they will find it a mere temporary advantage. The
                        conservatism of Virginia cannot be thus crushed out.</p>
                    <p>There is a party, however, that will be built up and encouraged by the course
                        of the Democracy toward those who differ with them in political opinion, as
                        it has been built up and encouraged in times past. The Democratic leaders
                        had been telling Brown that there were those in Virginia who sympathized
                        with him, until a conviction of the truth of the statement was forced upon
                        him. Satisfied that he would find helpers he came on his bloody mission.
                        There are other John Browns at the North still, and ex. Gov. Wise is still
                        telling them in his public speeches, which are scattered far and wide at the
                        North, that there are "helpers of Helper" even in the Metropolis of
                        Virginia. Often repeated it will be believed, and whenever satisfied that
                        the "helpers" are sufficiently numerous, the bereaved followers of Brown
                        will choose his successor for another descent upon our borders.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Editorial argues that it is not surprising that John Brown believed many
                    white Virginians would rally to his cause at Harper's Ferry. Spectator blames
                    the Democrats for accusing those who do not agree with them entirely as being
                    disloyal to slavery and to the South. This gives the impression that Virginians
                    are not united in their devotion to slavery and the South, and thus contributed
                    to the fanaticism of John Brown and to the impression among other fanatics of
                    the North that there is sympathy for the anti-slavery cause in Virginia.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/ssfeb60.html#2.7a</note>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sen.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Quoted text of Sen. Stuart's remarks in the State Senate with respect to
                    payment of expenses related to the Harper's Ferry invasion, printed "at the
                    request of the editor of the Vindicator."</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Extension of Town Limits</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Report that the Town Council of Staunton approved a plan to enlarge the
                    boundaries of the town and transmitted the plan to the General Assembly for
                    approval.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Report that the new Liberty dime has been issued by the mint and that "the
                    new coin is very pretty."</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Old Fogy States</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Comment that Tennessee and Kentucky have sent representatives to Ohio as if
                    the states still shared a fraternal spirit. Suggests sarcastically that South
                    Carolina should send a delegation to the states to inform them of the current
                    state of affairs.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Harper's Ferry Investigation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Report of the proceedings of the Congressional committee investigating the
                    raid at Harper's Ferry.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Report on the Harper's Ferry Affair</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Printed copy of the resolutions of the committee of the state legislature
                    on the Harper's Ferry incident.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Trial of Stevens</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Report of the beginning of the trial of Stevens, one of John Brown's
                    henchmen, at the Circuit Court of Jefferson County.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Weekly proceedings of State Legislature, column 4; of Congress, column
            5.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1860.02.07.03">
            <div type="l">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Election of Judge</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>R.L.J.</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fultz</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letter praising Judge Thompson's abilities as Circuit Court Judge and
                    defending Thompson against the criticisms of Mr. Fultz and his supporters.
                    Amasses court statistics to demonstrate the speed with which Thompson proceeds
                    through the court docket.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>To Long Glade and Mossy Creek</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>James M. Lilley</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lilley</ln>
                        <fn>James M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lilley responds to the accusation of "Long Glade and Mossy Creek" and
                    denies that he is part of any agreement to distribute deputyships after the
                    election for Sheriff.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>John J. Larew</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Larew</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Larew denies the accusation of "Long Glade and Mossy Creek" that he is part
                    of any combination to distribute deputyships after the election of Sheriff.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>To Long Glade and Mossy Creek</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Henry H. Peck</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peck</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Peck denies that he is part of any combination to distribute deputyships
                    after the election of Sheriff.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palmer</ln>
                        <fn>P.O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lamb</ln>
                        <fn>Eliza</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on February 2.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blain</ln>
                        <fn>J.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bailey</ln>
                        <fn>H.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rutlidge</ln>
                        <fn>Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on January 26 near Deerfield, Augusta.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>"D"</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Young died at his home near Tinkling Springs Church on February 3
                    at age 78.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>S.B.C.</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blair</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Blair died January 24 at his home near Parnassus.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1860.02.07.04">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
