<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1860/va.au.ss.1860.01.31">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Jeff McClurken</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/22/95</tagDate>
            <tagNote>2nd Pass; Josh Rothman did first pass.</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1860-01-31">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day>31</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1860.01.31.01">
            <div type="l">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>JUSTICE</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fultz</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Writer places responsibility for delays in trials and logjams on court
                    dockets upon lawyers and witnesses rather than on Judge Thompson. Defends Judge
                    Thompson's bid for re-election.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Bottom right is blotchy and blurry</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1860.01.31.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>State of the Country</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Of all the letters from distinguished men which the present political
                        excitement has called forth, we have read none which seems to us to meet the
                        case at all points so satisfactorily as the one addressed by the Rev. Dr.
                        Breckenridge, of Kentucky, to his nephew, the Vice-President of the United
                        States. Dr. Breckenridge declares that the settled and deliberate conviction
                        of Kentucky is that the dissolution of the Union is no remedy for anything
                        whatever, but that it is itself the direst of all calamities. Kentucky has
                        been exposed, along a frontier of seven hundred miles, to greater evils than
                        all the slave States which have no free frontier put together; yet she has
                        never entertained a single thought of secession. It is Maryland, Virginia,
                        Kentucky and Missouri that have bourne all the losses and annoyance, and are
                        to bear all the impending peril. To these States, therefore, the decision of
                        the national aspects of these impending perils emphatically appertains. In
                        like manner the border free States ought to remember that their borders are
                        as much exposed as ours; so that on them, with reference to the free States
                        behind them, rest the duty and the right of deciding the national aspect of
                        the subject of slavery on the free side of the line. It may be confidently
                        asserted that posterity will hold these border States, on both sides,
                        responsible for the fate of the nation, if they permit the country to be
                        ruined, and themselves to be thrown into a position of endless mutual
                        hostility, along a common frontier of fifteen hundred miles.</p>
                    <p>The true remedy for such disorders as we complain of is not in the breaking
                        up of the Government, but in the due enforcement of the laws. When any part
                        of the country refuses to respect the laws, the proper course is to take up
                        arms and compel obedience. Says Dr. Breckenridge:</p>
                    <p>"Civil war itself within the Union, horrible as civil war always is, is
                        necessarily temporary, and is consistent with the ultimate preservation of
                        everything distinctive in our present nationality, and in all our
                        institutions, general and particular; and a universal civil war at this time
                            <emph rend="italic">within the Union</emph> could hardly fail to end in
                        the permanent establishment, for the whole country, of just what our fathers
                        established from 1776 to 1789. But after the division of the Union upon the
                        slave line, and the necessary breaking out of fierce and interminable war
                        along the frontier extending from the Atlantic Ocean to the western border
                        of Missouri, no man can foresee a state of case when peace can ever be
                        preserved along that frontier as well as it can be in the Union, and every
                        man can see that any future union of the divided portions of the
                        Confederacy, if any union shall ever be possible, must be upon the very
                        terms which now exist. </p>
                    <p>It is alleged, however, that there is the utmost probability that a Northern
                        anti-slavery party will ultimately acquire controlling influence over every
                        department of the Federal Government, and that the slave States cannot,
                        consistently with honor, continue members of a Union controlled by such a
                        party.</p>
                    <p>"To this let me say," continues Dr. B., "first of all, that if every word
                        were true and certain, the wise, manly and successful alternative would be,
                        not the dissolution of the Union, but the recovery of the country, by force
                        if necessary, from those who shall have subverted its Constitution. Nor can
                        there be any doubt that the united South and the minority of the North will
                        be always and to every intent, without arms or with arms, more powerful in
                        the Union than the united, much less the divided South, can ever be out of
                        it. Nor does it appear to me to be loyal to the people of the North who are
                        faithful to the Constitution, even if they were the smaller number, for the
                        South to withdraw and leave them subject to a domination as intolerable to
                        them as it is offensive to us."</p>
                    <p>We can hardly doubt that if the real feelings and wishes of the people, North
                        and South, could be represented at Washington, uninfluenced by partizan
                        [sic] bias, the whole matter in controversy would soon be settled without
                        difficulty. How stands the case? The Republicans at the North generally
                        disclaim any intention or desire to interfere with slavery as it exists in
                        the Southern States, but profess to believe that it is the settled policy of
                        the South, by means of the Federal government, to extend slavery throughout
                        the country; and to resist this encroachment of the "slave power" as they
                        call it, they are organized into a political party. On the other hand, the
                        South generally believes that the Northern majority are banded together to
                        wage a fanatical crusade against the institution. The long continued and
                        virulent abuse of slavery and slave- holders by Republican speakers and
                        writers certainly encourages the impression alluded to. Admitting, for the
                        sake of argument, that slavery is a bad institution, it is difficult to tell
                        why those who have no responsibility on account of it, and no control over
                        it, should persist in denouncing it, unless they desire to raise a crusade
                        for its extermination. But if the Republicans are sincere in their formal
                        declarations, there need be little difficulty in coming to an amicable
                        settlement. With the exception of a few extreme men at the South, the people
                        of this section are not "slavery propagandists"--they have no desire to
                        carry slavery into any Territory now free, and it is not their interest to
                        do so.--They could give profitable employment to many more slaves than they
                        now hold, and the institution would only be weakened by being diffused.
                        They, however, with reason, object to being told that they shall not do what
                        they believe that they have a Constitutional right to do, although they have
                        no idea of doing it. Why then cannot all parties and both sections agree to
                        let the matter alone and cease agitation. Soil and climate will, without
                        doubt, ultimately settle the boundaries of slave and free territory to the
                        satisfaction of all reasonable people.</p>
                    <p>Should all efforts to restore peace to the country fail, we fall back upon
                        Dr. Breckenridge's idea. He says:</p>
                    <p>"The firm determination of every portion of the Union to maintain its rights
                        within the Union, under every extremity, would soon put an end to all
                        necessity for any portion of it to elect between terrible means of doing so.
                        It is horrible to reflect that the children of the Revolution might be
                        obliged to shed each others blood. How much more horrible to shed it in such
                        a manner that oceans of it could never restore what we had destroyed, while
                        every drop of it would be an eternal testimony against our folly!"</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Praises the letter of Rev. Dr. Breckenridge to his nephew, the Vice
                    President, in which Dr. Breckenridge argues that disunion is a cause of national
                    calamities rather than a solution to them. The Spectator agrees with the letter
                    writer that as a border state, Virginia stands to lose more in the event of
                    disunion than most states. Spectator calls for enforcement of the current laws
                    in order to forestall disunion. The Spectator believes that, if the Republican
                    party is sincere in its intentions not to attack slavery in the Southern states,
                    there should be no difficulty in settling the slavery debate, as most
                    Southerners have no desire to bring slaves into currently free territories.
                    Ponders the horrors of secession and calls for an end to agitation.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/ssjan60.html#1.31a</note>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>New Party</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Editorial about the creation and meeting of an Opposition National Party in
                    Philadelphia.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Military</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Report of a military gathering and announcement of the first public
                    appearance of the "Staunton Artillery" on February 22.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>A Big Purchase</head>
                <origin>Culpeper Observer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>D.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wine</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notice of a purchase of a large estate in Culpeper County by two Staunton
                    men.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Board of Visitors</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>J.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Esq.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harmon</ln>
                        <fn>W.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>General</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Colonel</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>List of Board of Visitors of the Virginia Institute for the Deaf and Dumb
                    and Blind, including three Staunton men.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Power of the Democratic Party</head>
                <origin>Baltimore American</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The hard common sense of the people, slow to arouse, is at last awakened
                    to the incompetence if not the infidelity of those to whom they have so long
                    trusted, and the absurd pretensions of the Democracy will not again be believed
                    until the strange conviction has lodged itself in the public mind that black is
                    white, and that pouring oil upon fire is the best mode of stopping a
                    conflagration."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A Southern Democratic journal, commenting upon the recent able and
                        praiseworthy address of the Central Committee of the opposition in
                        Mississippi, exclaims, "The Whig party has disappeared in the Union. The
                        American party is powerless everywhere." In reply to these assertions, it
                        should be seen that nothing more was needed than to refer to the fact that
                        they emancipate from a source rarely accused of simple accuracy in
                        connection with matters of party bias.</p>
                    <p>Any man capable of putting two and two together can predict with absolute
                        certainty what must follow the sentences quoted at the outsetting of this
                        article. "There is but one organization in the country retaining vitality
                        and force sufficient to make it a serious and hopeful resistance to Blak
                        Republican ascendancy in the councils and government of the Confederacy--and
                        that is the Democratic party." Of course, of course. The sun shines; one and
                        one make two; three thirds make a whole; there are four quarters to the
                        globe; day follows night; night follows day--how plain, how very plain it
                        all is. And yet the Black Republican party came into existence during the
                        Democratic administration, it has continued to grow and prosper while the
                        Democratic power was in power; it has received no serious check from
                        Democracy, nay, if the truth were told we fear it would be found that the
                        Black Republican party owes its very existence and every stage of its growth
                        to the unwisdom of that very organization which now so loudly vaunts that it
                        alone has force and vitality enough to oppose a serious and hopeful
                        resistance to Seward's ascendancy. What would be thought of as a sentinel
                        who having permitted the enemy to overrun the camp or failed to arrest them,
                        should repair to the commander-in-chief with the braggart and impudent
                        assertion that he must be retained in the post of honor and of danger,
                        because, forsooth, he alone is capable of holding it against all odds? And
                        if it were ascertained that this same sentinel, so boastful of his prowess,
                        had himself broken down the barrier and invited the enemy into camp? Yet
                        this is precisely the position of the Democratic party at this hour. The
                        hard common sense of the people, slow to arouse, is at last awakened to the
                        incompetency if not the infidelity of those whom they have so long trusted,
                        and the absurd pretensions of the Democracy will not again be believed until
                        the strange conviction has lodged in the public mind that black is white and
                        pouring oil upon fire is the best mode of stopping a conflagration. We by no
                        means believe what our Southern contemporary has ascribed about the Whig and
                        American parties, but, be the truth what it may in reference to those
                        organizations, one thing remains fixed in the popular judgement beyond the
                        chance of removal, and that is this: The Black Republican party has openly
                        avowed its sectionary and incendiary designs, and the Democratic party has
                            <emph rend="italic">proved</emph> its inability to cope with its
                        sectional antagonist. Therefore the people have no option other than to go
                            <emph rend="italic">outside</emph> of those parties if they would save
                        the country from ruin.--<emph rend="italic">Balt. American</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Baltimore American</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Baltimore American editorial severely criticizes a "Southern Democratic
                    journal" for arguing that the Democratic Party is the only viable protector of
                    Southern interests in politics. In reality, the editorial claims, the
                    Republicans rose to power under the watch of a Democratic administration and the
                    Democrats are partially to blame for the lack of checks against Republican
                    growth.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/ssjan60.html#1.31b</note>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>A Farmer</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fultz</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letter criticizes Mr. Fultz' qualifications to serve as Circuit Court Judge
                    and calls on voters to support the reelection of Judge Thompson.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>To James M. Lilly, John J. Larew, Henry H. Peck and Peter G. Steele</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Long Glade and Mossy Creek</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lilly</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Larew</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peck</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Steele</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Polmer</ln>
                        <fn>Phillip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letter writer accuses candidates for Sheriff of making a deal to make the
                    others deputies if one is elected. The writer calls for the candidates to answer
                    the charges. Exempts Capt. Phillip O. Polmer from this inquiry, as he has
                    already made his positions clear.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Union Feeling at the South</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Report of the resolution of a Union meeting held in Knoxville, Tennessee.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Observer</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Suggests abolishing the Corporation Court, arguing that many local
                    establishments violate licensing laws and are not prosecuted in Corporation
                    Courts. Calls for licenses to be placed under jurisdiction of the County Court.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Harper's Ferry Investigation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Summarizes proceedings at the investigation of the Harper's Ferry raid
                    occurring in Washington.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henton</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Esq.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Esq.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Elizabeth L. Wilson married David Henton on January 26.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blair</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Blair died near Parnassus on January 24.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Michael Hanger died at age 36 of heart disease in Missouri. He was the son
                    of David and Mary Hanger, formerly of Augusta.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Weekly proceedings of State Legislature, column 4; of Congress, column 5.
                Reprints letters to David Fultz calling upon him to run for Sheriff, and Fultz
                response/acceptance, column 6.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1860.01.31.03">
            <div type="l">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Judicial Election--Hon. Judge Lucas P. Thompson</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Z</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letter praising Judge Thomspon and supporting his reelection as Circuit
                    Judge.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>1-2</column>
                <head>From the Vindicator</head>
                <origin>Republican Vindicator</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Alex. H.H. Stuart</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>State Senator Stuart defends himself against the claims of the Vindicator
                    that he deprecated the activities of the Augusta County militia during the
                    invasion of Harper's Ferry. Stuart calls on the paper to repair the wrong done
                    to him when it misinterpreted his remarks. This letter is followed by a letter
                    from P.G. Coghlan, Senate Reporter, who states that he only abbreviated Stuart's
                    remarks in the record, and that in his full remarks the Senator indeed took
                    occasion to pay a compliment to the actions of Augusta volunteers at Harper's
                    Ferry.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Right half of page 3 is advertisements, including list of candidates for local
                offices. Also land sales, public auctions, etc.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1860.01.31.04">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
