<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1860/va.au.ss.1860.02.28">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Jeff McClurken</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/22/95</tagDate>
            <tagNote>2nd Pass; Josh Rothman did first pass.</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1860-02-28">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day>28</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1860.02.28.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Constitutional Union Party--Address of the National Central Executive
                    Committee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The political aspect of the country fills the public mind with painful
                        apprehension. The people are everywhere disturbed with the fear of some
                        disastrous crisis. Many are alarmed for the safety of the Union. All are
                        conscious that the sentiment of fraternity which once linked the States
                        together, even more firmly than the compact of the Constitution itself, has
                        been rudely shaken, and that discord has crept into the relationship of
                        communities which should have found, both in the interests of the present
                        and in the memories of the past, the strongest motives for mutual regard and
                        confidence.</p>
                    <p>What has produced these general and unhappy convictions?</p>
                    <p>It has been too apparent to escape the most casual observation that, for some
                        years past, there has been manifested a design, in the movements of
                        influential political leaders, to force the country into an organization of
                        parties founded on the question of slavery.</p>
                    <p>The first introduction of this subject into party politics engendered a
                        controversy which has constantly increased in extent and bitterness,
                        mingling with, or usurping the place of all other political questions, and
                        giving to those party politics a greater and more dangerous vehemence.--
                        Considerations of the public welfare seem to be cast aside, to make room for
                        wider and more unrestrained contention on this single and engrossing theme.</p>
                    <p>The two great parties in the country--the Democratic and Republican--have
                        been the chief actors in this fatal contest, if not its authors. Whether
                        they have always exerted themselves to allay the excitement to which it gave
                        rise, or, on the contrary, have both of them occasionally employed it for
                        the promotion of party purposes, it is not for us to determine. It is
                        sufficient to note that the mind of the people has been industriously
                        exercised by this contest to the service of sectional agitation, and that in
                        its progress the teachings of the fathers of the Republic, the lights of
                        history, the landmarks of constitutional power have been renounced, our old
                        and revered traditions of policy spurned and the welfare of the present and
                        the hopes of the future have been brought into jeopardy in the altercations
                        of passionate challenge and defiance between the angry disputants.</p>
                    <p>It is not our purpose to arraign or denounce either of these parties for
                        their past errors or transgressions, but we regard it as an indisputable
                        fact that by their conflicts they have been mainly instrumental in producing
                        the present lamentable state of public affairs. It would be easy to
                        establish this position by a reference to events in the recent history of
                        the country, with which the public is but too familiar; but we purposely
                        abstain from all comments upon them, as inconsistent with the limits of this
                        address, and as tending to revive controversies which is its object to
                        allay. We will simply state that the one, by its frequent and unnecessary
                        intrusion of the slavery question into politics, has exasperated sectional
                        feeling at the North and increased the growing spirit of disunion at the
                        South, while the other has been prompt to avail itself of these
                        opportunities for anti-slavery agitation.</p>
                    <p>After having so long agitated to the contrary by their reciprocal assaults,
                        these parties are now preparing for a sectional struggle far exceeding in
                        violence any that has yet occurred, the results of which may be disastrous
                        to the country.</p>
                    <p>As an indication of the character of this struggle, of its objects and
                        possible consequences, we need only point to the significant fact, that a
                        convention has been called by one of these parties to select a candidate for
                        the office of Chief Magistrate of the Union, from which, by the necessary
                        logic of construction, fifteen States of the Union are excluded.</p>
                    <p>Solemnly impressed with these facts, a number of gentlemen from different
                        parts of the country, among whom were members of the present Congress, and
                        of Congresses of former date, recently assembled in the city of Washington
                        to deliberate on means for averting dangers to which they may lead.</p>
                    <p>It was the unanimous opinion of the meeting, that immediate steps should be
                        taken to organize a "Constitutional Union Party," pledged to support "the
                        Union, the Constitution and the enforcement of the laws."</p>
                    <p>This organization was accordingly commenced by the appointment of a "Central
                        Executive Committee," charged with the general direction of the party and
                        with the preparation of an address to the people of the United States.</p>
                    <p>We need not assure you, fellow citizens, that we approach this task with
                        diffidence and anxiety. We are aware of the difficulty which attends the
                        endeavor, at any time, to persuade men to abandon political associations to
                        which they are allied, either by interest or preference, and we know how
                        much that difficulty is increased when party attachment is heightened by the
                        ardor of expected success or inflamed by the zeal of opposition. But there
                        are, nevertheless, junctures when honest-hearted citizens will be prepared,
                        at any sacrifice of prejudice or opinion, to perform this duty for their
                        country.</p>
                    <p>It is the policy of the dominant parties to underrate the real strength of
                        those whom disapprobation, indifference, or disgust force into the position
                        of neutrals in political warfare. The ordinary tactics of parties teach them
                        to discourage those whom they cannot enlist. But the fact is demonstrable
                        that the number who occupy this position at all times, and more especially
                        at the present time, constitute a most influential portion of the whole
                        people. If the investigation could be made, there is reason to believe it
                        would result in disclosing the fact that, as parties are now constituted a
                        little less than a million voters will be driven out of the sphere of active
                        participation of the coming election. The old Whig strength of the country
                        will be found to furnish no small contribution to this mass.</p>
                    <p>Even those of that association who have been induced to take sides in recent
                        elections with one or the other opponent divisions, acknowledged but scant
                        fealty to their new leaders; and the greater number of them will, it is
                        believed, be prompt to join their old comrades in rallying to a conservative
                        field to fight a new battle for the cause of the Constitution and the
                        restoration of lost harmony. Large numbers of the old Democratic party, who
                        withdrew from the line of march when they discovered it leading towards
                        internal strife, and the assault of the traditional policy by which that
                        party achieved its former triumphs, would, we have no doubt, supply a
                        powerful reinforcement to the friends of the Union.</p>
                    <p>In the American party, to which the breaking up of old organizations gave
                        birth, and which has been active in the endeavor to establish an
                        intermediate power between the contending forces that have engrossed the
                        field, will be found a very large element of conservative strength to</p>
                    <p>If we add to all these that mass of quiet, unobtrusive citizens, who have
                        always shunned the turmoils of political life, content to leave the destiny
                        of the country in the hands of those who, in the ordinary conditions of the
                        national progress, were most ambitious to assume its direction, and who have
                        reposer such faith in the patriotism of their fellow men as to feel no
                        concern in the question of the supremacy of party, but whom the
                        extraordinary incentives of a crisis like the present must awaken to the
                        resolve of an effort to protect the threatened safety of the confederacy, we
                        have elements sufficient by their combination to form a great party, to
                        which additional strength will be imparted by the exalted patriotism of its
                        principles and objects. Moreover, it is only just to the two contending
                        parties to say, that we do not despair of finding in the ranks of each,
                        numerous individuals who, tired of intestine strife, and alarmed at the
                        threatening aspect of affairs, will unite with the only party which holds
                        out to the country a prospect of repose.</p>
                    <p>Can it be possible that, with so glorious a cause before us, an appeal to the
                        patriotism of the land founded on such inducements as the present exigency
                        supplies, can fall upon unheeding ears, or fail to rouse the national heart
                        to the great emprise of this commanding duty?--Now, when every honest and
                        thoughtful citizen within the broad confines of this Union, every true son
                        of the Republic at home and every brother of our lineage abroad, is filled
                        with dismay at the sudden rupture of the national concord, can it be that
                        the power which is able to pour oil upon the troubled waters, and bring
                        gladness back to every man's fireside, will withhold its hand from the
                        labor? That this generation of American citizens, awakened by the clamor
                        that threatens the integrity of our Union, and conscious of its ability to
                        command the ending of the mad debate, and to re-establish the foundations of
                        a healthful, just and benignant administration of the duties and benefits of
                        the Constitution, will play the sluggard in this hour, and incur the
                        everlasting shame of looking on upon the demolition of this fabric of
                        confederated States? That this generation will prove itself so false to all
                        generations to come as to permit, when it has the power to forbid, the
                        destruction of this glorious heritage of so many millions of freemen, with
                        such immortal memories clustering around the path of their history, with
                        such grand hopes hovering over their career before them, the central point
                        of so many blessings, the subject of so many prayers of the enlightened
                        humanity of the whole world?</p>
                    <p>Let all men reflect upon the incredible folly of our quarrel.</p>
                    <p>The country is wrought into a tempest of excitement. Two great political
                        armies are contending for mastery. Both are infuriated with a rage that
                        threatens fearful enemies. The great mass of law-abiding citizens are
                        looking on with amazement, and an ominous apprehension of mischief. And yet
                        there is no danger impending over the Republic which human passions have not
                        created, and which human wisdom may not prevent.</p>
                    <p>We have pointed out the chief source of the present agitation, and think we
                        have shown that neither of the two parties who are now seeking to obtain the
                        control of the Government can be safely entrusted with the management of
                        public affairs. The only way to rescue the country from their hands is to
                        organize a party whose cardinal principles shall be: To remove the subject
                        of slavery from the arena of party politics, and leave it to the independent
                        control of the States in which it exists, and to the unbiased action of the
                        judiciary.</p>
                    <p>To remove all obstacles from the due and faithful execution of the provisions
                        for the rendition of fugitive slaves.</p>
                    <p>To cultivate and expand the resources of the country by such protection to
                        every useful pursuit and interest as is compatible with the general welfare
                        and equitable to all.</p>
                    <p>To maintain peace, as far as possible, and honorable relations to all
                        nations.</p>
                    <p>To guard and enforce the supremacy of laws by an impartial and strict
                        administration of the powers granted by the Constitution.</p>
                    <p>To respect the rights and reverence the Union of the States as a vital source
                        of present peace and prosperity, and the surest guarantee of future power
                        and happiness.</p>
                    <p>To teach reconciliation, fraternity and forbearance, as the great national
                        charities by which the Union is ever to be preserved; as a fountain of
                        perennial blessings to the people.</p>
                    <p>Let these principles be taken to the hearts of those who pledge themselves to
                        the support the party, and let them actuate their private life as well as
                        their public duty.</p>
                    <p>To promote this movement, measures should be adopted with as little delay as
                        possible, such as will afford an opportunity to the party to exert a
                        controlling influence on the approaching election, and to select candidates
                        upon whom its vote may be effectively concentrated.</p>
                    <p>To this end, we propose that a Convention be immediately held in each State,
                        which shall assume the duty of embodying the whole conservative strength of
                        each in such form as shall make it most effective.</p>
                    <p>That each of these conventions shall make a nomination of two candidates for
                        the Presidency, (omitting to nominate a Vice-President,) to be selected from
                        those most eminent and approved in public esteem, one of which candidates at
                        least, shall be a Citizen of some other State than that in which he is
                        nominated.</p>
                    <p>That these two candidates from each State shall be submitted to the
                        consideration of a General Convention, to be assembled at Philadelphia, at a
                        time that shall be designated by the National Executive Committee, which
                        General Convention shall be empowered to select for the whole number of the
                        nominations transmitted to it, a candidate for President and Vice-President,
                        as the candidates of the Constitutional Union party.</p>
                    <p>That this general Convention shall consist of a representative from each
                        State, composed of the same number of members as its representation in the
                        two houses of Congress.</p>
                    <p>That this representation of each State be chosen either by the State
                        Convention itself, or in some other manner as some convention, in view of
                        the shortness of the time for the proceeding, may appoint.</p>
                    <p>A convention constituted in accordance with this plan, we think, would be
                        satisfactory to all parts of the country, and altogether competent to the
                        duty of a discrete and judicious selection of candidates. The people who
                        have so much reason, in their habitual experience of the insufficiency of
                        conventions, to feel no little distrust of these bodies, might prefer some
                        other mode of nomination; if a better could now be adopted. But in the
                        present emergency, when delay would render any attempt to make a nomination
                        for the coming election useless, we are persuaded they will acquiesce in the
                        plan proposed, as the best the time will allow.</p>
                    <p>Such a convention will avoid some of the objections to which the ordinary and
                        accustomed composition of conventions is exposed. It will be confined to the
                        single duty of selecting the candidates from a number of eminent citizens
                        presented by the several States as worthy of the first office in the
                        Government; and it will most probably, find in the concurring opinion of
                        several State conventions in favor of one or more individuals a useful guide
                        to the most acceptable nomination. And as it will be restricted in its
                        choice to the names presented, it will under no circumstances, offend the
                        public wish by selecting candidates unknown to or unrespected by the
                        country.</p>
                    <p>Whether any other principles than those we have enumerated, shall be
                        enunciated, it will be for the Convention to determine. "Platforms" have
                        been so frequently employed as the shallow devices of party deception, that
                        they have come to be viewed with distrust by the people. We know of no
                        higher and nobler aim than the restoration of peace and harmony to a divided
                        and distracted country, and no platform more acceptable to every true
                        patriot than the "Union and the Constitution, and the enforcement of the
                        laws."</p>
                    <p>Fellow-citizens, the task that has been allotted to us is performed. We have
                        pointed out a path by which, in our opinion, the country may be rescued from
                        its perilous position. It is for you to determine whether you will pursue
                        that path, or continue in one which, however the approaching struggle may
                        terminate, may lead to victory, but not to peace; to a brief cessation of
                        strife, but not to a restoration of harmony.</p>
                    <p>Washington, February 22nd, 1860.</p>
                    <p><lb/>John J. Crittenden, Ky., <emph rend="italic">Chairman.</emph><lb/>Wm. C.
                        Rives, Va., <lb/>Washington Hunt, N.Y., <lb/>Wm. A. Graham, N.C., <lb/>Henry
                        M. Fuller, Pa., <lb/>Jno. P. Rockwell, Ct., <lb/>Jno. A. Wheeler, Vt.,
                        <lb/>J. Morrison Harris, Md., <lb/>Lewis Condict, N.J., <lb/>Chas. M.
                        Conrad, La., <lb/>Marshall P. Wilder, Mass., <lb/>Joshua Hill, Ga.,
                        <lb/>Jos. N. Snyder, Ohio, <lb/>Jno. Dunham, Conn., <lb/>Jno. A. Gilmer,
                        N.C., <lb/>C.C. Lathrop, Pa., <lb/>R.W. Thompson, Ind., <lb/>N.W. Shelley,
                        Ala., <lb/>Geo. Briggs, N.Y., <lb/>Wm. G. Brownslow, Tenn., <lb/>Wm. L.
                        Toole, Iowa, <lb/>Jno. Wilson, III, <lb/>Jere Clemens, Tenn., <lb/>E.J.
                        Whitlock, N.Y., <lb/><emph rend="italic">Committee</emph></p>
                    <p>Francis Granger, <lb/><emph rend="italic">Chair'n Nat. Whig Executive
                        Com.</emph></p>
                    <p>Jacob Broome <lb/><emph rend="italic">Chair'n Nat. American Executive
                        Com.</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Introductory address of the Constitutional Union Party, an alternative to
                    the two main parties that is dedicated to the preservation of Union. Signed by
                    John J. Crittenden of Kentucky and others.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/ssfeb60.html#2.28a</note>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1860.02.28.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Democratic Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Discusses some of the occurrences at the Democratic State convention in
                    Richmond. Spectator mockingly describes some of the internal political battles
                    between factions, such as those of Gov. Wise and Senator Hunter.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Valley Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Many citizens of the upper part of the county have petitioned the
                    legislature against the use of certain rail routes by the Valley Railroad.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Junius</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Author requests that the paper allow him to express his views concerning
                    both of the candidates for Circuit Judge.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>To Long Glade and Mossy Creek</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Isaac H. Steele</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Steele</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peck</ln>
                        <fn>H.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Larew</ln>
                        <fn>J.J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lilley</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Colonel</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Polmer</ln>
                        <fn>P</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Steele</ln>
                        <fn>P.G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sterrett</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Steele claims that he has no deals prearranged with other candidates for
                    Sheriff and that if elected he would ask all of them to be his deputies.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>To the Voters of Augusta County</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>William A. Burnett</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burnett</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Author writes that, contrary to rumors that he is withdrawing as a
                    candidate for Circuit Court Clerk, he is not and wishes to be elected.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>For the Spectator, Mossy Creek, Feb. 27, 1860</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Someone broke into the stable of Messrs. J.H. &amp; P. Todd on the
                    night of February 25th and stole a valuable mare. The horse was returned very
                    fatigued the next day.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Legion</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doyle</ln>
                        <fn>R.L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Herman</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>General</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Authors call on William H. Herman to announce he is a candidate for
                    reelection to office of Commonwealth's Attorney.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dempster</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dempster</ln>
                        <fn>Gilbert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Elizabeth Dempster died on February 14 near Greenville at age 72.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyers</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel Boyers died on February 22, age 66.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Bottom left is blotchy. Columns 3 and 4 contain a printed account of the
                proceedings of the State Opposition Party Convention held in Richmond. Weekly
                proceedings of State Legislature, column 5; Congress, column 6.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1860.02.28.03">
            <div type="l">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>To the Editors of the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Z</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fultz</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Author accuses David Fultz of misstating the figures regarding the
                    proceedings of the Circuit Court and reaffirms the efficiency and fine service
                    of Judge Thompson.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>R.H. Dudley</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dudley</ln>
                        <fn>R.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dudley declines the invitation to run for Sheriff.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Election of Judge</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Public Welfare</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Author supports Judge Thompson and thinks he is a nice guy and a righteous
                    judge.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Central Bank of Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>A Stockholder</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Author expresses disapproval for proposed changes to the charter of Central
                    Bank of Virginia, believing the changes will not increase dividends or protect
                    the Bank against runs.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports rumor that Democratic leaders recognize that if a Southern
                    candidate is nominated for President at the coming Charleston convention, then
                    the Cincinnati Platform will be reaffirmed. If a Northern candidate is
                    nominated, then an affirmation of the Dred Scott decision, along with the
                    Southern interpretation that slavery is allowed in the territories, will be
                    included in the platform.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Petersburg Intelligencer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A "gentleman" from Charleston writes to the Petersburg Intelligencer and
                    says the plan for a Southern Conference originated with Mr. Meminger of South
                    Carolina and a few secessionists. Most people in Charleston either do not know
                    of it or disapprove.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Mostly ads, land sales, etc.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1860.02.28.04">
            <pageNote>Advertisements; Bottom left illegible.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
