<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1860/va.au.ss.1860.06.12">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Jeff McClurken</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/22/95</tagDate>
            <tagNote>2nd Pass; Josh Rothman did first pass.</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1860-06-12">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="06">June</month>
            <day>12</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1860.06.12.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>6-7</column>
                <head>Mr. Everett Accepts</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter from Washington Hunt to Edward Everett offering him the
                    Vice-Presidential nomination of the Constitutional Union Party, and Everett's
                    return letter accepting the nomination.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Lengthy obituary for Lady Byron, with clips of Byron's poetry, excerpted from
                Richmond Index, columns 3-4. Bottom right of page is illegible.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1860.06.12.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Chestnut Burrs</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Excerpt of recent debate between Sen. Sumner and Sen. Chestnut on the issue
                    of slavery. The Spectator believes that Chestnut's rhetoric undoubtedly injured
                    Sumner.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Ancient Coin</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cary</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Report that Frederick Cary of Rockfish Gap discovered, while gardening, an
                    English coin dated from the 16th century.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Mails</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Spectator writes that citizens west of Charlottesville have been
                    complaining that the mail from the North has failed to arrive every other day.
                    Apparently the delay has been caused by the failure of connection between the
                    Central and Alexandria trains. Spectator follows the article with a letter from
                    E. Fontaine, President of the Virginia Central Rail Road, saying that he will
                    provide for the next issue of the Spectator an explanation and insuring citizens
                    that the Central Railroad is not to blame for the difficulties.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="j">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Circuit Court</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Circuit court has been engaged in the trial of criminal cases. Amtrose
                    Moyers--crime against nature, jury failed to agree; Sarah Eddy, felony,
                    convicted; James McMullen, felony, convicted; James E. Ross, placing
                    obstructions on Central Railroad near Waynesboro, convicted.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Another Division in the M.E. Church Expected</head>
                <origin>Baltimore Christian Advocate</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Excerpt from the Baltimore Christian Advocate discussing a chapter recently
                    written into the Methodist Discipline at the General Conference in Buffalo. The
                    chapter declares slavery a sin against God. The Christian Advocate questions
                    whether Southern Methodists can retain their connections to current Methodist
                    discipline and suggests the new discipline could presage a split in the
                    denomination.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Acceptance of Hon. John Bell</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter from Washington Hunt to John Bell offering him the Presidential
                    nomination of the Constitutional Union Party, and Bell's return letter accepting
                    the nomination.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Announcement of a meeting to be held in Staunton in August to discuss the
                nominations of Bell and Everett on the Constitutional Union party ticket, column 1.
                Bottom left of page is practically illegible, although there is a report of a fire
                on property owned by State Senator A.H.H. Stuart, next to the residence of D.S.
                Young. Results of Circuit Court criminal cases, column 2. Short articles about
                political rumors, internal party workings, etc., scattered about the page. Weekly
                proceedings of Congress, column 4.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1860.06.12.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Personal Appearance of Abraham Lincoln</head>
                <origin>Cleveland Plain Dealer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"A correct likeness of Mr. Lincoln would be condemned as a caricature by
                    any one who did not know it was true."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Short physical description of Abraham Lincoln.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Teagle</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William H.S. Teagle of Staunton died at age 45.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>O'Brien</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James H. O'Brien died. He was formerly a resident of Rockingham, but at the
                    time of his death he lived in Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>"C."</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bushong</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary C. Bushong of Augusta County died at age 70.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Mostly advertisements; bottom right illegible.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1860.06.12.04">
            <pageNote>Advertisements; bottom left illegible.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
