<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1860/va.au.ss.1860.08.07">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Jeff McClurken</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/22/95</tagDate>
            <tagNote>2nd Pass; Josh Rothman did first pass.</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1860-08-07">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="08">August</month>
            <day norm="07">7</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1860.08.07.01">
            <pageNote>Most of page is poetry and literature. Column 5 has excerpt of speech by
                Edward Everett from 1858. Bottom right of page is illegible.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1860.08.07.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>West Augusta--Liberty and Union</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Spectator recalls the brave and patriotic actions and spirit of citizens of
                    Augusta County during the Revolutionary War, and notes the danger in which the
                    country currently is placed by the divisive political situation. Calls upon the
                    divided Democrats who will soon be meeting in Staunton and Charlottesville to
                    unite in support of the Constitution and the Union.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Home Destroyed by Lightning</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donaghe</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Opie</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>During a storm, the house of William Donaghe was struck by lightning and
                    destroyed. Several of Col. Opie's slaves were awakened by lightning as well and
                    were stunned but not injured.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Terrific Storm--Great Loss--Staunton Nearly Ruined</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"A great many persons suffered damages whose names are not mentioned in
                    this account. Nearly every citizen suffered more or less."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eichelberger</ln>
                        <fn>H.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>L.J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kelley</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Antone</ln>
                        <fn>J.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hulst</ln>
                        <fn>J.P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Evans</ln>
                        <fn>J.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>P.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scherer</ln>
                        <fn>J.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beck</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Michie</ln>
                        <fn>T.J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hannan</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>O'Hare</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bledsoes</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Morris</ln>
                        <fn>O.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bruce</ln>
                        <fn>A.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elick</ln>
                        <fn>G.F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blake</ln>
                        <fn>Lyman</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Powell</ln>
                        <fn>P.N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn>G.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Report of a massive storm that swept through Staunton causing destruction
                    of a great deal of property, mostly via flooding. Pavement was completely washed
                    away on some streets and many businesses and buildings were damaged or
                    destroyed. Large individual losses cited include those to Dr. H.S. Eichelberger,
                    Druggist; Benjamin Crawford, Dry Goods merchant and Grocer; Mrs. L.J. Snyder;
                    Mrs. Kelley, milliner; J.B. Antons, confectioner; J.P. Hulst, grocer; J.B.
                    Evans, tobacconist; P.H. Trout &amp; Co., druggists; William Miller,
                    shoemaker; Charles T. Cochran, Tobacconist; Dr. Young, druggist; J.B. Scherer,
                    confectioner; J. Beck, confectioner; T.J. Michie, lawyer; James Hannan,
                    Bar-Room; John O'Hare, Bagatelle Saloon; Messrs. Bledsoes and Davis, Dry Goods
                    merchants and Grocers; O.C. Morris, Grocer and Dry Goods Merchant; A.M. Bruce,
                    Grocer; G.F. Elick, Saddler; Lyman R. Blake, Shoe Store; P.N. Powell, Commission
                    Merchant. The gable end of the home being built for G.W. Imboden collapsed.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Presentation of Banner and Picnic Near Brown's Spring</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peck</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peck</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Report of the two local military companies travelling to Fishersville to
                    witness the presentation of a flag to the Augusta Rifles. Detailed account of
                    the proceedings, with military units led by Capt. Koiner of the Augusta Rifles,
                    Capt. Peck of the Cavalry, and Capt. Imboden. Lieut. James Bumgardner presented
                    the banner. Turner's Band provided entertainment. The storm that passed through
                    the county produced an early end to the proceedings. Capt. Peck, Dr. King and
                    Mr. Reed were struck by lightning, which marred the occasion, but it was
                    otherwise an entire success.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Escapes from Drowning</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craford</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Report of a number of people who nearly drowned during the storm, including
                    "Old Uncle Sam," a "servant" of Benjamin Crawford, who was saved by James S.
                    Crawford.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Busy Scene</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Street Commissioners are busy repairing the damage done by the storm,
                    making streets concave instead of convex so that water flows to the center of
                    the street rather than out to the pavement and onto building foundations.
                    Spectator hopes the street will be repaired in time for the Douglas Democrat
                    convention on August 16.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Struck by Lightning</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peck</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>During the storm, Capt. Henry H. Peck, Dr. King and Mr. Reed were all
                    struck by lightning on the porch of a house at Brown's Spring near Fishersville.
                    All were stunned but none was seriously injured.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Abolition</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">To N.K. Trout, Mayor, and Gen. Harman and Capt. Baylor,
                            Commonwealth's Attornies [sic]--</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>Nothing is more common than to hear our citizens declaim against the
                        abolitionists. If a stranger comes into our midst who is even suspected of
                        entertaining or inculcating abolition sentiments, the whole community is at
                        once and justly in an uproar. Yet we have among our own people two classes
                        of persons who do more harm to our slave population than all the
                        abolitionists of the North combined. I refer, 1st., to those who stand as
                        nominal masters for negroes, who are really free, and who are permitted to
                        hire themselves out, and go at large at pleasure. I have reason to believe
                        there are negroes in Staunton and in the country who are living, trading and
                        acting as free persons, who have bought and paid for their freedom, except a
                        nominal balance which is permitted to remain unpaid, merely as a device to
                        evade the laws.--These cases should be looked after. And 2nd, there is
                        another class, who permit their slaves to live in independent houses from
                        their owners, to keep house, work for themselves and pay to their owners a
                        portion of their earnings. This matter ought to be inquired into by our
                        Mayor and Commonwealth's Attornies [sic] and Grand Juries. If orders were
                        given to the public officer to ferret out all such cases and report them to
                        the proper authorities, a good service would be done to the public.</p>
                    <p>Observer.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Observer</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>N.K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Author addresses his letter to N.K. Trout, Gen. Harman and Capt. Baylor,
                    arguing that citizens are always ready to rise up and oppose anyone suspected of
                    abolition sentiments, but that there are other types of people who harm the
                    institution of slavery even more than abolitionists but are never criticized. He
                    refers specifically both to those who nominally own blacks but who allow them to
                    act as freemen and hire themselves out and to those who allow their slaves to
                    live in separate houses and work for themselves. The author calls on public
                    officials to ferret out these cases and prosecute them for evading slave laws.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/ssaug60.html#8.7a</note>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Report of an accident on the Central Railroad, column 1. Page contains a
                number of stories reflecting well on the Bell/Everett ticket.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1860.08.07.03">
            <pageNote>Advertisements, land sales and auctions, etc. Bottom right of page is
                illegible.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1860.08.07.04">
            <pageNote>Advertisements; bottom left illegible.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
