<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1860/va.au.ss.1860.10.23">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Jeff McClurken</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/22/95</tagDate>
            <tagNote>2nd Pass; Josh Rothman did first pass.</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1860-10-23">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="10">October</month>
            <day>23</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1860.10.23.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Working Mothers--Idle Daughters</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article about families in which the mother works while the daughter is
                    idle.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>"D"</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>J. Marshall</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Meeting of the Waynesboro Bell/Everett Club, addressed by J. Marshall
                    Hanger.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>D.B. Croushorn, Chairman. W.H. Snapp, Secretary.</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Poage</ln>
                        <fn>R.T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fishburn</ln>
                        <fn>L.F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snapp</ln>
                        <fn>W.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snapp</ln>
                        <fn>C.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Croushorn</ln>
                        <fn>D.D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilkerson</ln>
                        <fn>A.P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fishburn</ln>
                        <fn>G.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stover</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn>H.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doyle</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>J.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Meeting held at Mowry's Mill for the purpose of organizing a Bell/Everett
                    Club.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Speech of Gen. Leslie Coombs to a Bell/Everett meeting in Cincinnati, columns
                3-4. Article on "Young Love," column 4. Series of short moral aphorisms, column 7.
                Campaign song for Bell, column 7.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1860.10.23.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>To the Union Party of Augusta</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>You responded most nobly on the 19th of October to the call for a Grand Union
                        Rally. -- True to your ancestral instincts, you came through storm and mire
                        to show how ready you are against all odds to answer your country's call for
                        even the slightest service. But many who would have then been with you,
                        found it impossible, and now ask only another chance, and they will join you
                            <emph rend="italic">regardless of weather.</emph></p>
                    <p>The eyes of the Union party of Virginia are now upon Augusta. The eloquent
                        Summers told you how longingly her daughter counties of the West were
                        looking to their old Mother in this hour of <emph rend="italic">danger to
                            the Union.</emph> Your boast is already published over the land, that
                        yours claims to be the banner Union county at the polls on the 6th of
                        November-next. <emph rend="italic">Your honor is now at stake, and each and
                            all must see that it is redeemed.</emph></p>
                    <p>We do not propose another "Rally," but invite an informal meeting from <emph
                            rend="italic">all over the county,</emph> and especially from the
                        precincts which were unprepared to come out on the 19th of October. -- In a
                        crisis like this <emph rend="italic">all</emph> must move, and in solid
                        column to cheer and encourage each other. </p>
                    <p>COME THEN ONCE MORE!</p>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">On Friday, the 2nd day of Next Month,</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>by 10 o'clock in the morning rain or sun shine, and hear your own eloquent
                        County men,</p>
                    <p>HON. ALEX. H. H. STUART!</p>
                    <p>AND</p>
                    <p>JOHN B. BALDWIN!</p>
                    <p>who promise, certainly, to address you. Other speakers and hearers from other
                        counties will be more than welcome; but we propose that this shall be a
                        meeting of the thousands of Union loving men of Old Augusta, to counsel
                        together on the Eve Of The Great Battle For The Union. It will be the last
                        occasion on which all of our countrymen can meet before the close of the
                        canvass; let it be a good family meeting, and let All The Family come. Let
                        all who were here in such gallant array on the glorious 19th of October come
                        back, with their banners and their bells, and "bring their shoaves with
                        them." Let the ladies and all lovers of the Union come, of whatever party
                        faith.</p>
                    <p>By order of the County Committee.</p>
                    <p>BOLIVAR CHRISTIAN</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Bolivar Christian</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>Alex.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>Bolivar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Editorial congratulating the people of Staunton for turning out for the
                    Union rally despite the stormy weather. But it calls for another "informal
                    meeting" on November 2 in order to bring out people from the county who were
                    unprepared or unable to attend the first rally.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/ssoct60.html#10.23a</note>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doyle</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>List of locations of speeches to be delivered by R.L. Doyle.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Massie</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Account of a political debate at Monterey.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Central Bell and Everett Club</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>Chapman</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Report of meeting of Central Bell/Everett Club.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Why Fusion was Refused</head>
                <origin>Tenth Legion (Woodstock, Shenandoah County)</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Explanation for the failure of fusion between wings of the Democratic
                    party.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Narrow Escape of Hon. A.H.H. Stuart</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>Alex.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Alexander Stuart fell into the James River Canal and nearly drowned.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2-3</column>
                <head>The Grand Rally! A Great Success!! "Old Augusta" Aroused!!! The People
                    Resolved to Save the Union!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"If there were any doubting Thomases before, there can be none since the
                    glorious demonstration of Friday last, for the most incredulous must be
                    convinced that the citizens of Augusta are, by an overwhelming majority, in
                    favor of the 'Union, the Constitution, and the Enforcement of the Laws.'"</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>A.H.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>Bolivar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Summary of proceedings of the Union Rally held in Augusta.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Are You Ready?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The time has come to meet the impending crisis in a manly, decided and
                    Constitutional manner."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p> In two weeks from this day the people of the United States will be called
                        upon to decide the most important election that has ever been held in this
                        country. The very existence of the Government, it may be, is dependent upon
                        the result of this election. The great and important issue is union or
                        disunion. Will we remain a united, free, prosperous and happy people, or
                        shall we be involved in all the evils of anarchy and discord, and all the
                        indescribable horrors of civil war and fratricidal strife? This is a time
                        when more considerations of party should be lost sight of entirely, and when
                        every one should look alone to the preservation of our government, and the
                        salvation of the Union, the only guarantee of our liberties. The man who, in
                        this fearful crisis of our country's fate, is controlled by mere partizan
                        [sic] considerations, is a traitor to his country. When the Government is
                        not threatened, and when the Union is not imperilled, when we are concerned
                        alone about the best mode of administering the Government, and differ only
                        about the measures of policy, it is well enough then to be controlled to
                        some extent by party preferences, and even blind party prejudice can be
                        tolerated, if not excused, but when the Government is in danger and the
                        Union is trembling upon the brink of ruin, it is time to turn a deaf ear to
                        the syren [sic] voice of party and obey the solemn injunctions of patriotic
                        duty. At this time our country calls and her voice should be obeyed. We
                        concur with the <emph rend="italic">Frederick (Md.) Examiner</emph> that the
                        issue is Union or disunion.--Other issues may be interpolated and magnified,
                        but they are of inferior consequence; the great and real issue is, the
                        preservation of our form of free government, or the evils of Civil Discord,
                        the danger of Anarchy and the prospect of States dissevered, discordant and
                        belligerent, as the alternative. </p>
                    <p>In this fearful crisis, every lover of his country is expected to do his
                        duty, as becomes a free-man. Fellow-citizens, are you prepared for the
                        responsibility? Gird on the armor of patriotism, carefully survey the field,
                        be ready, and may He who has hitherto guarded and guided us in every step by
                        which we have advanced to the dignity of a great, powerful and enlightened
                        nation, preserve us as a united people!</p>
                    <p>"Eternal vigilance is the price of liberty." See to it, therefore, that
                        apathy or neglect afford no occasion for vain regrets and remorse. Let every
                        man go to the polls, and forgetting party distinctions, repudiating the
                        behests of party leaders, and burying by-gone political animosities for a
                        season, vote with an eye single to the preservation of the Union, the
                        maintenance of the Constitution and the Enforcement of the laws.</p>
                    <p>The enemies of the Constitution, whose fanaticism threatens evil and danger,
                        are one in sentiment and purpose, The intoxication of prospective success
                        excites their zeal beyond the restraints of prudence. The opposition is
                        divided; its strength is frittered away in unprofitable contentions upon
                        abstract propositions, and fostered prejudices. If the Union be dissolved,
                        how can the factionists hope to decide their petty quarrels; where will the
                        demagogues then be; how shall the right, they now profess to struggle for,
                        be longer guaranteed them?</p>
                    <p>The time has come to meet the impending crisis in a manly, decided and
                        Constitutional manner. It is clear that the friends of the Union must make
                        common cause and rally under the leaders who can and will save the Union,
                        restore peace and mutual trust, and crush out sectionalism. Who can do it?
                        Can Douglas and Johnson achieve the repose the country so much needs? They
                        may be many times stronger in the popular and electoral vote than their
                        rival Southern faction; yet every one knows, they are impotent against
                        Lincoln and in no possible event can either of them be elected to the
                        Presidential office. Can Breckinridge and Lane accomplish more? Mr.
                        Breckinridge is practically out of the fight; his friends know he stands no
                        earthly chance, and that his continued candidacy only gives "aid and
                        comfort" to Lincoln. Granting all the strength his most zealous friends
                        claim for him, what can these avail? Absolutely nothing, except to weaken
                        and divide the strength of the Union nominees! The calculation of Mr. Lane's
                        election by the Senate is too remote and uncertain to authorize his course
                        thus far. The ONLY candidates, who STAND A CHANCE of DEFEATING Lincoln and
                        Hamlin, are BELL and EVERETT; the contest lies between Bell and Lincoln, and
                        the duty of every conservative citizen is plain and urgent. The Union must
                        and shall be preserved; Lincoln must and will be defeated, and the way to do
                        both is by giving a united and cordial support to Bell.</p>
                    <p>The struggle is no child's play; it will be fierce and arduous. "Work, work,"
                        Conservatives, your country calls. From this hour to the close of the polls
                        on election day, be active energetic and diligent. Reason with your
                        neighbors, see that every voter goes to the polls.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Editorial about the upcoming election, urging people to vote for the Union
                    and to stave off the horror of a national crisis. Urges voters to put aside
                    party devotions for the sake of the nation.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/ssoct60.html#10.23b</note>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Nothing to Dread from Lincoln</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"To break up the Government under these circumstances, simply because
                    Lincoln should be elected, would be adding madness to treason."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Even though Lincoln should be elected, and should be disposed to commit some
                        aggression upon the rights of the South, he could not do it. The Supreme
                        Court is against the theories of his party. The Senate is against them and
                        the Congress will be against them. There are 237 members of the
                        House--Oregon and California send three against him, Ohio ten, Indiana four,
                        Illinois five, Pennsylvania five, and the South eighty nine, 116 in all. We
                        have but to elect three other anti-Lincoln members and all is safe. New York
                        city alone will elect six. There cannot in any event then be danger of
                        present aggression against the South, and if conservatism and a Union spirit
                        shall prevail in the border Southern States, we may prevent any of the other
                        States, by reason and argument, from seceding, if Lincoln should be elected.</p>
                    <p>To break up the Government under these circumstances, simply because Lincoln
                        should be elected, would be adding madness to treason.--The danger is in the
                        Cotton States, and not in the North. The spirit of prohibition as
                        represented by Lincoln will be impotent for mischief, but the spirit of
                        disunion, as represented by Yancey and other extremists of the South may be
                        potential for indescribable evils. The people should do all they can to
                        elect the Union loving conservatives, Bell and Everett, for then there would
                        be no danger of disunion and civil war.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Editorial claiming that, even if Lincoln should win and should want to
                    commit an act of aggression against the South, he could not do so because of the
                    protections of the Congress and the Supreme Court.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/ssoct60.html#10.23c</note>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Subject of Disunion</head>
                <origin>Alexandria Gazette</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Alexandria Gazette</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Editorial summarizing and criticizing secessionist actions taken by other
                    Southern states, with excerpted material from other newspapers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Bottom left is illegible. Excerpt from 1850 speech of Daniel Webster, column
                5. Page has a number of short political articles of general interest as well, such
                as an article critical of the position of the Richmond Enquirer, column
            6.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1860.10.23.03">
            <div type="o">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Late Commodore Skinner</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>"S"</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>Charles William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Commodore</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Obituary for Commodore Charles William Skinner.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trimble</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trimble</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on October 18.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brashear</ln>
                        <fn>T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hartman</ln>
                        <fn>Lyttelton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on October 18. Dr. Hartman is from Albemarle County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rosenbarger</ln>
                        <fn>John D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Divine</ln>
                        <fn>Tabitha</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Rosenbarger, formerly of Augusta, but now living in Monroe County,
                    Missouri, married Miss Divine of Montgomery County, Missouri.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shipman</ln>
                        <fn>Agnes</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shipman</ln>
                        <fn>F.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Agnes Shipman of Bridgewater died at age 39 on October 10.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>"R"</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>Letitia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letitia Cochran died on October 5 at age 15 in Greenville.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Page is mostly ads, land sales, etc.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1860.10.23.04">
            <pageNote>Advertisements. Bottom left is blurry.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
