<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1861/pa.fr.vs.1861.06.01">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Colleen Doody</taggerName>
            <tagDate>1/3/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>first pass; 2nd pass 5/2/97</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1861-06-01">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="06">June</month>
            <day norm="01">1</day>
            <weekday id="SAT">Saturday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.06.01.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Important from Fort Monroe</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A force of 2,500 federal troops made an entrenched camp near the mouth of
                    the James River near Fortress Monroe. About 100 slaves arrived in the camp, were
                    given rations and put to work. Col. Butler met with the President to ask what he
                    should do with the fugitive slaves. He was told that the government endorses his
                    policy of protecting them and putting them to work.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>Look</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Important News from Western Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The rebel troops have evacuated parts of Western Virginia and Union troops
                    have moved in. Gen. McClellan issued a proclamation stating that his troops came
                    as friends, that the property of the local residents would be protected, and
                    that "no interference would be made with their slaves; but on the contrary, any
                    attempt at insurrection would be crushed with iron hand."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>Look</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>From Washington</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"Secession forces have thrown up earthworks of perhaps two hundred feet
                    square at Manassas Gap Junction, and commanding the track for perhaps a mile.
                    They are under the command of Gen. Bonham of South Carolina."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Miscellaneous News from the Capital</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Union navy has changed its signals, since the Southerners know the old
                    signals. Gen. Walbridge urged the government to sign up four or five hundred
                    thousand men into the army. "This demonstration, it is thought, will make the
                    war a bloodless one, and establish the military character of the nation abroad,
                    as well as overcome treason at home."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Affairs at Alexandria and its Vicinity</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Secretary of War made application for large quantities of the rolling
                    stock of the Baltimore and Ohio Railroad for use on the Orange and Alexandria
                    road. The Union army will probably first attempt to seize Manassas Gap Junction,
                    which is a highly important position on the Richmond Road. "The citizens [of
                    Northern Virginia] appear to submit to the new occupation with a sort of sullen
                    can't help myself feeling; they stand around in small squads, but appear
                    desirous of avoiding the military."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Sad Condition of the Troops at Lancaster</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The poor conditions in Camp Johnson, where the 14th and 15th Pennsylvania
                    Regiments are quartered, have utterly demoralized the troops. The commissariat
                    serves the volunteers rancid meat and an insufficient amount of bread.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Maryland Union State Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Union State Convention met in Baltimore and adopted a series of
                    resolutions in favor of Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"The people of Missouri have been assured that the President will not
                    require that State to take sides in the present conflict. No aggressions will be
                    made on the rights or property of her people."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"An enormous rifled cannon is just being finished at Pittsburgh for
                    Fortress Monroe."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Tennessee papers report that the hay and corn crops are not likely to
                    be good this year.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"A negro insurrection was recently discovered in Des Are, Arkansas. The
                    punishment of the offenders was summary and severe. One white man and three
                    negroes were hung, three more negroes banished, and a number of others were
                    severely whipped."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>See the above transcript.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>The Attack on Fort Sumter</head>
                <origin>South Bend (Indiana) Register</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Major Anderson's account of the bombardment on Fort Sumter.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Syracuse, NY Standard</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A Democratic State Convention is to be held at Syracuse on July 4th. "Its
                    probable purpose is the harmonizing of the party."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"Schuyler Colifax has arrived in Washington from Indiana, for the purpose
                    of urging the government to accept the services of six regiment of volunteers
                    from that state."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"Henry S. Foote, Jr., son of the ex-Senator, has been appointed second
                    Lieutenant in the Confederate State Army. He is a resident of Nashville,
                    Tennessee."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Board of Aldermen of Louisville have invited Major Anderston to visit
                    their city.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Miles Greenwood of Cincinnati has a government contract to make eight
                    hundred rifles and muskets per day.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.06.01.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Cavalry</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A company of cavalry from Carlisle Barracks will arrive in Chambersburg by
                    the Philadelphia turnpike on Saturday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Accident</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Mr. John Fisher, Hotel Keeper, shot himself in the abdomen while handling a
                    Sharp's Pistol. The wound is very serious.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Death Among the Soldiers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"A soldier belonging to a West Chester company died, at this place, of Camp
                    Fever, on Wednesday night last."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A soldier belonging to a West Chester company died, at this place, of Camp
                        Fever, on Wednesday night last. His remains were sent home to his friends.
                        On Thursday night two deaths from the same disease occured in the Hospital.
                        There are no new cases of this desease now among the soldiers at this post.
                        Two of the cases were among the troops that have just arrived and the
                        disease evidently existed in their system at the time of their coming
                    here.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Three soldiers died in Chambersburg of camp fever.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/june61.html#6.1a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Campbell's Artillery</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>About 45 men left Campbell's Artillery because they would not enlist for
                    three years. The remaining men were ordered to Uniontown, Pennsylvania, with the
                    cannon to recruit more men. They were not provided with horses.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Shame!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"The 4th and 5th Regiment of Pennsylvania Volunteers are familiarly known
                    in Washington as the ragged Militia. Is this right? or is it a burning shame on
                    those who should have taken pride in putting them into the field in a condition
                    at least equal to those from New England and New York. Are the homes of men who
                    will act so worth defending?"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Troops and their Destination</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Ten regiments are now encamped at Chambersburg. It is believed that, soon,
                    a total of fifteen will be here and then will march on Harper's Ferry. "They
                    will make short work at that point; but we still hope that the rebels will see
                    how wrong they are acting, lay down their arms and swear fidelity to the
                    Constitution and the Union, and not provoke the slaughter that must surely
                    follow if they attempt resistance."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Virginia Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The western counties of Virginia voted heavily against secession while the
                    eastern were almost unanimous in favor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"Augustus Jenkens has been mobbed at Portsmouth, New Hampshire, for saying
                    we ought to let the South go in peace. Zene Farrington and Cornelius Miller were
                    mobbed and much injured, in Wales, Mass., for declining to hoist a flag on
                    compulsion."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>"A Strong Smell of Thieves"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Republican papers don't appear to be surprised that Mr. Purviance
                    resigned as Attorney General. They knew he was an honest man, and no honest man
                    "can long stand the strong smell of thieves that fairly poisons the atmosphere
                    around Gov. Curtin." The Spirit believes that the Republicans made a mistake
                    when they nominated Curtin, who is hopelessly corrupt.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Position of England</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spirit believes that the British government's position vis-a-vis the
                    Confederate States is correct. Its recognition of the Confederate States as a
                    belligerent merely means that it will take no part in the struggle.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"On Sunday about two hundred Virginia troops reached Little Georgetown,
                    seven miles above Williamsport, and have encamped there, using the church as a
                    barracks."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Arrival of Troops</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>About eight thousand men are now encamped in Chambersburg--2nd, 3d, 6th,
                    7th, 8th, 10th, 21st, 23d, 24th Regiments and the Scott Legion of Pennsylvania.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>Look</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Choice Language</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Our dark-colored friends, taking advantage of the times are sprouting a
                    little too fast, and may be nipped by an untimely frost."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spirit has found a "choice morsel" from a paper published in Boston and
                    New York by a group of black and white men. The quote states that "If freedom
                    can only prevail through the agency of vengeance, so be it; if the Temple of
                    Liberty can stand securely on the corpses of slaveholders, so be it . . ." The
                    Spirit believes that the black publishers are taking advantage of the present
                    turmoil of the country, and that the liberty to express such statements will be
                    curtailed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>Look</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Kentucky</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A correspondent for the Louisville Tribune states that Union feeling is
                    strong in Kentucky.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Metropolitan Railroad</head>
                <origin>The National Intelligencer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A letter from C. F. Fletcher states that the war has shown the necessity of
                    a railroad from Washington to Frederick and Hagerstown, Maryland. He hopes that,
                    with the aid of the government, this "important opening through Maryland into
                    Pennsylvania and the far Northwest" may be completed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"Nearly every exchange paper we lay hands to now-days is filled with
                    letters from soldiers in the different Camps throughout the State as well as
                    outside of it; and nearly every one we read complains of either the clothing or
                    the food. The general complaint is of the clothing, they appear to have been
                    wofully [sic] cheated, and somebody has made money."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Captain Campbell's Flying Artillery</head>
                <origin>Harrisburg Patriot and Union</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>About one half of Captain Campbell's Artillery did not sign up for a
                    three-year enlistment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>A Card</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Riddle</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moffly</ln>
                        <fn>Sidney</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Quay</ln>
                        <fn>Thos.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn>Geo.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Jas.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Benner</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The men of the Curtin Guards, Company B, 10th Regiment want to thank Mr.
                    and Mrs. Ross and many other residents of Chambersburg for providing them with
                    cakes, pies, and bread.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Topographical Notes</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Brief geographical descriptions of certain key locations, including
                    Pensacola, Montgomery, and Richmond.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>A Good Suggestion</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Recommends that, when corresponding with a soldier, the writer include a
                    stamp in order to ensure a reply. The difficulty of obtaining stamps may prevent
                    soldiers from writing letters.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>"The Ragged Army of Penn'a!"</head>
                <origin>Philadelphia Inquirer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Complains that corruption is the order of the day in Harrisburg.
                    Pennsylvania residents have paid liberally to outfit their volunteers, but the
                    men are poorly clothed and fed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>The Situation of Affairs</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Description of the current position and status of the armies.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>From Fortress Monroe</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Everything is quiet at Old Point Comfort. Captain Engel of the Navy
                    believes that the rebel battery at Sewall's Point is impregnable.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>From Washington</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A gentleman who just arrived in Washington from Centreville, Virginia
                    reports that there are 4,000 troops in the area. He also stated that prominent
                    Union men in Virginia continue to be seized and held hostage.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Collision and Loss of Life</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Two trains, one of which was filled with Confederate troops, collided on
                    the Orange and Alexandria Railroad.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"Hon. Wm. A. Graham, of North Carolina, who ran for Vice President in 1852
                    on the Whig ticket with Gen. Scott, is delivering stump speeches in the tar,
                    pitch and turpentine State in favor of secession."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"The body of Col. Ellsworth was buried at Mechanicsburg, New York, on
                    Monday."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.06.01.03">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.06.01.04">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
