<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1861/pa.fr.vs.1861.03.20">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Brian Erb</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1861-03-20">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day>20</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.03.20.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Mr. Buchanan at Home</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports Ex-President Buchanan's arrival home in Lancaster to a large
                    welcome. A transcript of his impromptu speech is included with the article.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Another Terrific Gale in England.</head>
                <origin>London Times</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports a storm in England that caused much damage.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>From the Baltimore Exchange</head>
                <origin>Baltimore Courier</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Accuses the Lincoln Administration of filling all appointments with "the
                    most obnoxious partisans".</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Constitutional Amendments</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Gives the procedure for adopting a new Constitutional Amendment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Column 6 incomplete. Bottom illegible.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.03.20.02">
            <pageNote>Poetry, fiction, and anecdotes</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.03.20.03">
            <pageNote>Poetry, anecdotes, and ads</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.03.20.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>News of the Week</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>News from around the country regarding the secession crisis, particularly
                    rumors regarding Fort Sumter and the action of the border states.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Southern Confederacy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The Union is dissolved, the country on the eve of civil war, and the
                    Republican party is alone responsible for all the trouble."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The following articles extracted from the constitution established and
                        ordained by the Confederate States of America will be perused with interest
                        by our northern readers. This Constitution was unanimously adopted by the
                        Congress of the Southern Republic for its permanent government on the 11th
                        inst. It certainly looks as if secession was no myth and that the hope of
                        reconstructing the Union is "clean gone forever," what a humiliating
                        spectacle is here presented--the noblest government on the face of the earth
                        broken up for the sake of a platform of a party which is largely in the
                        minority in the country. We may as well look the present national calamity
                        squarely in the face--the Union is dissolved, the country on the eve of
                        civil war, and the Republican party is alone responsible for all the
                        trouble. It was their everlasting agitation of the "nigger question" and
                        their aggression on the South that have brought these disasters on the
                        country--ruined her business prospects and disgraced her in the estimation
                        of the whole civilized world. They cannot shift the responsibility of the
                        damning deed from their shoulders--it will stick to them like the poisoned
                        shirt of Nessus until the great wrong done their country is atoned for.</p>
                    <p>It will be observed that the African Slave trade is prohibited in the
                        Southern Constitution. In the late Presidential compaign [sic] the
                        Democratic party had to bear the odium of being in favor of this measure,
                        notwithstanding the positive proof that the party was opposed to it and that
                        the South did not want it. It will now be seen how much the Democratic party
                        was vilified in regard to this measure. The 9th Section of the 1st Article
                        of the Constitution of the Confederate States says:--</p>
                    <p>The importation of negroes of the African race from any foreign country other
                        than the slaveholding States or Territories of the United States of America,
                        is hereby forbidden; and Congress is required to pass such laws as shall
                        effectually prevent the same.</p>
                    <p>Congress shall also have power to prohibit the introduction of slaves from
                        any State not a member of, or Territory not belonging to this confederacy.</p>
                    <p>The 10th Section of Article 1st provides as follows:--</p>
                    <p>No State shall enter into any treaty, alliance, or confederation; grant
                        letters of marque and reprisal; coin money; make anything but gold and
                        silver coin a tender in payment of debts; pass any bill of attainder, or
                            <emph rend="italic">ex post facto</emph> law, or law impairing the
                        obligation of contracts; or grant any title of nobility.</p>
                    <p>No State shall, without the consent of the Congress lay any imposts or duties
                        on imports or exports, except what may be absolutely necessary for executing
                        its inspectation [sic] laws; and the net produce of all duties and imposts,
                        laid by any State on imports or exports, shall be for the use of the
                        Treasury of the confederate States; and all such laws shall be subject to
                        the revision and control of Congress.</p>
                    <p>No State shall, without the consent of Congress, lay any duty of tonnage,
                        except on sea going vessels, for the improvement of its rivers and harbors
                        navigated by the said vessels; but such duties shall not conflict with any
                        treaties of Confederate States with foreign nations; and any surplus of
                        revenue thus derived shall, after making such improvement, be paid into the
                        common treasury; nor shall any State keep troops or ships of war in time of
                        peace, enter into any agreement or compact with another State, or with a
                        foreign Power, or engage in war, unless actually invaded, or in such
                        imminent danger as will not admit of delay. But when any river divides or
                        flows through two or more States they may enter into compacts with each
                        other to improve the navigation thereof.</p>
                    <p>The election of the Executive officers of the government is the same as
                        provided for in the Constitution of the United States, with some slight
                        modifications. The President and Vice President are to hold their offices
                        for the term of six years. On the eligibility for the office of President
                        the Constitution provides as follow:--</p>
                    <p>No person except a natural born citizen of the Confederate States, or a
                        citizen thereof at the time of the adoption of this constitution, or a
                        citizen thereof born in the United States prior the 20th of December, 1860,
                        shall be eligible to the office of President; neither shall any person be
                        eligible to that office who shall not have attained the age of thirty-five
                        years and been fourteen years a resident with the limits of the confederate
                        States, as they may exist at the time of his election.</p>
                    <p>The oath taken by the President before entering upon the duties of his office
                        is the same as that in the Constitution of the United States, with some
                        unimportant change in the working, and reads as follows:--</p>
                    <p>"I do solemnly swear (or affirm) that I will faithfully execute the office of
                        President of the Confederate States, and will to the best of my ability,
                        preserve, protect and defend the constitution thereof."</p>
                    <p>The definition and punishment of treason is the same as that laid down in the
                        constitution of the United States. This Section is precisely the same as
                        that in the old Constitution with the exception that the words "Confederate
                        States" are used in place of "United States."</p>
                    <p>The article in the Constitution of the United States which provides that "no
                        person held to service or labor in one State" &amp;c., reads in the
                        Constitution of the Confederate States in this wise:--</p>
                    <p>No slave or other person held to service or labor in any State or Territory
                        of the Confederate States, under the laws thereof, escaping or lawfully
                        carried into another, shall, in consequence of any law or regulation
                        therein, be discharged from such service or labor, but shall be delivered up
                        on claim of the party to whom such slave belongs or to whom such service or
                        labor may be due.</p>
                    <p>The only change in this article is the introduction of the word "slave."
                        "Person," did not seem to cover the ground sufficiently to meet the views of
                        those who, although living in the South, are not taught to look upon the
                        possibility of the white race ever being designated by the term "slave."
                        They are not willing to confound <emph rend="italic">white</emph> and <emph
                            rend="italic">black</emph> under the single term "person." This
                        distinction must be viewed as right and proper.</p>
                    <p>The following Section of Article 4th embodies the most important changes made
                        between the two Constituents:--</p>
                    <p>Other States may be admitted into this confederacy by a vote of two-thirds of
                        the whole House of Representatives and two-thirds of the Senate; the Senate
                        voting by States; but no new State shall be formed or erected within the
                        jurisdiction of any other State; nor any State be formed by the junction of
                        two or more States or parts of States without the consent of the
                        Legislatures of the States concerned, as well as of the Congress.</p>
                    <p>The Congress shall have power to dispose of and make all needful rules and
                        regulations concerning the property of the confederate States, including the
                        lands thereof.</p>
                    <p>The Confederate States may acquire new territory, and Congress shall have
                        power to legislate and provide governments for the inhabitants of all
                        territory belonging to the Confederate States laying [sic] without the
                        limits of the several States, and may permit them, at such times and in such
                        manner as it may by law provide, to form States to be admitted into the
                        confederacy. In all such territory the institution of negro slavery as it
                        now exists in the confederate States shall be recognized and protected by
                        Congress and by the territorial government, and the inhabitants of the
                        several confederate States and Territories shall have the right to take to
                        such territory any slaves lawfully held by them in any of the States or
                        Territories of the Confederate States.</p>
                    <p>The Confederate States shall guarantee to every State that now is or
                        hereafter may become a member of this confederacy a republican form of
                        government, and shall protect each of them against invasion; and on
                        application of the Legislature (or of the Executive when the Legislature is
                        not in session) against domestic violence.</p>
                    <p>We have here presented for the information of our readers the most important
                        features in the Constitution adopted for the government of the Southern
                        Republic. It is copied almost verbatim from the Constitution of the United
                        States with the exception of the few alternations and additions we have
                        pointed out. The instruments are still so nearly alike in all essential
                        particulars that our secession friends can hardly claim that they are not
                        still living under the Constitution of the United States.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Extracts sections of the Confederate Constitution and bemoans the fact that
                    the "noblest government on the face of the earth has been broken up for the sake
                    of a party which is largely in the minority in the country".</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/march61.html#3.20b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>A Friendly Warning</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spirit expresses its difficulty in refraining from comment on "the vile
                    sheet" published by the "straight out Douglas town clique."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Dutch Plank</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Alleges that Lincoln promised Administrative appointments to get the German
                    vote. This has supposedly led to infighting between the Know Nothing Republicans
                    and the German Republicans.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Great Gaines Case</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces Supreme Court decision in the Gaines Case.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Population of Pennsylvania</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Table shows population of each county in Pennsylvania for 1850 and 1860
                    based on census data.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>United States Senator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that David Wilmot was selected to serve the unexpired term of Gen.
                    Cameron. The Spirit takes a jab at Wilmot claiming he can "readily change his
                    principles to suit every emergency."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Negro Applicants for Office</head>
                <origin>New York Express</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Asserts that many blacks have applied for government jobs and suggests that
                    each applicant be required to state their race on the application to weed out
                    the blacks before they are mistakenly hired.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The New York Tribune on Maj. Anderson.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spirit accuses the Tribune of hypocrisy for criticizing Maj. Anderson
                    for evacuating Fort Moultrie and refusing reinforcements at Sumter.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Southern Ports to be Blockaded</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>More news of the blockade plan and Southern reaction to this maneuver.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Bottom illegible.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.03.20.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Borough Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"In the South Ward the Democracy made a clean sweep, and in the North Ward
                    where we are usually beaten two to one, the Republican majority was whittled
                    down to so small a point that it leaves them nothing to brag of."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--The election in this place for borough officers on Friday last was warmly
                        contested. A larger vote was out than has ever before been polled at a town
                        election. In the South Ward the Democracy made a clean sweep, and in the
                        North Ward where we are usually beaten two to one, the Republican majority
                        was whittled down to so small a point that it leaves them nothing to brag
                        of. They only succeeded after the most strenuous exertions in their
                        Gibralter--the North Ward--in electing their Justice by seven of a majority
                        and their constable by five! The following are the officers elected:</p>
                    <p>NORTH WARD--<emph rend="italic">Justice:</emph> T. M. Fletcher; <emph
                            rend="italic">Judge:</emph> George Flack; <emph rend="italic"
                            >Inspectors:</emph> S. M. Shillito and B. F. Nead; <emph rend="italic"
                            >Assessor:</emph> K. S. Taylor; <emph rend="italic">Ass't
                        Assessors:</emph> Charles Gelwicks and Jacob Jarrett, <emph rend="italic"
                            >Constable:</emph> R. K. McClelland.</p>
                    <p>SOUTH WARD--<emph rend="italic">Justice:</emph> George Jarrett; <emph
                            rend="italic">Judge:</emph> S. M. Worley; <emph rend="italic"
                            >Inspectors:</emph> Wm. Guthrie and J. Boyd Wright; <emph rend="italic"
                            >Assessor:</emph> H. B. Davison; <emph rend="italic">Ass't
                        Assessors:</emph> James Reilly and A. J. Brand; <emph rend="italic"
                            >Constable:</emph> Samuel Boyd.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fletcher</ln>
                        <fn>T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flack</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nead</ln>
                        <fn>B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Getwicks</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jarrett</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClelland</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jarrett</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Worley</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guthrie</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>J. Boyd</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davison</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reilly</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brand</ln>
                        <fn>A.J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyd</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports the results of the borough elections.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/march61.html#3.20a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Death of John Heck</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heck</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports the death of former resident Rev. John Heck. He died in Smithsburg,
                    Md., where he had been in charge of the Lutheran Congregation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>How can the Revenue be Collected?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Questions how the revenue can be collected from the seceded states.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>A String of Pearls</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Criticizes Lincoln by using excerpts from his speeches.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Philips</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Graham</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Etchberger</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on March 12th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ault</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parks</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dulaborn</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on March 14th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McHenry</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lowry</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keller</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on March 14th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McHenry</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beeler</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hullinger</ln>
                        <fn>Susana</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on March 14th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Chambersburg and Baltimore markets</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.03.20.06">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.03.20.07">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.03.20.08">
            <div type="l">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>To the Editor of the Valley Spirit</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>X.Y.Z.</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter from XYZ telling the editor that he and his hunting party found a
                    poem amongst the animal remains of last year's hunting party on Ray's Hill. The
                    poem, entitled "The Camp," is included.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Cuban Messenger</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Havana has granted the establishment of warehouses to store
                    Southern cotton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
