<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1861/pa.fr.vs.1861.11.20">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Brian Erb</taggerName>
            <tagDate>04.22.96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 6/6/97</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1861-11-20">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="11">November</month>
            <day>20</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.11.20.01">
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Extract from a Private Letter</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The moment General Draton took to his horse in the panic of the 7th, his
                    two hundred servants took to the Wabash. This is worthy of notice, as putting
                    down the romance that the slaves were ready to fight for their masters."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The following is an extract from a private letter from one of the officers
                        engaged in the bombardment.</p>
                    <p>"I am sure our success will rejoice your heart. It has been complete, and
                        terror runs over the whole country. The negroes are wild, and plundering
                        their master's houses. The whites have been driving the negroes away by
                        force, and shooting them down, but they still come down to the gun-boats.</p>
                    <p>The moment General Drayton took to his horse in the panic of the 7th, his two
                        hundred servants took to the <emph rend="italic">Wabash</emph>--This is
                        worthy of notice, as putting down the romance that the slaves were ready to
                        fight for their masters. They surrounded Captain Ammen in crowds, at
                        Beaufort, one of them calling out, in the joy of his heart:--'I didn't think
                        you could do it, massa!"</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A letter from a Union officer engaged in the actions on the South Carolina
                    coast details the reaction of slaves to the Union victory.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Various items of national and war news, especially news of Gen. Sherman's
                actions in South Carolina.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.11.20.02">
            <pageNote>Poetry, fiction, and anecdotes</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.11.20.03">
            <pageNote>Poetry and advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.11.20.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>On the Right Track</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The National Administration appears to be getting its eyes open to the
                    fact the its worst enemies at the North are the traitor smellers who have been
                    counselling the mobbing of Democratic printing offices."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Asserts that the radical Republicans do more harm to the Union cause than
                    any Democrats do.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Our Time Coming</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>". . . we published official statistics of the resources of the South,
                    taken from the Census reports of our own government. We did this with no purpose
                    of creating or aiding rebellion anywhere, but merely to convince our belligerent
                    Republican friends that the conquest of the South would be no holiday affair,
                    and that in their frenzied partisan rancor they were deceiving themselves as to
                    the powers of resistance of that division of the country."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>At the outset of the difficulties which have culminated in open war between
                        the two sections of our country, and when we were imploring the dominant
                        party to make same concessions in order to avert the horrors of fraternal
                        strife, we published official statistics of the resources of the South,
                        taken from the Census reports of our own government. We did this with no
                        purpose of creating or aiding rebellion anywhere, but merely to convince our
                        belligerent Republican friends that the conquest of the South would be no
                        holiday affair, and that in their frenzied partisan rancor they were
                        deceiving themselves as to the powers of resistance of that division of the
                        country. We <emph rend="italic">knew</emph> that the South was not the
                        powerless, poverty stricken country that Republicans who passed among their
                        party for intelligent men were in the habit of representing it to be--we
                            <emph rend="italic">knew</emph> that it could not be whipped by a mere
                        corporal's guard of United States soldiers, no matter how brave or how well
                        disciplined they might be, and that it could not be starved into submission
                        in a fortnight by cutting off its supplies of flour and bacon; and we wished
                        to cram a little knowledge on these subjects into the heads of those who
                        were brawling for war in preference to compromise. We wanted our own section
                        of the Union, to which we are unchangeably attached, to go into the contest
                        with its eyes open, if it went into it at all, to go in with a full
                        knowledge of the strength and resources of its antagonist, and with adequate
                        preparations for any emergency. For rendering this service to our own
                        section of the country, we were denounced as secessionists by no
                        inconsiderable number of the opposite party, and by a few professing
                        "Democrats" who were several degrees blacker, as well as meaner, than the
                        blackest among Black Republicans. We did not swerve from our course,
                        however, for we very well know that time would vindicate us. And it has.</p>
                    <p>Immediately after the disastrous battle of Bull Run, Gov. Sprague went home
                        to Rhode Island and in an official communication to the Legislature told
                        them that the North deceived themselves in relation to the power and
                        resources of the South, and that the Southern soldiers, instead of being
                        half starved and half clothed, were in all respects better equipped than our
                        own.--Gen. BURNSIDE went home and told the same story. And from that time to
                        this, we have had from one prominent Republican after another, similar
                        confessions of Northern ignorance and self-deception about Southern
                        resources. We have been diligently collecting these <emph rend="italic"
                            >Republican vindications of the Valley Spirit</emph>, with the intention
                        of laying them before our readers; they can then <emph rend="italic"
                        >judge</emph> of the extent and correctness of some peoples information who
                        make pretensions to be a <emph rend="italic">judge!</emph> When we publish
                        these vindications, as we shall before long, our bitterest political
                        opponent, if he has one grain of fairness in his whole body, he will be
                        compelled to admit that the <emph rend="italic">Valley Spirit</emph> was the
                        only newspaper in the county that served the Union cause from the beginning,
                        because it was the only one that gave correct information of the power and
                        resources of the enemy. We shall on this point overwhelm our calumniators,
                        with evidence drawn from the highest Republican sources.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the Spirit and all Democrats are vindicated by the fact that
                    their dire warnings about the difficulties of war have come to pass.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>look</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Independent Apologizes</head>
                <origin>Patriot and Union</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"This rebellion will never end...until the Government of the United States
                    treat Abolition secession and Abolition treason and traitors precisely as it
                    does, and ought, traitors who are influenced against the Government by no matter
                    what motive or inducement."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Asserts that abolitionists and their organs in the press are just as
                    hostile to the Union as are slavocrats in the South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Providence Journal</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Journal believes that the war has done more to "develop the ingenuity
                    and cultivate the industry of the Southerners than years of peace." The war has
                    thus greatly increased the respect shown to skilled laborers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Pennsylvania Troops in Transit</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Over</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A soldier from Strasburg in Franklin County was lost overboard while being
                    transported to Kentucky on a river steamer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Camp Silfer</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brand</ln>
                        <fn>A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thomson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rhodes</ln>
                        <fn>Benj.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports on Franklin county soldiers in camp.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Death From Exposure</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spear</ln>
                        <fn>Alex</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A drunk reveler walking to a wedding party died of exposure after passing
                    out on the side of the road.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>In Town</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Housum</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lt. Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that Housum was in town recruiting for the 77th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Locals</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"No murders have been committed, no elopements taken place, nothing
                    shocking, horrible or revolting has happened since our last issue."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Jokingly bemoans a lack of local news.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Glad to Hear It</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Klink</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James Klink of Newville takes issue with an alleged slander printed about
                    him in one of the Chambersburg papers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.11.20.05">
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McHenry</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bonebrake</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bocenstos</ln>
                        <fn>Kate</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on November 10.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McHenry</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strock</ln>
                        <fn>J. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Getwicks</ln>
                        <fn>Rachel Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on November 13.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McHenry</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ebersole</ln>
                        <fn>Christian</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rutt</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on November 14.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McHenry</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Benastaffer</ln>
                        <fn>Martha</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on November 14.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneck</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mattes</ln>
                        <fn>Casper</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lawrence</ln>
                        <fn>Laura</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on November 7.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneck</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hart</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on October 17.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>Emma</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>Eliza</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Death of Emma Young.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Items of national and war news and advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.11.20.06">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.11.20.07">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.11.20.08">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
