<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1861/pa.fr.vs.1861.06.29">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Colleen Doody</taggerName>
            <tagDate>1/16/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; second pass 5/7/97</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1861-06-29">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="06">June</month>
            <day>29</day>
            <weekday id="SAT">Saturday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>semi-weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.06.29.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The War! From Washington</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A sentiment exists amongst Northern visitors to Washington that the federal
                    government should seek a compromise. It is rumored that Lincoln holds a similar
                    belief. Gen. Scott, while training the volunteers for battle, "is not disposed
                    to strike a decisive blow until after the meeting of Congress."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Interesting News from the Virginia Line</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A Maryland secessionist recently arrived in Frederick from Winchester
                    reports that the main body of the rebel army that had been at Harper's Ferry is
                    stationed at the Fair Grounds at Winchester.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Western Virginia Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The western Virginia convention has finished its business for the present
                    and has gone home. The new legislature will meet in Wheeling next Monday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Guerilla War in Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"Parties who have come in to-night from the interior counties [of
                    Virginia], represent them to be in a state of guerilla war. Great anxiety is
                    felt here [in Wheeling]. Effectual means should be taken to rid the State of the
                    scoundrels who now disturb its peace."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>From Fortress Monroe</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The gun boat Monticello made a reconnaissance trip up the Rappahanock river
                    and landed a small party at the home of a friend of the pilot. While the sailors
                    conversed with the ladies, three companies of rebels rushed into the party and
                    shot two men. The Captain of the Monticello opened fire on the rebels and killed
                    or wounded a large number. The house was completely demolished.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Southern News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Louisville Journal printed a letter stating that voters in the first
                    congressional district were asked whether they were for the North or the South.
                    A friend of Mr. Crittenden denies that Crittenden would offer a compromise or
                    advise Kentucky to secede.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Interesting Army Intelligence from the Upper Potomac</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Intelligence has arrived in Hagerstown indicating that Gov. Wise has
                    decided to go by steamer to Lewisburg, Greenbrier county with a force of 4,000
                    men to repel an expedition.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Later from Grafton--Anticipated Attack on the Federal Troops at Philippi</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>As soon as Gov. Wise arrives in the rebel camp near Philippi, he and his
                    men will attack the Federal camp there.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>From Washington</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paymasters of the army are paying off the regiments in the Washington
                    area. The President will not call for any compromise in his speech at the
                    opening of the extra session of Congress. Instead, the administration will
                    continue to follow the policies set out in the inaugural address.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Harper's Ferry--A View from the Maryland Heights</head>
                <origin>Correspondence N.Y. Herald</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes the abandoned Southern camp built on the Maryland Heights across
                    from Harper's Ferry.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>From Harper's Ferry</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Confederate troops returned to Harper's Ferry to recommence their
                    destruction. They set fire to the bridge over the Shenandoah and threw a
                    railroad locomotive into the water. When townspeople saw the troops coming, they
                    ran into the river and attempted to swim or wade to Maryland. The Confederates
                    arrested a number of prominent Unionists.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.06.29.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The War</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper has little war news because nothing is happening in the field. It
                    appears that Gen. Scott will not make a move until after Congress meets. The
                    President has no power to increase the regular army or enroll volunteers for
                    three years, so Scott will not enter the field until he knows what Congress will
                    do about the volunteers. The South appears ready to accept a compromise as long
                    as it can back down with grace. The Spirit doesn't want the South to receive an
                    offer that is dishonorable to the country. Instead, the secessionists should be
                    made an example of in order to prove a warning to the abolitionists. "Let both
                    be made to understand that they cannot trample upon the Constitution, and
                    disturb the peace of the country, whenever they feel disposed to ventilate their
                    peculiar ideas or exercise their bad propensities."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>Look</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Baltimore</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Major General Banks arrested the Baltimore Chief of Police because he
                    protected men who resisted the laws of Maryland.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Cameron vs. Curtin</head>
                <origin>Philadelphia Inquirer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Pennsylvania volunteers are barefoot and more or less naked because of
                    the shoddy clothing provided to them by Gov. Curtin. Curtin's followers have
                    gotten rich as a result of their state contracts to provide clothing for the
                    army.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>Look</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Promoted</head>
                <origin>Juniata Democrat</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>D. W. Chambers is doing well as the Postmaster of the 14th Regiment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Personal</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Valley Spirit once again beseeches its readers to give it money or the
                    paper will go out of business.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>An Unfounded Rumor</head>
                <origin>National Intelligencer</origin>
                <commentary>The Intelligencer contradicts the rumor started by the New York World
                    that Jefferson Davis had attempted to suspend the hostilities.</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Confederacy is increasingly determined to prosecute the war. There is
                    no evidence that Davis wants an armistice.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Frank H. Pierpont</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Frank Pierpont has just been elected Governor of Virginia. He took a firm
                    stand in defense of the government at the first outbreak of secession. He was a
                    member of the first Wheeling Convention and opposed the effort to organize a
                    provisional government.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Daniel Paisley</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Daniel Paisley is the new Lieutenant Governor of Virginia. At the first
                    Wheeling Convention, he proposed the policy of declaring Virginia state offices
                    vacant because all who held them were treasonous.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Election in Kentucky</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>All the Kentucky Congressional districts, with the exception of the First,
                    elected Union supporters.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Ben McCulloh</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Ben McCulloh, who is frequently referred to as a man of military renown,
                    never, except on one occasion, commanded more than a company of men. He is a man
                    of undoubted courage, but he isn't a soldier.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Latest from the South</head>
                <origin>New Orleans Delta</origin>
                <commentary>"The Delta provides 'the following intelligence concerning the conduct
                    of our officers in Alexandria.'"</commentary>
                <excerpt>"The Yankee officers at Alexandria parade the streets with negro women
                    leaning upon their arms, and seeking the smiles of the ebons promise to free
                    them."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary/>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>The Siege at the War Office</head>
                <origin>N.Y. World</origin>
                <commentary>The World "gives a description of the hordes of contractors and
                    office-seekers who besiege the office of Secretary Cameron."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Unflattering description of the contractors in front of the office of the
                    Secretary of War. Many of them are from "some rural village of the Keystone
                    State."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is rumored that the Administration is about to appoint Henry Winer Davis
                    to the Austrian Mission. Davis was defeated in his run for Congress from
                    Baltimore. The Spirit believes that "appointing discarded politicians to foreign
                    missions is at best doubtful--but no greater insult could be offered to the
                    Union men of Baltimore than to commission Henry Winter Davis."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Effects of the War</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Fifty newspapers have stopped publishing in the last ninety days as a
                    result of the war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>The Foreign Element</head>
                <origin>Albany Evening Journal</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Foreign born soldiers are proving their allegiance to the nation with their
                    disciplined service in the army.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"Every Farmer, Mechanic and Workingman will be benefitted by a speedy
                    restoration of Peace. . . . But for the unfortunate troubles now surrounding our
                    country, we ought to have most prosperous times. The country had recovered from
                    the reverses of 1757 [sic] and was ready to enter upon a career of unexampled
                    prosperity. With the establishment of a just and honorable peace, prosperity
                    must again soon smile upon our land."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>A Warming to Ultraism</head>
                <origin>Baltimore American</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Warns Northerners to not mistake the character of Union sentiment in
                    Maryland--Maryland is still with the South, but with every Union man of the
                    South. She rejects the ultraism of the North.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>The Rebel Army</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A Northern man who has worked on Southern railroads for the last five years
                    provides the Spirit with a description of Southern life since secession. He
                    believes that many Union men have been impressed into the rebel army. He
                    believes that the soldiers cannot compare in stature with the Union soldiers
                    because they aren't well clothed and lack discipline.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Strong Union Sentiment in California</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Democrats in Sacramento adopted a resolution stating that "the
                    Constitution and the Union, as others designed them, constitute the best
                    security for our liberties and prosperity."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>No Party</head>
                <origin>Patriot and Union</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Patriot and Union objects to the Republican policy of "no party." It
                    argues that this policy means that Democrats are dissuaded from putting up
                    candidates while Republicans continue to elect their own.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>Look</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.06.29.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Speech of Gov. Stevens</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Gov. Stevens, in his speech to the Convention for the territory of
                    Washington, stated that he opposed secession because, if Americans supported the
                    doctrine that one state can "alter or break up the contract without the consent
                    of the others, . . . anarchy will reign throughout the land, and all hopes of
                    regulated liberty will come to an end."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Capture of the Connecticut Officer</head>
                <origin>N.Y. Evening Post</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Story of the capture of an officer in Alexandria, who was "enticed" by
                    women into a home and then seized by secessionists.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Southern News via Richmond</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Miscellaneous war news from the South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sibbet</ln>
                        <fn>Nancy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sibbet</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Nancy Sibbet died on April 20.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kissal</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Kissal died on June 25th at 70 years of age.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.06.29.04">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
