<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1861/pa.fr.vs.1861.05.18">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Colleen Doody</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1861-05-18">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day>18</day>
            <weekday id="SAT">Saturday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>semi-weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.05.18.01">
            <div type="l">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Army Correspondence--Letter from Camp Scott</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter from J.S.K. in which he discusses being ordered to prepare to march
                    at a moments' notice, target practice, receiving gifts from the women of
                    Chambersburg, and the shooting of a member of the Johnstown Rifles who entered a
                    home in York, "abused the family and took hold of one of the women in the
                    house."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>Look</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Masonic Secession</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"We learn from Augusta that the Grand Chapter of Royal Arch Masons of the
                    State of Georgia have adopted a resolution disconnecting themselves from the
                    general Grand Chapter of the United States."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>From Washington</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Miscellaneous war news from Washington.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Important Statement of Colonel Anderson at Harrisburg</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Col. Anderson met briefly with the Governor, members of the Pennsylvania
                    Legislature and other state officials. He announced that John C. Breckinridge
                    would join him in Cincinnati to take command under him.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Pennsylvania Troops at Baltimore</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A portion of the First Pennsylvania regiments arrived at Woodbury. Other
                    Pennsylvania troops are on their way to Washington.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Governor Hicks and the Mayor of Baltimore--Condition of the City--Rumored
                    Arrests</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Governor Hicks denies Mayor Brown's charge that he authorized the
                    destruction of the railroad bridges.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Proclamation of the Governor of Maryland</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Governor of Maryland agrees to the President's request for four
                    regiments of infantry or riflemen to serve for three months as long as they
                    shall serve within the limits of Maryland or for the defense of the Capital.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Proclamation from Gen. Butler</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The General orders all traitorous actions in Maryland to cease. He states
                    that he will not seize property unless the owner is engaged in helping the
                    secessionists. He proclaims that the ordinary operation of the government of
                    Baltimore will continue.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>From Washington--Southern Spies</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The federal government does not seize or punish spies arriving from the
                    South, while the Confederacy continues to seize Northerners who travel to the
                    South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>News from the South</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Two men who have been living in the South report that military preparations
                    are being made in Virginia and North Carolina. General Lee has been given the
                    command of all Confederate forces in Virginia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Harper's Ferry</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>More troops continue to move to Harper's Ferry from Virginia, and an attack
                    is expected soon.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Precautions against Fire</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The government has begun taking precautions against future attempts to set
                    fire to or blow up buildings in which soldiers are located.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Arrest of Ross Winans by Federal Officers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Ross Winans, Baltimore arms manufacturer, was arrested by the government.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.05.18.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Campbell's Artillery</head>
                <origin>York Gazette</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"The artillery company of Capt. Campbell has drilled frequently on the
                    Common and the various movements are witnessed with great interest by our
                    citizens."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Religious</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Rev. J. Steck, Pastor of the Lutheran Church, will resume regular services
                    next Sunday. Rev. S. H. Reid of Huntington will preach in the German Reformed
                    Church next Sunday as well.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Getting Used to It</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Our citizens are becoming used to the novelty of the presence of a large
                    body of military in their midst."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Our citizens are becoming used to the novelty of the presence of a large body
                        of military in their midst. They seem to attract but little attention, or
                        interest, any longer and our people are settling down to their usual
                        occupations in their quiet way as formerly. The fear of an attack from "over
                        the line" has also died out, and we would not be much surprised to hear of
                        our young ladies and gentlemen getting up a pic-nic to Harper's Ferry some
                        pleasant day just for the novelty of the thing.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Townspeople are getting used to the presence of the soldiers. They also are
                    less fearful of an attack from the South. The Spirit "would not be much
                    surprised to hear of our young ladies and gentlemen getting up a picnic to
                    Harper's Ferry some pleasant day just for the novelty of the thing."</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/may61.html#5.18b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Capt. Reilly's Rifles</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Capt. Reilly's company from Camp McAllen marched through the streets of
                    Chambersburg and maneuvered in the Public Square. The large crowd present
                    admired them for their fine drill and appearance.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Regimental Parade</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The three regiments from Camp Slifer marched through town last Thursday.
                    The Spirit believes they have improved since their arrival here and "may now be
                    considered sufficiently drilled to enter battle and stand fire like veterans."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>A Worthy Example</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spirit praises the patriotism of Fletcher Webster, son of Daniel
                    Webster, who Lincoln removed from the office of Surveyor of the Port of Boston.
                    Webster volunteered to raise a regiment of volunteers for immediate service to
                    protect Washington.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Educational Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shoemaker</ln>
                        <fn>P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Educational Convention that was to be held at Harrisburg on the 21st.
                    has been postponed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Flag Presentation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"On Wednesday last a handsome flag was presented to the 7th Regiment, as a
                    mark of regard from the ladies of Chambersburg."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On Wednesday last a handsome flag was presented to the 7th Regiment, as a
                        mark of regard from the ladies of Chambersburg. The interesting ceremony
                        took place in the Diamond, in the presence of the 7th and 8th regiments and
                        a large concourse of citizens. The flag was presented by W. S. Stinger, on
                        behalf of the ladies in a very neat and able address. Col. Ripley responded,
                        on the part of the regiment, in a speech of great force and beauty. The
                        whole affair passed off very pleasantly and afforded a high degree of
                        gratification to the soldiers as well as our citizens.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stinger</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reipley</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that the women of Chambersburg presented a flag to the 7th
                    Regiment.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/may61.html#5.18a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Want In</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spirit denies a published report from the Harrisburg Telegraph that the
                    commissariat in Chambersburg is poor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Union Feeling in the South</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A letter from a Southern women whose husband is in the Confederate Army
                    states that he, along with many other men, would gladly leave and go North if it
                    were possible. The Spirit believes that the Confederate Army will suffer from a
                    large secession movement.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Newspaper Postage</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Chambersburg Times claims that the postage law states that weekly
                    papers will be mailed for free while semi-weekly papers will have regular
                    postage. The Spirit believes that this is just an attempt by the Times to be
                    sure that the three semi-weekly papers in the area have to pay postage while the
                    Times doesn't.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Maryland</head>
                <origin>Harrisburg Patriot and Union</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Several weeks ago, Maryland was in open rebellion against the Federal
                    Government. Now, however, the government has brought the state under control
                    through a "determined attitude . . . and a display of adequate restraining
                    force."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>A Letter from Camp Slifer</head>
                <origin>Luzerne Union</origin>
                <commentary>"The Union contains the following letter from Camp Slifer in
                    Chambersburg. It is from a member of the Wyoming Jackson Rifle company."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A letter written from a soldier at Camp Slifer. In it, he discusses camp
                    life and drilling.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Knapsacks for Democrats</head>
                <origin>New York Daily News</origin>
                <commentary>"It is a very fair parallel of the state of things in this section of
                    the country. As the Republican press here seems intent on making political
                    capital out of the war, and of charging the Democratic party and its presses
                    with disloyalty, we take it as perfectly legitimate that the facts should be
                    shown to the public."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Daily News claims that a large percentage of volunteers in the New York
                    militia are Democrats.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nixon</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davison</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keefer</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Everett</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strickler</ln>
                        <fn>Snively</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kuhn</ln>
                        <fn>Emmanuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ruthrauff</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davison</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craig</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duffield</ln>
                        <fn>P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elder</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillan</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wunderlich</ln>
                        <fn>D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hesors</ln>
                        <fn>Josiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingert</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greenwelt</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gehr</ln>
                        <fn>D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>List of elected officials of the Franklin County Farmers and Mechanics
                    Industrial Association.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>The Latest! From Washington</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Rumors abound in Washington that a Southern army is encamped behind
                    Arlington Heights. However, scouts who have recently returned from Virginia do
                    not confirm the rumors.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>From Annapolis</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Miscellaneous news from Annapolis. Brigadier General Butler was promoted to
                    Major General. "The presence of Ross Winans here yesterday created a deep
                    impression. The troops uncovered as he passed down the line."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Interesting from Baltimore</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Miscellaneous news from Baltimore. The New York and Massachusetts troops
                    withdrew from Federal Hill and returned to the Relay House. Also reports that
                    "The correspondent of the Lynchburg Virginian gives as a report the removal of
                    Washington's remains on the ground that the North was going to do the same."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>From Fortress Monroe</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The steamer Bowman arrived in New York from Fortress Monroe carrying the
                    women and children of the regular troops in the garrison. An attack on the
                    fortress is expected.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Commercial Revulsions and Failures</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Many trading houses are failing because they cannot get payments from their
                    Southern customers. In addition, some houses that trade extensively with the
                    West are also suffering.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>Look</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Bully for Chambersburg</head>
                <origin>Reading Daily Times</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Daily Times praises the ladies of Chambersburg for their generosity to
                    the soldiers and for their beauty.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>General Harney to the People of Missouri</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>General Harney published an address to the people of Missouri in which he
                    stated that the recently passed bill in the legislature amounts to an indirect
                    ordinance of secession. He believes that "Missouri must share the destiny of the
                    Union."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>The Convention at Wheeling</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Report of the convention in Wheeling to create the pro-Union "New
                    Virginia."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>From St. Louis</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The commander of state forces in Jefferson City, Missouri has issued an
                    order that any attack by soldiers or mobs on the property of citizens will be
                    dealt with harshly. When the Northern Methodist Church was stoned by a crowd of
                    drunken men, the Southern Church took up a subscription to make the necessary
                    repairs.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>News from Harper's Ferry</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Three thousand troops have reached Harper's Ferry in the past few days.
                    They are expected to make a foray into Pennsylvania in search of provisions. The
                    planters at the "entrance into the State" greatly fear John Brown, Jr.'s company
                    of black "avengers" who are said to be encamped in a valley sixty miles south of
                    Pittsburgh. The state of Pennsylvania is planning on taking measures to prevent
                    these men from "pursuing their evil design."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Attempt to Blow Up a Bridge</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that "An attempt was made last night [May 14] by Virginians to blow
                    up a bridge on the Baltimore and Ohio Railroad, just below Point of Rocks, but
                    it failed through their mismanagement. Another individual, suspiciously occupied
                    at the turnpike bridge, near Frederick, was fired upon, but escaped. As no down
                    trains have passed Frederick Junction for some hours, it is believed the track
                    or bridges above are destroyed. The country about [Chambersburg] is infested
                    with marauders whose only object seems to be destructive to private property."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.05.18.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Pay of the Army</head>
                <origin>New York Tribune</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Listing of the pay for officers and soldiers of the regular Army.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Army Regulations</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Miscellanous interesting army regulations.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Dastardly Outrages</head>
                <origin>Reading Gazette</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Gazette deplores the recent trend toward mob seizure and destruction of
                    property.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Scene in Church</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In a church in West Philadelphia, the Rev. Henry A. Wise, Jr., son of the
                    former governor of Virginia, left out the President during a Sunday prayer. A
                    prominent member of the congregation stood up and demanded that he should repeat
                    the prayer correctly. When he refused to do so, he left the pulpit without
                    saying his sermon. He has since moved to Richmond.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Markets</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lists prices at the Chambersburg, Philadelphia, New York, and Baltimore
                    markets.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneck</ln>
                        <fn>B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>York</ln>
                        <fn>Banjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Riddle</ln>
                        <fn>Ariana</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on "Thursday evening last."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Senseny</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Died on May 17th at 23 years of age.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.05.18.04">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
