				Brief Overview

	The Bureau of Refugees, Freedmen, and Abandoned Lands was established in March 1865. Its primary role was to safeguard the freedom of recently emancipated slaves. It was empowered to help black and white refugees who had been dispossessed by the war return home. The Bureau helped support them with sustenance, medicines, transportation, direction, and care. It resolved disputes involving violence and theft, and helped negotiate contracts between freedmen and white employers. The Bureau helped establish schools and churches with the aid of Northern charities.

	One of its primary achievements was the establishment of schools which awakened blacks to the need for education and established public education in the South. The contracts it negotiated often perpetuated a system of black subservience as they often served the white employer's purposes more than the black employee's. The job of an agent of the Bureau was often very dangerous for northerners who were regarded as "carpetbaggers." In texas 13% or 31 out of 234 agents were victims of some sort of violence.
	
	
	Its success was tempered by a lack of funding and support from the federal government in conjunction with opposition to it on the local level.

Below are a variety of perspectives of the Bureau:

1) "The local Bureau agent was expected to win the confidence of blacks and whites alike in a situation where race and labor relations had been poisoned by mutual distrust and conflicting interests."-Eric Foner, historian (64-65)

2) "It is not. . . in your power to fulfill one tenth of the expectations of those who framed the Bureau. I fear you have a Hercules task."-General William T. Sherman advising Bureau director O.O. Howard. (Foner, 65; W.T. Sherman to O.O. Howard, 17 May 1865 O O H Papers.

3) "The real test of the Freedmen's Bureau was. . . whether the institution could use the power Congress had granted to it to meet the most pressing needs of the freedmen."-Historian William S. McFeeley of the Bureau's inability to prevent blacks from dying of malnutrition. (Yankee stepfather, McFeeley, 1968, Yale University Press, New Haven)

4) The Freedmen's Bureau "didn't rank very high in the recrds around here. We lost a war and it had been forced into us." It was "distasteful in the eyes of the citizens, so they tended to ignore it."-Richard Hamrick, Staunton resident and history expert
