			Project's Development

	This website was built by four students at the University of Virginia in HIUS 403: Digital History and the Civil War.

Peter Brownfeld is a second year student from Alexandria VA and a history major. He will graduate in May 2000. He can be reached by email at peb7h@virginia.edu. (Link)

Ji Sun Hwang

Dominique Picou

Alessandro Santarelli

	Our goal was to discover how productive the Freedmen's Bureau was during Reconstruction. We based our research on records from the National Archives in Washington D.C., two newspapers: the Staunton Spectator, and the Staunton Vindicator, and a variety of secondary resources. Please see our Bibliography (Link) for a full listing of resources we used.
	
	One stumbling block we ran into was the lack of records and images regarding the Bureau. The individuals and organizations that we consulted in Staunton included the Staunton Historical Society, the Staunton Public Library, Mary Baldwin College, and local historical experts. These sources had little if any information regarding the Bureau. We believe this trend is not indicative of the failings of these organizations, but rather shows that during Reconstruction the Staunton community largely ignored the Bureau. As a result, our information is primarily drawn from the Bureau's records, newspapers, and secondary sources.

	We hope this website portrays what the Bureau was empowered to do, and how it coped with the many problems which it faced.
