<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1863/va.au.rv.1863.03.27">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andrew Chancey</taggerName>
            <tagDate>04/19/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>1st Pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 6/2/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1863-03-27">
            <year>1863</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day>27</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1863.03.27">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The System of Impressment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The present practice is exciting a very wide-spread and bitter
                    dissatisfaction. The seizure itself, under the best management, is very
                    distasteful to the people, but when it is accompanied by what they feel to be a
                    refusal of just compensation, it renders the policy of the Government, and
                    ultimately the Government itself, hateful."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Honorable</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reprint of letter from Honorable John B. Baldwin to Honorable James A.
                    Seddon, Secretary of War and of reply from J. A. Campbell, on behalf of Seddon,
                    on the issue of impressment. Baldwin complains about the "repeated seizures of
                    private property" in his district and argues that the acts have no legal basis.
                    Further, he calls for just compensation. Campbell's reply states that the War
                    Department does not deem a discussion of the legality of impressments or of just
                    compensations important, in light of "the extraordinary and anamolous [sic]
                    conditions that now exist." He hopes Congress will address the situation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Impressments</head>
                <origin>Richmond Whig</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor accuses the Secretary of War and the Commissary Department of
                    usurpation by practicing impressment without legal backing and of taking it upon
                    themselves to make laws. Only Congress has the power to enact legislation, as
                    stated by the attorney general.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Market Price of a Grievance</head>
                <origin>Enquirer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"[W]e have learned political economists here, who, in their ardent pursuit
                    of grievances, declare that the impressment of provisions for our troops and
                    artillery horses, in this great emergency and stress of war, is a grievance,
                    unless the army pay for it at the highest rate that sudden demand and extreme
                    need can run up the price to."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor wonders where the "widespread and bitter dissatisfaction"
                    Baldwin refers to may be found regarding impressment and states that the only
                    hateful government is the Northern one.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>A Good Hotel Story</head>
                <origin>Atlanta Confederacy</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates the story of a military officer who stayed at an Atlanta hotel and
                    thought his bill at the end was too high. His complaint made the owner so mad
                    that he whipped three African-American minors to vent his hostility.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>This page also includes a reprint of President Davis's proclamation on a day
                of fasting, a poem, reports from the Confederate Congress and the Virginia
                legislature, and various war news.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1863.03.27">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>To Our People</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor notes that he has become aware of families that, no matter their
                    hard work, are not able to supply their families sufficiently and may be too
                    proud to ask for assistance. He calls on farmers to distribute their crops at
                    reduced rates or free to these people and on all people to look out for one
                    another so that husbands and fathers in the field may know their loved ones are
                    not suffering unnecessarily.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Genl.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Genl.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The editor reports that General W. H. Harman read a letter from General
                    Imboden at the adjournment of county court on Monday night. The letter relayed
                    the news of ten destitute families in Pendleton County. The few people in
                    attendance contributed $350 and provisions, and Samuel H. Bell offered to buy
                    enough wheat to supply the families.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Our Neighbor</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We . . . content ourselves by saying generally that his premises are bad,
                    his reasoning worse and conclusions consequently incorrect, his inferences
                    overdrawn, and the only fact he asserts perverted."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor chastises the editor of the Spectator for criticisms of the
                    Vindicator. The editor of the Spectator had accused the editor of the Vindicator
                    of silence on issues such as war bonds and impressment and had faulted him for
                    his positions on reunification and northwestern Virginia. The editor of the
                    Vindicator responds to each of these criticisms.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Proceedings of the Baltimore Annual Conference</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jefferson</ln>
                        <fn>G. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rippetoe</ln>
                        <fn>W. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hildebrand</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moore</ln>
                        <fn>J. A. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dice</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gaver</ln>
                        <fn>H. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baird</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Haslip</ln>
                        <fn>L. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Baltimore Annual Conference of Preachers met in Churchville, Augusta
                    County, for five days beginning March 19. Reports from daily business are
                    included. A list of appointments to the conference of persons from Augusta
                    County includes J. S. Martin, Churchville District; Thomas Hildebrand and J. A.
                    H. Moore, Churchville; G. R. Jefferson and W. D. Rippetoe, West Augusta; J. C.
                    Dice, Staunton; H. A. Gaver and J. L. Snyder, Augusta; R. Smith, Mt. Sidney; and
                    W. S. Baird, Principal, Wesleyan Female Institute and Member of Staunton
                    Quarterly Conference. L. W. Haslip is a member of the Augusta Quarterly
                    Conference.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>J. Wayt</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Col. M. G. Harman has sent loads of wood to poor families in town, as have
                    other local farmers. J. Wayt Bell sells his flour locally at a rate lower than
                    what he could get if he shipped it elsewhere.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Ball at the Odd Fellows' Hall</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hardy</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Marquis</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGuffin</ln>
                        <fn>D. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>N. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A ball to be held March 31 will benefit soldiers' families. The committee
                    planning the ball consists of J. M. Hardy, J. C. Marquis, D. C. McGuffin, and N.
                    K. Trout.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Impressment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Points readers to the letters and editorials regarding impressment and
                    calls on readers to see both sides of the question.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Also on this page are the text of a Confederate currency bill, advertisements,
                and notices.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
