<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1863/va.au.rv.1863.11.13">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andrew Chancey</taggerName>
            <tagDate>05/03/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>1st Pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 6/15/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1863-11-13">
            <year>1863</year>
            <month norm="11">November</month>
            <day>13</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1863.11.13.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Negro Recruiting Officer Killed</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A recruiting officer for African-American soldiers was killed in St. Mary's
                    County, Maryland. Lieutenant White, the officer killed, had heard that prominent
                    slave owner Colonel John H. Sotheron had two slaves tied up so they could not
                    enlist. White visited Sotheron, who refused to release the slaves and who, with
                    his son, threatened to attack White. White proceeded to a field where some of
                    Sotheron's slaves were working and announced that he was willing to enlist
                    anyone so interested. He was then killed by the two Sotherons.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>A South Carolina Negro in New York</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A chaplain left behind with the wounded at Gettysburg reports that few
                    African Americans captured at Gettysburg took the oath of allegiance to the
                    Yankees. He relates a conversation between a South Carolina African American and
                    Yankee General Morris in which the former refuses to fight for the North.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Also on this page are a list of deserters from the 52nd Regiment of Virginia
                Volunteers, an article on diphtheria, war news, anecdotes, advertisements, notices,
                and a poem.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1863.11.13.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>War News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>General</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>In a weekly column on developments in the war, the editor writes this week
                    that the enemy is about fifty miles west of Staunton and is advancing towards
                    the town.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Aiding and Abetting Deserters</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yates</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George Yates from Augusta County plus several from Rockingham County,
                    including one father and son team, arrived in Staunton Wednesday evening. They
                    had been sent from Richmond to stand trial for the charge of "piloting deserters
                    through our lines to the Federal camps."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>A Bride Worth Having</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lucy F. Roller, the daughter of a wealthy farmer in Rockingham County,
                    married recently. She made everything she wore, from her straw hat to her shoes
                    to the material for her dress and cloak. She was not compelled by poverty or
                    necessity but by a desire to demonstrate her independence, "showing the world
                    how independent Southern girls are."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Stonewall Jackson and Religion in the Army</head>
                <origin>Central Presbyterian</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This excerpt from the Central Presbyterian discusses the role of
                    Christianity in the life of Stonewall Jackson and the revival that has swept
                    through his troops since his death. More than two thousand soldiers have made
                    professions of faith within the past two months.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Means and Resources</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article lists the valuations of property in each of the Confederate
                    states as based on the 1860 census, suggests that inflation of the war increases
                    each value five fold, and argues that the financial backing to carry out the war
                    is "well nigh inexhaustible" for the Confederates.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hawpe</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hawpe</ln>
                        <fn>Adam M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Maggie A. Hawpe, daughter of Adam M. Hawpe of Augusta County, married
                    Simeon E. Miller of Burnwell, S. C., on November 5, with Rev. Mr. Hicks
                    officiating.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Marshall</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George W. Marshall, 26, died October 3 at the home of his father in Augusta
                    County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Notice to Furloughed Soldiers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paul</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieutenant</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Byers</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Captain J. S. Byers, enrolling officer for the 11th congressional district,
                    notifies soldiers on furlough that they must register their presence with
                    Lieutenant S. Paul, the enrolling officer for Augusta County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Augusta Raid Guard!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Colonel</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Colonel John B. Baldwin, having been elected to the temporary command of
                    the county organization, calls for members to make immediate preparations for
                    emergency rather than wait for the selection of permanent officers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Also on this page are articles containing war news, advertisements, and
                notices.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
