<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1863/va.au.rv.1863.03.20">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andrew Chancey</taggerName>
            <tagDate>03/22/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>1st Pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 6/2/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1863-03-20">
            <year>1863</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day>20</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1863.03.20">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Press</head>
                <origin>Dispatch</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The Press of the South has been the life and breath of this Revolution. .
                    . . It has aroused the patriotism, encouraged the hopes, nerved the hearts, and
                    strengthened the arms of the people of the South throughout this contest."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Praises the role of the press in furthering the Southern cause and asserts
                    the superiority of the role of the press over that of politicians, who corrupt
                    people and sacrifice principle in advancing their own causes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>New York Tribune and New York Argus</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Two excerpts from New York newspapers discuss the shift from cotton
                    production to corn production in the South. One writer notes the failure of the
                    experiment of free African-American labor in Beaufort, South Carolina, and
                    argues that an attempt to produce corn in the same way will fail also.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that a bill has been introduced in the United States Senate calling
                    for the establishment of an academy to educate African-American youth in
                    Washington, DC.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>This page also contains a reprint of the proclamation from President Davis
                calling for a day of fasting, a poem, reports from the Virginia and Confederate
                legislatures, and various war news.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1863.03.20">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The African as a Citizen</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the United State Congress ratified a treaty with the Republic
                    of Liberia stating that Liberians were eligible to become United States citizens
                    through the same process available to persons from other countries. The editor
                    notes that the point of establishing Liberia in the first place had been "to
                    relieve the United States of a population, which, whenever assembled in any
                    number, has been a disagreeable and deleterious element of society." The editor
                    warns Liberians that citizenship will mean they will be put on the front lines
                    and that few privileges of citizenship await them after the war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A concert at the Presbyterian Church on March 26 will benefit families of
                    soldiers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>An Old Man of Experience</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor of the Vindicator chides the editor of the Spectator for his
                    silence on positions "of vital importance" and for his criticism of the
                    Vindicator for what amounted to a proofreading error.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Tax and Currency</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor calls for Congress to take action to increase the value of
                    Confederate currency.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turk</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGuffin</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Turk and McGuffin of Mt. Solon have developed matches that light easily and
                    burn freely.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Thespians</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Soldier's Thespian Society played two nights to full houses but had to
                    cancel one night's performance because of the meeting of the county court.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wheeler</ln>
                        <fn>J. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoy</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Haldeman</ln>
                        <fn>Sallie M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Isaac L. Hoy and Sallie M. Haldeman, both of Augusta County, were married
                    March 18 by Rev. J. R. Wheeler.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hardesty</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>T. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>James H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hardesty</ln>
                        <fn>Lizzie A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hardesty</ln>
                        <fn>John E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. James H. Harris of Mt. Meridian, Augusta County, married Lizzie A.
                    Hardesty, daughter of the late John E. Hardesty, at the home of her grandfather,
                    Isaac Hardesty of Harrisonburg. Rev. T. B. Bell performed the ceremony. No date
                    is given.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mitchell</ln>
                        <fn>George H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lieut. George H. Mitchell, age 49, died February 13 at his home near
                    Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>David C. Hanger of Missouri, son of Jacob Hanger of Augusta County, died of
                    wounds he received in the battle of Kirksville, Missouri.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shiflet</ln>
                        <fn>Pemelton C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Pemelton C. Shiflet, 26, died near Vicksburg, Mississippi on December
                    7, 1862. He was a member of the Waynesboro Guards, 52nd Regiment Virginia
                    Volunteers. He was taken prisoner at the fight on Allegheny Mountain in December
                    1861, was in prison camp at Camp Chase, Ohio, for a year, and was on his way to
                    Vicksburg to be exchanged when he died.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roberts</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lucado</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palmer</ln>
                        <fn>P. O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Margaret E. Lucado, 30, wife of William F. Lucado of Lynchburg and second
                    daughter of Captain P. O. Palmer of Augusta County, died at the home of her
                    brother-in-law, Captain Roberts, near West View, Augusta County. She was a
                    member of the Methodist Church in Lynchburg and had been married three years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Notice to Conscripts</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>J. S. Byers, Captain and Enrolling Officer for Augusta County</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Byers</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shelby</ln>
                        <fn>W. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. S. Byers, Captain and Enrolling Officer for Augusta County, calls for
                    all men between 18 and 40 who are awaiting examination to report on March 27 and
                    28, by order of the Examining Board of the 11th Congressional District. W. A.
                    Shelby, Examining Surgeon, will be available for examination of conscripts on
                    those days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>List of Deserters from the Staunton Artillery</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>A. W. Garber, Capt., Staunton Artillery</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>O'Conner</ln>
                        <fn>Terence</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eddings</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Row</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fuller</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robinson</ln>
                        <fn>Marcellus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cannon</ln>
                        <fn>Martin Con</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Honnahan</ln>
                        <fn>Patrick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Markley</ln>
                        <fn>F. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ryan</ln>
                        <fn>John F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mader</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garber</ln>
                        <fn>A. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A. W. Garber, Captain of the Staunton Artillery, lists the following men
                    (all privates) as deserters and offers thirty dollars for their apprehension and
                    delivery to their company: Terence O'Conner, Staunton, 6th Virginia Cavalry;
                    Robert Eddings, Port Republic; H. Row, near Greenville; John Fuller, Marcellus
                    Robinson, Martin Con Cannon, Patrick Honnahan, George Brown, Staunton; F. A.
                    Markley, near Middlebrook; John F. Ryan, Scottsville; William F. Mader, near
                    Mint Spring; John Tanbald, J. T. Robertson, Stafford County; John King, alias
                    Haley, Maryland. The list is dated March 20, 1863.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>This page also contains various war news, advertisements and announcements,
                including one for runaway slaves in Alleghany County, and a calendar.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
