<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1863/va.au.rv.1863.02.27">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andrew Chancey</taggerName>
            <tagDate>02/27/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>1st Pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 6/2/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1863-02-27">
            <year>1863</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day>27</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1863.02.27.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>To the People of North Western Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"If you have not all acted with equal firmness, we are grateful to believe
                    (as we have many reasons for believing) that a large majority of the citizens of
                    North Western Virginia have cherished a loyal attachment to the State and that
                    they abhor treason and traitors."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Charles W. Russell, Robert Johnston, T. S. Haymond, G. D. Camden, J. M.
                    Bennett, Joseph Johnson, U. M. Turner, L. S. Hall, H. Fitzhugh, Cyrus Hall,
                    William L. Jackson, E. D. Camden, Charles W. Newlon, W. W. Newman, William
                    Johnson, E. J. Armstrong, D. McLaughlin, J. A. Alderson, J. T. Martin, James
                    Neeson</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>This letter, written by leaders of northwestern Virginia, communicates the
                    assurance that the South will emerge victorious and that northwestern Virginia
                    will remain with the rest of the state and thus with the South, where its
                    loyalties and identity lie.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"You have enjoyed [?] two years of Yankee rule, and know how to appreciate
                    its blessings! It is now in your power to throw off the yoke, assert your
                    manhood, and finally drive your oppressors from a soil their presence
                    dishonors."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>J. D. Imboden, Brigadier General, Commanding</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn>J. D.</fn>
                        <sf>Brigadier General, Commanding</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letter from Brigadier General J. D. Imboden to the "Loyal and Patriotic
                    Young Men of North Western Virginia," dated March 1, 1863. Imboden calls
                    attention to the previous letter, written by leaders from that part of the
                    state, and asks the loyal citizens from there to rid themselves of their
                    traitorous government and to join the many others from their area in the
                    Confederate military. They should be aware, he warns, that the North's goal of
                    making the South acknowledge African Americans as social and political equals
                    will begin there if they do not act hastily.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>For the Vindicator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Jno. McGill, Chaplain, 52nd Reg't Va. Vol.</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGill</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf>Chaplain</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letter from Chaplain John McGill of 52nd Regiment thanking the Gospel Hill
                    Sewing Society of Staunton for clothing and thanking the S. R. A. of
                    Fishersville for clothing and blankets.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Also on this page are news items related to the war, a report from the state
                legislature, a letter to Postmaster General Reagan concerning railroad rates for
                transporting mail, and an article about General Joseph Johnston crying when he met
                his childhood slave nurse.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1863.02.27.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Northwestern States</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"From these reasons, and from what we believe to be the policy of the
                    Confederacy to annex no territory but where slavery can be carried, because of
                    the ultimate necessity of expansion for that divine institution . . . we would
                    desire to see the Northwest a separate republic, and not a part of our
                    Confederacy."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This editorial argues that the Northwest should become its own republic,
                    independent of the tyrannical North, and, because slavery would not work there,
                    separate from the South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Honor to old Augusta</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eakle</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Capt. James Cochran of the Churchville Cavalry has been promoted to colonel
                    and Capt. B. F. Eakle of the Greenbrier Cavalry has been promoted to major, both
                    in the 14th Virginia Cavalry.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Concert</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Alby</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tinsley</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tipping</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tinsley</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guy</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The concert held last Tuesday night at the Presbyterian Church raised $400
                    and drew high praise for its performers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Concert</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The vocal and instrumental concert scheduled for February 27 has been
                    postponed until March 6.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wheeler</ln>
                        <fn>Jos. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lotts</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Corby</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel Lotts, Augusta County, married Margaret C. Corby, Augusta County, on
                    February 24, with Rev. Joseph R. Wheeler officiating.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Leapes</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Redman</ln>
                        <fn>Nancy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Nancy Redman, 63, died at the home of her son-in-law, Joseph Leapes, on
                    February 18.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>This page also contains a Confederate and a Virginia legislative report, news
                item related to the war, a reprint of the list of deserters from the 52nd Regiment,
                Virginia Volunteers, advertisements and announcements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
