<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1863/va.au.rv.1863.04.03">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andrew Chancey</taggerName>
            <tagDate>04/19/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>1st Pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 6/2/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1863-04-03">
            <year>1863</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day norm="03">3</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.sv.1863.04.03.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>"Gov." Pierpoint's Message</head>
                <origin>Richmond Dispatch</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Governor Pierpoint of northwestern Virginia asserts that Virginians have
                    been the chief supporters of the rebellion in men and supplies. The editor of
                    the Vindicator, while proud of the role of Virginians, asserts that such a claim
                    is slanderous to other Southerners.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Outspoken and Truthful</head>
                <origin>Boston Courier</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>On the issue of raising African-American regiments, the Boston Courier
                    states that the prospect of such an act is degrading, to be at a point to be
                    willing to call on inferiors for defense. The prospect is also impractical, as
                    inequality between the races renders a mixed-race regiment ineffective and as
                    supplying 150,000 African-American troops with weapons is madness.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Yankee Women</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Disparages reports that 12,824 Yankee women have signed a petition calling
                    for Lincoln "to remove the host of intemperate and incompetent military
                    officials."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor reports that men of means throughout the Confederacy have begun
                    selling produce at greatly reduced rates to soldiers' families.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Significant</head>
                <origin>Mississippian</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Mississippian notes that the Northern press has recently begun
                    referring to Confederate politicians and officers by their proper titles instead
                    of "the most opprobrious" ones used previously. In addition, the press has
                    referred to the "Government of the Confederate States," as if the Confederacy
                    were a recognized power.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Jeff. Davis's Black Battallions</head>
                <origin>Nashville Union</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>"Let not history record that, while slavery was the cause of the rebellion,
                    and the slaveholder the prime mover of the rebellion, you were such degenerate
                    dastards as to allow negro slaves to be the instruments of your country's
                    downfall, and the agency which made the rebellion so successful."</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>This excerpt reports that in a recent skirmish, the 85th Indiana was
                    attacked by two African-American regiments. The editor of the Nashville Union
                    abhors the use of African Americans among the Southern troops, as the war's
                    purpose is to free them.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>This page also includes a reprint of the act to regulate impressment, a poem,
                reports from the Virginia legislature, and various war news. Several holes and
                splotches make some of this page unreadable.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1863.04.03.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Confederate Tax Bill</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor offers a summary of the tax bill recently passed by the House of
                    Representatives.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Eight Per Cent Bonds</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor proudly states where these bonds may be purchased and offers
                    details on them.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Fellow Citizens of Augusta</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn>Howe Y.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Howe Y. Peyton announces his candidacy for the House of Delegates and seeks
                    support. In spite of his age (25 years), he asserts that he is qualified and
                    capable and motivated by devotion to service, not pride.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>For the Vindicator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Orlando</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>This writer complains of debris in public places, unclean streets and
                    gutters, defective water works, mismanaged gas works, extortion and speculation,
                    selling of alcohol without a license, and inefficient police.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Impressment Bill</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor calls readers' attention to the Impressment Bill published
                    elsewhere in the newspaper. He states that the bill seems intended to protect
                    the producer and the buyer and that farmers can grow their crops with the
                    confidence that they will not be impressed at unfairly low prices.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Alexander Patterson, 53, died March 26, near Waynesboro.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armentrout</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Charles Armentrout, 58, died March 26, in Augusta County. A native of
                    Rockingham County, he had lived in Augusta for twelve years. Four of his sons
                    served in the army, one killed at Murfreesboro, one crippled at Manassas, and
                    one a prisoner of war taken last spring when Jackson evacuated the Valley.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>New Advertisements</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shumate</ln>
                        <fn>William J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. B. Lavell of Rockbridge offers $100 reward if his escaped slaves are
                    captured in Augusta or Rockbridge counties or $200 if captured elsewhere in the
                    state. Lavell bought Nelson three months ago from William J. Shumate of Augusta.
                    The escaped slaves, Nelson and Ezekiel, may be near Staunton, as one of them has
                    a free wife there.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Not A Deserter</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eddins</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Robert Eddins was "surprised and mortified" to learn he was listed as a
                    deserter and offers proof in this advertisement that he has a legitimate medical
                    furlough.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Notice to Conscripts</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>H. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Major and Q. M.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Major and Quartermaster H. M. Bell calls for teamsters from this district
                    for sixty days, with possible renewal.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>This page also contains a report from the Confederate Congress, a calendar, a
                reprint of a list of deserters from the 52 Regiment of Virginia Volunteers, a
                reprint of a list of deserters from the Staunton Artillery, and
            advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
