<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1863/va.au.rv.1863.08.28">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andrew Chancey</taggerName>
            <tagDate>04/28/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>1st Pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 6/11/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1863-08-28">
            <year>1863</year>
            <month norm="08">August</month>
            <day>28</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1863.08.28.01">
            <pageNote>This page includes a list of deserters from the 52nd Regiment of Virginia
                Volunteers, a proclamation from President Davis, information on the Tax Act, a
                remedy for diphtheria, an article on the exodus of African Americans in Mississippi,
                war news, and advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1863.08.28">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Patriotic Spirit Shows</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"There was no panic here, but a fixed determination to teach the enemy an
                    additional lesson to the one involuntarily learned at Wytheville. This was
                    really a glorious day for Staunton."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>General</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Colonel</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On last Friday, the day of fasting, word reached the Commandant of the Post
                    that an enemy force was contemplating a raid on Staunton. General Imboden
                    immediately moved his forces from Rockingham to just a few miles from Staunton.
                    On Sunday night, the enemy crossed the mountains at Buffalo Gap, about twelve
                    miles from Staunton. Everything was readied for the raid, including the citizens
                    volunteer units. All citizens were eager to participate and help. The editor
                    praises the turnout and states that the event demonstrates that the hearts of
                    the citizens support the cause of the war. He claims that the county was ready
                    in case there had been an attack.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Fatal Accident on the Central Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An accident on the Central Railroad occurred last Tuesday at Bumpass's
                    Furnace when the train ran off the track, killed two persons, and injured
                    several others.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>School Exhibition</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ide</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Professor</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scherrer</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The first annual commencement of the St. Francis School will be at the
                    Catholic Church in Staunton, August 31, at 8:00 p.m. The exhibition will include
                    recitations and music, under the direction of Professor Ide. Tickets are one
                    dollar. Proceeds will pay the expenses of the event, with surplus going to the
                    benefit of sick soldiers in the General Hospital. Tickets may be bought at John
                    Scherrer's store or at the door.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>$25 Reward</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickle</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Scott, a slave, 12, light complexion, straight hair, ran away on August 13
                    from John A. Bickle. Bickle thinks Scott is still in the area and offers $25 for
                    his return.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Also on this page are a list of market prices for crops and staples, the text
                of Governor Letcher's proclamation calling for a meeting of the General Assembly, a
                reprint of orders concerning the granting of furloughs, an editorial on taxes, war
                news, advertisements, and legal notices.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
