<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1863/va.au.rv.1863.12.11">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andrew Chancey</taggerName>
            <tagDate>05/05/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>1st Pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 6/15/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1863-12-11">
            <year>1863</year>
            <month norm="12">December</month>
            <day>11</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1863.12.11.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Patriotism of Southern Women</head>
                <origin>Chicago Journal</origin>
                <commentary>The editor proudly asserts the patriotism and self-sacrifice of Southern
                    women, to the point of humbling the "mean little soul" of a Northern army
                    correspondent who observed them in action in Nashville.</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A Northern army correspondent from Chicago compares the patriotism of
                    Southern women with that of Northern women and finds that Southern women are
                    just as patriotic, however misguided their cause, as Northern women. In fact, he
                    continues, Southern women are so committed as to be feared. He cites examples
                    from their sacrifice and service to Confederate soldiers in Nashville.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Also on this page are a list of deserters from the 52nd Regiment of Virginia
                Volunteers, war news, stories and anecdotes, advertisements, and notices.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1863.12.11.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Feeding the Prisoners</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Northern prisoners have received the same rations that Confederate soldiers
                    receive, along with any extra packages Northerners sent to them. The Northern
                    government, however, wants to send them provisions, a practice to which the
                    Confederate government objected. The Confederate government contended that as
                    long as Northern prisoners received the same poor fare that Confederate soldiers
                    received, then the Northern government would be more interested in establishing
                    an exchange of prisoners. Knowing Northern men were cared for in Southern
                    prisons with food sent from the North made the issue of prisoner exchanges less
                    pressing. Thus, Southern prisoners in the North suffer longer because the North
                    is not as interested in exchanging prisoners. The editor calls for the return of
                    provisions from the North so that Northerners will be forced to exchange
                    prisoners.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Exhibition</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An exhibition by the Baptist Sunday school on Wednesday night raised $305
                    for clothing poor children. The turnout was so great that many people did not
                    get to see the exhibit, so it will be repeated tonight.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The President's Message</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor summarizes President Davis's speech submitted to Congress on
                    December 8. Davis reviewed military operations, condemned Great Britain's policy
                    towards the Confederacy, discussed the necessity of raising additional revenue
                    and troops, and called on the North to accept a proposal for peace that would
                    allow the two nations to go their own way.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamilton</ln>
                        <fn>James H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James H. Hamilton of Augusta County married Emma V. Watkins of Richmond at
                    the Monumental Church in Richmond, November 25, with Rev. George Woodbridge
                    officiating.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Augusta Raid Guard</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Marquis</ln>
                        <fn>James C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>J. Alex</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donaghe</ln>
                        <fn>B. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mason</ln>
                        <fn>C. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowman</ln>
                        <fn>F. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gamble</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The General Orders, dated December 5, 1863, calling for the service of and
                    giving instructions for the Augusta Raid Guard are printed here, along with a
                    list of the following appointments: James C. Marquis, Adjutant; Dr. J. Alex
                    Waddell, Surgeon; Dr. B. B. Donaghe, Assistant Surgeon; C. R. Mason,
                    Quartermaster; Rev. F. H. Bowman, Chaplain; and William Gamble, Sergeant Major.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Also on this page are war news, advertisements, and notices.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
