<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1863/va.au.rv.1863.11.20">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andrew Chancey</taggerName>
            <tagDate>05/03/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>1st Pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 6/15/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1863-11-20">
            <year>1863</year>
            <month norm="11">November</month>
            <day>20</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1863.11.20.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Negroes in Memphis</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The poor slaves will be left to die unaided, while not a pang of sorrow
                    will pervade the breasts of thousands of those who sent their emissaries to
                    entice them from kind masters and comfortable homes."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Thirty-five thousand slaves have escaped and made their way to the
                    Mississippi River and now look to Northern philanthropists and abolitionists for
                    assistance, only to find that those people who wanted them to gain their freedom
                    are ill equipped to help them.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>A Faithful and Sensible Slave</head>
                <origin>Augusta Constitutionalist</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates the story of a slave who escaped from the Union Army, made his way
                    to his former plantation in Mississippi, and then went to Georgia, where his old
                    master had relocated as a refugee. The slave had many stories about his
                    mistreatment by the federal troops. The Constitutionalist believes that he
                    serves as an example for other slaves who might be "deluded by false notions of
                    freedom and of the friendship of the Yankees."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>A Woman's Advantages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This collection of sayings itemizes how being a woman is so much more
                    advantageous than being a man. One excerpt that reflects the tone of all the
                    other sayings is "She can take a snoose after dinner, while her husband has to
                    work."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Also on this page are a list of deserters from the 52nd Regiment of Virginia
                Volunteers, articles on the war, an article on a balloon accident in France,
                advertisements, notices, anecdotes, and a poem.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1863.11.20.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Our Mountaineers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>General</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Quotes the praise in the Richmond Whig for the patriotic spirit exhibited
                    in Lynchburg and the surrounding area when enemy troops threatened there. The
                    editor remarks that when he returned home from viewing the response in
                    Lynchburg, the citizens of Augusta County had already assembled in their units
                    and were awaiting orders from General Imboden. The citizens of Rockingham, the
                    cadets of Virginia Military Institute, and the citizens of Augusta were ready
                    not only to defend their home territory but also to lend their assistance to
                    their neighboring counties.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Begin the Good Work!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor reminds readers of his call several weeks ago to begin making
                    socks and other items that will be needed by the soldiers in the approaching
                    winter. He is concerned that there has been so little response but is confident
                    that the people will come through on this important task.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Be Just</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phillips</ln>
                        <fn>R. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Withrow</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf>Jr., Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Withrow, Jr., Esq., of Waynesboro, wrote Assistant Quarter Master
                    in charge of the Army Clothing department at Staunton, asking if the socks he
                    and the aid societies were sending were being used by the soldiers or by the
                    quartermasters. Phillips assures Withrow that the socks are reaching the
                    soldiers and that the need for socks in the approaching winter far exceeds the
                    supply donated to that point. The editor endorses Phillips's statements and
                    cautions readers not to believe rumors that quartermasters were misusing
                    donations.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Robbery</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The smokehouse of Captain William Peyton, one and a half miles from
                    Staunton, was broken into last Monday night. Peyton had just slaughtered hogs;
                    fourteen pieces of pork and a quantity of sausages were taken.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Sent to Lexington</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The ten disloyal citizens from Rockingham County and the lower part of
                    Augusta County were sent to Lexington for trial.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Tax-Payers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor reminds those who have not paid their Confederate taxes to do so
                    by December 1 or risk doubling their tax.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Official Report of Gen. Imboden</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn>J. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Brig. Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Brig. Gen. J. D. Imboden writes his chief of staff regarding his advance on
                    Charlestown and subsequent events there.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Supplies for Soldiers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>H. M.</fn>
                        <sf>Quartermaster</sf>
                        <pf>Major</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Major H. M. Bell, Quartermaster, issues a notice stating that a car will
                    leave Staunton, Fishersville, and Waynesboro each Friday morning carrying
                    supplies to soldiers. Anyone wishing to send packages is instructed to deliver
                    them on Thursdays.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Also on this page are war news, advertisements, and notices.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
