<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1860/va.au.rv.1860.01.20">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Anne Sarah Rubin</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1860-01-20">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day>20</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1860.01.20.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>The Lesson of the Lawrence Massacre</head>
                <origin>New York Herald</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"But they are philanthropists, these corporators of Lawrence. Very likely
                    they give a great deal to home and foreign missions. Without doubt they
                    sincerely sympathize with the negro who picks, in Alabama, the cotton which
                    their slaves weave at Lawrence. They will give money to help that cotton picker
                    to rise and murder his master, and to make up for that expense will put the
                    screws tighter to the cotton weaver, who is . . . a free laborer . . . free to
                    labor many hours at scanty pay in an insecure building, and free to be crushed
                    to death at last!"</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">From the New York Herald</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>We are compelled to continue the sad record of the terrible calamity at
                        Lawrence Mass. where, through the penny wise and pound foolish meanness of a
                        soulless corporation, nearly two hundred operatives lost their lives and
                        another hundred or more are maimed for the remainder of their days.</p>
                    <p>There are some shocking accidents--such as fire at sea and shipwrecks--the
                        results of which, however painful they may be, can only be regretted. Human
                        foresight in many of those cases could neither have prevented their
                        occurrence at the time nor have provided against the possibility of their
                        repetition. This Lawrence murder is not one of those cases wherein we say
                        that men and women died by visitation of God, or through the workings of
                        some inscrutable dispensation of divine providence. That there will not be
                        wanting in Massachusetts people, perhaps journalists and persons to take
                        such ground, we can readily imagine; it will be as sheer blasphemy as if it
                        were pleaded as an excuse by a wretch who came into court with his hands
                        died in the blood of his brother.</p>
                    <p>Let us examine the case. In the centre of a large manufacturing town there
                        has been erected a building to be used as a manufactory, to be filled with
                        ponderous machinery, and to be occupied during ten hours in each working day
                        by eight hundred men and women. It is found, after the erection of the
                        building, that it is not safe, and it is patched up with iron plates, as if
                        they could insure the stability of a structure which was doubtless insecure
                        from its foundation to its roof trees. The corporation makes itself secure
                        against pecuniary loss by full insurance. The spindles are in motion, the
                        busy fingers of the white slaves guide the magic thread whereon hang fat
                        dividends. The President and Directors doze over their after dinner wine,
                        its ruby color deepened with the blood of the operative. The manufactory may
                        fall to pieces, or may be burned down. No matter. It is insured--fully
                        insured--in good offices. Another glass of wine. And the director enjoys his
                        port, as fine old Boston gentlemen have done before him for many a day gone
                        by, and will for many a day to come. He has dropped into a gentle slumber,
                        and is dreaming of two per cent per month, when their comes a crash, a
                        shriek, a death wail. Two hundred young men and women have been crushed and
                        burned to death since that fine old Boston gentleman ate his last almond.
                        But he is insured. Where is the insurance for the kindred of the slain?
                        Where the recompense for the bereaved father and hear broken mothers, and
                        weeping sisters, and agonizing brothers, who stand over the mangles and
                        charred remains of their kindred? Who shall pay the premium that will be
                        demanded from the fine old Boston gentleman at the last great account--that
                        day when the books of the rich and poor, the high and low, Dives and
                        Lazarus, the beggar and the king, shall be squarely and evenly balanced with
                        the golden rule? - What company will insure the fine old Boston gentleman
                        against that risk? Not we.</p>
                    <p>But they are philanthropists, these corporators of Lawrence. Very likely they
                        give a great deal to home and foreign missions. Without doubt they sincerely
                        sympathize with the negro who picks, in Alabama, the cotton which their
                        slaves weave at Lawrence. They will give money to help that cotton picker to
                        rise and murder his master, and to make up for that expense will put the
                        screws tighter to the cotton weaver, who is--God save the mark!--a free
                        laborer--free as the galley slave who clanks his chains at Brester Toulou;
                        free as the British soldier who faints under the burning sun of India--free
                        to labor many hours at scanty pay in an insecure building, and free to be
                        crushed to death at last! That is free white labor from a State street point
                        of view.</p>
                    <p>Here we may be met with the old plea that the gentlemanly vice of avarice can
                        only be curbed by legislative enactments. Well, we have a government--a
                        federal and a State government--an extensive and costly machine, which we
                        work, or which works us, at any expense of many millions per annum. Every
                        year we have as many as two or three thousand new laws about one thing and
                        another. But the moment that any act is proposed to provide against the
                        occurrence of such massacres as that at Lawrence, capital comes in, buys
                        Legislatures like so much merchandise; and there's the end of all. We need
                        not go to Lawrence to see examples of this. The Greeks are at our own doors.
                        There are hundreds of insecure building in New York, and a very large number
                        of unsafe steam boilers hissing beneath the feet of our citizens as they
                        pursue their daily avocations. In the matter of the boilers, the Common
                        Council, we believe has passed an ordinance appointing an Inspector, but the
                        man has not yet been selected, and probable (sic) will not be until after
                        the next explosion.</p>
                    <p>It will be seen that all these dangers to which we have alluded menace more
                        particularly the laboring classes, who are generally unfriended, living from
                        hand to mouth and fighting the battle of life upon empty stomachs. Truly,
                        they have the civil law to resort to. The law is open to everybody and so is
                        the Fifth Avenue Hotel. Perhaps a bereaved father or mother might succeed in
                        an action against the proprietors of the Pemberton Mills; but who would go
                        security for the costs preliminary to the result? What poor devil can fight
                        a wealthy corporation? The operative looks, then, to the journalist as his
                        only friend--And the journalist should accept cheerfully the championship
                        thus thrown upon him. The press should unite to demand that special laws, as
                        in the case of railways, should be enacted for the insurance of the
                        operatives as well as of the building wherein they labor. The law should
                        declare in the simplest way, that proprietors of building used as
                        manufactories must guarantee their employees against such accidents as that
                        at Lawrence. Further, that if such building falls, the fact is prima facie
                        evidence of culpability on the part of the owners, and legal proceedings for
                        the relief of the sufferers should be commenced in the names of the State,
                        and at its expense. We employ a District Attorney to bring to justice the
                        man who takes away the life of one other, while the slaughterer of hundreds
                        goes to his bed of down unpunished, sleep well...and "little cupids dropping
                        on his urn their marble tears."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Discusses the killing and maiming of 300 workers in Lawrence,
                    Massachusetts. The article is very critical of the "soulless corporation," which
                    uses "white slaves" to make its products.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvjan60.html#1.20a</note>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1860.01.20.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Meeting on Monday the 23rd</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Meeting on Monday the 23rd.</p>
                    <p>By an inadvertency of the editor, the object of this meeting was misstated in
                        the last Vindicator. It is for the purpose of appointing delegates to the
                        State Convention, which meets in Richmond on the 16th of February--and to
                        the District Convention, which nominates delegates to the Charleston
                        Convention.</p>
                    <p>We consider this an appropriate time to address a few words to the Democracy
                        of the country in reference to the duty which they will have to perform in
                        their primary meeting. You have, Democrat of August, to send delegates to a
                        Convention which is to plank out the platform of principles upon which the
                        Democracy of Virginia are to stand during the coming canvass, and which is
                        to guide the Virginia delegation in the Charleston Convention. This,
                        fellow-Democrats, is a grave duty at all times, and one, we blush to say,
                        too seldom appreciated by the masses of the party; but at present it will
                        become your duty, in connection with the Democracy of the Union, to decide
                        issues which rise high above the questions which ordinarily engage the
                        attention of parties and politicians.</p>
                    <p>There is one question which has enchained the attention of the nation for the
                        last six or twelve months, to which we would particularly call the attention
                        of the Democracy of Augusta, to wit: Shall or shall not the slaveholders of
                        the South who go into the common territories of the Union be protected in
                        their property as the Federal Constitution provides?</p>
                    <p>Compromisers and the advocates of squatter sovereignty may argue, and
                        mistify, and denounce this question as an abstraction, as much as they
                        please; but, in our opinion, it is the practical , and the only practical
                        form into which the slavery question has resolved itself. Seward may again
                        and again promulgate his brutal "irrepressible conflict" theory; orators by
                        hundreds of the Wendell Phillips school may continue to preach treason and
                        infidelity to the besotted fanatics of New England; scores of John Browns
                        may attempt the invasion of the South, only to swing appropriately from the
                        gallows, but so long as we retain that jewel, protection for our slave
                        property in the Territories, the institution of slavery will remain as firm
                        and immovable as the everlasting hills. Take this sacred constitutional
                        right from us and slavery in the Union is a condemned and doomed
                        institution. Gov. Wise luminously says that the anti-protection theory "is a
                        short cut to all the ends of Abolitionism," and it is our deliberate
                        opinion, after close examination of the subject, that of all the expedients
                        of abolition ingenuity, Squatter Sovereignty aims the truest and deadliest
                        blow at the institution of slavery.</p>
                    <p>Thinking thus, we feel it to be our duty to invoke the earnest attention of
                        the Democracy to this question. We entreat them to come up, one and all, to
                        the primary meetings, with their minds fully made up, and their ideas
                        thoroughly arranged on the questions of the day, resolved not to be
                        senseless automatons in the hands of politiciads (sic). Above all, know well
                        the views of the delegates whom you send to the Convention, and scrutinize
                        closely the resolutions offered.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Vindicator reminds Democrats of their duty to send delegates to a
                    convention to "plank out the platform of principles upon which the Democracy of
                    Virginia are to stand during the coming canvass." The key issue that they have
                    to consider is whether or not southern slaveholders who move to the territories
                    will have their property protected, as the Constitution provides.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvjan60.html#1.20b</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Mr. Stuart's Speech</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Vindicator is "surprised and mortified" by a speech given by Stuart.
                    Apparently he has offended the volunteer militia companies by not wanting to pay
                    them. Augusta constituents don't support him on this issue.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Mr. Memminger</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Discusses South Carolina's 1852 assertion of a right to secede. Now South
                    Carolina wants to put together a Southern coalition.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Effects of Non-Intercourse</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Southern policy of non-intercourse is beginning to make itself felt in
                    the Northern economy. Northern businessmen are starting to see that support for
                    the Republican party "is causing a real and business estrangement between the
                    North and South . . ."</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="j">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Apportionment of the School Quota for the Year 1860</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCoy</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Poague</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gamble</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seawright</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Airhart</ln>
                        <fn>Phil</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hogshead</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>Alex</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kerr</ln>
                        <fn>N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Finley</ln>
                        <fn>S. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>J. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Withrow</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Simms</ln>
                        <fn>W. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>R. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pilson</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coyner</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>William F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilkeson</ln>
                        <fn>D. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McPheeters</ln>
                        <fn>A. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smiley</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCutcheon</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Calhoun</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>F. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bear</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Berry</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Montgomery</ln>
                        <fn>W. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Apportionments of varying amounts to Augusta county school
                commissioners.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Legislative report in column 4.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1860.01.20.03">
            <div type="l">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>For the Vindicator: Napoleon III and his Policy--He not [sic] the Ally for the
                    South</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Depend then O South! upon the proud support of your own soldiers. If war must
                        come, let it come.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Jan 17th, 1860 WAR</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Who should the South look to for help? Not to Napoleon III, despite
                    suggestions that it should. He will probably ally with the North. All European
                    monarchs are abolitionists.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coiner</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Died at age 22.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Tracts for the South</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Edmund Ruffin pamphlets for sale: The Political Economy of Slavery; African
                    Colonization Unveiled; Two Great Evils of Virginia, and their One Common Remedy
                    (Free Negro problem).</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Markets in column 3.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1860.01.20.04">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
