<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1860/va.au.rv.1860.07.06">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Josh Rothman</taggerName>
            <tagDate>6/12/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>3rd Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1860-07-06">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day norm="06">6</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1860.07.06.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Mr. Douglas' Letter of Acceptance</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>S. A. Douglas</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Douglas accepts the Presidential nomination of the Baltimore Democratic
                    convention and explains his political stance.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Acceptance of Hon. Marshall V. Johnson</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Johnson accepts the nomination for Vice President on the Douglas ticket.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Virginia Central Railroad, President's Office, To the Editors of the Sentinel</head>
                <origin>Sentinel</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barbour</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fontaine</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Several items about the Central RR and the Orange and Alexandria RR and the
                    mail delivery problem.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1860.07.06.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>National Democratic Nominees</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>National Democratic nominees and Democratic Electors from each district.
                    Includes 11th District elector, Wm. Harman.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Our Position</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Our Position.</p>
                    <p>The present aspect of the Democratic party, split in twain as it is, and
                        presenting to the American people the unparalleled fact in its history of
                        having two candidates for the Presidency, is painful to every friend of the
                        old organization. But there is no time like that when clouds of adversity
                        hang thickly over us, so fitting for us firmly, decidedly and proudly to
                        stand forth in the support and defense of that which we deem to be right.
                        Friendship and devotion are but mockery and hypocrisy if they do not shine
                        the brighter when the hour of need arrives. If there is a principle, it is
                        worth fighting for, and the more determined and steady that contest is made,
                        in that proportion is its virtue developed.</p>
                    <p>Thus believing, we this week hoist the names of STEPHEN A. DOUGLAS, of
                        Illinois, and HERSCHEL V. JOHNSON, of Georgia, as our candidates for the
                        Presidency and Vice Presidency of the United States, having been, in our
                        opinion, nominated by the regularly organized National Convention of the
                        Democratic party. Our devotion is to the party and not the men.</p>
                    <p>In taking this position we are actuated by a conscientious conviction, and a
                        sense of honor, which we hold to be sacred. To violate these would justly
                        subject us to the scorn and loathing of every honorable man, even though his
                        convictions of political duty were different from our own. And in the course
                        of this canvass we confidently expect to demonstrate, to every candid mind,
                        that we are right. We expect clearly to prove that the position assigned us
                        by the District Convention, held at Harrisonburg on the 9th of April last,
                        is that upon which our ticket stands, and which this District has
                        endorsed--not only this, but the position the States herself assumed through
                        the election of a majority of her delegates to Charleston--the position, in
                        fact, upon which the Democratic party of the United States stands by virtue
                        of solemn and honorable compact.</p>
                    <p>In discussing the questions which legitimately present themselves in this
                        canvass, we intend to be governed by a spirit of candor and fair dealing,
                        which is the natural off-spring of a conviction of right. We shall not
                        assail the motives of those of the Democratic party who now differ with us,
                        nor attack the character of the candidates of their choice. We mean
                        carefully to abstain from any line of animadversion which might lead to a
                        further breach in our ranks, or encourage and cultivate a feeling of
                        individual hostility. We will write our honest convictions, deduced from
                        fair and correct bases, in courteous and becoming terms, thus endeavoring to
                        perpetuate the kindly feelings which have existed between party friends with
                        whom we have stood shoulder to shoulder heretofore in crossing swords with a
                        common enemy. A more painful and sever task was never imposed by a sense of
                        duty, but we shall march to the work with a firm and steady step.</p>
                    <p>Having thus indicated the line of policy we shall pursue, it only remains for
                        us in this connection to tender most cheerfully to those of our Democratic
                        friends who may differ with us, the free use of the columns of the
                        Vindicator for fair and legitimate discussion. We want the whole Democratic
                        party to have a hearing, and publishing a Democratic paper, we will
                        cordially yield it as a medium through which those who desire to address the
                        public, can do so. We ask the same tolerance for our convictions and views
                        that we extend to others, and when the battle is fought and the victory won,
                        we will yield as quietly and as gracefully to the will of the majority as
                        any other man.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Vindicator expresses its official support for Douglas for President.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvjuly60.html#7.6a</note>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Ladies' Fair</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announcement of a Fair by the women of the M. E. Church. The proceeds will
                    help the M.E. Church complete its new building, which is presently "languishing
                    for want of funds."</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>To Our City Fathers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Vindicator states that, if the city fathers want to do the town an
                    "actual good," they should fix the pump at Bickle's corner.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>A Word Personal</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Editorial refutes claims that the editor was promised a job or reward if
                    Douglas was elected in return for supporting Douglas at the Baltimore
                    Convention.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>A Suggestion</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"In the present distracted and divided condition of the Democratic party,
                    any plan, it seems to us, which can so harmonize its elements as to concentrate
                    them in the result ought, as a matter of State pride and Democratic devotion, to
                    be adopted."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A Suggestion</p>
                    <p>In the present distracted and divided condition of the Democratic party, any
                        plan, it seems to us, which can so harmonize its elements as to concentrate
                        them in the result, ought, as a matter of State pride and Democratic
                        devotion, to be adopted. The Alexandria Sentinel, in that spirit of
                        conciliation and conservatism which ever marks its counsels, has suggested
                        the principle of the true solution of the difficulty in the State. The
                        Rockingham Register has adopted it, as have other papers. We, ourselves,
                        receive the principle of a single Electoral Ticket, with the understanding
                        that if Douglas receives more Electoral votes outside of Virginia than
                        Breckinridge, the vote of Virginia be cast for him, and if Breckinridge
                        receives more Electoral votes outside of Virginia than Douglas, then the
                        vote be cast for him. <emph rend="italic">This would secure the Electoral
                            vote of Virginia for a Democratic candidate for the Presidency.</emph>
                        This proposition it seems to us contains a simple solution of all the
                        difficulties which present themselves in Virginia, and will enable us,
                        instead of waging a fratricidal warfare, to direct our blows against a
                        common enemy. The destiny of the Virginia Democracy is the same--its efforts
                        should harmonize in the accomplishment of that destiny--and, if we should,
                        as we now do, differ as to the means to be employed, let us so control our
                        action that it may result in maintaining our Democratic ascendancy.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Vindicator agrees to adopt the proposal that would give Virginia's
                    electoral votes to Breckinridge, if he receives more electoral votes outside of
                    Virginia than Douglas does, or vice versa.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvjuly60.html#7.6b</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Population of Staunton</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Watts</ln>
                        <fn>J.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seawright</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Esq.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lilley</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The census of Staunton, done by J. B. Watts, showed Staunton to have 3717
                    people. North Augusta County was done by R. Burke and the South by Col. James
                    Lilley.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary, a black girl "belonging to the estate of James Ruddle of Shenandoah,"
                    was burned to death when her clothes caught fire.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Wesleyan Female Institute</head>
                <origin>Staunton Spectator</origin>
                <commentary>The present Principal, Prof. Arbogast, has made it an excellent school.</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Two graduates, Miss L. Ruse and Miss B. Persinger, read a dialogue entitled
                        "The folly of devoting too much time to accomplishments."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Arbogast</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Professor</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cooke</ln>
                        <fn>Mattie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCoy</ln>
                        <fn>Mollie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reprint of the Spectator's article that praises the Wesleyan Female
                    Institute and details the recent commencement exercises. Mattie Cooke and Mollie
                    McCoy of Augusta graduated from the school.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Virginia Female Institute</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phillips</ln>
                        <fn>R.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Virginia Female Institute held its commencement ceremony on June 25.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Fourth of July</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turner</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>T.L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barleycorn</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Fourth of July celebration included Turner's Silver Coronet Band, the
                    West Augusta Guards under Capt. Baylor, and the Staunton Artillery under Lt. T.
                    L. Harman.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Officers of the Junior Blues</head>
                <origin>Staunton Spectator</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lilley</ln>
                        <fn>J.D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Philips</ln>
                        <fn>R.T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>A.H.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blackburn</ln>
                        <fn>J.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turner</ln>
                        <fn>C.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lilley</ln>
                        <fn>J.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wayt</ln>
                        <fn>J.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Berkeley</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stribling</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brook</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scherer</ln>
                        <fn>J.R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>E.O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stafford</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scherer</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lists officers of the Junior Blues, a juvenile military company.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Hon. H.L. Hopkins</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>Hopkins is "one of the most consistent and able Democrats in the State."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter from H.L. Hopkins, the Democratic elector from the 2nd District,
                    Virginia, in which he criticizes the actions of the seceders from the regular
                    Democratic convention. He rejects their claim that the Convention that nominated
                    Breckinridge and Lane was the regular Democratic Convention. He expresses his
                    loyalty to the party and its principles.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Democrats of Albemarle County agreed to support the nomination of
                    Breckinridge and Lane, although they are willing to cooperate with "our friends
                    of the Democratic party throughout the State."</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Esq.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Joseph Waddell was appointed to fill W. Baylor's spot as Commissioner in
                    Chancery for the Circuit Court of Augusta.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Virginia Female Institute</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Churchman</ln>
                        <fn>F.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>R.P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woodward</ln>
                        <fn>C.J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Details of the Commencement Exercises at the Virginia Female Institute,
                    including the names of the graduates and the prizes awarded. Most of the
                    students are from others counties in Virginia, with the exception of the three
                    Augusta women listed above.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Reception of Governor Letcher in Staunton</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>T.L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lilley</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turner</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Governor Hatcher came and spoke in Staunton. He was welcomed by the West
                    Augusta Guard under Capt. Baylor and the Staunton Artillery under Lt. Harman as
                    well as Turner's Cornet Band and the Junior Blues under Capt. Lilley.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>For the Vindicator, To the Democracy of Augusta and Highland</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Breckinridge said, "Instead of breaking up the Union, we intend to strengthen
                        and lengthen it. [A voice from the crowd said 'Cuba.']"</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Many Friends</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter reprints part of a speech that Breckinridge gave in which he stated
                    that he wanted to strengthen the Union, not break it up. The writer cautions
                    readers "against pledging yourselves to any particular candidate until you have
                    had an opportunity of hearing all the reasons both for and against him."</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1860.07.06.03">
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garber</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cullen</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jackson</ln>
                        <fn>Mildred A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on June 14.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Peter, aged 6, and William, aged 7, died on June 18 and June 20,
                    respectively. They were the second and third children of Peter and Margaret
                    Hanger to die in June.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Herring</ln>
                        <fn>Jane B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Herring</ln>
                        <fn>Bethuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jane Herring died at her brother's residence on June 27.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snapp</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Bell</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snapp</ln>
                        <fn>Robert B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snapp</ln>
                        <fn>Mary L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary Bell Snapp died on June 15 at age 6 months.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Article about the friends of Douglas campaign in Petersburg, column
            1.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1860.07.06.04">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
