<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1860/va.au.rv.1860.05.11">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Anne Sarah Rubin</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1860-05-11">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day>11</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1860.05.11.01">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1860.05.11.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Suggestion</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article requests that people congregating on the depot platform make an
                    effort to leave space for people, especially ladies, to exit the train cars and
                    make their way to hotels.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Gen Wm. M. Harman</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>William M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>General</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Harman, subbing as editor for Yost, has been promoted to Brigadier General
                    by Gov. Letcher.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Unit Vote of Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Virginia needs to vote together to maintain influence at the Convention.
                    The Vindicator urges friends of Hunter and Wise to unite.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Charleston Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"They went out. They are out, and we hope and trust will ever remain out.
                    We look upon such men as no better than Northern fanatics. They care not for the
                    Union. They would tear down the temple of liberty itself to accomplish the ends
                    of selfish ambition . . ."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Charleston Convention.</p>
                    <p>Our readers are aware that the Democratic National Convention, which convened
                        in Charleston on the 23d of April, adjourned on the 3d of May, without
                        making nominations, to meet in Baltimore on the 18th of June next. The
                        policy of this action, after the secession of several of the Southern
                        States, cannot reasonably be questioned. It was possible, and even probable,
                        Judge Douglas could have been nominated in a few more ballots,
                        notwithstanding the arbitrary and unjustifiable ruling of the President of
                        the Convention relative to the two thirds vote; but vacancies existing in
                        several of the States, it was deemed advisable to adjourn, and thus afford
                        the non-represented States the opportunity of appointing delegates. Had the
                        Convention proceeded to the nominations, a potent lever would thus have been
                        placed in the hands of the Opposition to attack the nationality of the
                        Democratic party, and it might also have engendered bad feeling with the
                        national men of the seceding States, who are anxious to be represented at
                        Baltimore, and thus redeem their section from the taint of disunion and
                        rebellion which might otherwise rest upon it. The seceding delegations
                        clearly misrepresented the great mass of the unsuspecting people of their
                        States, who, being aroused by the action of the agitators who nestle in
                        their bosom, and have betrayed them, will rush gladly to the work of
                        asserting their nationality, and attest their devotion to the Union by
                        sending delegates to the Baltimore Convention, to fill the vacancies which
                        have been created.</p>
                    <p>The disruption and secession at Charleston, occasioned by the action mainly
                        of Alabama, was preconcerted, and not unexpected. The arch-agitator in the
                        programme, W. L. Yancey, has directed all his thoughts and energies to
                        bringing about a dissolution of the Union for the last 20 years. In 1848 he
                        seceded from the Democratic Convention which nominated Gen. Cass. In 1858 he
                        attempted to establish what he termed a "Southern League," the object of
                        which was to "precipitate the cotton States into a revolution." The mask was
                        effectually torn from him in this effort, by Roger A. Pryor, and the
                        insidious attack upon the Union exposed. The plot and its author fell
                        stillborn, and Mr. Yancey was heard nothing more of until he succeeded in
                        getting into the Charleston Convention, the importance and respectability of
                        which position enabled him to accomplish that which he had heretofore failed
                        in accomplishing--the apparent disruption of the Democratic party. He and
                        his followers went into that Convention for no other purpose. The
                        resolutions adopted previously by them, and the arrogant and insolent
                        demands made, precluded all possibility of harmony and unity.</p>
                    <p>They went out. They are out, and we hope and trust will ever remain out. We
                        look upon such men as no better than Northern fanatics. They care not for
                        the Union. They would tear down the temple of liberty itself to accomplish
                        the ends of selfish ambition, and erect upon the ruins of our common
                        country, "a Southern Confederacy!" It is for this they aim, and not
                        intrinsically for an empty abstraction. What care they for the rights of the
                        South, practically, in the Territories? When Missouri was bleeding at every
                        pore--lavishing her money by the million in the practical assertion of
                        Southern rights in Kansas, where then were these seceding States--these
                        extreme friends of the slavery interest? Not one dollar did their
                        Legislatures appropriate--not one company of men did they organize to help
                        Missouri in her struggle for their rights. They were themselves secure for
                        their rights. They were themselves secure from invasion and loss, with more
                        territory than they could ever find negroes to populate, and hence permitted
                        the hardy and gallant citizens of Missouri to spend their means and spill
                        their blood, without a particle of aid from them. But now, when no rights
                        are to be invaded, when no interests of the South are in fact suffering,
                        these Gulf States are ready to rend the Union in twain, if Congressional
                        intervention is not incorporated into the Democratic platform, when the
                        doctrine of non-intervention has been proclaimed and adopted by the
                        Democratic party a thousand times; and Judge Douglas is not defeated for the
                        Presidential nomination, when Missouri, who has suffered more than all the
                        slave-holding States in the Union, stands firmly for him! This is the
                        consistency of these States. They skulk the issue when it comes to practice,
                        and rant and rave when there is nothing at stake.</p>
                    <p>The Democratic party, this day, is stronger than it has ever been. The
                        secession of this element of discontent from their ranks, will arouse the
                        reflecting men both in the North and the South, and the party being relieved
                        of the disunion faction, which heretofore, has been ambitious of mischief
                        through the instrumentality of the Democratic organization, the conservative
                        sentiment of the country will come to its support, and waft into power the
                        man who may be put forward by the Baltimore Convention of June next.--The
                        people are for the Union. They see the difficulties that stare us in the
                        face, and they will determine, in the majesty of their might, to remove
                        them. We are glad the Charleston Convention terminated as it did. The
                        disunionists of South Carolina, who hissed down conservative speakers, and
                        shouted hosannas to a "Southern Confederacy," will not disturb the harmony
                        of the proceedings of the June Convention. The honest sentiment of the
                        country will have a free channel of issue, and from the centre of the Union
                        will go forth to every extreme a conservative doctrine, awakening a kindred
                        feeling in every State until, factions and fanatics shall hang their
                        diminished heads, and sink into oblivion.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article about the Convention, including the walkout initiated by Yancey.
                    The Vindicator is angry about the disruption, and argues that the delegates that
                    walked out are hypocrites, since they offered no help to the territories
                    earlier.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvmay60.html#5.11a</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Territorial Question</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Territorial Question.</p>
                    <p>The <emph rend="italic">Spectator</emph> of the 8th closes a very moderate
                        and sensible article on the Charleston Convention, with the following
                        paragraph:</p>
                    <p>"With such an irreconcilable difference of opinion, the question arises
                        whether there is no way of getting rid of the difficulty, or whether the
                        peace of the country and the Union itself must be sacrificed to abstract
                        theories. The only way we know of is to agree to disagree upon questions of
                        really no practical importance. If let alone, the question of slavery in the
                        Territories will settle itself to the satisfaction of all reasonable and
                        patriotic men in both sections of the Republic."</p>
                    <p>That a difference of opinion has always existed among the great men of the
                        country in regard to the power of Congress in the Territories, is a well
                        known fact to every reading man. This difference has not only existed among
                        members of the same party, but has been tolerated without impairing their
                        political influence, or compromising their party fealty. In 1847 and 1848,
                        when the agitation growing out of this very question shook our government to
                        its centre, Senator Clayton offered his celebrated compromise, which,
                        acknowledging the existence of a difference of opinion, referred the whole
                        matter to the Supreme Court of the United States, whose decisions in any
                        case involving the question were to be final and binding. This idea was
                        incorporated into the Compromise of 1860 [sic: s.b. 1850], which compromise
                        was endorsed by both the great parties of the Country in 1852--reindorsed by
                        the passage of the Kansas-Nebraska bill in 1854; and again re-affirmed by
                        the Democratic party at Cincinnati in 1856. All of the leading Statesmen of
                        the present day are committed to this solution of the difficulty--are bound
                        as honorable men to stand by these several compromises, and observe in good
                        faith the spirit and point they declare.</p>
                    <p>Up to 1857 the mere doctrine had been agreed upon that the adjudication of
                        the Supreme Court was to be the peaceful arbiter between conflicting
                        opinions, whose rulings were to be received as a settlement. The popular
                        mind lay calmly reposed in this belief, although no case had been presented
                        for adjudication by which the law was to be established. The Kansas-Nebraska
                        bill especially provides for appeal from the decisions of the inferior and
                        Superior Courts of the Territories, to the Supreme Court of the United
                        States, not limiting at all, the amount in controversy, where slave property
                        is involved. In l857 the question was brought to a practical test in the
                        Dred Scott case. The Supreme Court ruled that the Territorial Legislature
                        was merely the agent of Congress, and consequently could exercise no powers
                        which Congress could not confer. Congress not having the power to prohibit
                        or establish Slavery, it followed that such power did not vest in its
                        creature, the Territorial Legislature. It is true, the opinion express by
                        the Court is charged to be extra judicial. This may be so, and yet not
                        impair the binding form of theopinion in a moral sense, for who doubts for a
                        moment that the <emph rend="italic">opinion</emph> of the Supreme Court
                        deliberately given will not be its <emph rend="italic">decision</emph> when
                        the case arises.</p>
                    <p>Thus it is not clear that this whole subject matter of controversy has been
                        referred by the legislation and compromises of the country, to which the
                        common consent of the people has again and again been given to the Court?
                        Then why should this vexed question be again opened? The declaration of the
                        abstract right of the South to the protection of its property in the
                        Territories can be of no possible practical good at this time, but which we
                        are sure if insisted upon must result in the defeat of the Democratic party,
                        and the rending asunder of this Union of States. No patriot, no true
                        Democrat, who values the existent of our free government, can Lend his aid
                        and counsel to the encouragement of an agitation fraught with so many
                        fearful disasters. The North and the South have been educated to think
                        differently, each honest in their convictions. That difference has been a
                        subject of legislative compromise and judicial reference, a faithful regard
                        to which cannot fail to be a peaceful and honorable solution of the
                        difficulty. Let then the honest masses, the uncorrupted and incorruptible
                        yeomanry come forth and rally around the compromises, the honor and the flag
                        of their country, and in the exercise of an indisputable and irresistible
                        majesty, crush out fanaticism both North and South. The time has come for
                        the people to act, and not the politicians--the people, whose firesides and
                        homes, whose domestic peace and tranquillity and national honor are in
                        jeopardy, to rise up and rebuke rebellion and disunion. The great heart of
                        the country is for the preservation of the Union--the great heart of the
                        patriots of the South beats responsively to the noble defenders of the
                        constitution at the North who are grappling hand to hand every day with
                        Black Republicanism, and we will not forsake them now that our aid may
                        strengthen them to strike the decisive blow which will break down the
                        enemies of the country and yet more firmly establish our free system of
                        government. Let immaterial and abstract isses be thrown to the winds, that
                        we may address ourselves to the great practical work of preserving this
                        Union, by sacredly regarding the compromise upon which it is based. It is no
                        time for members of the great Democratic party, who have at heart the
                        perpetuity of our government, to be solicitous about personal favorites for
                        this or that station. The standard of revolt has been raised, the "three
                        cheers for the Southern Confederacy" given. Let the infamous sentiment and
                        yet more daring action be repudiated and rebuked, that the Star-spangled
                        banner may continue to wave over the land of the free and the home of the
                        brave.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Provides a history of the conflict over the question of the proper role of
                    Congress in the Territories.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvmay60.html#5.11d</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Crime Against Nature</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Crime Against Nature.</p>
                    <p>A young man named Moyers was committed to the jail of this County on the 8th
                        inst., charged with sodomy, or crime against nature, by association with a
                        horse.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moyers</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A man named Moyers was sent to jail charged with a "crime against nature."</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvmay60.html#5.11b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Flag and Sword Presentation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>W.S.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Harman, on behalf of the ladies of Staunton, is presenting the Staunton
                    Artillery with a flag; the West Augusta Guards are presenting Baylor with a
                    "beautiful" sword.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Lynchburg Republican</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Tenth Legion Democrats are standing behind the party, not the
                    secessionists, and will continue to do so in Baltimore. They endorse popular
                    sovereignty.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>First of the Season</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>First of the Season.</p>
                    <p>Our friend Brown of the American Hotel, with his accustomed energy, surprised
                        his dinner table and those who sat at it, on Thursday, with a handsome
                        display of fresh Strawberries. This dilicious delicacy will be served up
                        frequently at our Hotels now that we can get them from Richmond in eight
                        hours.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The American Hotel has begun serving strawberries to its guests.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvmay60.html#5.11c</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Bad print--blurry and hard to read. More about slavery in the
            territories.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1860.05.11.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Union Constitutional Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Report from the Union Convention in Baltimore.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rice</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Emma</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rice</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rice</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary Emma, an infant, died on May 6.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCarty</ln>
                        <fn>Minerva</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCarty</ln>
                        <fn>W.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. McCarty, wife of Rev. McCarty, died at the Western Lunatic Asylum on
                    May 2 at age 30. Rev. McCarty was formerly of the Western Virginia Conference of
                    the M.E. Church.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coalter</ln>
                        <fn>Maria</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coalter</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Maria J. Coalter died on May 4 at age 77. She was the widow of the late Dr.
                    Thomas J. Coalter and mother-in-law of William B. Crawford, at whose house she
                    died.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Candidates announcements in columns 1 and 2; Markets in column 3.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1860.05.11.04">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
