<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- !DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd' -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1860/va.au.rv.1860.04.06">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Anne Sarah Rubin</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1860-04-06">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day norm="06">6</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote>Cropping problem on p. 1.</editionNote>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1860.04.06.01">
            <pageNote>Columns 5-7 are cut off. Also right edge of column 4, but still readable.
                Letter from Pres. Buchanan to House of Representatives.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="01a" image="va.au.rv.1860.04.06.01a">
            <pageNote>Only one of the columns missing from p. 1. Appears to be column 7. Left edge
                is cut off.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1860.04.06.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>John D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shomo</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announcement of contracts for construction of a new building at the Lunatic
                    Asylum.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Word to Democrats</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A Word to Democrats.</p>
                    <p>We are on the eve of an important political campaign, and it is all important
                        to the success of the Democracy that every voter in the county should have a
                        Democratic paper. We therefore appeal to our Democratic friends to exert
                        themselves in extending the circulation of the VINDICATOR. Let every man who
                        feels an interest in the triumph of our cause, and the healthy and
                        profitable existence of a Democratic organ in "Old Federal Augusta," procure
                        an additional name. We want none but <emph rend="italic">paying
                        subscribers</emph>. We will shortly present the paper in an improved and
                        handsome dress, by which we will be enabled to give a larger amount of
                        reading matter, and in more readable type. See to it, Democrats, that our
                        list in increased.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Asks Democrats to subscribe to the Vindicator, couching the request in
                    terms of achieving Democratic victories at the polls.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvapr60.html#4.6a</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Presidency</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Presidency.</p>
                    <p>The line of demarcation which divides the Democratic and Opposition parties,
                        is daily assuming a more distinct and pertinent significance. As with Abram
                        and Lot, either the right or the left has to be taken, and a palpable line
                        of separation designated. The aspirant of the Opposition who presents the
                        most modified and plausible claim, by reason of his geographical position,
                        is Mr. Bates, of Mo., who has recently written a letter which fully throws
                        him into the embrace of the Black Republican party, and places him in the
                        position of a formidable competitor with Mr. Seward for the Chicago
                        nomination. There is nothing in all the tactics and pretensions of the
                        Opposition which discourages the idea of a programme being adopted at the
                        National Convention, which will make all other issues and questions
                        subsidiary to the all-engrossing one of opposition to the Democratic party
                        and the interest and institutions of the South. Any difference of opinion
                        which heretofore may have existed upon questions of governmental policy, is
                        totally ignored, and the painfully significant aspect presented of a party
                        seeking and determined to make the next Presidential contest hinge upon and
                        aggression, on the one part, of the Constitutional rights of one section,
                        and on the other, a defense of those rights. There is not an organ in the
                        confidence of the Opposition which does not freely admit that there is not
                        the shadow of a hope for carrying the electoral vote of a single State south
                        of Mason &amp; Dixon's line. If successful at all, they expect to attain
                        it purely by a sectional vote--an expression of deep seated and aggressive
                        hostility to the South--and upon principles so entirely antagonistic to, and
                        destructive of, the equality of the Southern States, as to make that success
                        the synonym of dissolution.</p>
                    <p>This being the position of the Opposition, defiantly and boldly taken, it
                        only rests with the Democratic party to again come to the rescue of our
                        inheritance of constitutional freedom, and again vindicate its claim to the
                        proud character of being the only <emph rend="italic">national</emph>
                        organization known to the country.--This solemn and momentous duty thus
                        pressing heavily, it will be a question of the weightiest concern, as to
                        whom the Charleston Convention will designate as the proper person to be
                        presented for the suffrages of the people of the United States. The great
                        battle of the Union and the Constitution against the heterogeneous mass of
                        corruption which compose the Opposition, will have to be fought in New
                        Jersey, Pennsylvania, Illinois, Indiana, and Minnesota.--There are 303
                        electoral votes, 152 of which will be necessary to secure an election. Of
                        these, 120 are cast by the southern slaveholding States, which can be safely
                        claimed to be fore the Democratic candidate. We will then have to secure 32
                        more votes to achieve a triumph. If we carry Illinois, (11) Indiana, (13)
                        California, (4) Oregon, (3) Minnesota, (3) and New Jersey, (7) we will have
                        then 161 votes--more than sufficient by 9 to elect. Or even should w lose
                        New Jersey and Pennsylvania, and win the others, we will still have a
                        surplus of two votes. It will thus be seen that the contest will necessarily
                        be thrown into the non-slaveholding States we have mentioned, and the
                        important duty will devolve upon the Charleston Convention of selecting a
                        Candidate who can carry 32 of the 68 votes cast by the free States
                        enumerated.</p>
                    <p>We are free to confess that our predilections are strongly in favor of some
                        sound, conservative Southern man, not only for the reasons of a confirmed
                        faith in the safety of such nomination, but for the additional consideration
                        that it is justly due of the South upon the ground of reciprocal claim and
                        courtesy. But the issues involved in the action of the Charleston
                        Convention, and the result of the November election, loom up in such grand
                        and momentous proportions, as to make all questions of individual preference
                        or sectional predilection pale into insignificance, and present in bold
                        relief the great paramount idea of the <emph rend="italic">success of the
                            Democratic party and the defeat of the Black Republicans</emph>.--That
                        is the question. <emph rend="italic">Men</emph> are mere ciphers save only
                        in the proportion of their ability to achieve that end. That is the
                        essence--the Alpha and Omega--of the issue, and he is the proper person for
                        the nomination--be he from the North or South, East or West--who can the
                        more surely secure so desirable a result.</p>
                    <p>It is a duty as sternly incumbent upon the delegates to Charleston to go
                        there in a spirit of conciliation, free from individual partisanship or
                        captious prejudices, and open to the light and information which must
                        necessarily flood in upon them as it is for them to consult the interests of
                        the Democratic party, and respect the dignity and importance of the position
                        they will fill. If it is made apparent, or even probable, that a Southern
                        man can not carry a sufficient number of electoral votes in the free States
                        to secure his election, then, by every consideration of policy and
                        patriotism, that man who can receive such votes, should, with cordiality and
                        unity, be chosen. It is made the duty of the Democratic party to crush out
                        the odious factions that have combined against it, and which, with ruthless
                        and impious tread, would trample down the Constitution and the laws of the
                        country. <emph rend="italic">Success</emph> we must have, though men now
                        prominent in the public eye, sink beneath the surging current of the
                        people's patriotism, never again to rise. No sacrifice of personal and
                        individual attachments and predilections is too great, when it is made to
                        secure the triumph of our principles; and by this controlling, conservative,
                        catholic feeling, every delegate to Charleston should be actuated--a
                        patriotic ambition to do the country good, instead of the contracted desire
                        of promoting the interests of men.</p>
                    <p>It seems to us, then, in order to embrace and comprehend the whole range of
                        considerations involved, that Charleston would be the proper place to mature
                        an intelligent opinion as to the most available, at the same time orthodox
                        Democrat, to be nominated. If this idea is acted upon, harmony and good
                        feeling will pervade the deliberations, and a spirit of confidence and
                        enthusiasm be inspired, that will lead us on to a victory as decisive and
                        significant as that which defeated John C. Fremont in 1856.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that the Opposition in the 1860 election will make all issues
                    "subsidiary to the all-engrossing one of opposition to the Democratic party and
                    the interest and institutions of the South." Article details the breakdown of
                    electoral votes by section and criticizes the Opposition for being a purely
                    sectional party that ignores the interests of the South. The Vindicator
                    expresses its hope that the Charleston convention nominates a conservative
                    Southerner.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvapr60.html#4.6b</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Botts and Stuart</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Says that rivalry between Botts and Stuart is like the Montagues and the
                    Capulets.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>County Court</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guy</ln>
                        <fn>W.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guy</ln>
                        <fn>Robt.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eidson</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huff</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Report on County Court session, including names of the Justices.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>No Sunday Train on the Central Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>No Sunday Train on the Central Railroad.</p>
                    <p>By an order of the Board of Directors of the Central Railroad, there will not
                        be hereafter a Sunday train of cars on that road further west than
                        Charlottesville. Whether this remarkable determination is the result of a
                        superabundance of piety on the part of the Directory, or the fruits of the
                        absence of common prudence and justice, we are unable, with the lights now
                        before us, to divine. How much greater violation of the moral laws of the
                        christian dispensation it would be to continue the cars to Staunton, than it
                        is to run them to Charlottesville on Sunday, is a nice question in
                        metaphysical theology, which is alone solvable by the pious disciples who
                        preside over the destinies of the Central Road. There may be an immense deal
                        of justice in the policy of making the stockholders west of the Blue Ridge
                        pay for the accommodation of the people east of the mountain, but if so, it
                        is past our dull comprehension to perceive it. We respectfully suggest that
                        the Board have committed a very grievous, unjustifiable and inexcusable
                        wrong, and nothing but a prompt return to the former usage can atone for it.
                        If it is not their wish to do so, an appeal will be made to the Postmaster
                        General, through the Representatives in Congress from this, the Albemarle
                        and the Botetourt Districts, to see whether the Central Road cannot be made
                        to repeal their "penny wise and pound foolish" action. This pharisaical and
                        puritanical movement is too transparent to deceive or mislead any one, and
                        the sooner the board retrace their steps the better for them. The people
                        along the western line of the Road have rights as well as those east of the
                        Blue Ridge, and they do not mean to quietly submit to so palpable an
                        imposition.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Board of Directors of the Central Railroad has decided that Sunday
                    trains will no longer run west of Charlottesville. The Vindicator scoffs at the
                    moral inconsistency of running trains on the Sabbath to Charlottesville but not
                    beyond, and argues that the railroad has made a gross error that should be
                    corrected immediately.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvapr60.html#4.6c</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Boot, Shoe and Leather Manufacturing Company</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Boot, Shoe and Leather Manufacturing Company.</p>
                    <p>Our enterprising citizens, availing themselves of a late act incorporating a
                        company by the above title, have already subscribed $20,000 to the capital
                        stock, and organized by the election of the following officers:</p>
                    <p>President - H. W. Sheffey.</p>
                    <p>Directors - M. G. Harman, Benj. Crawford, R. G. Bickle, Jno. D. Imboden, W.
                        J. D. Bell.</p>
                    <p>It is proposed at once to establish a large Tannery, and connect with it an
                        extensive manufactory of Boots and Shoes. A committee has been appointed to
                        select suitable grounds for the building, who will shortly report, when the
                        work of erecting the establishment will immediately commence.</p>
                    <p>We are glad to see this evidence of reviving enterprise. Instead hereafter of
                        sending our hides to the North to be dressed, manufactured into Boots and
                        Shoes, and then returned to use with a heavy profit to Northern enterprise,
                        we will have a producing and consuming market of our own--facilitating home
                        commerce and enriching our citizens.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffy</ln>
                        <fn>H.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M.G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickle</ln>
                        <fn>R.G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn>Jno. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>W.J.D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Local citizens have incorporated a tannery and leather manufacturing
                    company. Praises their enterprise, especially as it fosters Southern
                    independence.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvapr60.html#4.6d</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Corporation Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Election for Corporation officers came off on the 4th inst., and resulted as follows: For 
                    Mayor   N. K. Trout. Sergeant B. W. Stevenson. Council M. G. Harman, E. M. Taylor, Simpson F. 
                    Taylor, J. H. Skinner, H. M. Bell, George Baylor, Benj. Crawford, B. F. Points, W.G. Sterrett, 
                    J. D. Imboden and G. E. Price. </p>
                    <p>There was no contest, except for the office of Sergeant, the 
                    candidates being R. W. Stevenson, James H. Waters and Wm. Craig.  Mr. Craig withdrawing in the 
                    morning, Mr. Stevenson was elected by 34 majority. </p>
                    <p>The council on Wednesday, after being sworn 
                    in, proceeded to elect officers, which resulted in Mr. Stevenson being chosen Chief of Police; 
                    W. H. Harman, Chamberlain; Benj. Crawford, Recorder; James W. Patterson, Clerk, and M. G. 
                    Harman, W. G. Sterrett, John D. Imboden, J. H. Skinner and S. F. Tylor, Aldermen.
                    </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>N.K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stevenson</ln>
                        <fn>R.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M.G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>E.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>S.F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>H.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Points</ln>
                        <fn>B.F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sterrett</ln>
                        <fn>W.G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn>J.D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Price</ln>
                        <fn>G.E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kayser</ln>
                        <fn>W.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>R.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>A.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCoy</ln>
                        <fn>Judson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Evans</ln>
                        <fn>J.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Results of Town Corporation elections. Trout is mayor again.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvapr60.html#4.6e</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Military</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>W.S.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn>J.D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Remarks on endurance of military spirit after Harper's Ferry. Compliments
                    Augusta Guards and Staunton Artillery.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Another Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stevenson</ln>
                        <fn>R.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>An election will take place on April 14th to fill the vacancy in the office
                    of the Commissioner of Revenue for the Corporation of Staunton. A vote will also
                    be taken to extend the Corporation limits of the town.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Corporation Election.</p>
                    <p>The Election for Corporation officers came off on the 4th inst., and resulted
                        as follows:</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">For Mayor </emph> N. K. Trout.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Sergeant</emph> B. W. Stevenson.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Council</emph> M. G. Harman, E. M. Taylor, Simpson F.
                        Taylor, J. H. Skinner, H. M. Bell, George Baylor, Benj. Crawford, B. F.
                        Points, W.G. Sterrett, J. D. Imboden and G. E. Price.</p>
                    <p>There was no contest, except for the office of Sergeant, the candidates being
                        R. W. Stevenson, James H. Waters and Wm. Craig. Mr. Craig withdrawing in the
                        morning, Mr. Stevenson was elected by 34 majority.</p>
                    <p>The council on Wednesday, after being sworn in, proceeded to elect officers,
                        which resulted in Mr. Stevenson being chosen Chief of Police; W. H. Harman,
                        Chamberlain; Benj. Crawford, Recorder; James W. Patterson, Clerk, and M. G.
                        Harman, W. G. Sterrett, John D. Imboden, J. H. Skinner and S. F. Tylor,
                        Aldermen.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blakemore</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blakemore</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moorman</ln>
                        <fn>Catherine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanman</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Two women have been appointed postmistress, one in Mt. Solon and one in
                    Franklin, Pendleton County.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Column 1 has an announcement requesting orders for election
            tickets.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1860.04.06.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Fire in Waynesborough</head>
                <origin>Staunton Spectator</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Massie</ln>
                        <fn>Jon S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Massie</ln>
                        <fn>N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Fire at the Massie's stable.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Graves</ln>
                        <fn>Worthington</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Died on March 28 at 22 years of age.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woods</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Died on March 28 at age 47.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Columns 6-7 have been cropped out. Print is faint and has a lot of scratches.
                Candidates announcements in column 3, Markets in column 4.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1860.04.06.04">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
