<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1860/va.au.rv.1860.10.05">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Josh Rothman</taggerName>
            <tagDate>6/12/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>3rd Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1860-10-05">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="10">October</month>
            <day norm="05">5</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1860.10.05.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>A Lie Nailed to the Counter--The Proof Overwhelming</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Another article attacking the idea that Douglas is allied with the
                    Abolitionists.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Column 7 is difficult to read. Poem at the bottom of column 7.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1860.10.05.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The cars of the Central Railroad no longer run on Sundays and only make 3
                    trips a week west of Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"W. Lamb, Breckinridge, and L. H. Chandler, Bell Electors, had a
                    fisticuff-sette last Friday evening during a discussion between them. The
                    everlasting nigger was the cause."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lamb</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chandler</ln>
                        <fn>L.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary/>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Esq.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>J.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>A.H.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Hugh Sheffey spoke to the Bell men of Richmond, while Col. Baldwin and A.
                    H. H. Stuart addressed a meeting in Alexandria.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>An Unjust Prejudice</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>An Unjust Prejudice.</p>
                    <p>One of the staple arguments of the secessionists is that the election of
                        Lincoln will be a practical declaration that the people of the North are at
                        war with the people of the South. This assumption is contrary to the actual
                        facts in the case, and unjustly prejudicial to the conservative sentiment of
                        the North. Let the conservative, national, union-loving element of the North
                        have a hand-to-hand contest with the fanatical hordes who, with vandal
                        impulses, seek to destroy the force of constitutional obligations and
                        infringe upon the rights of the citizens of one portion of the confederacy,
                        and we will guarantee that the friends of equality and the Constitution will
                        significantly triumph over the ismatists. Instead of that, however, party
                        leaders, and designing demagogues initiate political movements which are
                        calculated to divide the conservative sentiment, and thus give power to an
                        united and consolidated enemy who is really in the minority. There is a
                        preponderance in favor of conservatism in the North, decidedly and
                        uncompromisingly friendly to all the guaranteed rights of the South, yet
                        when divided it is powerless to accomplish the very object for which we
                        blame them in failing to effect. We should no more hold the great mass of
                        the Northern people responsible for the Personal Liberty Bills of
                        Massachusetts and Vermont, than should the entire South be held accountable
                        for the extreme views of South Carolina. It is unjust to the people of the
                        North to brand them as enemies of the Constitution and the rights of the
                        South, when we assist in creating the divisions which paralyze their efforts
                        to give practical efficiency to their real sentiments. It is hypocrisy and
                        cowardice and ingratitude in us to charge the brave and true and high-souled
                        men of the North with being our enemies when they are daily grappling with
                        an avowed foe and seeking to strangle him to death. There never has been
                        exhibited a grander and more sublime devotion to the Union and the
                        constitutional rights of the South than the late fusion in New York between
                        the friends of three candidates for the Presidency opposed to the
                        "irrepressible conflict" candidate. Laying aside party attachments, yielding
                        up party organizations and individual predilections as a holy oblation upon
                        the alter of the Constitution and the Union, the conservative elements have
                        banded together in a common fight against the avowed enemy of the South.
                        When and where has ever been presented in the political history of the
                        country a nobler spectacle of love for the right than in this union? It is
                        for <emph rend="italic">our</emph> rights that they have united--it is to
                        defend <emph rend="italic">us</emph> that these brave and true men have come
                        together to beat down our enemies. And yet men in the South talk about
                        dissolving their connection with <emph rend="italic">such</emph> men! No! If
                        a Black Republican should be elected by the divisions we are helping to
                        create among the conservative men at the North, and that Black Republican
                        should attempt to transgress one single letter or syllable of the
                        Constitution, we will not, like cowards and poltroons, fly from the invader,
                        but calling upon the conservative and constitution-loving <emph
                            rend="italic">majority</emph> of the North, we will march upon the
                        traitor, and in the language of Judge Douglas, "hang him ten feet higher
                        than Virginia hung old John Brown." We cannot, as men, respecting our
                        manhood, <emph rend="italic">be driven away from the Constitution</emph>. We
                        must stand by and defend it. It is <emph rend="italic">our</emph>
                        inheritance, and we owe it to ourselves and to our posterity to keep it
                        spotless from the touch of traitorous hands. It would be a pretty spectacle
                        for those who boast themselves of their chivalry and courage, to run from a
                        shadow, a phantom, and leave it in the hands of their sworn foe all that
                        should be held dear by a patriot! If the South should fly from the contest,
                        we will avouch that the Northern conservatives will rally as one man to the
                        rescue, and wrest the government from the hands of the spoilers and
                        traitors. It was never designed by God Almighty that this edifice, founded
                        and built up for his glory in the spread of free religious and political
                        principles and the development of human capacity for
                        self-government--unfettered by imperial edicts or arbitrary
                        enactments--should be torn down to gratify the passions of a band of
                        infidels in heart to every principle of rational progress and legitimate and
                        healthy intellectual expansion.</p>
                    <p>We must stand by the brave men of the North who, rising above sectional
                        prejudice, are now standing by the Constitution. We must fight for it as we
                        would our own firesides, and consider every man a friend and brother, who
                        will lock shields with us to meet the charge of the enemy. Whenever the
                        contest comes, if come it should, Southern men who have reviled and traduced
                        and belied and besmeared the character of Judge Douglas will see him coming
                        forward, as in times past, boldly and firmly bearing aloft the banner of the
                        Union under the Constitution and equal rights to all, to join hands and
                        heart with them in its defense. He now leads a column of gallant spirits in
                        the North, many of whom have extended a helping hand to the South in time of
                        need. They will do it again, and from such men we cannot separate. We have a
                        common object in view, and by united action we can and will achieve it.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Addresses the possibility of Lincoln's election and what that would mean
                    for the South.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvoct60.html#10.5a</note>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Hon. Wm. Yancey</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Hon. Wm. L. Yancey.</p>
                    <p>This gentleman delivered a speech to between two and three hundred persons,
                        in the armory building of this place, on Wednesday evening last. As a
                        declaimer and specious reasoner, he has few superiors. As an ingenious
                        debater, seeking to place fairly and frankly before the country a faithful
                        record of facts and an incontrovertible accumulation of unimpeachable
                        testimony, he was, in his effort of Wednesday, totally and painfully
                        deficient. While at times the flashes of a great mind would mark its line
                        through the mass of his sophistry and superficiality, yet no one could fail
                        to perceive that he relied upon impassioned appeals to sectional prejudice,
                        and excited denunciation and execration to produce an effect. For instance,
                        in alluding to the charges preferred against him, based upon his own
                        writings, of entertaining disunion sentiments, he denied that he did, and
                        indignantly exclaimed--"I scorn it--(stamp)--I trample it under my
                        feet--(stamp)--I grind it beneath my heel"--(stamp). This kind of logic did
                        not answer the demand of a reading, intelligent people, like the audience
                        that listened to him. They wanted him to explain why it was he had written
                        his Slaughter letter, in which he faintly foreshadowed his plan for "<emph
                            rend="italic">precipitating the Cotton States into a revolution</emph>"
                        by "<emph rend="italic">keeping up the old party relations on all other
                            questions</emph>," and holding the "<emph rend="italic">Southern issue
                            paramount</emph>," "<emph rend="italic">influencing</emph> PARTIES,
                        LEGISLATURES and STATESMEN." He said in that letter it would not do at that
                        time--1858--to dissolve the Democratic party.--"If the Democracy were
                        overthrown, it would result in giving place to a greater and hungrier swarm
                        of flies." Mark--it was merely a matter of <emph rend="italic">policy</emph>
                        with him to keep the Democracy united then, and not regard for the
                        time-honored principles and historical and canonized patriotism of the
                        Democracy. The "Southern issue" was "paramount," and every other issue and
                        agency had to be bent to subserve that one. It was the Aaron's rod that
                        swallowed up all others. The people of Augusta desired and expected to hear
                        from Mr. Yancey's own lips the true interpretation of that remarkable
                        letter, if by any process of contortion he could change the literal and
                        palpable meaning of his own language. It is an easy matter to prate about
                        the "Constitution--Union of the Constitution," and the like. It would not
                        have been very <emph rend="italic">politic</emph> for him to have talked in
                        any other way before a conservative, law-abiding people, such as inhabit the
                        "mountain fastnesses of West Augusta." But Mr. Yancey, when down in Alabama,
                        remote from the "slave depopulated" border State of old Virginia [all
                        bosh--we have more slaves now than we had ten years ago] can <emph
                            rend="italic">write</emph> his disunion manifestoes, and then come to
                        Virginia and stir the inmost depths of the soul by his eloquent appeals for
                        "the Union of the Constitution." What does Stephen A. Douglas both <emph
                            rend="italic">write</emph> and <emph rend="italic">speak</emph> on this
                        subject?--In his letter accepting the nomination of the Baltimore
                        Convention, he says: "The Federal Union must be preserved. <emph
                            rend="italic">The Constitution must be maintained in all its
                        parts</emph>. Every right guaranteed by the Constitution must be protected
                        by law in all cases where legislation is necessary to its enjoyment. The
                        judicial authority, as provided in the Constitution, must be sustained, and
                        its decisions implicitly obeyed and faithfully executed. <emph rend="italic"
                            >The laws must be administered and the Constitution authorities
                        upheld</emph>, and all unlawful resistance suppressed." Not only has he thus
                        written, but in every speech that he has made since the Baltimore
                        Convention, he has declared from the hustings the same undying and
                        unswerving devotion to the Constitution--or, if you please, "the Union of
                        the Constitution and the equality of the States." Mr. Douglas' word will go
                        as far with the people of Virginia as will Mr. Yancey's--therefore Mr. Y.
                        gains nothing in his tour in the wake of Judge Douglas in his lachrymose
                        paeans to the "Union of the Constitution." This being so, then compare their
                            <emph rend="italic">writings</emph>, and which of the two will
                        Virginians trust in this hour of contention? W. L. Yancey, who is in favor
                        of "<emph rend="italic">precipitating the Cotton States into a
                        revolution</emph>," or Stephen A. Douglas, who declares that the "FEDERAL
                        UNION MUST BE PRESERVED. THE CONSTITUTION MUST BE MAINTAINED INVIOLATE IN
                        ALL ITS PARTS?" It is true Mr. Yancey is not a candidate for any high
                        office, ["although he <emph rend="italic">might</emph> have been," as he
                        says,] yet he is the representative man of the Breckinridge party. He is the
                        great entity of the secession movement that nominated Mr. Breckinridge. He
                        is the selected champion to follow after Mr. Douglas, and dispel his
                        "heresies." He is the mouth piece, fugle-man, and thinking machine of that
                        faction;--and the friends of Mr. Breckinridge are responsible for his
                        sentiments, heretofore and now uttered. The Executive Committee at
                        Washington are afraid to let Mr. Breckinridge himself take the stump. They
                        prefer a more indirect and irresponsible course to counteract the uprising
                        of the popular heart for Douglas wherever he has been. Hence they keep Mr.
                        B. at home--seal his lips--and send Mr. Yancey out, whose remarkably
                        versatile intellect and great power as a public debater, they imagine will
                        stay the onward current in favor of Douglas and Democracy. How misguided!</p>
                    <p>Those who listened to Mr. Yancey and who also heard Mr. Douglas, could not
                        fail to have marked the difference in the character of their speeches.
                        Douglas was frank, open, bold, courteous and statesman-like. He denounced no
                        one, but like a man anxious to conceal nothing and give to the country his
                        entire views, he marched to the work of eliminating his opinions upon
                        current questions, and especially the Territorial "dogma." Mr. Yancey was
                        disingenuous and evasive, and not unfrequently absolutely suppressed facts
                        materially affecting the points he was discussing and the true position of
                        Judge Douglas.</p>
                    <p>To sum up the whole of the effects of his speech and the impression created
                        on his audience--the expectation of his hearers was fully met in his power
                        as a speaker. His immediate friends were satisfied with the speech
                        throughout. The bulk of the audience were dissatisfied in his not clearing
                        up his Slaughter and Pryor letters. They were chagrined at the quibbles and
                        special pleading to which he resorted to prejudice the popular mind against
                        Judge Douglas, and in which he exhibited a liberal proneness to do him gross
                        injustice. The Bell men were disgusted at the raking of their candidate, and
                        Democrats of both parties highly delighted.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Hon. Yancey spoke to more than 200 people at the Armory last Wednesday. The
                    Vindicator believes that he used emotional appeals to try to answer logical
                    questions.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvoct60.html#10.5b</note>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Yancey and Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Attacks Yancey's speech and opposes his secessionist views.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Yancey and Bayonets</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Refutes Yancey's claim that Douglas would bring Virginia to elect a Black
                    Republican at the point of a bayonet.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Yancey and Douglas</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>J.A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Yancey brought up again in his speech the charges of Douglas's alleged
                    coalition with the Republicans, even after Capt. Harman pointed out that it had
                    been denied by many reputable people.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Yancey and the Vice Presidency</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Yancey would not answer Capt. Harman's question about Yancey's alleged
                    nomination to be on Douglas's ticket.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Douglas Club</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>G.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Col. Baylor and G. M. Cochran spoke to the Douglas and Johnson Club on the
                    legitimacy of Douglas's nomination and the "myth" of Squatter Sovereignty.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="j">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Federal Court</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn>Willis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kayser</ln>
                        <fn>D.A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Esq.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Federal Court was hearing the case of U. S. vs. Willis, a slave of Mr.
                    Kayser who was accused of mail robbery. He was defended by Messrs. Baldwin,
                    Harman &amp;amp; Bell who claimed that the Federal Court had no jurisdiction
                    because Willis was a slave and if he was found guilty, his owner would not be
                    compensated for his loss. The Judge agreed and turned the case over to a State
                    Court.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1860.10.05.03">
            <div type="l">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>For the Vindicator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Little Giants</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Esq.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Churchman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Esq.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harrison</ln>
                        <fn>Powell</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Esq.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letter from a Douglas supporter who attended the formation of a Bell and
                    Everett Club with John Churchman as chair. James Bumgardner and Powell Harrison
                    spoke. "Little Giants" was polite, but critical of the Bell supporters.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Our Staunton Correspondence</head>
                <origin>New York Herald</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprint of a New York Herald article that lauds Staunton as "One of the
                    most charming spots known in all Western Virginia . . . a town, even at this
                    period of the nineteenth century, so delightfully primitive and free from city
                    innovations."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>[illegible]</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Thomas [illegible] died on September 27 of a lingering illness at his home
                    at age 40. He was a native of Ireland.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Mary J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>William R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary Smith, wife of William Smith was "struck down by disease" on September
                    18 at age 44. She left behind five children.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Another article attacking Yancey and defending Douglas in column 2.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1860.10.05.04">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
