<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- !DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd' -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1860/va.au.rv.1860.12.21">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Josh Rothman</taggerName>
            <tagDate>6/12/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>3rd Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1860-12-21">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="12">December</month>
            <day>21</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>03</extent>
        <editionNote>Only 3 pages.</editionNote>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1860.12.21.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Three carpenters were hung in Mississippi for inciting slaves to rebellion.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Letter from South Carolina. Columbia, S. C. Dec. 20, 1860.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript><p>COLUMBIA, S. C.,<date value="1860-12-03">Dec. 3d, 1860.</date></p> 
                    <p>DEAR SIR:--As yet, I have seen but 
                        little of the city, for such it claims to be.--The present census, 
                        imperfectly taken all admit, makes the population near ten thousand.  
                        From the State House, the corporate limits extend a mile towards each 
                        point of the compass.  The ground sloping gracefully in every direction 
                        affords very desirable building sites, anywhere.  The streets are one 
                        hundred feet wide, and planted with the willow and live oak and China 
                        trees.--The residences have spacious grounds most tastefully ornamented 
                        with all the evergreens and shrubs common to this clime.--The most 
                        interesting part of the town, containing the residence of the late Wade 
                        Hampton, now occupied by his son-in-law, Col. John Preston, I have not 
                        yet seen.--This spot it was where the distinguished orator of the South, 
                        Wm. C. Preston lately breathed his last.  The new State House, in 
                        progress of building, commands a beautiful view, the site reminding me 
                        much of ours.  
                        The granite of which it is constructed is nearly equal to that at 
                        Richmond--perhaps not quite so fair in color, or fine in texture.  The 
                        style is Corinthian, and judging from a beautiful drawing in the 
                        architects office, will be more striking than the National Capitol.  The 
                        busts of McDuffie and Hayne, in basso-relievo, adorn the front, on 
                        either side of the door opening from the second story, on to the 
                        portico.--In rear of the new, and in front of the old State House, 
                        stands the monument erected to the memory of those brave men of the 
                        Palmetto Regiment who fell in Mexico.--The base is of iron, some eight 
                        feet in height, with sides inclining towards each other at top, and with 
                        an open space at bottom, in which is a copper block, inscribed with the 
                        names of the officers and men, and the whole surmounted with a Palmetto 
                        tree of copper, but so true to life, that you are only convinced by 
                        handling it that it has not just been removed from that beautiful grove 
                        you will remember, on the south of Charleston harbor.  
                        In the original design the monument was to have been made much higher, which will be done when the 
                        new Capitol is finished, by placing it on a more elevated base.  In 
                        these days you can scarcely open a paper from the North, that you do not 
                        find taunts and innuendos indulged in by those miserable Black 
                        Republican journals, against the bravery and courage of this people.  It 
                        has been my pleasure since I came here to become well acquainted with 
                        two of the brave Captains of that noble regiments, one of whom holds the 
                        position of Adjutant and Inspector General of the State, and the other 
                        represents most worthily the District of Newberry in the present House 
                        of Representatives, and wears the title of General. Before the battle of 
                        Cherubusco, I think it was, that Gen. Butler, in writing to Gen. Worth, 
                        said--"Col. Dickinson deserves a place in the picture, near the flashing 
                        of the guns."  Gen. Worth, on the day of battle, said to Gen. Shields, 
                        "there is not a South Carolinian here, who will not follow you to de!
                        ath."--"Aye, to the death," responded private Whitfield Brooks.  "Stand 
                        the fire at all hazards, remembering you are from South Carolina," were 
                        the last inspiring words of Lieut. D. R. Clarke.  But I cannot give you 
                        a better description of their noble bearing on that bloody field, than 
                        in the description taken from the "Life and Correspondence of Gen. John 
                        a. Quitman." which I enclose.  The following is an extract of the 
                        description of the battle of Cherubusco:<lb/> 
                        "Col. Butler, of the South 
                        Carolinians,, had left his sick bed against the remonstrances of his 
                        friends, to lead the Palmettos to the combat.  Early in the engagement 
                        his horse was shot under him.  Soon after he received a painful wound in 
                        the knee, yielded the command to Lieutenant Colonel Dickinson.  Taking 
                        the Palmetto flag from the hands of Sergeant Beggs, Dickinson placed 
                        himself in front, and Beggs was immediately shot down.  Col. Butler now 
                        came up to resume the command and was killed by the side of Dickinson !
                        while standing under the flag. Dickinson himself soon fell mor!
                        tally wounded, (he died some weeks afterwards,) and Major Gladden received it 
                        from his hands, and committed it to Lieut. Baker, who being unable, from 
                        debility and exhaustion, to carry it, Major Gladden placed it in the 
                        hands of Patrick Leonard, and led his regiment to the charge.  His men 
                        fell rapidly, but not one wavered, from first to last, under the 
                        concentrated fire of the enemy.  In the whole history of war there has 
                        never been a more striking example of indifference to death, the result 
                        of stern resolve.  Each man fought for the honor of Carolina.  Several 
                        companies were almost annihilated.--Some had not men enough to bury 
                        their dead, or bear their wounded to the ambulances.  The uniforms of 
                        some of the officers were literally torn from their persons;  the 
                        color-bearers were shot down;  but the flag, bathed in their blood, was 
                        always seized as they fell and borne to the front.  Proudly it floated 
                        through the tempest of death until the victory had been won, and then, 
                        all torn and blood-stained, it dropped over its own glorious dead.  The regiment 
                        entered the battle with 273 rank and file, and when it was over it 
                        mustered 169!  It had no missing:  its dead and wounded made up the 
                        deficiency. Cadets of a noble State, sons of a sunny clime, branded by 
                        their country as traitors, for defending the Constitution and their 
                        rights from usurpation and outrage, yet dying cheerfully for that 
                        country in a foreign land--the world may learn that such a race, in 
                        defense of their own homestead and institutions, can never be subdued?</p> 
                    <p>Now, my friend, I deem it a privilege to have looked upon "that flag," 
                        or the shreds and remains of it; and I pardon the excess of State pride 
                        of a people who can boast of such trophies.  It is preserved where it 
                        ought to be in a glass case in their Capitol, where her sons and 
                        daughters may see it--the former to learn the lessons so gallantly 
                        taught them, and the latter to cherish their memories and inspirit their 
                        sons and brothers to emulate their deeds.  You may rest assured that when that evil day shall come (and may kind Heaven avert it!) that shall see the North in 
                        battle array against the South--South Carolina will send as brave and as 
                        gallant and as true men into the field, as the noble spirits that 
                        carried that Palmetto flag from Vera Cruz and planted it on the 
                        battlements of the halls of the Montezumas.  And, more than that, as 
                        fair and beautiful and spirited mothers and wives and daughters will 
                        send them forth to battle for their household gods, as any, the most 
                        highly favored of this once happy nation, could ever boast.  The spirit 
                        of the fair is excited beyond that of the other sex in this crisis, and 
                        he would be a craven base who would not fight for homes, graced with 
                        such inmates.</p>
                    *  *  *  *  *  *  *  *<lb/>
                    <p>But permit me here, in connexion 
                        with this last subject, (the slave trade,) to do justice to the people 
                        of S. C., and to defend them fully and decidedly against this charge 
                        brought against them.  I speak what I  do know, when I say that not one 
                        sixth part of her population is in favor of re-opening this trade--I have it from her 
                        Senators and Representatives, from every part of the State, and they 
                        disapprove of it unequivocally and most decidedly, as inhumane, cruel, 
                        uncalled for, and inexpedient.  They tell me that a few men along the 
                        coast and in some of the lower parishes, and generally of the Rhett 
                        school, are in favor of it.  I have heard but one man advocate it, and I 
                        have purposely sought conversations with them, to find out their views.  
                        I could but be impressed with the fact, that S. C. is ahead of Virginia 
                        in humanity, in regarding as sacred the marriage relations among her 
                        slaves, and frowning down a disposition to separate husband and wife, 
                        parent and child.  Public opinion is strong, decided, unmistakable, and 
                        departure from this course is the exception. In no part of the South is 
                        the slave more cared for, more humanely treated, better clothed, fed and 
                        nursed when sick; and what untold and unspeakable comfort would 
                        there be to the thousands of houseless sufferers, especially females, 
                        in the Northern States, this winter, and at this very moment, if they 
                        could not only share the blessings of these slaves--aye, but if they 
                        could but enjoy what they waste, what they throw away.  And yet, those 
                        myrmidons of hell--the Sumners and Garrisons and Wilsons, and all that 
                        class of pseudo-philanthropists--not only shut their eyes to these 
                        starving, suffering, wretched thousands famishing at their doors, but 
                        must incite these happy, contented, well cared for slaves to murder and 
                        pillage, to rapine and blood.  Not only do they instigate, by their 
                        counsels and their teachings, that all this is doing God service, but 
                        their blind fanaticism has applied the incendiary's torch to this noble 
                        fabric, that has sheltered us for three-parts of a century, and has rent 
                        this glorious Union into fragments.  If there be a spot in the region of 
                        the damned, where the torture is greater--where the serpent stingeth 
                        deeper--to that spot ought they to be consigned.  Pardon the warmth of 
                        this digression.  In a conversation with a large rice planter from the 
                        coast, who works some three hundred negroes, he informs me the task 
                        system prevails, which the hand can accomplish in a half of three parts 
                        of a day with ease, and devote the remainder to his own amusement or 
                        profit.  And one source of both is in shooting ducks, which they sell.  
                        On my expressing surprise at their being permitted to have arms, he 
                        remarked, nothing was more common, and he supposed that on his 
                        plantation there were forth or fifty of one kind or another, and that in 
                        a hostile invasion he felt perfectly assured those arms would be used in 
                        the defence of their master, instead of against him.  To show the 
                        absurdity of the idea entertained by these aforesaid satellites of his 
                        Infernal Majesty--that the labor of the South can as well be performed 
                        by the white as the negro--I will state that gentlemen of unquestionable 
                        integrity inform me, there are plantations within a dozen of miles of 
                        the city of harleston, the owners of which would no more dare to sleep on one night than to lie down under the shade of the deadly Upas, and yet the 
                        negroes enjoy uninterrupted health.  The overseer, whose duty it is to 
                        be almost constantly with them, has his residence off on the sand hills, 
                        as convenient as can be, and often falls a victim to disease.  Of course 
                        I refer to the cultivation of rice.  I find no sort of apprehension 
                        entertained by the people, whether from the mountain, the interior, or 
                        the low-land districts, in regard to their slaves.  Such is their 
                        humanity towards them, and the strength of attachment, that all the 
                        influences the designing and mischievous can, with their limited 
                        opportunities, bring to bear on this class, is inoperative.</p>
                    <p> As I have 
                        been disposed to run a parallel between South Carolinians and 
                        Virginians, I will do so in another instance, and, I regret to say, the 
                        comparison is unfavorable to us.  I refer to the subject of temperance.  
                        I have been now well night a week in intimate friendly social 
                        intercourse with the representatives of both branches of the Legislature of the State, and seen 
                        much, also, of other dignitaries, such as Judges, ex-Governors, &amp;c., and 
                        I have not seen a drink at the bar indulged in by any on of these 
                        gentlemen since I have been here.  I have seen more liquor drank at the 
                        bar of the Virginia Hotel in two hours of a Court day, or in a half-hour 
                        at the bar of the Exchange hotel, than I have seen drank by all classes 
                        here since I came.  In many of the districts of the State there is not a 
                        licensed grog-shop of any kind, and the representative of the district 
                        of Marlboro' informed me that there had not been one in his for the 
                        period of twenty years, and what may seem singular, the Board of 
                        Commissioners, whose duty it is to grant these licenses, were men fond 
                        of the article, but yet, actuated by a sense of duty to others, 
                        invariably refused all applications.  I may have observed in a former 
                        letter the marked homogeneous character of this people.  It is 
                        particularly true as applied to the representatives.  To one familiar with the members 
                        of our Legislature, the fact would be quite noticeable. They have no 
                        subjects of political difference, nor any local questions that make the 
                        asperity you sometimes see in our legislative halls.  In the great 
                        questions now agitating the State, they are a unit.  'Tis remarkable, 
                        that of their prominent men, Col. Pettigree, of Charleston, and Col. 
                        Perry, of one of the upland districts, are the only two men who differ 
                        seriously with the mass of the people, and they withdraw all opposition, 
                        and bow to the popular will.</p></transcript>
                <trailer>Yours sincerely,<lb/>J. M. McC.</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Long letter from J. M. McCue in South Carolina detailing recent events in
                    the Legislature there and defending the actions of the Palmetto State.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvdec60.html#12.21b</note>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The weather outside is frightful. Lots of snow and cold although the
                    "Sleigh bells kept up merry music."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Presbyterians of South Carolina</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Report of the South Carolina Presbyterian Synod on the issue of separation
                    from the Northern branch of their church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Congressional notes in column 6. Can't read most of column 7.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1860.12.21.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Religious</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Arnold</ln>
                        <fn>D.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baird</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Communion will be celebrated at Churchville by Rev. Baird.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Disunion from a Love of Disunion--Disunion by Reason of a Failure to Correct
                    the Breaches of the Constitution</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Disunion from a Love of Disunion--Disunion by Reason of a Failure to Correct
                        the Breaches of the Constitution.</p>
                    <p>Passing by as a number too few even to merit classification, those citizens
                        of the South who are liable to the reproach of "Submissionists," two parties
                        do actually exist in the South impelled in their action by different
                        motives, and animated with different emotions in the position which they
                        occupy in regard to the present political crisis, and the future destiny of
                        the Union and the States of the Union. There does exist in the South a party
                        of men who are disunionists <emph rend="italic">per se</emph>--not
                        disunionists alone because of a failure on the part of the Northern people
                        to fulfill the obligations which they, through their State sovereignties,
                        assumed in the Federal Constitution-- not from any dark spot which might
                        tarnish the bright escutcheon of their honor, by virtue of their affiliation
                        with the North--but <emph rend="italic">disunionists,</emph> believing that
                        the Cotton States will be advanced in the scale of wealth, prosperity,
                        happiness and glory to an infinitely higher degree, if separated from the
                        States of the North and confederated in a government of their own, than if
                        they are members of the present Federal Union, even if all the provisions of
                        the Federal Constitution are fully complied with, and every right and
                        guarantee contained in the government is honestly adhered to. We do not
                        think we would be hazarding too much when we express the opinion that South
                        Carolina entertains this sentiment, and all those of the South who are
                        willing to secede from the Union, notwithstanding satisfactory assurances
                        and perfect guarantees are given by the North that hereafter our privileges
                        and our property shall sustain no damage from Northern legislation, and
                        ample indemnification is provided for every attack on individual rights and
                        interests by fanatical mobs and abandoned outlaws. </p>
                    <p>There does exist in the South a party--a bold, brave, conservative
                        party--which does not only act for the protection of their present
                        interests, and the vindication of their honor, but are incited in their
                        purposes by the purest motives of philanthropy and patriotism which ever
                        actuated any body of men striking for the freedom of their country and the
                        safety and integrity of their household alters. That party is the one which
                        agrees to remain in the Union, ample satisfaction being given by notorious
                        deed and legitimate method, that <emph rend="italic">abolition
                        fanaticism</emph> shall no more triumph over and trample upon Southern
                        interests and Southern property. To condense in a few words: we have
                        disunionists through a love of disunion, and we have disunionists through a
                        hatred to usurpation and tyranny. We have no word of disrespect for South
                        Carolina and other Southern States which see proper to leave the Union. They
                        are Sovereign States, entitled to judge and act for themselves, and to weigh
                        the consequences of their acts. There have been grievous breaches of the
                        federal bond, we know, and it affords them favorable occasion to hoist the
                        banner of secession, with no alternative of change. But whilst we concede to
                        these States the power to determine their own destiny, we, without the
                        slightest hesitancy, attach ourselves to that party which believes that the
                        Federal Government, if legitimately administered and honestly adhered to, is
                        the best adapted to the condition and the hopes of the people of the United
                        States of North America, of any other species of government we have ever
                        read of or ever heard of.</p>
                    <p>We are for a continuation of the Federal Union, if the Northern people
                        repudiate and abandon their unjust course, and afford us sufficient security
                        that they mean to deal honestly with the South in this regard. We are for
                        secession on the part of Virginia, the border States and the South, and a
                        proper division of the common property, if this security is not given.</p>
                    <p>After secession, new Confederations, we have no doubt, will be formed. We
                        trust, sincerely trust, that every Southern State will be a member of a
                        common Confederation, if this necessity-- which Heaven forbid--is forced
                        upon us.</p>
                    <p>We hope that those true friends of justice in the North who have stood by us
                        in the darkest hour of our peril, will either make their homes in this
                        Southern Republic, or correct public opinion and control public sentiment in
                        their own States sufficiently to justify the South in receiving them into
                        any future alliance which they may adopt. We are determined to unite with no
                        State which does not admit Virginia's equality with her--does not eschew
                        every badge of royalty, and every idea of aristocracy, monarchy and caste.
                        We must have a Confederacy of free States, under a free government, with a
                        written Constitution.--If Virginia cannot get this, let Virginia stand alone
                        or fall.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Vindicator distinguishes between disunionists who want secession
                    because they believe that the South would be better off on its own and
                    disunionists who support the Union, but will leave it if the North fails to
                    protect Southern interests and Southern property. The Vindicator puts itself in
                    the latter category, one of the first times that the paper has embraced any type
                    of disunion sentiment.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvdec60.html#12.21d</note>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"There will be bloodshed if the 'Minute Men' of South Carolina demand the
                    surrender of Fort Moultrie."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary/>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Border State Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Border State Convention.</p>
                    <p>We are gratified to notice that our suggestion for a Convention of the Border
                        States is being generally endorsed and recommended by the press of all
                        parties in this and other States. We believe that is the most efficacious
                        remedy that can be adopted if a National Convention should not be called.
                        Let the Border States assemble in convention, take their position upon the
                        present Constitution, with any modifications a free conference and patient
                        deliberation may recommend, and then invite all the States of the Union to
                        join them. A union would be more speedily effected upon a more lasting basis
                        than the present, from which doubtless would be excluded South Carolina and
                        the New England States. Or, if they came into it, they would have to do so
                        upon such conditions as would forever preclude them from disturbing the
                        harmony of the confederacy again. A Border State Convention is the most
                        feasible idea upon which the Union can be reconstructed, the forms of
                        republican government preserved, and the growth, power and prosperity of our
                        country secured.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Vindicator endorses the idea of a Convention of the Border States. It
                    hopes that this convention can invite the rest of the States to join it and
                    resolve the current sectional problems.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvdec60.html#12.21c</note>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>State Convention--Its Duty</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Editorial arguing that a Virginia State Convention should address the
                    taxation system as well as the secession issue.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Educating the Northern Mind</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Compares slaves to Northern workers and says that at least slaves are taken
                    care of by their masters.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Notice</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>No paper will be published next week due to the Christmas holidays.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Peter Independence Kurtz</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Peter Kurtz will perform Christmas Carols on Christmas Day.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The slave that escaped to Canada after killing a man is being returned to
                    the US.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Vindicator complains again about the disrepair of Augusta Street.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6&amp;7</column>
                <head>Letter from South Carolina. Columbia, S. C., Dec. 13, 1860</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Letter from South Carolina.</p>
                    <p>COLUMBIA, S. C., Dec. 3d, 1860.</p>
                    <p>DEAR SIR:--As yet, I have seen but little of the city, for such it claims to
                        be.--The present census, imperfectly taken all admit, makes the population
                        near ten thousand. From the State House, the corporate limits extend a mile
                        towards each point of the compass. The ground sloping gracefully in every
                        direction affords very desirable building sites, anywhere. The streets are
                        one hundred feet wide, and planted with the willow and live oak and China
                        trees.--The residences have spacious grounds most tastefully ornamented with
                        all the evergreens and shrubs common to this clime.--The most interesting
                        part of the town, containing the residence of the late Wade Hampton, now
                        occupied by his son-in-law, Col. John Preston, I have not yet seen.--This
                        spot it was where the distinguished orator of the South, Wm. C. Preston
                        lately breathed his last. The new State House, in progress of building,
                        commands a beautiful view, the site reminding me much of ours. The granite
                        of which it is constructed is nearly equal to that at Richmond--perhaps not
                        quite so fair in color, or fine in texture. The style is Corinthian, and
                        judging from a beautiful drawing in the architects office, will be more
                        striking than the National Capitol. The busts of McDuffie and Hayne, in
                        basso-relievo, adorn the front, on either side of the door opening from the
                        second story, on to the portico.--In rear of the new, and in front of the
                        old State House, stands the monument erected to the memory of those brave
                        men of the Palmetto Regiment who fell in Mexico.--The base is of iron, some
                        eight feet in height, with sides inclining towards each other at top, and
                        with an open space at bottom, in which is a copper block, inscribed with the
                        names of the officers and men, and the whole surmounted with a Palmetto tree
                        of copper, but so true to life, that you are only convinced by handling it
                        that it has not just been removed from that beautiful grove <emph
                            rend="italic">you</emph> will remember, on the south of Charleston
                        harbor. In the original design the monument was to have been made much
                        higher, which will be done when the new Capitol is finished, by placing it
                        on a more elevated base. In these days you can scarcely open a paper from
                        the North, that you do not find taunts and innuendos indulged in by those
                        miserable Black Republican journals, against the bravery and courage of this
                        people. It has been my pleasure since I came here to become well acquainted
                        with two of the brave Captains of that noble regiments, one of whom holds
                        the position of Adjutant and Inspector General of the State, and the other
                        represents most worthily the District of Newberry in the present House of
                        Representatives, and wears the title of General. Before the battle of
                        Cherubusco, I think it was, that Gen. Butler, in writing to Gen. Worth,
                        said--"Col. Dickinson deserves a place in the picture, near the flashing of
                        the guns." Gen. Worth, on the day of battle, said to Gen. Shields, "there is
                        not a South Carolinian here, who will not follow you to death."--"Aye, to
                        the death," responded private Whitfield Brooks. "Stand the fire at all
                        hazards, remembering you are from South Carolina," were the last inspiring
                        words of Lieut. D. R. Clarke. But I cannot give you a better description of
                        their noble bearing on that bloody field, than in the description taken from
                        the "Life and Correspondence of Gen. John a. Quitman." which I enclose. The
                        following is an extract of the description of the battle of Cherubusco:</p>
                    <p>"Col. Butler, of the South Carolinians,, had left his sick bed against the
                        remonstrances of his friends, to lead the Palmettos to the combat. Early in
                        the engagement his horse was shot under him. Soon after he received a
                        painful wound in the knee, yielded the command to Lieutenant Colonel
                        Dickinson. Taking the Palmetto flag from the hands of Sergeant Beggs,
                        Dickinson placed himself in front, and Beggs was immediately shot down. Col.
                        Butler now came up to resume the command and was killed by the side of
                        Dickinson while standing under the flag. Dickinson himself soon fell
                        mortally wounded, (he died some weeks afterwards,) and Major Gladden
                        received it from his hands, and committed it to Lieut. Baker, who being
                        unable, from debility and exhaustion, to carry it, Major Gladden placed it
                        in the hands of Patrick Leonard, and led his regiment to the charge. His men
                        fell rapidly, but not one wavered, from first to last, under the
                        concentrated fire of the enemy. In the whole history of war there has never
                        been a more striking example of indifference to death, the result of stern
                        resolve. Each man fought for the honor of Carolina. Several companies were
                        almost annihilated.--Some had not men enough to bury their dead, or bear
                        their wounded to the ambulances. The uniforms of some of the officers were
                        literally torn from their persons; the color-bearers were shot down; but the
                        flag, bathed in their blood, was always seized as they fell and borne to the
                        front. Proudly it floated through the tempest of death until the victory had
                        been won, and then, all torn and blood-stained, it dropped over its own
                        glorious dead. The regiment entered the battle with 273 rank and file, and
                        when it was over it mustered 169! It had no missing: its dead and wounded
                        made up the deficiency. Cadets of a noble State, sons of a sunny clime,
                        branded by their country as traitors, for defending the Constitution and
                        their rights from usurpation and outrage, yet dying cheerfully for that
                        country in a foreign land--the world may learn that such a race, in defense
                        of their own homestead and institutions, can never be subdued?</p>
                    <p>Now, my friend, I deem it a privilege to have looked upon "that <emph
                            rend="italic">flag</emph>," </p>
                    <p> or the shreds and remains of it; and I pardon the <emph rend="italic">excess
                            of State pride</emph> of a people who can boast of such trophies. It is
                        preserved where it <emph rend="italic">ought</emph> to be in a glass case in
                        their Capitol, where her sons and daughters may see it--the former to learn
                        the lessons so gallantly taught them, and the latter to cherish their
                        memories and inspirit their sons and brothers to emulate their deeds. You
                        may rest assured that when that evil day shall come (and may kind Heaven
                        avert it!) that shall see the North in battle array against the South--South
                        Carolina will send as brave and as gallant and as true men into the field,
                        as the noble spirits that carried that Palmetto flag from Vera Cruz and
                        planted it on the battlements of the halls of the Montezumas. And, more than
                        that, as fair and beautiful and spirited mothers and wives and daughters
                        will send them forth to battle for their household gods, as any, the most
                        highly favored of this once happy nation, could ever boast. The spirit of
                        the fair is excited beyond that of the other sex in <emph rend="italic">this
                            crisis</emph>, and he would be a craven base who would not fight for
                        homes, graced with such inmates.</p>
                    <p>* * * * * * * *</p>
                    <p>But permit me here, in connexion with this last subject, (the slave trade,)
                        to do justice to the people of S. C., and to defend them <emph rend="italic"
                            >fully</emph> and <emph rend="italic">decidedly</emph> against this
                        charge brought against them. I speak what I do know, when I say that not
                            <emph rend="italic">one sixth</emph> part of her population is in favor
                        of re-opening this trade--I have it from her Senators and Representatives,
                        from every part of the State, and they disapprove of it <emph rend="italic"
                            >unequivocally and most decidedly</emph>, as inhumane, cruel, uncalled
                        for, and inexpedient. They tell me that a few men along the coast and in
                        some of the lower parishes, and generally of the Rhett school, are in favor
                        of it. I have heard but one man advocate it, and I have purposely sought
                        conversations with them, to find out their views. I could but be impressed
                        with the fact, that S. C. is ahead of Virginia in <emph rend="italic"
                            >humanity</emph>, in regarding as sacred the marriage relations among
                        her slaves, and frowning down a disposition to separate husband and wife,
                        parent and child. Public opinion is strong, decided, unmistakable, and
                        departure from this course is the exception. In no part of the South is the
                        slave more cared for, more humanely treated, better clothed, fed and nursed
                        when sick; and what untold and unspeakable comfort would there be to the
                        thousands of houseless sufferers, especially females, in the Northern
                        States, this winter, and at this very moment, if they could not only share
                        the blessings of these slaves--aye, but if they could but enjoy what they
                        waste, what they throw away. And yet, those <emph rend="italic">myrmidons of
                            hell</emph>--the Sumners and Garrisons and Wilsons, and all that class
                        of pseudo-philanthropists--not only shut their eyes to these starving,
                        suffering, wretched thousands famishing at their doors, but must incite
                        these happy, contented, well cared for slaves to murder and pillage, to
                        rapine and blood. Not only do they instigate, by their counsels and their
                        teachings, that all this is doing God service, but their blind fanaticism
                        has applied the incendiary's torch to this noble fabric, that has sheltered
                        us for three-parts of a century, and has rent this glorious Union into
                        fragments. If there be a spot in the region of the damned, where the torture
                        is greater--where the serpent stingeth deeper--to <emph rend="italic">that
                            spot</emph> ought they to be consigned. Pardon the <emph rend="italic"
                            >warmth</emph> of this digression. In a conversation with a large rice
                        planter from the coast, who works some three hundred negroes, he informs me
                        the task system prevails, which the hand can accomplish in a half of three
                        parts of a day with ease, and devote the remainder to his own amusement or
                        profit. And one source of <emph rend="italic">both</emph> is in shooting
                        ducks, which they sell. On my expressing surprise at their being permitted
                        to have arms, he remarked, nothing was more common, and he supposed that on
                        his plantation there were forth or fifty of one kind or another, and that in
                        a hostile invasion he felt perfectly assured those arms would be used in the
                        defence of their master, instead of against him. To show the absurdity of
                        the idea entertained by these aforesaid satellites of his Infernal
                        Majesty--that the labor of the South can as well be performed by the white
                        as the negro--I will state that gentlemen of unquestionable integrity inform
                        me, there are plantations within a dozen of miles of the city of Charleston,
                        the owners of which would no more dare to sleep on one night than to lie
                        down under the shade of the deadly Upas, and yet the negroes enjoy
                        uninterrupted health. The overseer, whose duty it is to be almost constantly
                        with them, has his residence off on the sand hills, as convenient as can be,
                        and often falls a victim to disease. Of course I refer to the cultivation of
                        rice. I find no sort of apprehension entertained by the people, whether from
                        the mountain, the interior, or the low-land districts, in regard to their
                        slaves. Such is their humanity towards them, and the strength of attachment,
                        that all the influences the designing and mischievous can, with their
                        limited opportunities, bring to bear on this class, is inoperative. </p>
                    <p>As I have been disposed to run a parallel between South Carolinians and
                        Virginians, I will do so in another instance, and, I regret to say, the
                        comparison is unfavorable to us. I refer to the subject of temperance. I
                        have been now well night a week in intimate friendly social intercourse with
                        the representatives of both branches of the Legislature of the State, and
                        seen much, also, of other dignitaries, such as Judges, ex-Governors,
                        &amp;c., and I have not seen a drink at the bar indulged in by any on of
                        these gentlemen since I have been here. I have seen more liquor drank at the
                        bar of the Virginia Hotel in two hours of a Court day, or in a half-hour at
                        the bar of the Exchange hotel, than I have seen drank by all classes here
                        since I came. In many of the districts of the State there is not a licensed
                        grog-shop of any kind, and the representative of the district of Marlboro'
                        informed me that there had not been one in his for the period of twenty
                        years, and what may seem singular, the Board of Commissioners, whose duty it
                        is to grant these licenses, were men fond of the article, but yet, actuated
                        by a sense of duty to others, invariably refused all applications. I may
                        have observed in a former letter the marked homogeneous character of this
                        people. It is particularly true as applied to the representatives. To one
                        familiar with the members of our Legislature, the fact would be quite
                        noticeable. They have no subjects of political difference, nor any local
                        questions that make the asperity you sometimes see in our legislative halls.
                        In the great questions now agitating the State, they are a unit. 'Tis
                        remarkable, that of their prominent men, Col. Pettigree, of Charleston, and
                        Col. Perry, of one of the upland districts, are the only two men who differ
                        seriously with the mass of the people, and they withdraw all opposition, and
                        bow to the popular will. Yours sincerely,</p>
                    <p>J. M. McC.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Yours respectfully, J. M. C.</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Another letter from J. M. McCue relating the present happenings in the
                    capital of South Carolina.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Drama--Should be Encouraged?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn>John D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Esq.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turk</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Article on a theater company that left several unpaid debts in Staunton.
                    John Imboden and Col. Turk caught them and brought them back to Staunton to
                    stand trial.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Very blurred and difficult to read around edges. Article on South Carolina
                Convention in column 7.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1860.12.21.03">
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarkson</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McComb</ln>
                        <fn>Marina</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Clarkson was married to Marina McComb by Rev. Baker on Dec. 11.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Congressional notes in columns 1&amp;amp;2. Page looks like it had been
                folded over. Hard to read.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
