<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1860/va.au.rv.1860.01.13">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/13/03</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1860-01-13">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day norm="13">13</day>
            <weekday id="Fri">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1860.01.13.01">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1860.01.13.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Homespun Movement</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We like it much. It has the sweet savour of the cargo of tea that was thrown
                        overboard in other days. Let Massachusetts remember that tea, and tremble at
                        the homespun movement. The same spirit that animated her Southern sisters
                        then, and brought their chivalry to her side, to avenge the injustice of a
                        foreign tyrant, animates them now, and enables them to dare and suffer
                        everything in defense of their Constitutional rights--their honor, and
                        sovereign equality.</p>
                    <p>We like it too, because it enables us to fight the battles of the
                        Constitution within the Union, in the most effective manner, and by the use
                        of the most simple machinery.--Without arms, without even legal enactments,
                        let every Southern man, woman and child exercise their undoubted right to
                        determine with whom they will deal. Let them resolve each for himself that
                        not one cent shall go from the South into the services of the Aid Societies,
                        Underground Railroads, and Freedom Shriekers of the North, either through
                        the merchant princes, manufacturers, institutions of learning, yankee
                        book-sellers, yankee teachers, yankee pedlars, or any other channel. By such
                        a policy, the Union will be perpetuated, and the immense resources of the
                        South built up.--By such a policy alone can the conservatism of the Northern
                        States be aroused into action, and the reign of their demagogues be
                        terminated. Governor Wire has well said that the spirit of Northern
                        conservatism is "passive," and has remained so, until it is rendered
                        powerless for good. Let them be made to feel that a cheerful obedience to
                        the compacts of the Constitution is necessary for their preservation, as
                        well as for ours. Let their distinguished men, such as Millard Fillmore, lay
                        down their maudlin sensibilities, and be taught that the great character of
                        our liberty and Union is not so abhorrent to the laws of God and of Justice,
                        as to make it "a painful duty" for modern philanthropists to carry out its
                        provisions, in obedience to their solemn oaths. This is the sentiment among
                        many Northern men, who call themselves conservative, which feeds
                        abolitionism. It must be corrected before fraternity can exist between the
                        North and the South; and while the two great and only objects of government
                        are the protection of persons and property, Northern men must know that the
                        most valuable property of the South is as sacred and as much entitled to
                        protection as any other. They are greatly in the dark at this time on this
                        subject, and can only be enlightened by a pressure on their pocket nerve. We
                        say, then, success to the homespun movement.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors call for a southern homespun movement that will save the Union
                    by demonstrating the South's resolve and enlisting the sympathy of northern
                    conservatives.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Right Spirit</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We are pleased to observe a disposition on the part of the Volunteer
                        Companies forming throughout the State, to adopt for their uniform goods of
                        our own manufacture. One of the Lynchburg companies was supplied a few days
                        since with some three hundred yards of beautiful cadet mixture, from the
                        Staunton Factory, and we learn that a number of other orders have been
                        received. By the way, we hazard nothing in saying that the goods
                        manufactured at the Staunton Factory, will compare favorably either in
                        quality or appearance with any other establishment of the kind.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors announce their approval of the decision of many state volunteer
                    companies to buy from Staunton cloth for uniforms.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1860.01.13.03">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1860.01.13.04">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
