<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1860/va.au.rv.1860.06.22">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Josh Rothman</taggerName>
            <tagDate>6/12/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>3rd Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1860-06-22">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="06">June</month>
            <day>22</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1860.06.22.01">
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>From the Rockingham Register, Messrs. Editors</head>
                <origin>Rockingham Register</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"The time seems at length to have arrived when a member of the M.E. Church in
                        Virginia can speak his sentiments, freely and fully, upon the subject which,
                        most of all others, has engrossed our attention, and wounded our hearts for
                        a period of eight or ten years--I mean the subject of slavery in our
                        church."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>PAX</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Discusses the Methodist Conference in Buffalo that condemned slavery.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Poem, "Celt and Saxon" in column 4, "Strange Women Wanted" in column
            7.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1860.06.22.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A collection of several newspapers' reactions to a report that a white man
                    was beaten by a "party of negroes" while he pursued runaway slaves in
                    Pennsylvania.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvjune60.html#6.22a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Romney (Va.) <emph rend="italic">Intelligencer</emph> tells of the
                        mobbing of a citizen of Springfield, Hampshire co., by a party of negroes in
                        Blairsville, Pa. He had gone thither in pursuit of fugitive slaves. He was
                        unarmed at the time of the assault and was very severely beat. The
                        Blairsville <emph rend="italic">Record</emph> says:</p>
                    <p>"It is supposed there were not less than fifty persons looking with apparent
                        complacency on this barbarous and inhuman tragedy, many of whom would have
                        the world believe that they are quite intelligent and respectable
                        characters.</p>
                    <p>We have only limited time and space to say, that officers of the law were
                        present, whose duty it is to maintain the public peace, and we expect to see
                        those darkies and those who countenanced them brought to condign punishment.
                        We intend to recur to this diabolical and disgraceful affair next week."</p>
                    <p>The <emph rend="italic">Intelligencer</emph> says:</p>
                    <p>"We are informed by one of the party, that shortly after arriving at the
                        county seat of Indiana county, two of the party, wearied and fatigued, they
                        were waited upon by the <emph rend="italic">Attorney for the
                        Commonwealth</emph> of that co., a beautiful specimen of a conservator of
                        the peace he must be, who informed them, that he was authorized or rather
                        deputised by a public meeting to say to them that <emph rend="italic"
                            >fifteen minutes</emph> would be allowed to them to leave the place, and
                        that in case they did not do so, they would be tarred and feathered, and
                        that he, although sworn to see that the laws were not violated, <emph
                            rend="italic">would assist in doing it!</emph> Out upon such a
                    rascal!"</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary/>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parcut</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McNamara</ln>
                        <fn>Patrick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Parcut was qualified as Asst. Police Officer for Staunton and McNamara as a
                    police officer for Thornrose Cemetery.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="j">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ewing</ln>
                        <fn>Allen</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Ewing was convicted of passing counterfeit money and sentenced to life in
                    prison.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Bear Captured</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>J.J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Montgomery</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A bear was captured in the neighborhood of Mint Spring by Montgomery and
                    others.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>D., D. and B. Institution</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The public is invited to the annual exhibition at the Deaf, Dumb and Blind
                    Institution.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Central and Orange Alexandria Railroads</head>
                <origin>Office Orange and Alexandria R. R. Co.</origin>
                <commentary>The editor notes that the conflict between the two companies has been
                    resolved.</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>John S. Barbour, Jr., President</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barbour</ln>
                        <fn>John S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fontaine</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Orange and Alexandria Railroad responds to the statement in the
                    previous week's paper by the Central Railroad.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Democratic National Convention--Baltimore</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Democratic National Convention</p>
                    <p>BALTIMORE, June 18.--The Convention assembled here at [?] o'clock to-day. The
                        Theatre was densely packed. The assemblage was called to order by the Hon.
                        Caleb Cushing. Prayer was offered by the Rev. Dr. McCro--. The President
                        congratulated the Convention on its re-assembling, and expressed the hope
                        that harmony would prevail.</p>
                    <p>The New York delegation introduced a resolution that the claims to seats by
                        delegates from the Cotton States be referred to the Committee on
                        credentials, and that the report of that committee be final, with the
                        understanding that no one be admitted who does not pledge himself to abide
                        by the decision of the Convention, and support the nominees.</p>
                    <p>An hour was spent in discussing points of order and motions to adjourn. The
                        New York delegation . . . [word missing] . . . to sustain the call for the
                        previous question, which was lost.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Gilmer, of Pa., offered the following resolution:</p>
                    <p>Resolved, That the President of this Convention be directed to issue tickets
                        of admission to seats in the Convention to the delegates from the States of
                        Texas, Florida, Mississippi and Arkansas, in which States there are no
                        contesting delegations.</p>
                    <p>The Convention then adjourned 'till 5 o'clock, P. M.</p>
                    <p>The Convention re-assembled at 5 o'clock. The President stated that he had
                        had placed in his hands credentials of gentlemen claiming seats in the
                        Convention from the States of Delaware, Georgia, Alabama, Florida,
                        Mississippi, Louisiana, Texas, and Arkansas, including in that . . . [text
                        missing] . . . in this place, by Mr. Howard, of Tennessee, in behalf of the
                        gentlemen claiming seats from the State of Mississippi, and in addition to
                        that, there has been addressed to the chair a communication from Mr.
                        Chaffee, claiming a seat from the State of Massachusetts.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Gilmer, for the purpose of arranging difficulties, withdrew his
                        resolution, and asked leave to offer another, embodying the original
                        resolution with an addenda, as follows:</p>
                    <p>Resolved, That the President of this Convention be authorized to issue
                        tickets of admission to seats in the Convention to the delegates from the
                        States of Arkansas, Texas, Florida and Mississippi, in which States there
                        are no contesting delegations; and that in those States, to wit: Delaware,
                        Georgia, Alabama, and Louisiana, where there are contesting delegations, a
                        committee on credentials shall be appointed by the several delegations to
                        report upon said States.</p>
                    <p>A spirited and able debate was continued up to near nine o'clock. The
                        previous question on the pending resolution and amendments was moved and
                        seconded, when a motion to adjourn until ten o'clock Tuesday morning
                        prevailed.</p>
                    <p>SECOND DAY.--BALTIMORE, June 19.--The Convention met this morning at 10
                        o'clock.</p>
                    <p>The resolutions on the admission of delegates were amended so as to read that
                        the credentials of all persons claiming seats in this Convention, made
                        vacant by the secession of delegates at Charleston, be referred to the
                        committee on credentials.</p>
                    <p>This was adopted under a call for the previous question.</p>
                    <p>The Convention then adjourned until 5 P. M., to await the report of the
                        committee.</p>
                    <p>At 5 o'clock the Convention met pursuant to adjournment, and the Committee on
                        Credentials not being ready to report, adjourned until to-morrow.</p>
                    <p>THIRD DAY.--BALTIMORE, June 20.--The Convention met at five o'clock, and
                        adjourned till ten to-morrow. The Committee on Credentials are still unable
                        to report.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Avery, of North Carolina, Mr. Saulsbury, of Delaware, and other Southern
                        Delegates, waited on Dean Richmond, Chairman of the New York delegation, to-
                        day, with a proposition to admit all the seceding delegates, with the
                        understanding that no candidate shall be nominated who was voted for at
                        Charleston, thus excluding Douglas, Hunter, Dickinson, Lann, Guthrie, Davis
                        and Johnson, but it is not probable that the proposition will be accepted.</p>
                    <p>There is no foundation for the report that the Douglasites have threatened to
                        withdraw from the Convention under any circumstances.</p>
                    <p>It is rumored that the delay of the report of the Committee will embarrass
                        the Seceders, as the Convention in Richmond is advertised to meet to-morrow.
                        But this is not entitled to credence, as it is known that the President of
                        that Convention, together with the South Carolina delegates and others, are
                        now in Richmond, ready to meet at the appointment of the time, and adjourn
                        from day to day till the rising of the Convention here.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Discusses the first three days of the Baltimore Convention and what the
                    Convention does about the states with competing delegations.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvjune60.html#6.22b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Wesleyan Female Institute</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wheeler</ln>
                        <fn>J.K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announcement of the commencement exercises of the Wesleyan Female
                    Institute. The Baccalaureate Sermon will be preached by Rev. Wheeler.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>From the Valley Star</head>
                <origin>Valley Star</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>John Hamilton, Ch'n.; Wesley Hardy, Sec'y.</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Rockbridge County members of the M. E. Church have decided to separate
                    themselves from the General Conference.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>John C. Middleton, Ch'n.; Robert I. Hillie, Sec'y.</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lexington Station M.E. members agree with the action of the Rockbridge
                    members.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Military Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>F. C. Roberts, Chairman; J. Olin Hobbs, Sec'y.; Spec copy.</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roberts</ln>
                        <fn>F.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hobbs</ln>
                        <fn>J. Olin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A notice for the meeting of the West View Volunteer Company to elect
                    officers.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The M. E. Church and Slavery</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Loudon County M. E. members also reject the General Conference's action on
                    the subject of slavery.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Singular Affair</head>
                <origin>Lewisburg Chronicle</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Lewisburg Chronicle</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>A runaway slave is caught after coming to a town and living there for
                    several years, marrying and having two kids.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>The "Rail Maker"--A Keen Retort</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Another article supporting Douglas and attacking Lincoln.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>North Carolina</head>
                <origin>Wash. States</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Wash. States</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Several North Carolina electors are supporting Douglas.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>The Railroad Connection--Difficulties Answered</head>
                <origin>Alex. Gazette</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Alex. Gazette</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Orange and Alexandria and the Virginia Central R. R. have resolved
                    their differences, so the mail will get through.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Congressional notes in column 2. Discussion of the assassination of the
                Japanese Prince Regent in column 4. Letter from PAX to "Alexandria" about the M.E.
                Church in column 5. Biographical sketch of Abe Lincoln in column 5. Also several
                article from various papers on the wheat crop. Whole page is very difficult to
            read.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1860.06.22.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Shocking Tragedy in Texas</head>
                <origin>Hoskins Monitor</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A Texas slave, after being whipped, killed his master and his master's
                    family, confessed and was hung, along with three other black men.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Vigilance Committee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A committee was formed to rid Orange County, Virginia of anyone inciting
                    slaves to disobey their owners.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wheeler</ln>
                        <fn>J.R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Freed</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barger</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on June 7.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wheeler</ln>
                        <fn>J.R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gollady</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Williams</ln>
                        <fn>Martha</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on June 14.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary Hanger died on June 8 at age 3.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Humphreys</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel Humphreys died near Greenville on June 11 at age 75.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Apportionment of the Capitation Tax</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>G. W. Imboden, Sup't S. A. C.</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCoy</ln>
                        <fn>Judson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ponge</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gamble</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seawright</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>J.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Airhart</ln>
                        <fn>Phillip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hogshead</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>Alex</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kerr</ln>
                        <fn>N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Finley</ln>
                        <fn>S.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>J.G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mowry</ln>
                        <fn>G.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Withrow</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coiner</ln>
                        <fn>Cyrus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>R.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pilson</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coiner</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilkeson</ln>
                        <fn>D.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McPheeters</ln>
                        <fn>A.A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sunley</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCutchen</ln>
                        <fn>Ad.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Calhoun</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>S.K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bear</ln>
                        <fn>J.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Berry</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Montgomery</ln>
                        <fn>W.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn>G.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A list of the Augusta County school commissioners and the tax from each
                    district.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>European news in column 1. Story of 14 year old girl and 31 year old man
                getting married in column 2. Small blurb about Lincoln in column 2.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1860.06.22.04">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
