
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1868/pa.fr.fr.1868.02.12">

    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>

        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>05/05/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>

        <address>
<city>Chambersburg</city>
<county>Franklin</county>
<state>Pennsylvania</state>
</address>

        <date n="1868-02-12">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day>12</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
    </header>

    <paperBody>

        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.02.12.01" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.02.12.02" exists="no">


            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>A. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A. K. McClure will deliver a lecture in the Court House on Mormonism.
                    Proceeds will go to benefit the poor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The recent spontaneous and positive expressions of the Republicans of a
                        number of counties in Pennsylvania, presenting the name of ANDREW G. CURTIN
                        as their choice for Vice President on the national ticket with Gen. Grant,
                        have no common significance, and indicate an ultimate unanimity of sentiment
                        that will carry the whole moral power of our great State to Chicago to urge
                        his nomination. It is most natural that such expressions should come from
                        the faithful citizens of the State, and coming as they do from the hearts of
                        the people rather than from systematic political effort, they indicate an
                        earnestness to which the coming State Convention will heartily respond.</p>
                    <p>The fitness of such a nomination we need not now discuss. It is recognized by
                        all classes of loyal men from convictions which have associated with them
                        the liveliest recollections of his eminent fidelity and patriotism, while
                        Chief Magistrate of our mighty Commonwealth during six years of the most
                        trying period of our history; and his noble deeds, his unstained record, and
                        his high measure of administrative success in every department, are pointed
                        to with pride by every lover of his country's cause. Especially with the
                        soldiers of the Republic, is his name a tower of strength. In every issue
                        affecting their interests he was their ablest and most potent champion. In
                        adversity his presence and eloquence in their camps inspired them to fresh
                        deeds of valor. In victory he told the story of their triumphs and pointed
                        to the beneficent fruits of man's noblest struggle for man. In sickness he
                        visited and comforted them, and his ministrations were felt in every section
                        of the country where sorrow shadowed the defenders of the Flag, and in the
                        sad bereavements for the martyred dead the silver lining to the cloud was
                        visible as he gathered the fallen heroes to sleep with their kindred. The
                        first great victor of the revolution of 1860, he was again the invincible
                        leader who restored our State to loyal supremacy in the dark days of 1863,
                        and when he had filled the constitutional measure of Executive duties, he
                        retired with the emphatic endorsement of the people, and left our great
                        Commonwealth mightier and nobler and more prosperous than ever before in our
                        history.</p>
                    <p>The presentation of GOV. CURTIN'S name for the Vice Presidency is no empty
                        compliment. His fame needs no such gilding--his proud record needs no such
                        commendation. His name is presented in obedience to the earnest desire of
                        earnest and faithful men who ask the prestige of his name on the ticket for
                        the great national struggle of 1868. Not only in his own State, but in every
                        State where loyalty is cherished, he is esteemed one of the first of the
                        representative men of the Republic, and we feel well assured that the appeal
                        of Pennsylvania for his nomination will be warmly responded to in other
                        sections of the Union. We believe that he can be nominated if Pennsylvania
                        will be true to herself, and when the People shall have spoken through their
                        convention, we cannot doubt that there will be such cordial and earnest
                        support of their expression as must command the enthusiastic endorsement of
                        the Republican National Convention.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper endorses the candidacy of Governor Curtin for the Vice-Presidency
                    on the Republican ticket. The article outlines his record as governor during the
                    war and claims that he would command overwhelming support among all states in
                    the Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cooper</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper reports that John M. Cooper of the Valley Spirit is front-runner
                    for nomination as a Democratic Party candidate for the office of surveyor
                    general. The editors sarcastically remark that since the "duties of the office
                    consist in appearing at the counter of the Treasury once a quarter and drawing a
                    salary" Cooper is "eminently qualified."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper urges Republicans not to neglect the spring elections. Democrats
                    are hoping to take advantage of any Republican complacency.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that Republicans are almost unanimously in favor of
                    renominating General John F. Hartranft and Col. Jacob M. Campbell for the
                    offices of Auditor General and Surveyor General. They carried the 1865 election
                    by over 20,000 votes, and appear likely to defeat leading Democratic
                    candidates--Col. W. H. Davis and J. P. Linton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.02.12.03" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Revival of Religion</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunter</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Rev. John Hunter of Chambersburg recently concluded a large religious
                    revival that had been held for the past eleven weeks in Fayetteville's Baptist
                    Church. "The house was nightly crowded, and many who walked in spiritual
                    darkness are now rejoicing in the hope of eternal life." Eighty-eight
                    individuals made professions of faith, including a family of seven who joined
                    the church together. The Rev. Hunter is receiving accolades for his efforts.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Waynesboro Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilbert</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Douglas</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beaver</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Forney</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lidy</ln>
                        <fn>George F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove </ln>
                        <fn>William F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Waynesboro Building Association elected the following directors: Henry
                    Gilbert, Joseph Douglas, Jacob Beaver, Jacob S. Forney, George F. Lidy, William
                    F. Grove.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Lectures</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneck</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>A. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper declares the lecture series for the benefit of the poor a big
                    success. A large audience attended Rev. Dr. Schneck's lecture on "The Ruins of
                    Pompeii and Herculaneum." That evening's collection raised $23.47. Col. A. K.
                    McClure will deliver the next lecture on Mormonism. He recently travelled in
                    Mormon territory and will share his opinions and impressions.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="l">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Card of Thanks</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunter</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The ladies of the Baptist Church of Chambersburg express thanks to the
                    members of the town's other Christian denominations for their help in supporting
                    Rev. J. Hunter.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>I. O. G. T.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Findlay</ln>
                        <fn>R. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Slick</ln>
                        <fn>M. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>North</ln>
                        <fn>Mary C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eberly</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Murray</ln>
                        <fn>E. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>Harriet</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>North</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scheller</ln>
                        <fn>C. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ford</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whetstone</ln>
                        <fn>A. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Cune</ln>
                        <fn>M. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>Kate</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lamison</ln>
                        <fn>Jennie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Geyer</ln>
                        <fn>Emma</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brownson</ln>
                        <fn>R. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The members of the Mercersburg Lodge of Good Templars elected the following
                    officers: R. S. Findlay, M. J. Slick, Miss Mary C. North, Charles Eberly, E. B.
                    Murray, Miss Harriet White, John North, C. B. Scheller, Henry Ford, Rev. A. M.
                    Whetstone, M. S. M'Cune, Miss Kate Trout, Miss Jennie Lamison, Miss Emma Geyer.
                    Lodge Deputy R. S. Brownson installed the new officers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deceased</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kane </ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Susan Kane died at her residence in Quincy from the effects of a
                    recent fall. She was about 80 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Death of Mrs. Winger</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Winger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Winger</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Winger, wife of Col. B. F. Winger, Franklin's member of the House of
                    Representatives, died in Greencastle on Wednesday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hyssong</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Anna M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>S. H. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>David Hyssong and Miss Anna M. Miller, both of Chambersburg, were married
                    on February 4th by the Rev. S. H. C. Smith.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ludwig</ln>
                        <fn>George J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burk</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brownscombe</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George J. Ludwig of Chambersburg and Miss Mary Burk of Wilkesbarre, were
                    married in Wilkesbarre on January 19th by the Rev. H. Brownscombe.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Winger</ln>
                        <fn>Susan J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Winger</ln>
                        <fn>B. Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duffield</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Susan J. Winger, wife of Col. B. Frank Winger and daughter of the late
                    William Duffield of Welsh Run, died on February 5th. She was 31 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.02.12.04" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

    </paperBody>
</hwp>
