
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1868/pa.fr.fr.1868.11.11">

    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>

        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>05/25/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>

        <address>
<city>Chambersburg</city>
<county>Franklin</county>
<state>Pennsylvania</state>
</address>

        <date n="1868-11-11">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="11">November</month>
            <day>11</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
    </header>

    <paperBody>

        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.11.11.01" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.11.11.02" exists="no">

            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Triumph</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Gen. U.S. Grant has been elected to the Presidency by a popular majority not
                        even surpassed by Lincoln in 1864. Twenty-six States out of thirty-four
                        declared in his favor, and the popular majority is not less than 300,000.</p>
                    <p>Such a verdict after the struggle we have witnessed, and in view of the
                        grounds upon which the opposition resisted Grant's election, has a
                        significance which cannot be misunderstood; and which the Democracy would do
                        well to consider. This election makes the third time in unbroken succession
                        that the people have declared themselves in favor of the principles of
                        government, cherished and supported and defended by the loyal Republican
                        party; once when the Democracy threatened rebellion if they adhered to them,
                        again when treason had raised its bloody hand in pursuance of its threats,
                        and now when the rebellion is crushed and the last test of the strength of
                        the government is made in its reconstruction.</p>
                    <p>There is now no mistaking the determination of the people that those who were
                        faithful to the cause of true liberty and gave of their blood and treasure
                        without stint to preserve it in its terrible struggle with treason shall
                        direct the destiny of the Republic until peace and Union are secured to all
                        on a foundation that shall last through all time. Just how this shall be
                        done those who in their madness have held a high carnival of blood
                        throughout the South, and those who encouraged and abetted them in the North
                        need not the power of inspiration to see. The self preserving power of the
                        government must be vindicated and submission to the supremacy of its laws
                        must be complete and unmistakable. This is what the election of Grant to the
                        Presidency means. This is the lesson the loyal people have taught to the
                        enemies of the country.</p>
                    <p>The following is the ascertained result of the electoral votes together with
                        the popular majorities as nearly as they can be ascertained:</p>
                    <p> FOR GRANT AND COLFAX</p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>
                                <emph rend="italic">States</emph>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <emph rend="italic">Electors</emph>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <emph rend="italic">Popular Maj.</emph>
                            </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Maine</cell>
                            <cell>7</cell>
                            <cell>28,000</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>New Hampshire</cell>
                            <cell>5</cell>
                            <cell>8,000</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Massachusetts</cell>
                            <cell>12</cell>
                            <cell>80,000</cell>
                            <cell>Rhode Island</cell>
                            <cell>4</cell>
                            <cell>6,000</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Connecticut</cell>
                            <cell>6</cell>
                            <cell>1,800</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Vermont</cell>
                            <cell>5</cell>
                            <cell>30,000</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Pennsylvania</cell>
                            <cell>26</cell>
                            <cell>29,000</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>West Virginia</cell>
                            <cell>5</cell>
                            <cell>8,000</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Ohio</cell>
                            <cell>21</cell>
                            <cell>35,000</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Indiana</cell>
                            <cell>13</cell>
                            <cell>5,000</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Illinois</cell>
                            <cell>16</cell>
                            <cell>50,000</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Michigan</cell>
                            <cell>8</cell>
                            <cell>25,000</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Wisconsin</cell>
                            <cell>8</cell>
                            <cell>15,000</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Iowa</cell>
                            <cell>8</cell>
                            <cell>30,000</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Nebraska</cell>
                            <cell>3</cell>
                            <cell>4,000</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Tennessee</cell>
                            <cell>10</cell>
                            <cell>40,000</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>California</cell>
                            <cell>5</cell>
                            <cell>1,000</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Nevada</cell>
                            <cell>3</cell>
                            <cell>1,000</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Missouri</cell>
                            <cell>11</cell>
                            <cell>10,000</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Kansas</cell>
                            <cell>3</cell>
                            <cell>5,000</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>North Carolina</cell>
                            <cell>10</cell>
                            <cell>8,000</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Minnesota</cell>
                            <cell>4</cell>
                            <cell>5,000</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Oregon</cell>
                            <cell>3</cell>
                            <cell>1,000</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Arkansas</cell>
                            <cell>4</cell>
                            <cell>20,000</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>South Carolina</cell>
                            <cell>8</cell>
                            <cell>1,355</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Florida</cell>
                            <cell>3</cell>
                            <cell>By Legislature</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Total</cell>
                            <cell>210</cell>
                            <cell>446,355</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <p> FOR SEYMOUR AND BLAIR</p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Kentucky</cell>
                            <cell>11</cell>
                            <cell>75,000</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Maryland</cell>
                            <cell>7</cell>
                            <cell>25,000</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Delaware</cell>
                            <cell>3</cell>
                            <cell>2,000</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Louisiana</cell>
                            <cell>6</cell>
                            <cell>25,000</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Georgia</cell>
                            <cell>9</cell>
                            <cell>40,000</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>New York</cell>
                            <cell>33</cell>
                            <cell>5,000</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>New Jersey</cell>
                            <cell>7</cell>
                            <cell>1,000</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Alabama</cell>
                            <cell>9</cell>
                            <cell>1,900</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Total</cell>
                            <cell>84</cell>
                            <cell>174,000</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Total No. of votes in Electoral College</cell>
                            <cell>294</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Necessary to a choice</cell>
                            <cell>148</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Total for Grant and Colfax</cell>
                            <cell>210</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Total for Seymour and Blair</cell>
                            <cell>84</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Grant's electoral majority</cell>
                            <cell>126</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Grant's popular majority</cell>
                            <cell>272,355</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor praises the election of Grant in the presidential contest. He
                    cites the election as a vindication of Republican policies and a complete defeat
                    of the Democrat's opposition to Reconstruction. In addition, the paper printed
                    the voting results by state.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Grant's Election the Triumph of Common Sense</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Common Sense has been defined to be the "convictions which we receive from
                        nature, which all men possess in common, and by which they test the truth of
                        knowledge and the morality of actions." It has been said, too, to be "such
                        ordinary complement of intelligence, that, if a person be deficient therein,
                        he is accounted mad or foolish."</p>
                    <p>Indeed it may be said that not only the willingness to accept the war and the
                        recent popular expression in favor of its principal actor, but the very
                        inception and origin of the republic, are due to the common sense of the
                        people. The very preamble to the constitution of the United States furnishes
                        the most potent and unanswerable arguments in favor of the American
                        republic, and is replete with common sense. It sets forth that the
                        constitution is ordained and established "in order to form a more perfect
                        union, establish justice, insure domestic tranquility, provide for the
                        common defence, promote the general welfare, and secure the blessings of
                        liberty."</p>
                    <p>The year 1860 found the American people confronted by great dangers. They
                        were asked to give up the Union altogether and to consent that the country
                        might be severed into a score of petty, discordant communities; to forego
                        the establishment of justice and consent that an empire might be founded
                        upon their soil having slavery for its corner-stone; to surrender domestic
                        tranquility for interminable intestine feuds and broils; to subordinate the
                        common defense and the general welfare to sectional hate; and to give up the
                        blessings of liberty in the interest of oppression and despotism.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Black's counsel to Mr. Buchanan, that the government possessed no
                        constitutional authority to coerce a State threatening to secede, struck the
                        American mind as untrue. Indeed it would have been a foolish opinion
                        proceeding from a common intellect, but emanating as it did from a jurist
                        and theretofore reputed statesman, it was wicked and criminal.</p>
                    <p>Abraham Lincoln succeeded to the seat of his timid predecessor, and in
                        obedience to the behests of the American People, proceeded to enforce the
                        constitution of the United States, and render it the paramount law upon
                        every foot of American territory. He proclaimed that the constitution was
                        established for the conservation of the republic and not to secure its
                        destruction. He announced that the republic had the right to live and, God
                        helping him, should not die, whilst he controlled its destinies.</p>
                    <p>In other words, the common sense of the good President echoed by the great
                        heart of the people, secured a triumph. Whilst Lincoln was practical and
                        efficient in the cabinet, Grant displayed no less common sense in the field.
                        He had no pet theories or plans in warfare; all were equally his. His
                        objective point was the suppression of the rebellion, and, keeping this
                        steadily in view, discarding all personal ambition and selecting his helpers
                        with masterly judgment, he wrought out in his own time and way the salvation
                        of his country.</p>
                    <p>With the death of Mr. Lincoln came new and unthought of troubles. Mr.
                        Johnson's early prejudices mastered him and he again allied himself to the
                        cause of the South. The Democratic party that had been powerless during the
                        war saw or thought they saw that their time had come, and made haste to do
                        obeisance to Mr. Johnson. They planted themselves squarely upon the doctrine
                        that the war must be ignored, and all people and States, the disloyal as
                        well as the loyal, restored to the condition of 1860 and 1861.</p>
                    <p>Here common sense again stepped in. If so why so?--said the American people.
                        Speaking of the war they said, what was it all for? Can men rebel, can
                        States rebel, and quit at pleasure, and then claim immunity? Can the nation
                        that was compelled by fire, sword and cannon to maintain its authority, not
                        demand security against the recurrence of insurrection and war? Are matters
                        of such vital importance as the payment of the public debt, the repudiation
                        of the debt contracted in trying to destroy the Government, the
                        disfranchisement of the principal rebels, and the citizenship of the
                        government's allies, to be left open matters, footballs between parties?</p>
                    <p>The common sense of the American people, as expressed in the election of
                        General Grant, said no! There must be guarantees exacted! The fruits of the
                        war must be fully gathered! And now, with the election of the great leader
                        of our armies, we think we see evidences of the return of a better state of
                        feeling upon the part of all our people. The Democrats who lately predicted
                        such dire disaster in the event of the success of the Republicans, now admit
                        that Grant will probably do. We believe that the era of Grant will be one of
                        repose. The rebels will settle into quiet, and like men of common sense, as
                        most of them are, accept the inevitable. The world will respect and fear
                        us--respect us for having done ourselves the credit to elect to rule over us
                        the man to whose prowess we are indebted for deliverance from intestine
                        trouble,--fear us because of our consolidated strength, vast resources and
                        popular common sense.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The columnist explains what Grant's election meant for the country.
                    Specifically, the continuation of Republican policies was simply "common sense"
                    to most people because it worked, whereas the Democrats' plans of immediate
                    reconciliation would have rendered the cause of the Union worthless.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Too Much Haste</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Some of our exchanges are full of conjectures and suggestions as to General
                        Grant's Cabinet. This playing at making appointments for the new President
                        is doubtless more interesting to those engaged in it than entertaining to
                        the people who hope to see a strong and upright administration, or to
                        General Grant, himself, whose wise and judicious appointments in the field
                        should be a sufficient guarantee as to how he will perform so important a
                        matter as the appointment of a Cabinet.</p>
                    <p>One thing is a matter of rejoicing to the loyal people. General Grant goes
                        into the Presidency wholly unincumbered by political hacks and tricksters,
                        and can select his advisors from the most able and patriotic men of the
                        country. And we have no doubt that in this, as in every difficult matter
                        heretofore, he will show himself master of the situation. In this respect he
                        has greatly the advantage of many of his predecessors.</p>
                    <p>Beside the manufacturing of cabinets, there will doubtless be a rattling
                        among the dry bones of the lesser political fossils, and a raising of the
                        past dead to secure the offices at <sic>the the</sic> disposal of the new
                        administration. Indeed the rattling has already begun, and the breath of
                        political life has animated shoals of them. Successful Congressmen are even
                        now overwhelmed with a host of the warmest and most unselfish friends. One
                        can only wonder that the immaculate loveliness of Congressmen elect could
                        have been concealed from the gaze of men who see so clearly now. These
                        patriotic gentlemen, the suddenly animated class, are cormorants of office
                        and are laying their plans to attain their hungry desires. They may not have
                        done a thing for the good of their country or humanity; they may have
                        grumbled and complained their way through the long and bitter campaign,
                        discouraging all whom they could influence by the way, and be in doubt even
                        when they reached the ballot-box for whom they should vote. But they are in
                        doubt no longer upon whose banner victory has perched, and they make
                        unseemly haste to explain away the ugly past and rush with their
                        congratulations to the successful candidates before their faces have had
                        time to change from a scowl to a smirk, or their tongues <sic>ot</sic>
                        unlearn the words of calumny and complaint and take up those of flattery and
                        sycophancy. Humanity is not complimented by the existence of such men, and
                        political parties are not benefitted by them, but that they do live and find
                        their way into politics are facts which must be lamented, but cannot be
                        prevented.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper expresses confidence that President Grant will make wise choices
                    in his cabinet selections. It also shows distaste towards those who switched
                    their positions after the voters defeated them. </summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The result of the Presidential election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The result of the Presidential election in Franklin county is a splendid
                        triumph for the Republican party, and we doubt if any where in the State a
                        county has done more than ours. In one year a Democratic majority of 187 has
                        not only been wiped out, but a Republican majority of 280 rolled up. While
                        we do not believe that the Democratic majority of last year fairly
                        represented the relative strength of the two parties, it yet showed clearly
                        that the Republicans had grown much weaker than in 1866, when they carried
                        the county by a majority of 193, and that their opponents had acquired a
                        ficticious supremacy which would give them great advantage in the contest
                        this fall. With the prestige of last fall's <sic>succest</sic> and a
                        majority of nearly two hundred in their favor, the Democracy were confident
                        of success while the Republicans labored under a corresponding difficulty.
                        The contest in October, made as it certainly was with this weighty advantage
                        on the side of the Democracy, was no insignificant triumph when we carried
                        the county by a majority of 43. It was desperately waged by both parties,
                        and we do not mean merely by those who assume to be leaders. Almost every
                        Republican did something more than merely cast his suffrage on election day,
                        and the voters who are not politicians, in the odious sense that term is now
                        employed, gave us the county. We may well be proud of the Republican party
                        of Franklin county. They have done more than those of any county in the
                        district, though all have done well. In one year they have made a change in
                        their favor of <emph rend="italic">four hundred and seventy votes</emph>,
                        thereby making the county decidedly Republican for years to come. In this
                        good work nearly every district has had its share. The table of official
                        votes in '66 and '68 will enable each district to see what it has done, but
                        we cannot neglect to mention among the most favorable Guilford, Quincy,
                        Washington, Antrim, Welsh Run and Hamilton. In the Democratic districts
                        their majorities of last year have with a few exceptions been greatly
                        reduced, and in the Republican districts the old majorities of '66 have been
                        regained. But in those districts above mentioned, they have far exceeded
                        anything they have done for years past.</p>
                    <p>Let us not forget that it is in our power to retain the county, and if we
                            <sic>loose</sic> it again our own indifference after the victory is won
                        will be the cause.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor congratulated the Republicans of Franklin county for regaining
                    the majorities they enjoyed back in 1866.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The results of the October and November elections</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The result of the October and November elections in Franklin county give
                        abundant proof that the <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> is neither a
                        prophet nor the son of a prophet, and we have had repeated occasion to show
                        both its false hoods and fallacies. The official returns of last week's
                        election are in striking contrast with the predictions of the <emph
                            rend="italic">Spirit</emph>, made immediately after those of October had
                        been received. What it then said is this:</p>
                    <lb/>

                    <p>"This year, upon an aggregate vote of 8,614, the largest ever cast, the
                        majority for Hartranft is only 43. This vote establishes the fact beyond
                        doubt that in all ordinary elections, Franklin county will give a Democratic
                        majority. At the late election local causes operated to bring out a class of
                        voters who will not go to the polls next month. Opposition to the Road Law
                        brought out men who would not have come out at all if that question had not
                        been before the people. Once at the polls, they were persuaded to vote the
                        Radical ticket."</p>
                    <lb/>

                    <p>The consolation the <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> then poured into the
                        ears of the defeated, that opposition to the Road Law brought out many
                        voters who would not otherwise have come out, but having come voted the
                        Republican ticket, now turns to wormwood and gaul. The official returns make
                        the total vote in November 23 greater than it was in October.</p>
                    <p>We take occasion to say this, not so much to show that the <emph
                            rend="italic">Spirit</emph> was mistaken in fact in this matter, for
                        about this we care nothing, as to vindicate the patriotism and intelligence
                        of the Republican voters of the county. The difference of a few dollars road
                        tax, more or less a year, may very properly engage the attention of our
                        farmers, and to reduce it they may go to the polls to vote, but nothing but
                        the stupidity of the <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> made it allege that
                        so large and intelligent a class of voters could be influenced by this, and
                        yet be indifferent to the momentous importance of the issues in the
                        Presidential contest. It must be blind, indeed, and hopelessly ignorant of
                        our people. The Republicans of Franklin county understood and appreciated
                        the grave importance of this election. They knew that the Democracy had
                        endangered the life of the Republic, and that their success would bring
                        untold disaster upon the country. Hence they turned out and polled the
                        largest vote ever polled in the county, and increased the Republican
                        majority over that of October by 237 votes. Well done Republicans of
                        Franklin county.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor ridicules the reasoning of the Democratic newspapers for the
                    Republican triumphs. The Democrats said the Republican victory was narrow and
                    only happened because some people turned out to vote on the Road Law. In
                    response, he cites the increased turnout in November to prove the Republican
                    victory was not a fluke.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper mocks the Democrats for quickly changing their stance on Grant
                    after his election. "Before the election of Grant and the defeat of Seymour, the
                    former was a miserable blunderer, a bloody murderer, and an ignorant tool of the
                    Radicals, while the latter was the greatest statesman of the age." Now the
                    tables are turned, and Democrats are softening toward Grant while
                    second-guessing their nomination of Seymour. They especially stress that Grant
                    was once a Democrat and hope he follows in the path outlined by Johnson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.11.11.03" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Election Day</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Since the surrender of Cornwallis to Washington or of Lee to Grant, there has
                        been no day so big with events for the weal or woe of America, as Tuesday,
                        the 3d inst. The people felt this to be so, and although the October
                        elections had virtually decided the contest, yet the success of Republican
                        principles was still in doubt and until finally settled, the nation was in a
                        state of danger. The revolutionary programme set forth by the leaders of the
                        opposition had aroused those who had been in earnest in the contest against
                        treason and placed in jeopardy all for which we had fought and suffered. The
                        memories of our "Boys in Blue," who had marched and fought and died for
                        Liberty and Union, were to be blotted out or forever live as part of the
                        glorious history of American patriotism, the sacrifices of loyal mothers and
                        fathers, sisters and brothers; of the country's widows were to have been in
                        vain or go down to posterity as a glorious heritage; the immortal sentence
                        of the Declaration of Independence, that "all men are created free and
                        equal; that they are endowed by their Creator with certain inalienable
                        rights, that among these are Life, Liberty and pursuit of happiness," was to
                        be proclaimed a lie for the ages to come, or to be placed high above the
                        destroyer's hand as the guiding star of a free people. We were to be honest,
                        or repudiate a debt contracted for our existence; we were to have war or
                        peace; and finally, rebels who tried to destroy the nation or loyal men who
                        saved it in its hour of peril were henceforth to rule it all these questions
                        and more were to be determined on the 3d of November, 1868. The day dawned
                        bright and clear. This was regarded as a favorable omen by Republicans; our
                        vote would certainly be polled. Events showed that they were right. At the
                        polls in Chambersburg everything passed off quietly. Both parties worked
                        hard, but the Democracy were disheartened, discouraged and almost
                        demoralized. They saw the handwriting on the wall. The polls closed at seven
                        p.m. The Republicans retired to the office of Cook &amp; Hays, where
                        arrangements had been made for receiving the news. Messrs. Kimmel &amp;
                        M'Lellan's office was for a while the headquarters of the downcast
                        Democrats. North Ward showed in short time a gain of 3, but when South Ward
                        came in with 27 Radical majority the game was up. Hamilton gave a gain of 16
                        for Grant on the October election. This was heart-rending, and out went the
                        lights in Mr. M'Lellan's office, and the Democracy too. The opposition was
                        in a bad way. They had no place where they could go, they were sheep without
                        a fold, a flock without a leader. They very naturally cursed severely
                        persons who had been promising them victories and yet left them forsaken and
                        forlorn. The news at Republican headquarters was received with the most
                        vociferous cheers and as State after State wheeled into line for Grant the
                        enthusiasm was unbounded. Congratulations and rejoicings were met on every
                        side.</p>
                    <p>The Boys in Blue and many others turned out about 12 m. and marched through
                        our principal streets, and with torches and music.</p>
                    <p>The campaign is ended. Right has won and we can now extend to men of all
                        classes and conditions and say "Let us have Peace," let us be friends.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor rejoices at the Republican victories in the recent elections,
                    especially in Franklin County. He says the contest favors Republican
                    reconstruction policies and repudiates the Democrats.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Dedication of Masonic and Odd Fellows Hall at Orrstown</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Laverty</ln>
                        <fn>D. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Bro.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dougherty</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hawkins</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The people of Orrstown celebrated the dedication of the new hall built to
                    house the local Masons and Odd Fellows. The day included addresses by prominent
                    community members, and processions of the fraternal orders. The Silver Cornet
                    Band of Chambersburg played. "The fair sex of the town were out, and with their
                    lovely faces and radiant smiles added much to the pleasure of the day."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Vote of Franklin County</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The following is the official vote of Franklin county for President at the
                        late election, as also the vote for Governor in 1866 and the vote for
                        Auditor General in October last:</p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>
                                <emph rend="italic">Governor,'66</emph>
                            </cell>[covers two columns] <cell>
                                <emph rend="italic">Aud. Gen,'68</emph>
                            </cell>[covers two columns] <cell>
                                <emph rend="italic">President,'68</emph>
                            </cell>[covers two columns] </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>Geary</cell>
                            <cell>Clyner</cell>
                            <cell>Hartfranft</cell>
                            <cell>Boyle</cell>
                            <cell>Grant</cell>
                            <cell>Seymour</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Antrim</cell>
                            <cell>545</cell>
                            <cell>521</cell>
                            <cell>570</cell>
                            <cell>517</cell>
                            <cell>583</cell>
                            <cell>497</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Chamb'g, N W</cell>
                            <cell>379</cell>
                            <cell>216</cell>
                            <cell>400</cell>
                            <cell>253</cell>
                            <cell>397</cell>
                            <cell>246</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Chamb'g, S W</cell>
                            <cell>297</cell>
                            <cell>275</cell>
                            <cell>285</cell>
                            <cell>281</cell>
                            <cell>299</cell>
                            <cell>272</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Concord</cell>
                            <cell>29</cell>
                            <cell>105</cell>
                            <cell>30</cell>
                            <cell>108</cell>
                            <cell>34</cell>
                            <cell>109</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Dry Run</cell>
                            <cell>121</cell>
                            <cell>99</cell>
                            <cell>117</cell>
                            <cell>118</cell>
                            <cell>122</cell>
                            <cell>110</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Fayetteville</cell>
                            <cell>284</cell>
                            <cell>224</cell>
                            <cell>252</cell>
                            <cell>235</cell>
                            <cell>255</cell>
                            <cell>241</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Greenvillage</cell>
                            <cell>215</cell>
                            <cell>112</cell>
                            <cell>213</cell>
                            <cell>113</cell>
                            <cell>214</cell>
                            <cell>115</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Guilford</cell>
                            <cell>207</cell>
                            <cell>224</cell>
                            <cell>220</cell>
                            <cell>212</cell>
                            <cell>225</cell>
                            <cell>205</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Hamilton</cell>
                            <cell>128</cell>
                            <cell>173</cell>
                            <cell>128</cell>
                            <cell>186</cell>
                            <cell>128</cell>
                            <cell>174</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Letterkenny</cell>
                            <cell>165</cell>
                            <cell>249</cell>
                            <cell>173</cell>
                            <cell>240</cell>
                            <cell>181</cell>
                            <cell>235</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Lurgan</cell>
                            <cell>112</cell>
                            <cell>147</cell>
                            <cell>99</cell>
                            <cell>153</cell>
                            <cell>100</cell>
                            <cell>153</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Loudon</cell>
                            <cell>93</cell>
                            <cell>113</cell>
                            <cell>95</cell>
                            <cell>131</cell>
                            <cell>97</cell>
                            <cell>130</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Metal</cell>
                            <cell>166</cell>
                            <cell>98</cell>
                            <cell>146</cell>
                            <cell>120</cell>
                            <cell>157</cell>
                            <cell>114</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Montgomery</cell>
                            <cell>249</cell>
                            <cell>181</cell>
                            <cell>243</cell>
                            <cell>194</cell>
                            <cell>270</cell>
                            <cell>184</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Orrstown</cell>
                            <cell>80</cell>
                            <cell>149</cell>
                            <cell>88</cell>
                            <cell>150</cell>
                            <cell>94</cell>
                            <cell>145</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Peters</cell>
                            <cell>175</cell>
                            <cell>52</cell>
                            <cell>159</cell>
                            <cell>73</cell>
                            <cell>165</cell>
                            <cell>66</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Quincy</cell>
                            <cell>247</cell>
                            <cell>305</cell>
                            <cell>258</cell>
                            <cell>323</cell>
                            <cell>265</cell>
                            <cell>299</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Southampton</cell>
                            <cell>69</cell>
                            <cell>82</cell>
                            <cell>60</cell>
                            <cell>86</cell>
                            <cell>60</cell>
                            <cell>79</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Sulphur Spring</cell>
                            <cell>34</cell>
                            <cell>41</cell>
                            <cell>32</cell>
                            <cell>42</cell>
                            <cell>33</cell>
                            <cell>47</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>St. Thomas</cell>
                            <cell>167</cell>
                            <cell>227</cell>
                            <cell>166</cell>
                            <cell>225</cell>
                            <cell>168</cell>
                            <cell>231</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Washington</cell>
                            <cell>351</cell>
                            <cell>259</cell>
                            <cell>387</cell>
                            <cell>309</cell>
                            <cell>388</cell>
                            <cell>307</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Warren</cell>
                            <cell>61</cell>
                            <cell>56</cell>
                            <cell>59</cell>
                            <cell>61</cell>
                            <cell>59</cell>
                            <cell>65</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Welsh Run</cell>
                            <cell>135</cell>
                            <cell>178</cell>
                            <cell>141</cell>
                            <cell>148</cell>
                            <cell>157</cell>
                            <cell>147</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>4299</cell>
                            <cell>4106</cell>
                            <cell>4321</cell>
                            <cell>4278</cell>
                            <cell>4451</cell>
                            <cell>4171</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <p>Hartranft's maj., October, 43; Grant's maj., Nov., 280.</p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>No. of votes cast October, 1868</cell>
                            <cell>8,599</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>No. of votes cast November, 1868</cell>
                            <cell>8,622</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Increase in total vote</cell>
                            <cell>23</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Increase in Republican vote since October</cell>
                            <cell>130</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Decrease in Democratic vote since October</cell>
                            <cell>107</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper printed the results for the presidential election and election
                    for Auditor General in 1868, as well as the totals for the election for governor
                    in 1866.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fletcher</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lt. J. W. Fletcher was sworn in as Sheriff of Franklin County. He appointed
                    Sheriff Brown to serve as his deputy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The members of the Young Men's Christian Association have opened their
                    reading rooms to the public. They are well-stocked with religious and secular
                    journals. They also hold a daily prayer meeting in the building. Donations of
                    books, papers, and magazines are welcome. "The aim of this association is to
                    benefit the young men of the town, both mentally and spiritually, and to provide
                    a place for them to spend their leisure time, and improve their minds. Let all
                    friends of truth and christianity do all they can to encourage these young men
                    in their good work."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Gowan</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper reports that a "sad sight" met the eye of those near the
                    Democratic headquarters on Friday. The party removed "what was left of
                    Democracy," including half-burnt candles, transparencies, and pine benches. It
                    was all hauled away by "an American citizen of African descent." Janitor M'Gowan
                    tolled the bell at the Court House as the large transparency was removed. Crowds
                    on the streets cheered.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>I. O. G. T.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roney</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tolbert</ln>
                        <fn>William E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Linderman</ln>
                        <fn>Agnes</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>H. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burnes</ln>
                        <fn>Edward W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kirby</ln>
                        <fn>D. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoke</ln>
                        <fn>Harry E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunter</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vance</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flory</ln>
                        <fn>Hattie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dyson</ln>
                        <fn>Laura</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barber</ln>
                        <fn>Cartie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilcox</ln>
                        <fn>Edwin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>O'Bannon</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lodge Deputy W. S. Roney installed a number of officers for McMurray Lodge,
                    No. 119. I. O. G. T.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Appointments</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunter</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Townsend</ln>
                        <fn>D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sigler</ln>
                        <fn>G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beck</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>U. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A number of appointments were made at a recent session of the East
                    Pennsylvania Eldership of the Church of God. Rev. John Hunter, now stationed in
                    Chambersburg, was appointed to Carlisle. Rev. D. Townsend was appointed to
                    Chambersburg and Fayetteville; Rev. G. Sigler to Shippensburg; Rev. B. F. Beck
                    to Middletown; and Rev. U. L. Jones to Orrstown and Newburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Cumberland Valley Good Templars Convention will hold their semi-annual
                    session in Waynesboro on November 25th. Delegates from Franklin and surrounding
                    counties will attend.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Border Damages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that Franklin has advanced 1,504 war-damage claims;
                    Fulton, 127; Perry, 5; Bedford, 47; and Cumberland, 132. Adams will most likely
                    have 1,000, and York several hundred. The value of the claims falls between
                    $1,500,000 and $2,000,000.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woods</ln>
                        <fn>John F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamilton</ln>
                        <fn>Mary J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Howe</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John F. Woods and Miss Mary J. Hamilton, both of Roxbury, were married in
                    Greenvillage on November 1st by the Rev. W. Howe.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bosserman</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Joseph Bosserman died in Montgomery on November 2nd. He was 58 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grossman</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grossman</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Mary Grossman, wife of Michael Grossman, died near Welsh Run on
                    November 2nd. She was 62 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.11.11.04" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

    </paperBody>
</hwp>
