
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1868/pa.fr.fr.1868.01.08">

    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>

        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>05/08/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>

        <address>
<city>Chambersburg</city>
<county>Franklin</county>
<state>Pennsylvania</state>
</address>

        <date n="1868-01-08">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day>08</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
    </header>

    <paperBody>

        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.01.08.01" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.01.08.02" exists="no">

            <div type="e">

                <column>02</column>
                <head>Principles vs. Expediency and Availability</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>When a servant is willing and able to execute the commands of his master, it
                        is immaterial what his political or religious belief may be, but when he
                        attempts to usurp the place of the master, and to put in force his own
                        peculiar views, it is altogether time he was discharged from his office. If
                        the people of the United States had put in force, in the National family,
                        the rules which each one would not fail to enforce in his own affairs, the
                        public servant, who has made himself the Public's master and usurped the
                        functions of its representatives, would now be classed with Charles 1st of
                        England, and Louis the sixteenth of France. But the peoples' representatives
                        did not deem it expedient to impeach and punish the bold usurper--we cannot
                        but believe that a majority of them believed that he ought to be impeached
                        and that he deserved the extreme penalty of the law--and hence Andrew
                        Johnson continues to outrage public sentiment and common decency. The time
                        was when the Chief Magistrate of the nation regarded himself only as the
                        servant of the people, believed that he fulfilled his office when he
                        executed the will of the people as expressed through their representatives
                        in Congress. So long as the President held these modest views of his office,
                        it was not very material what his political faith was. The laws would be
                            <sic>excuted</sic> notwithstanding they did not exactly agree with <emph
                            rend="italic">his</emph> policy. But those halcyon days are of the past.
                        The complacent, self-confident individual who now holds and disgraces the
                        Presidential office deems himself the chief depository of wisdom. The
                        combined wisdom of Congress is foolishness compared with his profound
                        discernment. "My policy" is the only basis of reconstruction. While he does
                        not--because he dares not--directly prevent, he resorts to every expedient
                        to embarrass the execution of the reconstruction laws. When it suits his
                        purpose he is a stickler for the letter of the law. When it don't, he
                        construes liberally. In either case the concise and sententious Binckly,
                        with whom opinions are as plenty as blackberries, holds himself in readiness
                        to furnish the argument. Andrew Johnson has taught us the necessity of
                        consulting something besides expediency and availability in the selection of
                        a candidate for President. Devotion to these narrow views made him Vice
                        President, and accident made him President, behold the man and his deeds.
                        All true friends of Progress see now the error we committed then and do not
                        wish to repeat it. Certain results of the late contest are to be secured.
                        Too much blood was spilled; too much suffering endured; too much sorrow
                        brought upon the community, to permit those results to be lost through our
                        inaction or through our subserviency to such narrow policy as that of
                        expediency. There are certain progressive principles which the Republican
                        party originated long ago, they have been carried almost to fruition, shall
                        we go back upon them now? Shall we sacrifice them to preserve a party name?
                        Would it not be more manly to maintain them? aye! and carry them out to
                        their logical conclusions. We know that those principles are founded in
                        right and justice. We know that they will prevail in the end. Let us not
                        look for those whose only qualification is that they have--more through
                        chance than any thing else--the strength necessary to elect them. But rather
                        search for those who when elected will carry out those principles which are
                        best fitted to promote the welfare of the people. Let us put no such mean
                        interrogatories as, "Is he available?" "Is it expedient to adopt this
                        measure or that?" But rather, "Is he fit?" "Do the principles which we wish
                        carried out live in him?" "Are the measures just and right?"</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors severely criticize Andrew Johnson and his policies and call him
                    a usurper for ignoring the will of the electorate. They use Johnson as an
                    example to show what happens when candidates are chosen because of expediency
                    instead of upholding party principles. The editors also urge Republicans to
                    select candidates for future elections based on their desire to carry out the
                    party's progressive vision.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="l">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>The Chambersburg Woolen Mills</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">To the Editors of the Franklin Repository</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>I have just been reading a fly-sheet, or circular, giving a statement of the
                        past and present condition of the Chambersburg Woolen Mill. That circular
                        has been prepared, I suppose, by the authorized officers of the mill. Its
                        statements are candid and fair, as all must admit who read it without
                        prejudice or ill-will. Its appeal also to the large and small capitalists of
                        the town, to aid in the undertaking is enforced by arguments as clear, as
                        they are unanswerable. According to their statement, the company has done
                        well for the first year. It could not be expected that the mill would clear
                        itself the first twelve months. If it has done without going backward the
                        past year, it has beat a great many of its old competitors. But so far from
                        losing, we believe that it has made handsome gains. For the wealthy men of
                        Chambersburg to let the mill and its dependants suffer, when they can so
                        easily avert it, would be sheer madness on their part. No sensible man needs
                        to be informed, that a business to be successful, must be supported in a
                        tangible form. "Money is the soul of trade." If a town like Chambersburg,
                        with a population of seven or eight thousand inhabitants cannot run <emph
                            rend="italic">one</emph> mill without running it ashore, what shall we
                        say of those towns in New England, whose population are less than this,
                        running eight to twelve mills. The growth of New England is mainly due to
                        its manufacturing interests. Without its Woolen and Cotton Manufactories, it
                        would be but a barren waste. On the other hand, Chambersburg is surrounded
                        by rich agricultural lands, such as are not found in New England, only in
                        isolated places. This is very much in our favor, as it enables all classes
                        of people here to live at a much cheaper rate. Coal also is much cheaper
                        here than in New England, and coal is an important item to a manufacturer.
                        Chambersburg too has as good a chance as New England in procuring skillful
                        hands to operate its manufacturing establishments. Notwithstanding these
                        great advantages as a manufacturing centre, our monied men seem to have more
                        faith in Government Bonds. By the way, these government securities are the
                        ruination of trade. This high rate of interest causes the capitalist to
                        invest his money in them, and let precarious business slide. This is an
                        injury to the laboring class, who are dependent for a living upon their
                        honest labor. It is labor too that has to create the wealth wherewith to pay
                        this high rate of interest. The national debt--or at least a large part of
                        it--ought to be allowed to lay over a few generations like the national debt
                        of England, so that we may be better able to compete with that nation in
                        manufacturing. It is all nonsense to attempt to run a manufacturing race
                        with England, with the heavy load of debt we are now carrying. We must lay
                        some of it down, if we mean to run lightly and win. But let us return to
                        Chambersburg and its woolen interests once more, as it is only in its
                        infancy, and needs our fostering care; while the government will take care
                        of itself, and stand for ages, when we are mouldering in the dust. The town
                        of Chambersburg has outgrown itself in the matter of stores, with but little
                        outside population to sustain them. Foster and encourage manufacturing and
                        the town will grow and prosper, and the storekeepers will be benefited
                        thereby. The success of this our first enterprise in the manufacture of
                        woolen fancy cloths ought to interest of all. To let it go down for want of
                        funds, would demoralize in a measure the whole town, and would prove a
                        damper to all future enterprises of a like character. Some contend that the
                        big fish will eat the little ones up. Let us hear how they will do it. So
                        far as that is concerned, I cannot see how the large stockholder can
                        appropriate what belongs to the small stockholder, any more than the captain
                        of a ship can rob a ship's passenger of his trunk</p>
                    <p> LOOKER ON.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"Looker On" writes to comment on the state of manufacturing in
                    Chambersburg, specifically the Chambersburg Woolen Mill. He asserts that the
                    mill did well for itself in its first year and urges more investment in such
                    mills in the future. "Looker On" also calls on investors to steer away from
                    government bonds and invest more in local manufacturing.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.01.08.03" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Directory</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The following is a directory of the officers of Franklin county and the
                        Borough of Chambersburg, of the ministers of Chambersburg, and the time of
                        meeting of the different associations:</p>
                    <p> FRANKLIN COUNTY OFFICERS.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">President Judge</emph>--Hon. Alex King.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Associate Judges</emph>--Jas. Ferguson, Jno. Armstrong
                        Esqs.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Prothonotory</emph>--William H. M'Dowell.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Register and Recorder</emph>--Henry Strickler.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Deputy Register and Recorder</emph>--Henry S. Shade.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">District Attorney</emph>--W.S. Stenger.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Clerk of Courts</emph>--Thaddeus M. Mahon.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Treasurer</emph>--George W. Skinner.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Sheriff</emph>--John Doebler.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Deputy Sheriff</emph>--J.W. Fletcher.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Surveyor</emph>--Emanuel Kuhn.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Jury Commissioners</emph>--Addison Imbrie, Wm. Boyd.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Commissioners</emph>--Daniel Skinner, Jonas C. Palmer,
                        Wm. Shenafield. <emph rend="italic">Clerk</emph>--Geo. Foreman. <emph
                            rend="italic">Counsel</emph>--Wm S. Everett, Esq.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Directors of Poor</emph>--James H. Clayton, M.W.
                        Heintzelman, John Gillan, Jr. <emph rend="italic">Steward</emph>--John
                        Ditzler, <emph rend="italic">Counsel and Clerk</emph>--E.J. Bonebrake. <emph
                            rend="italic">Treasurer</emph>--Charles Gelwicks. <emph rend="italic"
                            >Physician</emph>--Dr. J.C. Richards</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Physician to Jail</emph>--Dr. John Lambert.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Auditors</emph>--M. Martin, Samuel W. Nevin, Samuel
                        Myers.</p>
                    <p> BOROUGH OFFICERS.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Burgess</emph>--Wm. S. Everett.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Council</emph>--George Palmer, Samuel F. Greenawalt, Adam
                        Hamilton, Benjamin Rhodes, Allen C. M'Grath, B. Latrobe Maurer. <emph
                            rend="italic">Treasurer</emph>--D.S. Fahnestock. <emph rend="italic"
                            >Clerk</emph>--John A. Seiders.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Street Commissioner</emph>--John Forbes.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Constable</emph>--Michael W. Houser.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">School Directors</emph>--James Hamilton, J.S. Nixon, J.N.
                        Snider, S.M. Shillito, J. Henninger, Calvin Gilbert. <emph rend="italic"
                            >President</emph>--S.M. Shillito. <emph rend="italic"
                        >Tresurer</emph>--Jacob Henninger.</p>
                    <p> MINISTERS.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Presbyterian</emph>--Rev. J.A. Crawford.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">First Lutheran</emph>--Rev. Irving Magee.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Second Lutheran</emph>--Rev. G. Roth.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">First German Reformed</emph>--Rev. P.S. Davis.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Second German Reformed</emph>--Rev. Dr. Schneck.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Methodist</emph>--Rev. S.H.C. Smith.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">United Brethren</emph>--Rev. H.Y. Hummelbaugh.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Church of God</emph>--Rev. Mr. Hunter.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Roman Catholic</emph>--Rev. Mr. Cox.</p>
                    <p> ASSOCIATIONS.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">George Washington Lodge</emph>, No. 143, A.Y.M., meets on
                        the first Friday on or before full moon, in the Masonic Hall, Second street.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Olive Branch Encampment</emph>, No. 13, I.O.O.F., meets
                        on the 2d and 4th Monday evenings of each mouth, in the third story of the
                        Repository Building.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Columbus Lodge</emph>, No. 75, I.O.O.F., meets every
                        Thursday evening in the third story of the Repository Hall.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Chambersburg Lodge</emph>, No. 175, I.O.O.F., meets every
                        Tuesday evening, in the third story of the Repository Hall.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Falling Spring Division</emph>, No. 122, Sons of
                        Temperance, meets every Friday evening, in the third story of Mr. Ludwig's
                        Building, N.W. corner of the Diamond.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">M'Murray Lodge</emph>, No. 119, I.O.G.T., meets every
                        Monday evening in the third story of Mr. Ludwig's building, North-west
                        corner of the Diamond. <emph rend="italic">Degree Lodge</emph> meets on the
                        1st and 3d Wednesday evenings of each month in same place.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Post No. 24, Grand Army of the Republic</emph>, holds its
                        meetings on the 1st and 3d Wednesday evenings of each month, in the third
                        story of Mr. J.N. Snider's building on the Diamond.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn>Alex</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ferguson</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armstrong</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Dowell</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strickler</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shade</ln>
                        <fn>Henry S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stenger</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mahon</ln>
                        <fn>Thaddeus M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doebler</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fletcher</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kuhn</ln>
                        <fn>Emanuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imbrie</ln>
                        <fn>Addison</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyd</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palmer</ln>
                        <fn>Jonas C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foreman</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Everett</ln>
                        <fn>William S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clayton</ln>
                        <fn>James H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heintzelman</ln>
                        <fn>M. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillan</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ditzler</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bonebrake</ln>
                        <fn>E. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gelwicks</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richards</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lambert</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nevin</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Everett</ln>
                        <fn>William S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palmer</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greenawalt</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamilton</ln>
                        <fn>Adam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rhodes</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Grath</ln>
                        <fn>Allen C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maurer</ln>
                        <fn>B. Latrobe</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fahnestock</ln>
                        <fn>D. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seiders</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Forbes</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houser</ln>
                        <fn>Michael W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamilton</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nixon</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snider</ln>
                        <fn>J. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shillito</ln>
                        <fn>S. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henninger</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilbert</ln>
                        <fn>Calvin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Magee</ln>
                        <fn>Irving</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roth</ln>
                        <fn>G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>P. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneck</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>S. H. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hummelbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>H. Y.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunter</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cox</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper provides a very detailed directory of the names of men who hold
                    local office, ministers of various churches, and the meetings times and places
                    of various associations in town.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Rev. Henry Harbaugh, D. D., Dec'd</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The funeral of this eminent divine, whose death was announced in our last
                        issue, took place with proper christian solemnities, at Mercersburg, on
                        Tuesday, the 31st ult., at 11 o'clock, A.M. His death had brought together a
                        large number of prominent ministers and elders of the church to which he
                        belonged. Rev. John W. Nevin, D.D., President of Franklin and Marshall
                        College at Lancaster, conducted the services and delivered the discourse. He
                        was assisted by Drs. Gerhart, Schneck, Theodore Appel and others.</p>
                    <p>Dr. Harbaugh was born near Waynesboro', in this county, in October, 1817, and
                        was fifty years and two months old at the time of his decease. In acquiring
                        his early education he labored under great disadvantages. Receiving no aid
                        or sympathy from his friends he went to Ohio and taught school, studying at
                        night by the light of hickory-bark fires, to keep in advance of his pupils.
                        Pecuniary difficulties also compelled him to relinquish his college course
                        at the end of the Sophomore year, at which point he entered the Theological
                        Seminary. But such were his talents and his untiring industry that he soon
                        won distinction in the church, and was honored with the degree of Master of
                        Arts, by the institution in which he had previously studied. His Doctorate
                        was subsequently conferred by the authorities of Union College at
                        Schenectady, N.Y.</p>
                    <p>Dr. Harbaugh was undoubtedly a remarkable man. He was well known as a writer
                        and a theologian, not only in this country, but across the Atlantic. As an
                        author he was not only voluminous but eminently interesting and instructive.
                        Among the productions of his pen we may mention "The Future Life" in three
                        volumes, comprising "The Sainted Dead," "The Heavenly Recognition," and "The
                        Heavenly Home;" "The Birds of the Bible;" The Life of Schlatter;" "The Lives
                        of the Fathers of the Reformed Church of America"--two or three volumes;
                        "The True Glory of Woman," and several devotional books and tracts, all of
                        which are exciting a great and good influence. Besides, he contributed
                        largely to the leading periodicals of the country, published for thirteen
                        years a monthly for the young, and was, at the time of his death, editor of
                        the <emph rend="italic">Mercersburg Review</emph>. Some of his books have
                        passed through a great many editions, and their high character is such, that
                        the demand for them is not likely to be abated. We are glad to learn that
                        another volume of the "Lives of the Fathers," and his "Lectures on the
                        Heidelberg Catechism" are ready for the press.</p>
                    <p>At different periods of his life, Dr. Harbaugh was pastor of several
                        prominent congregations in the Reformed Church, and in 1863 he was elected
                        Professor of Didactic Theology in the Seminary at Mercersburg, which
                        position he filled with marked ability until the time of his death. Since
                        his acceptance of the professorship, he has been earnestly engaged in
                        preparing a system of Divinity, and although he was not spared to finish
                        this work, we hope that what he has done in this direction will yet be of
                        much advantage to the church.</p>
                    <p>Dr. Harbaugh was not only possessed of rare and versatile talents, but was
                        wonderfully industrious and became to be a man of vast acquirements. As a
                        public speaker it may perhaps be said that he never failed to interest those
                        whom he addressed, whether grave divines in the Synod or little children in
                        the Sunday School, and no man within the bounds of his denomination has
                        exercised a more permeating and widely extended influence. His earnest
                        christian character, and his genial nature made him a general favorite, and
                        he will live long in the hearts not only of his brethren in the ministry,
                        but of thousands of others to whom he has given words of instruction and
                        comfort. It will be hard to find any one fully able to take his place.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Extended obituary of the late Rev. Henry Harbaugh that highlights the
                    accomplishments of his early education, his publications, and the various
                    pastorships he headed in his lifetime. The paper asserts that he was an ideal
                    citizen and will be sorely missed by his fellow ministers and parishioners.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Extension of the Franklin Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The maps and profiles of the recent surveys of the two routes of extension
                        which are proposed to Williamsport, made by Maj. Edward Watts, Chief
                        Engineer, have been submitted to the proper authorities and approved. It now
                        remains to be determined which of the two contemplated routes shall be
                        adopted. The one extends from the point on the Franklin Railroad, at which
                        it crosses the State line, west of the Salisbury ridge, direct to Fenton
                        opposite Williamsport, a distance of nine miles, with a maximum grade of
                        49.10, and at a cost of about $314,000. The other route commences at the
                        termination of the Railroad in Washington street in Hagerstown, and running
                        along Walnut street to Antietam, where it makes a slight curve, and thence,
                        with the exception of one small deflection, in a perfect bee-line to Fenton,
                        a distance of six miles, with a maximum grade of 52.03, and at a total cost
                        of about $303,000. The Hagerstown route, it will be seen, is three miles
                        shorter than the State Line route; but in the length of road from
                        Williamsport to Harrisburg, the State Line route is three miles shorter. The
                        charter is already secured and the proper officer will at once call upon
                        property holders along the line, to arrange, justly and amicably, for the
                        passage of the road through their farms.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper comments on surveys of two possible routes for an extension of
                    the Franklin Railroad. The article provides details on the proposed routes and
                    ongoing negotiations with local property-holders to gain approval for building
                    the railroad through their farms.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Greencastle Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stover</ln>
                        <fn>David E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The directors of the First National Bank of Greencastle declare dividends
                    of five per cent for the last six months. The citizens of Greencastle met on
                    December 30th to organize a building association. Subscriptions are being
                    solicited. David E. Stover, a former proprietor of the Repository, left
                    Greencastle for California.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Sons of Temperance</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Culloh</ln>
                        <fn>G. W. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wanamaker</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henderson</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kirby</ln>
                        <fn>D. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ebert</ln>
                        <fn>Leonard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillan</ln>
                        <fn>James B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>W. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schlosser</ln>
                        <fn>N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Appenzeller</ln>
                        <fn>David K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Embich</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolf</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henninger</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hazelet</ln>
                        <fn>R. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kirby</ln>
                        <fn>D. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reilly</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Aughinbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Mollie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Forbes</ln>
                        <fn>Annie C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jarrett</ln>
                        <fn>Emma</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Oaks</ln>
                        <fn>Tillie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Falling Spring Division, No 122, Sons of Temperance, elected officers.
                    G. W. P. M'Culloh installed them on Friday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>New Turnpike</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An application has been made to construct a turnpike from Carns' blacksmith
                    shop on the Waynesboro, Greencastle, Mercersburg turnpike to a point near
                    Claylick by way of the Greentree Inn. It will be called the Welsh Run turnpike.
                    Subscriptions to stock are already being made.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Improvement</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Cumberland Valley Railroad company has built more facilities in
                    Chambersburg to handle increasing traffic on the road. They have recently
                    remodeled and enlarged the Robert Morris engine, and are working on the Col.
                    Gehr.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Week of Prayer</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Evangelical Alliance has designated the present week a "week of
                    prayer." Local churches will hold meetings throughout the week.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>A Row</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brooks</ln>
                        <fn>Sam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Several white and black men got in a fight Thursday evening on Second
                    Street in Chambersburg. Two white men attacked a black man named Sam Brooks.
                    Brooks fled and procured some friends who "in turn inflicted a severe
                    castigation on his white assailants."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Arrested</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoner</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Montgomery</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamman</ln>
                        <fn>Philip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Stoner was arrested for the shooting of David Montgomery in a bar
                    in Wolfstown. Stoner had eluded the law for several months, but was arrested in
                    Williamsport and brought to Chambersburg by Philip Hamman to stand trial .</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Free Lecture</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>S. H. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Rev. S. H. C. Smith will deliver the first in a series of lectures for
                    the benefit of the poor. Their is no entrance fee, but a collection will be
                    taken up. The paper encourages all to attend.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Enforce the Ordinance</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper complains about the condition of the town pavements. The editors
                    are especially upset about lax enforcement of the ordinance providing for the
                    clearing of snow after a storm.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Reduction in Price of Gas</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Chambersburg Gas Company announces that after the 1st of January gas
                    will cost $5 per 1,000 feet. A reduction of 40 cents per 1,000 feet will be made
                    from the final bill if payments are made at the secretary's office on or before
                    the 10th of each month.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Masonic</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bennett</ln>
                        <fn>Edward</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Rev. Edward Bennett has been appointed District Deputy Grand Master for
                    the counties of Franklin, Cumberland, Montour, and Berks.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Religious</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Magee</ln>
                        <fn>Irving</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Rev. Irving Magee, pastor-elect of the Lutheran Church, will preach an
                    introductory sermon on Sunday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pawling</ln>
                        <fn>Sue</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Johnson of Greencastle and Miss Sue Pawling of Mercersburg were
                    married in Mercersburg on December 24th by the Rev. J. Brown.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hager</ln>
                        <fn>S. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gray</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>S. S. Hager of Franklin and Miss Maggie J. Cook of Ohio were married in
                    Pittsburgh on December 12th by the Rev. W. S. Gray.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cleverstone</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baity</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stewart</ln>
                        <fn>O. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Daniel Cleverstone and Miss Sarah Baity, both of Greencastle, were married
                    on December 12th by the Rev. O. M. Stewart.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lynch</ln>
                        <fn>T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bohn</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stewart</ln>
                        <fn>O. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>T. Lynch of Maryland and Miss Mary E. Bohn of Franklin were married on
                    January 2nd by the Rev. O. M. Stewart.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gsell</ln>
                        <fn>Jonas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hassler</ln>
                        <fn>Hallie F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stelling</ln>
                        <fn>G. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jonas Gsell of Franklin and Miss Hallie F. Hassler of Dauphin were married
                    in Harrisburg on January 2nd by the Rev. G. F. Stelling.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Binnix</ln>
                        <fn>William C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grayham</ln>
                        <fn>Francis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Callendar</ln>
                        <fn>S. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William C. Binnix of Hagerstown and Miss Francis Grayham of Franklin were
                    married on December 24th by the Rev. S. N. Callendar.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Binkley</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stine</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Callendar</ln>
                        <fn>S. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>David Binkley and Miss Margaret Stine, both of Franklin, were married on
                    December 26th by the Rev. S. N. Callendar.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grayham</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hawbecker</ln>
                        <fn>Helen A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Callendar</ln>
                        <fn>S. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Robert Grayham and Mrs. Helen A. Hawbecker, both of Franklin, were married
                    on December 31st by the Rev. S. N. Callendar.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Curtis</ln>
                        <fn>Isadore</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wallach</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wightman</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Isadore Curtis and Miss Susan Wallach, both of Antrim, were married on
                    December 22nd by the Rev. J. W. Wightman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cradler</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palmer</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shaffer</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John W. Cradler of St. Thomas and Miss Mary Ann Palmer of Hamilton were
                    married on December 31st at the bride's residence by the Rev. J. Shaffer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fleagle</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Markey</ln>
                        <fn>Nancy C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George Fleagle and Miss Nancy C. Markey, both of Horse Valley, were married
                    on January 2nd by the Rev. J. B. Jones.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mills</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Mills died near Greencastle on January 1st. He was 57 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Henry Grove died in Shady Grove on December 27th. He was 45 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>A. Wilson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A. Wilson Skinner died near Dry Run on January 1st. He was 21 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ramsey</ln>
                        <fn>Sylvester</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ramsey</ln>
                        <fn>Brice</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sylvester Ramsey, son of Brice Ramsey, died near Dry Run on January 2nd. He
                    was 11 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Leberknight</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Leberknight</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Leberknight</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Margaret J. Leberknight, daughter of Daniel and Elizabeth Leberknight, died
                    in Hamilton on January 1st. She was 9 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bratten</ln>
                        <fn>James Huston</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. James Huston Bratten died in Chambersburg on January 3rd of chronic
                    bronchitis. He was 50 years old. "The deceased was well known to the people of
                    the town and country, having spent the greater portion of his life in our midst.
                    He was a man of noble and generous impulses, of great energy and perseverance of
                    character, and considerable ability as a public speaker. After his conversion,
                    which occurred more than twenty years ago, his whole aim in life seemed to be to
                    do good to his fellow-men. To this end he entered the Gospel Ministry, in which
                    calling he continued to labor for the salvation of souls, until he was disabled,
                    less than a year ago, by the disease which finally carried him to his grave. He
                    belonged to the United Brethren Church until about six years ago, when he left
                    that denomination and connected himself with the Lutheran Church, in whose
                    communion he died. His last charge was in Huntingdon county this State, where,
                    about a year ago, in going to one of his appointments through a violent storm,
                    he contracted a severe cold, which eventuated in his death. Thus did he
                    literally wear out his life in the service of his Master. He leaves a wife and
                    four children."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.01.08.04" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

    </paperBody>
</hwp>
