
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1868/pa.fr.fr.1868.01.29">

    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>

        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>05/04/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>

        <address>
<city>Chambersburg</city>
<county>Franklin</county>
<state>Pennsylvania</state>
</address>

        <date n="1868-01-29">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day>29</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
    </header>

    <paperBody>

        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.01.29.01" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.01.29.02" exists="no">

            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>WE believe it is recorded in the book of Ecclesiastes, as the saying of the
                        wisest of men, "woe to thee oh land when thy king is a child." What might
                        have been the proverb of the illustrious son of David had he lived in the
                        "living present" and contemplated the ruler of our land, we know not. The
                        first minds of the nation, after much thought upon the subject, enunciated a
                        plan for the reconstruction of the Southern States; it was meet that that
                        plan should be fairly tried before setting it aside. But Andrew Johnson,
                        with the self-confidence which comes of ignorance, forgetting that "in the
                        multitude of counsellors there is safety," joined hands with the enemies of
                        the Republic to defeat the plan of Congress, by substituting a plan of his
                        own, which, although it would have the effect to restore unrepentent rebels
                        to power--he supported with all the strength of his position. It is
                        unnecessary to rehearse the despicable means he resorted to to accomplish
                        his ends. They are well known to the people, who will, when his term of
                        office is ended, consign him to a state of obscurity only equalled by that
                        which surrounds the "Sage of Wheatland." But what has been the result of
                        this opposition to Congress? If the President, instead of assuming to
                        legislate for the nation, had kept within the bounds of his office, and duly
                        executed the laws which the proper legislative bodies had devised, then the
                        disaffected people of the South would have known how to conduct themselves,
                        and instead of indulging the false hope, of attaining by means of a false
                        Executive, what they had failed to attain by the appeal to arms, they would
                        have accepted the terms offered by the conquerors, and peace and prosperity
                        would now dwell with them instead of anarchy and want. Then Congress and the
                        people of the North, instead of exciting themselves over the question "how
                        to reconstruct the South," could give their attention to the devising of
                        means to pay off the national debt and to other measures <emph rend="italic"
                            >pro bono publico</emph>. Andrew Johnson is responsible for the
                        unsettled condition of things, North and South, and we would paraphrase the
                        saying of Solomon, "Woe to thee oh land when a fool is thy ruler."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper severely criticizes President Johnson for vetoing the
                    Reconstruction Acts recently passed by Congress. The editors assert that his
                    actions gave power back to unreconstructed rebels, which allowed anarchy to
                    prevail in the South. The veto also forced the North to waste time coming up
                    with new Reconstruction plans instead of turning their attention to northern
                    interests.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>EVERY day it approaches nearer certainty that Gen. Ulysses S. Grant will be
                        the next Chief Magistrate of the Republic. For a time the great party of
                        progress was pretty nearly equally divided between two candidates. Those who
                        would provide, to a perfect certainty, against a repetition of the fatal
                        error committed in the choice of a Vice President in '64, expressed
                        themselves in favor of one who during all his life has been identified with
                        every progressive movement and who now fills with honor the most honorable
                        office in the gift of the people. Without a shadow of a doubt Salmon P.
                        Chase would represent the principles of the Radical party. Yet eminently
                        fitted as he is for the Presidency, he would not at this time have been
                        spoken of as a candidate, had we not been so utterly deceived in the present
                        incumbent. All chivalric ideas have not yet vanquished. As of old, mankind
                        delight to honor the successful warrior. And had Grant been so entirely
                        committed to Radical principles as the Chief Justice, he would have been
                        named by the unanimous voice of the Radical party. Yet, had Andrew Johnson
                        never been called to scourge the nation, no Republican would ever have
                        thought of questioning the fitness of Grant. To be sure he has not, like
                        Chase, been all his life in the vanguard of the party of progress, still it
                        was under his leadership that the greatest forward movement was made. Like
                        his competitor, he has a record which he cannot ignore. Knowing well the
                        cost of that step forward, he will not easily be persuaded to make a
                        retrograde movement. With Grant for our standard bearer, we can enter the
                        coming campaign confident of success, not only in electing him, but also in
                        restoring harmony and prosperity permanently to our country. That this may
                        speedily be accomplished is the wish of every true patriot.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper endorses Ulysses S. Grant for the Republican nomination for
                    president. The editor admit that Salmon P. Chase would also make a good
                    candidate, but believe that Grant represents the best man in the present
                    circumstances and gives several reasons why.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper denounces General Hancock as "the idol of the rebels." The
                    editors criticize the New Orleans commander for his close relationship with
                    ex-Confederates.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.01.29.03" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Court Proceedings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The January term of the several Courts of Franklin county was convened on
                        Monday, the 20th, President Judge King and Associates Ferguson and Armstrong
                        on the bench. The following cases were disposed of:</p>
                    <p> QUARTER SESSIONS.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Jacob Helsey.--Larceny on oath of Joseph Wallach. A true bill.
                        Verdict not guilty.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Calvin Plowden.--Assault and Battery, on oath of Daniel Daily. A
                        true bill. Verdict not guilty. Each party to pay half of the costs.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Joseph Plowden.--Assault and Battery, on oath of Daniel Daily. A
                        true bill. Verdict not guilty. Each party to pay half of the costs.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Franklin Hollingsworth.--Perjury, on oath of John Walter. A true
                        bill. <sic>Defendand</sic> pleaded not guilty, verdict guilty. Sentenced to
                        pay a fine of $5, costs of prosecution and undergo an imprisonment in the
                        county jail for a period of six months.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Wm. and Peter Ackerman.--False Pretence, Conspiracy to Cheat, on
                        oath of Peter Snider. A true bill. Defendants pleaded not guilty, verdict
                        guilty of conspiracy. Sentenced each to pay a fine of $1 and costs of
                        prosecution, William to undergo an imprisonment of one year in the county
                        jail and Peter of one day.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Daniel Daily.--Surety of the Peace, on oath of Calvin Plowden. Bound
                        over in sum of $100 to keep the peace, and pay cost of prosecution.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Elias Butler--Keeping a Disorderly House, on oath of James Hunter. A
                        true bill. Defendant pleaded not guilty, verdict guilty. Sentenced to pay a
                        fine of $10 and cost of prosecution, and undergo imprisonment in county jail
                        for ten days.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. James Hunter.--Surety of the Peace, on oath of Elias Butler. Case
                        dismissed and defendant to pay costs.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. William Doyle and James Lane.--Riot and Assault and Battery, on oath
                        of Michael Fallen. A true bill. Defendants pleaded not guilty, verdict
                        guilty. Sentenced to each pay a fine of $5, cost of prosecution and undergo
                        an imprisonment in the county jail for a period of fourteen months.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. James Lane--Assault and Battery, on oath of Jacob Rockwell. A true
                        bill. Defendant pleaded guilty and submits to court.--Sentenced to pay a
                        fine of $1 and costs of prosecution.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Mary Pense--Surety of the Peace, on oath of Sophia Riddle. Case
                        dismissed by court, each party to pay half the costs.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Lewis Anderson.--Larceny, on oath M. Latus. A true bill. Defendant
                        pleaded guilty, and submits to court. Sentenced to pay a fine of $1, costs
                        of prosecution, and undergo an imprisonment in the Eastern Penitentiary for
                        a term of one year and three months.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. William Stoner.--Assault and Battery with intent to kill, on oath of
                        David Montgomery. A true bill. Defendant pleaded not guilty, verdict guilty.
                        Sentenced to pay a fine of $1, costs of prosecution, and undergo an
                        imprisonment in the Eastern Penitentiary for a term of six years and eight
                        months.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. John Plowden.--Assault and Battery on oath of Daniel Daily. A true
                        bill. Defendant pleaded not guilty, verdict guilty of assault. Sentenced to
                        pay a fine of $1 and costs of prosecution.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Calvin Plowden.--Larceny, on oath of Eli Gates. A true bill.
                        Defendant pleaded not guilty, verdict guilty. Sentenced to pay a fine of $1,
                        costs of prosecution, and undergo an imprisonment in the Eastern
                        Penitentiary for a period of one year and one month.</p>
                    <p> COMMON PLEAS</p>
                    <p>George Knepper, Sr., and George Knepper, Jr., vs. Addie L. Jurtz, Adm'rx of
                        James Reed, dec'd. Summons in Covenant. Verdict for plaintiff for $1,050.37.
                        Sharpe for plaintiff; Brewer for defendant.</p>
                    <p>A.H. Stump and G.H. Stump vs. Daniel S. Reisher and Samuel S. Reisher.
                        Summons Case. Verdict for plaintiffs for $125.20. M'Clure &amp; Stewart
                        for plaintiffs, Kimmell and Brewer for defendants.</p>
                    <p> LICENSES</p>
                    <p>Licenses to keep hotels were granted to Wm. C. M'Nulty, John Miller and Henry
                        Feltman, Chambersburg; William Bratton, Jr., St. Thomas; Wm. Bratton, Sr.,
                        St. Thomas township; Jacob L. Detrich, Greencastle; Samuel Staver and Henry
                        Kurtz, Roxbury; Henry Shiery, Funkstown; James Coffee and George E. Stewart,
                        Dry Run; David Guyer, Letterkenny township.</p>
                    <p>Licenses for restaurants were granted to Geo. Ditman and Frank Dengler,
                        Chambersburg; Philip Fendricks, Mercersburg; H.B. Blair, Montgomery
                        township; J.P. Miley, Quincy.</p>
                    <p>The application of James Snyder, Montgomery township, and Jacob Newcomer,
                        Greencastle, for licenses to keep restaurants were refused.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heisey</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wallach</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Plowden</ln>
                        <fn>Calvin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Daily</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Plowden</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Holingsworth</ln>
                        <fn>Franklin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walter</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ackerman</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ackerman</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Butler</ln>
                        <fn>Elias</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunter</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doyle</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lane</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rockwell</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pense</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Riddle</ln>
                        <fn>Sophia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Latus</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoner</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Montgomery</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Plowden</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gates</ln>
                        <fn>Eli</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Knepper</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf>Sr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Knepper</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kurtz</ln>
                        <fn>Addie L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stump</ln>
                        <fn>A. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stump</ln>
                        <fn>G. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Resiher</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reisher</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Clure</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stewart</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kimmell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewer</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Nulty</ln>
                        <fn>William C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Feltman</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bratton</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bratton</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf>Sr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Detrich</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Staver</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kurtz</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shiery</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coffee</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stewart</ln>
                        <fn>George E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guyer</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ditman</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dengler</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fendricks</ln>
                        <fn>Philip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blair</ln>
                        <fn>H. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miley</ln>
                        <fn>J. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newcomer</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper records the proceedings of the county courts and its verdicts.
                    The crimes include assaults, larcenies, sureties of the peace, etc., with
                    verdicts consisting of fine, court costs, and jail time. Also lists the names of
                    those who were granted licenses for restaurants and hotels.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Life Insurance</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper calls attention to the American Life Insurance Company and
                    stresses the importance of insurance.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Lectures for the Poor</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Cauley</ln>
                        <fn>I. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Magee</ln>
                        <fn>Irving</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneck</ln>
                        <fn>B. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nixon</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>I. H. M'Cauley will step in for the Rev. Irving Magee and deliver the
                    latest lecture in the series for the benefit of the poor. He will give a
                    previously-delivered lecture on "The Conquest of Spain by the Moors." So far,
                    the series has raised $50.74, including donations of $16.25 from M'Murray Lodge,
                    No. 119, I. O. G. T., and $10 from Falling Spring Division, No. 122, S. of T.
                    Dr. B. S. Schneck was elected president of the series and Jacob S. Nixon,
                    treasurer. The Rev. Mr. Hunter will lecture next.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Fire</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deiter</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reisher</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A fire did $2,000 worth of damage to the store room of John A. Deiter. The
                    fire also spread to the home of Daniel S. Reisher and did $133 worth of damage.
                    Insurance covered all losses.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Another Veteran Gone</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swann</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Swann, a well-known citizen of Franklin, died at the Alms House on
                    January 20th. He was 83 years old. He had practiced the trade of a tanner, and
                    was also active in Franklin in the notion business.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Annual Taxes</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The tax assessors of the United States have been ordered to begin work.
                    Income and special tax returns must be made by March 1st, or a fifty percent
                    penalty will be incurred. "The assessors are instructed to enforce the
                    provisions of the law in every case of delinquency, and it will be well for all
                    interested to give attention to making their returns within the time proscribed
                    by law."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Mill Burned</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foreman</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Frederick Foreman's three-story stone-framed grist mill on West
                    Conococheague Creek was destroyed by fire. Five thousand bushels of wheat were
                    lost, and the value of the machinery was estimated at $10,000.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Anniversary</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Magee</ln>
                        <fn>Irving</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Methodist Episcopal Church of Chambersburg will hold a missionary
                    anniversary celebration next Sunday. The Rev. D. H. Carroll of Carlisle will
                    preach. Anniversary celebrations for the Sabbath school will also be held. Other
                    speakers will include the Rev. J. A. Crawford of the Presbyterian Church and the
                    Rev. Irving Magee of the Lutheran Church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Important to Soldiers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The members of the following Pennsylvania regiments are entitled to $100
                    bounties: 26th, 27th, 28th, 29th, and 71st. Also, all those who enlisted between
                    April 15th and July 22nd, 1861, and who were discharged upon surgeon's
                    certificates of disability before collecting a bounty are eligible to claim one.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snively</ln>
                        <fn>A. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crooks</ln>
                        <fn>W. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Downey</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Fayetteville Excelsior Debating Society elected officers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Chaplain of the House</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Forney</ln>
                        <fn>C. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Rev. C. H. Forney, former pastor of Chambersburg's Baptist Church, was
                    appointed chaplain of the State House of Representatives. The editors declare it
                    a good choice.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gehr</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Daniel O. Gehr of Chambersburg was elected vice-president of the
                    Pennsylvania State Agricultural Society.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Resler</ln>
                        <fn>Winzen</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ruths</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Buhrman</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Winzen Resler and Miss Elizabeth Ruths, both of Waynesboro, were married on
                    December 25th by the Rev. A. Buhrman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bryant</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Row</ln>
                        <fn>Barbara A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Buhrman</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John W. Bryant and Miss Barbara A. Row were married on January 3rd by the
                    Rev. A. Buhrman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bender</ln>
                        <fn>Christian Wesley</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Poole</ln>
                        <fn>Laura S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crider</ln>
                        <fn>T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Christian Wesley Bender and Miss Laura S. Poole, both of Franklin, were
                    married on November 17th by the Rev. T. Crider.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Holestine</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lance</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crider</ln>
                        <fn>T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel Holestine and Miss Mary Ann Lance, both of Franklin, were married on
                    January 14th by the Rev. T. Crider.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fields</ln>
                        <fn>Russell</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guyer</ln>
                        <fn>Emma R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dyson</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Russell Fields and Miss Emma R. Guyer, both of Horse Valley, were married
                    on January 16th by the Rev. F. Dyson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Neff</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rinehart</ln>
                        <fn>Charlotte C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dyson</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel J. Neff and Miss Charlotte C. Rinehart, both of Franklin, were
                    married on January 24th by the Rev. F. Dyson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Cook died in Quincy on January 21st. He was 82 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.01.29.04" exists="no">


            <pageNote>Advertisements appear on this page.</pageNote>
        </page>

    </paperBody>
</hwp>
