
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1868/pa.fr.fr.1868.11.25">

    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>

        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>05/25/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>

        <address>
<city>Chambersburg</city>
<county>Franklin</county>
<state>Pennsylvania</state>
</address>

        <date n="1868-11-25">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="11">November</month>
            <day>25</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
    </header>

    <paperBody>

        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.11.25.01" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.11.25.02" exists="no">

            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Miss Wilson's Gift--Female Education</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The giving of thirty thousand dollars by Miss Wilson, of this county, to the
                        Carlisle Presbytery, in aid of the establishment at Chambersburg of a
                        college for the education of females, is a matter that deserves public
                        mention. It is certainly the greatest act of munificence within the
                        recollection of the present generation hereabouts, and it may be doubted
                        whether it has ever been equalled in this community. It will cause Miss
                        Wilson's name to be remembered in future years not only as a public
                        benefactor, but as one who had the wisdom to furnish substantial aid in a
                        branch of educational effort heretofore too much overlooked. This
                        benefaction with minor sums already subscribed and the aid that the several
                        churches are expected to furnish, ensures the establishment of a school at
                        this point, which for size and advantages in a few years will have scarcely
                        a rival. The management thus far has for the most part devolved upon the
                        Rev. Dr. Edwards, of Hagerstown, and we but express the sentiment of a large
                        majority of the public when we say that this profound scholar and Christian
                        gentleman should be pressed to assume the permanent control of the
                        institution.</p>
                    <p>The superior education of females has been too much neglected in the past,
                        and in large part committed to incompetent persons of the same sex, or to
                        unsuccessful clergyman. The teachers in the Wilson Female College, for such
                        we believe is to be its name, should be elected on account of their merit
                        and attainments solely, and not because they are needy or have failed in
                        some other employment. It were a pity that there should be any delay in this
                        institution assuming the high rank which it must ultimately fill, through
                        any mistaken charity in its outstart.</p>
                    <p>We think we see evidences that the public mind is undergoing a change upon
                        the subject of female education. We do not mean that the vagaries of those
                        who would unsex the female by introducing her into the excitement of the
                        exchange or the turmoil of politics are gaining adherents, but that there is
                        an increasing disposition to better qualify her for the discharge of her
                        appropriate duties. It has been too commonly supposed that educational
                        advantages of a high order are due to the male sex only, so that they may
                        become qualified to discharge the duties of some profession or employment in
                        life for <sic>whlch</sic> they are intended; whereas the real object of
                        education is to qualify one for everything and enable him to excel in
                        anything. So soon as men divest themselves of the idea of a necessary
                        connection between education and future employment, just so soon will they
                        be ready to admit that education is a good thing for the more retired and
                        less conspicuous female.</p>
                    <p>When moral defects do not intervene to defeat the illustration, it will be
                        found that those persons who have been liberally educated, that is educated
                        beyond the popularly supposed requirements of their adopted callings, have
                        been the most respected and successful in business, whether farmers,
                        artisans, tradesmen, or professional men. Education then has an elevating,
                        strengthening effect upon our mental and moral natures. It ennobles men and
                        women, not indeed to titular rank and dignity, but gives them other and
                        better conceptions of their duty to one another and themselves. It is the
                        foundation of all that is happy in the family and great in the state. If he
                        whose wisdom and eloquence achieved for every child the opportunity of
                        acquiring a rudimentary education, made his name deathless, what measure of
                        fame shall not be his who shall devise a plan by which all, the children of
                        the poor as well as the children of the rich, the daughters as well as the
                        sons, shall have the opportunity afforded them to master all human learning,
                        and to drink unchallenged at some perennial fountain of knowledge!</p>
                    <p>All effort on the part of the sterner sex to promote the cause of female
                        education must exert a reflex influence for good, commensurate with its
                        character and thoroughness. Woman is too closely interwoven with every human
                        relation not to make herself felt at all times, and everywhere. As mother,
                        daughter, sister, wife, she is potential. At every step from infancy to old
                        age she is with us and about us. From association with her we derive much of
                        our tastes, our inclinations and our habits. All <sic>inperceptibly</sic> to
                        herself and ourselves, she shapes our thoughts and moulds our character. It
                        is therefore the part of true wisdom to see that the education of females
                        shall no longer be merely superficial and ornamental, but substantial and
                        thorough. In thus seeking to elevate women we but promote our own happiness,
                        and advance the interests of the human race.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper gives its full support for the efforts of Miss Wilson to further
                    the cause of female education. The editor lists many reasons why educating young
                    women is not only right but necessary.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>War Against the Indians</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper applauds the government's aggressive Indian policy. "The Indians
                    must become peaceful or become a sacrifice to the inexorable law of progress,"
                    the editors maintain. No effort on the Indians' part can stop the railroads, and
                    settlers must be protected, no matter what idealistic Indian sympathizers might
                    think. "If they could be wholly annihilated, down to the last papoose, and the
                    last filthy vermin-nurturing squaw, it would make excellent food for romantic,
                    crack-brained poets who sing their praises a thousand miles away from the
                    dangerous swoop of the scalping knives, and save thousands of useful and
                    adventurous lives in the future."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Operations of the Ku Klux Klan</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper prints a report of recent Klan violence, and an accompanying
                    complaint from General Thomas that public opinion turns a blind eye to it.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.11.25.03" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Concert</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper urges citizens to attend the concert held by the Monumental
                    Association on Thanksgiving Day. The exhibition will feature the best musical
                    talent of Chambersburg and will benefit a good cause.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shyrock</ln>
                        <fn>S. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Curriden</ln>
                        <fn>E. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>S. S. Shyrock sold his large bookstore in Repository Hall to E. W.
                    Curriden. Shyrock's has been known for a long time as one of the best bookstores
                    in the state outside of Philadelphia, and Curriden promises to uphold that
                    reputation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duncan</ln>
                        <fn>C. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Housum</ln>
                        <fn>P. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Chambersburg's militia company will be known as the Housum Zouaves by
                    request of C. M. Duncan, who received the highest number of votes at the fair.
                    The name honors Col. P. B. Housum "the gallant soldier" who "layed down his life
                    in defense of the Old Flag during the rebellion...It is a fitting and honorable
                    tribute of respect to the memory of the gallant son of Chambersburg, and will we
                    think give universal satisfaction." The company has been invited to Greencastle
                    for Thanksgiving and is rapidly adding members.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>I. O. G. T.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shiveley</ln>
                        <fn>A. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greenawalt</ln>
                        <fn>D. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Black</ln>
                        <fn>Sadie J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Elroy</ln>
                        <fn>R. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>Nan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lego</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Disert</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boggs</ln>
                        <fn>Laura</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shiveley</ln>
                        <fn>Helen</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Black</ln>
                        <fn>Beckie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Black</ln>
                        <fn>Lib</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolf</ln>
                        <fn>L. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A. B. Shively installed officers for Gilmore Lodge No. 358, I. O. G. T. of
                    Fayetteville.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brotherton</ln>
                        <fn>D. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Maj. D. H. Brotherton of Waynesboro left Franklin for Fort Hays, Kansas.
                    Brotherton is an 1854 graduate of West Point, and has been "one of the most
                    faithful soldiers in the service" ever since. He has been actively campaigning
                    for ten years, and will likely take part in Sheridan's upcoming campaigns
                    against the Indians.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fletcher</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doebler</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lt. J. W. Fletcher took over as sheriff from the departing ex-sheriff
                    Doebler. Fletcher gave a lavish dinner and appointed ex-sheriff Brown his
                    deputy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chase</ln>
                        <fn>S. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The members of M'Murray Lodge, No. 119, I. O. G. T., will celebrate their
                    third anniversary on Friday. Music and addresses will entertain the public.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Lecture</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>James F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Rev. James F. Kennedy will deliver a lecture on "Blindness" at Union
                    Hall in Fayetteville on November 26th. The proceeds will benefit Fayetteville's
                    U.S. School. Admittance is 20 cents.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duncan</ln>
                        <fn>C. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Aughinbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Ed</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The flag that C. M. Duncan purchased for the Housum Zouaves is on exhibit
                    at the jewelry store of Ed Aughinbaugh. A formal presentation will be made to
                    the company at the Court House before they leave on their Thanksgiving Day visit
                    to Greencastle.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Low Rates</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Western Union Telegraph Company reduced their rates from Chambersburg
                    to Hagerstown, Greencastle, Gettysburg, and Shippensburg to 25 cents, and to
                    Newville, Carlisle, Mechanicsburg, and Harrisburg to 30 cents for 10 words.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Thanksgiving Sermon</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnes</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. S. Barnes of the Methodist Church will deliver a Thanksgiving day
                    sermon before a meeting of the German Reformed Church in Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Adams Express Company shipped 13,000 lbs of eggs and poultry from
                    Chambersburg on November 16th and 17th. Another 8,000 lbs of poultry was left in
                    charge of the company on Monday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deitz</ln>
                        <fn>George A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Six thousand pounds of Early Rose potatoes worth $60,000 and purchased by
                    George A. Deitz in New York and New Jersey arrived in Chambersburg on November
                    17th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A musical association named Kennedy's Glee Club has been organized in
                    Greencastle.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hummelaine</ln>
                        <fn>S. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wyant</ln>
                        <fn>S. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mowers</ln>
                        <fn>S. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>S. F. Hummelaine and Miss S. F. Wyant, both of Franklin, were married in
                    Chambersburg on September 16th by the Rev. S. A. Mowers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Michaels</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zarger</ln>
                        <fn>Anna M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dyson</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Joseph W. Michaels and Miss Anna M. Zarger, both of Chambersburg, were
                    married on November 19th by the Rev. F. Dyson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dosh</ln>
                        <fn>Michael W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lehman</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J. Keller</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Michael W. Dosh of Guilford and Miss Margaret Lehman of Hamilton were
                    married at the residence of Rev. J. Keller Miller on November 19th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Raffensperger</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richerson</ln>
                        <fn>Mary C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J. Keller</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. H. Raffensperger and Miss Mary C. Richerson were married on November
                    19th by the Rev. J. Keller Miller.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spoonhour</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Spoonhour died in Green township on October 28th. He was 84 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Mrs. Rosanna Spoonhour, wife of John Spoonhour, died on October 28th. She
                    was 74 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bushey</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Henry Bushey died in Montgomery on October 28th. He was 74 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.11.25.04" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

    </paperBody>
</hwp>
