
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1868/pa.fr.fr.1868.11.04">

    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>

        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>05/25/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>

        <address>
<city>Chambersburg</city>
<county>Franklin</county>
<state>Pennsylvania</state>
</address>

        <date n="1868-11-04">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="11">November</month>
            <day>04</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
    </header>

    <paperBody>

        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.11.04.01" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.11.04.02" exists="no">

            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Contest is Ended</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>To-day the struggle for the Presidency is over; the great political battle of
                        1868 is ended. The people have made it a leaf in history, and we doubt not
                        all persons rejoice that the reign of passion and prejudice has expired, and
                        that their power for evil is removed. Their baneful fruits may and will
                        reach into the future, for political hopes and hates do not die in a moment,
                        but the fuel which fed their flames has been cut off with the close of the
                        contest, and the vanquished will yield the victory to those who have won it.</p>
                    <p>The contest, for it was more than a controversy, was momentous in its import.
                        Perhaps never have the people battled through a National contest with such a
                        keen sense of its awful importance, with such mingled emotions of hope and
                        fear, as did they through the one just closed. This was apparent in every
                        stage of its progress. There was none of the volatile effervescent
                        enthusiasm which marked Presidential campaigns before the war. It meant
                        business, the gravest business to which a people who own their government
                        can betake themselves. Both parties were marked by a stern, unrelenting
                        determination to do something too deep, too serious to bubble over in
                        jubilees and frolicks. It was a conflict of ideas which, though old as the
                        world, have never ceased to strive for the mastery. It began in the cradle
                        of the earth and accompanied man in all his steps through the misty past,
                        from the Garden of Eden down to to-day, when we find him battling for the
                        Right on the American Continent. The essence of this warfare never changes,
                        though the weapons often do. It exists in the nature of things that truth
                        and error, right and wrong, liberty or freedom to do right and license or
                        freedom to do wrong, can never compromise. They can never lay down their
                        arms and live side by side. They are antagonistic and one or the other must
                        prevail. It is the history of a life. It is the history of society. It is
                        the history of the race written in ineffaceable characters of blood.</p>
                    <p>Our Presidential campaign was but one of the phases of this eternal conflict
                        of ideas. Hence its gravity. The supremacy of conflicting ideas was striven
                        for, hence there was no glorifying any man. Men were used but as the
                        exponents of these principles and save as they represented these they were
                        nothing. No man living is so eminently entitled to all the honor Americans
                        have to bestow as General Grant. His services to his country wholly obscured
                        those of General Harrison or Henry Clay. Yet the campaign of 1840 was a
                        national ovation to the man who had made successful warfare against the
                        Indians, and in 1844 thousands of strong men wept at the defeat of gallant
                        Harry of the West." They were the people's idols. But the people had no time
                        or taste to crown their hero's brow now. Men sank into insignificance and
                        man worship had no place in the colossal issues of this conflict. The
                        supporters of Gen. Grant fought for a nation's life and as a trusty and
                        tried leader in a similar conflict, but with different weapons, they chose
                        him as their leader again. We doubt not a similar process of reasoning, but
                        from very different premises, led the Democratic party to Horatio Seymour as
                        the true representative of the principles which they hoped through him to
                        see triumph.</p>
                    <p>We write this without any knowledge as to the result of the contest, but we
                        rejoice that it is over. Some things engendered by its heat and bitterness,
                        and not wholly on one side or the other, were well forgotten. Long political
                        excitement obscures the moral perceptions.--Men forget the holy relations of
                        the citizen to law and order, and are led step by step first to the approval
                        of crime in others and then to the commission of it themselves. As bad men
                        are found in the ranks of both political parties this is true of both. But
                        while true of individuals in both, on the side of the Democratic party there
                        was an organized disregard of law, a willingness to override law that it
                        might secure the reins of the Government. It began with the initial step of
                        that party in the campaign in the nomination of candidates who had declared
                        themselves in favor of snatching from the loyal people the dearly bought
                        fruits of the war, and the yielding up of the control of the party into the
                        hands of unrepentant rebels, and the voluntary declaration that through its
                        success they should secure all that they had hoped to win by the rebellion.
                        Thereby treason was made honorable, and those who had been forgetful alike
                        of patriotism, honor and country, had striven to rend and destroy their
                        Nationality, were encouraged in their treason and directed to look towards
                        the Democracy for its approval. From that moment the floodgate of their evil
                        passions was opened afresh, and the worst days of the dark ages were visited
                        upon the unprotected heads of Southern loyalists. Murder stalked through the
                        land in the broad light of day, and the lives of thousands were sacrificed
                        to the diabolical passions of these men encouraged by the Democratic party.
                        Devotion to country alone was the test by which these victims were tried.
                        Guilty of this and none were too lowly to escape them or too high in
                        position to find protection. The blood of the white man and of the negro, of
                        the proud and the despised race, was shed like water by this spirit of
                        lawlessness and rebellion invoked by the Democracy. These things were known
                        to all men who did not wilfully close their understandings during the
                        campaign, but they were never denounced by Democratic journals. The
                        management of the party was in the hands of traitors, and whether men
                        approved them or not, their tongues were tied or if they wagged at all, it
                        was to deny or to explain them away. We hope yesterday's setting sun closed
                        upon these scenes forever, and that, with the dawn of today begins an
                        endless era of peace and protection.</p>
                    <p>We believe that the people will honor themselves and prove their fitness for
                        the sacred duty of freemen by electing Gen. Grant, and hope to be able to so
                        announce it in this paper. But it is possible that we may be deceived, and
                        that the destiny of the country may be placed in the hands of Horatio
                        Seymour. If so, we would have all men, whatever their political belief,
                        prepare to yield a willing obedience to the laws, to cast off the soiled
                        garments of passion and bitterness and leave them behind on the field of
                        strife, and make common cause for the preservation of the government.</p>
                    <p>As its constitutional head, we should sustain Seymour in all things looking
                        to the safety and permanence of our institutions. Judging from the past, we
                        should differ form him in many of his measures and counsel against much of
                        his policy; but looking always to the careful observance of the law in its
                        spirit as our safety in person, property and liberty, we would labor to
                        strengthen rather than weaken his power so long as he strove to maintain the
                        unity of the government and root out treason from the land.</p>
                    <p>The same is equally the duty of our opponents if Gen. Grant becomes our Chief
                        Magistrate in conformity with the laws. Let them not forget that bitter
                        hostility to his election and extreme opposition to the policy of the party
                        which placed him in power, can justify no open or covert measures to defeat
                        the government in its efforts to restore a united and happy people.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor expresses relief that the presidential contest is over. He
                    admitted that wrongdoing was done by both sides but still insisted most of the
                    immoral acts were done by the Democrats. No matter what the outcome, he calls on
                    both parties to fully support whoever wins the election as long as that
                    candidate supported loyal men and denounced traitors.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Out of the Depths We Cry Unto You</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We condole with the <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph>. From the deep valley
                        of humiliation and despair comes a voice of wailing. It is the voice of the
                            <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph>. It feels badly and refuses to be
                        comforted. The <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> cried out to the people, it
                        said, in a voice of warning, but the obstinate people thought it a voice of
                        mockery and fled from it. It appealed to them but they refused to hear, and
                        gave it only disappointment for its appeals. Verily it is a journal of
                        sorrow and acquainted with grief. It piped and they refused to dance; it
                        wept and they mourned not; it gave them here a little and there a little,
                        but not of truth, but the ignorant people turned a deaf ear to the sapient
                            <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> and voted just as it didn't want them
                        to vote.</p>
                    <p>O you foolish people, and slow to believe. You have eyes, but the <emph
                            rend="italic">Spirit's</emph> loveliness you see not; you have ears, but
                        the <emph rend="italic">Spirit's</emph> counsel you hear not; you have
                        understandings, but the force of the <emph rend="italic">Spirit's</emph>
                        arguments you perceive not; you have ballots, but the <emph rend="italic"
                            >Spirit's</emph> ticket you vote not. Therefore is the <emph
                            rend="italic">Spirit</emph> sad. When human beings become very sick and
                        disgusted with life they wish to die. Why cannot this animal, so full of
                        grief, its feelings so plowed and harrowed with despair at the awful images
                        of the future which dwell in its imagination, give up the ghost and be at
                        rest? Beside, this would be an apposite moment to shuffle off, we almost
                        said its <emph rend="italic">coil</emph>, when thousands of mourners weep
                        around the lifeless remains of Copperheadism. It could almost flatter itself
                        into the belief that some of this weeping and wailing was at its own taking
                        off. It might even derive some consolation from its own obsequies. But no.
                        It won't die. With its brains and its bottom knocked clean out of it by the
                        October elections, it confirms the truth of the tenacity of life peculiar to
                        its race. It still retains its wind, and so long as this lasts its
                        monotonous, croning cry will be heard, and the burdent of that cry is the
                        "nigger." Like water to a mad dog, the "nigger" always throws the <emph
                            rend="italic">Spirit</emph> into a spasm. The one is just as harmless as
                        the other, and the effect of the one just as unaccountable as the effect of
                        the other.</p>
                    <p>The <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> asks, "Do the Republicans of
                        Pennsylvania think that because the negro does not vote in this State he
                        does not stand upon terms of equality with them?" If the <emph rend="italic"
                            >Spirit</emph> would do more listening and less howling we would say we
                        rather think they do. If the <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> says the
                        negroes <emph rend="italic">do</emph> stand on an equality with them, we
                        suppose as a fair and candid <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> it would not
                        object to exchanging its rights in Pennsylvania with some intelligent negro,
                        especially as by its own position it could not be damaged thereby. The proof
                        of the pudding, &amp;c., you know. If the <emph rend="italic"
                        >Spirit</emph> means social equality why then of course we could not ask it
                        to make the exchange without first consulting the negro.</p>
                    <p>Before beginning the next sentence the <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> must
                        have taken a nip of hasheesh, which is said to intensify the imagination,
                        for its says:</p>
                    <lb/>

                    <p>"True, he does not elbow them at their voting places. He does not spread his
                        perfume around their polls. His ivories no not shine like a polished steel
                        trap through the window where their ballots are taken in . But in those
                        places where the destinies of the nation are decided he meets them on terms
                        of equality and speaks in a voice as potential as theirs.</p>
                    <p>"There will be Senators in the United States Senate on the fourth of march
                        next, who were elected by the negro members of the Legislature of Southern
                        States. There will be members of the House who were elected by the direct
                        votes of negroes at the ballot box. Each Senator thus elected by negroes in
                        the Legislature, and each member thus elected by negroes at the polls, will
                        have a voice and a vote equal to each Senator and each member elected by the
                        white people of Pennsylvania.</p>
                    <p>"To this position of political equality with the intelligent white men of the
                        North have the ignorant negroes of the South <sic>boen</sic> elevated by the
                        reconstruction policy of the Radicals. Every Northern man who votes for
                        Grant votes to weigh a Southern negro in the scale against himself.--And
                        what is worse, he gives the negro a chance to out-weigh him."</p>
                    <p>"Many Republicans look upon this elevation of the Southern negroes merely as
                        a deserved degradation of the Rebels. They overlook the fact that it is also
                        degradation of the white people of the North. We confess our fear that they
                        will continue to look at it in a wrong light, and only awake to a true view
                        of it when they find Negro Equality <sic>fastenned</sic> upon the country
                        beyond their power to shake it off. Negro Equality did we say? Let us say
                        Negro Superiority, that is what it amounts to when a few thousand Florida
                        negroes can stifle the voice of three million white Pennsylvanians in the
                        United States Senate.</p>
                    <p>"All who are in favor of Negro Superiority will vote for Grant; and let no
                        one who votes for Grant forget <emph rend="italic">what</emph> he is voting
                        for."</p>
                    <lb/>

                    <p>We are sorely tempted just here to say a word or two in defence of the
                        "ignorant negroes of the South" whose political equality with the
                        "intelligent white men of the North" has so agitated the fountains of the
                            <emph rend="italic">Spirit's</emph> little soul; but we abstain. We
                        began by condoling with the <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> and we mean to
                        do so to the end. Who so hard hearted as to turn a deaf ear to the panic
                        striken cry of the <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> when it is in momentary
                        dread of being put in the balance with a Southern negro, and what is worse
                        with a negro who is to have an even chance with itself, which, in the words
                        suggested by its fears, "gives the negro a chance to outweigh it?" Of course
                        it does. The <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> is the very minimum of light
                        weights, and it would be mere idle folly to set <emph rend="italic"
                        >it</emph> against a brawny cotton picker who learned to write the word
                        liberty with the point of his bayonet, and whose soul swelled with its
                        inspiration as he stood side by side with the best white blood of the land,
                        nobly fighting to preserve our freedom and secure his own. We earnestly
                        entreat the friends of the <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> to rescue it
                        from such a horrible dilemma. Alas! 'tis worse than a dilemma. 'Tis the
                        demon of Equality which haunts the <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> in its
                        dreams. Why there will soon be Senators in the United States Senate elected
                        by negro members of Legislatures of Southern States. There will be members
                        of the House who were elected by the direct votes of negroes at the
                        ballot-box, and, says the <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph>, these Senators
                        and Members will each have a full vote and a voice just like the Senators
                        and Members elected by the white people of Pennsylvania; they will be <emph
                            rend="italic">equal</emph> to them. This <emph rend="italic"
                        >equal</emph> vote and voice of white Senators and white Representatives
                        from the South is evidently all wrong. It seems the <emph rend="italic"
                            >Spirit</emph> favors nothing that is equal politically except taxation.
                        But then taxation does not give the "ignorant negro" a chance to outweigh
                        the "intelligent" <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph>. Therefore equal
                        taxation is right. Just what fraction of a vote and a voice these Southern
                        Senators and Members should have we are not informed, but however little, if
                        it be necessary to protect the "intelligent whites" against the superiority
                        of the "ignorant negroes," let them have just that little. If it degrades
                        the white people of the North to do justice to their fellow man whom they
                        have rendered poor, ignorant and helpless by slavery, then let them not do
                        him justice.</p>
                    <p>The <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> expresses its fears "that they (the
                        people) will continue to look at it in the wrong light." If it be the wrong
                        light to strike the chains from off the enslaved, to set the bondman free,
                        to elevate, civilize and christianize, to make them equal under the law, to
                        give them an equal start in the struggle of life, then we believe, in the
                        Providence of God, they will so see it, even though, as the <emph
                            rend="italic">Spirit</emph> dreads, it would result in negro
                        superiority. It can never degrade to do right. It always must degrade to do
                        wrong. The white people cannot make the negro their equal. They can, and we
                        confidently believe, as we believe that God is just, they will give him
                        equal rights. Beyond this his destiny is in his own hands. If his
                        intelligence, his virtue and integrity should equal those of the white race,
                        he will then be our equal. Should they surpass them he will be our superior,
                        and all the howling and raving of time serving demagogues, of which the
                            <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> is one, can no more prevent it than it
                        can countervail the law of gravity.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper gloats that voters still voted for Republicans despite all the
                    panicked warnings sent out by the Valley <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph>, the
                    local Democratic newspaper. The latter tried to scare voters with visions of
                    "negro superiority", which the editor finds ridiculous. He also defends the
                    Republicans' reconstruction plans.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Official Vote for Additional Law Judge</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper gives the official vote for additional law judge for the district
                    including Franklin. Franklin gave 4,353 votes to the Republican Rowe and 4,234
                    to the Democrat Baer. Overall, Rowe received 10,711 votes and Baer 10,419 votes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.11.04.03" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Court Proceedings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>There were no civil cases tried in court last week. The following criminal
                        cases were disposed of in the Quarter Sessions up to Friday noon, when court
                        adjourned until Monday next, the 9th inst:</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. John Wolff.--Wilful taking and carrying away of fruit, on oath of
                        Simon Bitner. A true bill. Defendant pleaded not guilty. Verdict not guilty,
                        and prosecutor to pay the costs.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Peter Plowden.--Assault and Battery, on oath of Martin Hoover. A
                        true bill. Defendant pleaded not guilty. Verdict guilty, and sentenced to
                        pay a fine of one cent and costs of prosecution.</p>
                    <p>Com vs. Wm. Hauce.--Larceny, on oath of Isaac Kuhn. Defendant pleaded guilty,
                        and sentenced to pay a fine of one cent and costs of prosecution, and
                        undergo an imprisonment in the Eastern Penitentiary for 1 year and 6 months.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Charles Jones--Assault and Battery, on oath of Peter Dorte. A true
                        bill. Defendant pleaded not guilty. Verdict guilty, and sentenced to pay a
                        fine of one cent and costs of prosecution.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Elijah W. Wallace.--Larceny, on oath of Jacob Shaffer. A true bill.
                        Defendant pleaded not guilty. Verdict, guilty. Sentenced to pay a fine of $1
                        and costs of prosecution, and undergo an imprisonment in the county jail for
                        12 months.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Columbus Green.--Larceny, on oath of W. N. Horner. A true bill.
                        Defendant pleaded not guilty. Verdict not guilty.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. David Overkeesh--Assault and Battery, on oath of Wm. M. Reed. A true
                        bill.--Defendant pleaded not guilty. Verdict, not guilty, and each party pay
                        half the costs.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Jacob Golden.--Obstructing Highway, on oath of George W. Kale. A
                        true bill. Defendant pleaded not guilty. Verdict, not guilty, and each party
                        pay half the costs.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. George Kyle, Jr.--Surety of the Peace, on oath of Hannah Holland.
                        Case heard and defendant sentenced to pay the costs.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs Peter Dorte.--Assault and Battery on oath of Charles Jones. Not a
                        true bill, and prosecutor to pay the costs.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Martin Hoover.--Assault and Battery, on oath of Peter Plowden. Not a
                        true bill, and prosecutor to pay the costs.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Isadore Stumbaugh--Assault, on oath of Brant Williams. Not a true
                        bill, and prosecutor to pay the costs.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Susan Buckner.--Assault, on oath of Peter Dorte. Not a true bill,
                        and prosecutor to pay the costs.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Elizabeth Williams.--Assault and Battery, on oath of Thomas
                        Williams. Not a true bill, and prosecutor to pay the costs.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Margaret Johnson.--Assault and Battery, on oath of Rebecca Robinson.
                        Not a true bill, and prosecutor to pay the costs.</p>
                    <p>Coms. vs. Rebecca Barnes.--Assault, on oath of Cambridge Norris. Not a true
                        bill and prosecutor to pay costs.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Robert Lane.--Assault and Battery, on oath of Cambridge Norris. Not
                        a true bill, and prosecutor to pay the costs.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Edward Harmon.--Assault and Battery, on oath of James M'Elhare. Not
                        a true bill and prosecutor to pay the costs.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolff</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Plowden</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoover</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hance</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kuhn</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dorte</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wallace</ln>
                        <fn>Elijah W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shaffer</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Green</ln>
                        <fn>Columbus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Overkeesh</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>William M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Golden</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kale</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kyle</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Holland</ln>
                        <fn>Hannah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Isadore</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Williams</ln>
                        <fn>Brant</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Buckner</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Williams</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Williams</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robinson</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnes</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Norris</ln>
                        <fn>Cambridge</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lane</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harmon</ln>
                        <fn>Edward</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper prints the business of the county court, mostly dealing with
                    criminal cases such as larceny and assault.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Inauguration of Dr. E. V. Gerheart</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gerheart</ln>
                        <fn>E. V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harbaugh</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nevin</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. Dr. E. V. Gerheart was installed in Mercersburg on October 26th as
                    Professor of Theology at the Seminary of the German Reformed Church. He replaces
                    the late Dr. Harbaugh. Rev. Dr. J. W. Nevin led the ceremonies and addressed the
                    crowd. "Dr. Gerheart who now takes his place at the head of the German Reformed
                    Church, though still comparatively a young man, has favorably impressed the
                    theological world. Several works from his pen, among others a treatise on the
                    system of Logic, have marked him a thinker of much clearness and logical force,
                    and we doubt not his association with the Theological Seminary will widen its
                    influence and infuse into it additional strength and vigor."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Monumental Association</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCulloh</ln>
                        <fn>A. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper reports that the Franklin County Monumental Association is
                    flourishing in its work. They will hold a concert in Repository Hall on
                    Thanksgiving that will showcase "the best musical talent of the town." The paper
                    calls for a large turnout to support the construction of a monument. The
                    organization will also hold a fair December 22-25. Contributions can be made to
                    A. H. McCulloh.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Franklin County Teacher Institute</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Franklin County Teacher's Institute will meet in Chambersburg beginning
                    on November 16th. Prominent instructors from around the country will attend.
                    "There can be no interest half so important to the community as that of
                    Education, for upon the success of this depends the correct solution of almost
                    every problem of our varied human life. The favorable character of Chambersburg
                    for hospitality is so well known that it is not necessary to suggest to its
                    citizens the propriety of opening their doors to the teachers during their brief
                    stay."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Latest News! Grant Triumphantly Elected! The Republic Saved! Treason Defeated!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper prints state election returns from around the country showing a
                    large victory for Grant.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Vote of Franklin County</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>
                                <emph rend="italic">Governor,'66</emph>
                            </cell>[covers 2 columns] <cell>
                                <emph rend="italic">Aud. Gen,'68</emph>
                            </cell>[covers 2 columns] <cell>
                                <emph rend="italic">President'68</emph>
                            </cell>[covers 2 columns] </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>Geary</cell>
                            <cell>Clymer</cell>
                            <cell>Hartranft</cell>
                            <cell>Boyle</cell>
                            <cell>Grant</cell>
                            <cell>Seymour</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Antrim</cell>
                            <cell>545</cell>
                            <cell>521</cell>
                            <cell>570</cell>
                            <cell>517</cell>
                            <cell>86</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Chamb'g, N W</cell>
                            <cell>379</cell>
                            <cell>216</cell>
                            <cell>400</cell>
                            <cell>253</cell>
                            <cell>150</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Chamb'g, S W</cell>
                            <cell>297</cell>
                            <cell>275</cell>
                            <cell>285</cell>
                            <cell>281</cell>
                            <cell>27</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Concord</cell>
                            <cell>29</cell>
                            <cell>105</cell>
                            <cell>30</cell>
                            <cell>108</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Dry Run</cell>
                            <cell>121</cell>
                            <cell>99</cell>
                            <cell>117</cell>
                            <cell>118</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Fayetteville</cell>
                            <cell>284</cell>
                            <cell>224</cell>
                            <cell>252</cell>
                            <cell>235</cell>
                            <cell>14</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Greenvillage</cell>
                            <cell>215</cell>
                            <cell>112</cell>
                            <cell>213</cell>
                            <cell>113</cell>
                            <cell>101</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Guilford</cell>
                            <cell>207</cell>
                            <cell>224</cell>
                            <cell>220</cell>
                            <cell>212</cell>
                            <cell>20</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Hamilton</cell>
                            <cell>128</cell>
                            <cell>173</cell>
                            <cell>128</cell>
                            <cell>186</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                            <cell>42</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Letterkenny</cell>
                            <cell>165</cell>
                            <cell>249</cell>
                            <cell>173</cell>
                            <cell>240</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Lurgan</cell>
                            <cell>112</cell>
                            <cell>117</cell>
                            <cell>99</cell>
                            <cell>100</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Loudon</cell>
                            <cell>93</cell>
                            <cell>113</cell>
                            <cell>95</cell>
                            <cell>131</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Metal</cell>
                            <cell>166</cell>
                            <cell>98</cell>
                            <cell>146</cell>
                            <cell>120</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Montgomery</cell>
                            <cell>249</cell>
                            <cell>181</cell>
                            <cell>243</cell>
                            <cell>194</cell>
                            <cell>90</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Orrstown</cell>
                            <cell>80</cell>
                            <cell>149</cell>
                            <cell>88</cell>
                            <cell>150</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Peters</cell>
                            <cell>175</cell>
                            <cell>52</cell>
                            <cell>159</cell>
                            <cell>73</cell>
                            <cell>99</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Quincy</cell>
                            <cell>247</cell>
                            <cell>305</cell>
                            <cell>258</cell>
                            <cell>323</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                            <cell>34</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Southampton</cell>
                            <cell>69</cell>
                            <cell>82</cell>
                            <cell>60</cell>
                            <cell>86</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                            <cell>20</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Sulphur Spring</cell>
                            <cell>34</cell>
                            <cell>41</cell>
                            <cell>32</cell>
                            <cell>42</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>St. Thomas</cell>
                            <cell>167</cell>
                            <cell>227</cell>
                            <cell>166</cell>
                            <cell>225</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                            <cell>55</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Washington</cell>
                            <cell>351</cell>
                            <cell>259</cell>
                            <cell>387</cell>
                            <cell>309</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Warren</cell>
                            <cell>61</cell>
                            <cell>56</cell>
                            <cell>59</cell>
                            <cell>61</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Welsh Run</cell>
                            <cell>135</cell>
                            <cell>178</cell>
                            <cell>141</cell>
                            <cell>148</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>4299</cell>
                            <cell>4106</cell>
                            <cell>4321</cell>
                            <cell>4278</cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper prints the results of the vote of Franklin County in the most
                    recent election for auditor general and president, along with the 1866 results
                    for governor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heckman</ln>
                        <fn>David A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flack</ln>
                        <fn>Eliza A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J. Keller</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>David A. Heckman and Miss Eliza A. Flack, daughter of George Flack, both of
                    Hamilton, were married on October 27th at the residence of the bride's father by
                    the Rev. J. Keller Miller.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Monn</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Monn</ln>
                        <fn>Alfred G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Alfred G. Monn died suddenly on October 24th near Quincy at the residence
                    of his brother Andrew S. Monn. He was 31 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.11.04.04" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>


    </paperBody>
</hwp>
