
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1868/pa.fr.fr.1868.12.30">

    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>

        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>05/30/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>

        <address>
<city>Chambersburg</city>
<county>Franklin</county>
<state>Pennsylvania</state>
</address>

        <date n="1868-12-30">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="12">December</month>
            <day>30</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
    </header>

    <paperBody>

        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.12.30.01" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.12.30.02" exists="no">

            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>President Johnson's Proclamation of Universal Pardon</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>President Johnson having abused and lost the confidence and friendship of
                        those who put him in charge over the interests of the Nation, like the
                        unjust steward, sits down and writes quickly to its enemies that their debt
                        of treason has been forgiven. We suppose in this he too is wise in his day
                        and generation and finds it better to make friends of those who aspired to
                        be their country's murderers than to have no friends at all. On Christmas
                        day Mr. Johnson published to the few remaining unpardoned rebels "a full
                        pardon and amnesty for the offence of treason against the United States, or
                        of adhering to the enemies thereof in the late civil war, with a restoration
                        of all rights, privileges and immunities under the constitution, and the
                        laws made in pursuance thereof."</p>
                    <p>This proclamation, our readers will see, is made without reservation, and is
                        a message of unqualified pardon to such rebels as <sic>Jef Davis</sic>,
                        Breckenridge, Mason, Slidell, Benjamin, Jake Thompson and others who have
                        been wandering uneasily over Europe and anxiously longing to return to their
                        former homes in the South. They can now return whenever they please without
                        fear of molestation or harm.</p>
                    <p>The last act of the play, bloody tragedy in the beginning and unmitigated
                        comedy at the conclusion, is ended. If it be sublime to suppress an
                        indefensible and unwarranted rebellion which ravaged the whole land for four
                        years and made its streams run with innocent blood, and then unqualifiedly
                        pardon every rebel, the United States have made themselves sublime. We
                        believe a little judicious hanging would have been wiser and better for all
                        concerned, and that punishment should cease only in the proportion that
                        crime diminishes.</p>
                    <p>The proclamation of pardon and amnesty does not, however, put these rebels in
                        exactly the same relation to the government as are those who never needed
                        pardon. The President, fortunately, has not the power to do this, and can
                        only restore to the leaders of the rebellion their rights as private
                        citizens. It gives them no right to hold office of any sort, civil or
                        military, State or national. This can only be secured to them by a
                        two-thirds vote of each house of Congress.</p>
                    <p>The fourteenth constitutional amendment, section three, debars from any civil
                        or military office under the United States, or any State, any man who having
                        taken an oath as a civil or military officer of the United States, or as a
                        civil officer of any State, to support the constitution of the United
                        States, shall have participated in rebellion against the same, or given aid
                        or comfort to the enemy; but Congress may by a vote of two-thirds of each
                        house remove such disability. While these rebels can live in the country,
                        hereafter, and be as fully protected in all their restored rights as those
                        who never sinned, we are in no immediate danger of disgrace and shame by
                        seeing them elevated to high official position, as we would be but for the
                        constitutional power in the hands of Congress to prevent it.</p>
                    <p>There is nothing more that Mr. Johnson can do for his friends, the rebels.
                        During his whole administration he has served them well. But the sun of his
                        official life is low in the West, and the long and ghostly shadows it casts
                        admonish him that when it sinks beneath the horizon he too will disappear
                        forever. The dawn of better times is already lighting up the gates of the
                        East, and, in two short months, will bring light and peace and joy under the
                        wise and judicious and economical reign of Grant.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor is incensed that President Johnson granted sweeping pardons to
                    all former rebels. However, he takes comfort in knowing that the 14th amendment
                    prevents these former rebels from holding office.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Grant's Policy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper praises Grant for opposing further subsidies to the Pacific
                    Railroad, as well as other measures that tend "to deplete the public treasury
                    and to increase the already enormous public debt." These policies will help a
                    "country groaning under the weight of an enormous public debt, and plundered on
                    every hand by President Johnson's dishonest office holders."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.12.30.03" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Beloved Brethren in Christ of Every Land</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Evangelical Alliance invites Christians to observe a week of prayer in
                    January and publishes a list of daily topics.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Concert on Christmas Evening in the M. E. Church</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnes</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Noftsker</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A large crowd attended the Christmas Concert in the M. E. Church. The
                    building was decorated for the season, and a number of holiday tunes were
                    performed. The pastor, Rev. S. Barnes, presided. Prof. Noftsker directed the
                    music.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Horticultural Society</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Suesserott</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ruthrauff</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dickey</ln>
                        <fn>Seth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoke</ln>
                        <fn>Elias</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garver</ln>
                        <fn>Luther</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Engle</ln>
                        <fn>Enos B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nixon</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elder</ln>
                        <fn>J. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyle</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jenkins</ln>
                        <fn>T. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guthrie</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stouffer</ln>
                        <fn>Adam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>S. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brand</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cooper</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keefer</ln>
                        <fn>John P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deitz</ln>
                        <fn>George A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A number of citizens gathered at the Ryder Nursery Association to found a
                    Horticultural Society. The committee drafted a constitution and by-laws, and
                    elected officers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper unfortunately reports that the fair held in Repository Hall to
                    benefit the monumental association proved less successful than it had hoped. The
                    editors state that the exhibition of goods was excellent, and the ladies worked
                    unceasingly "for this noble object, and deserve great credit for their patriotic
                    efforts." The public, however, gave only lukewarm support, perhaps due to the
                    lack of money. About $600 was raised. The results demonstrated that
                    "Chambersburg is not able, without assistance from our towns and townships, to
                    build a monument for Franklin county soldiers, and unless our citizens in
                    Waynesboro, Greencastle, Mercersburg and elsewhere, lend a helping hand, our
                    attempt will be a failure."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Gough's Lecture</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>Corwin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Prof. Corwin Wilson will recite in the M. E. Church a lecture on temperance
                    delivered by John B. Gough in Exeter Hall, London. Wilson has recited the
                    lecture before, and the paper praises his delivery. Tickets are 25 cents, 15
                    cents for children.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Concert</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Union Sabbath School of Fayetteville will hold a concert on New Year's
                    Eve in Union Hall. The Brass Band will perform.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shumaker</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. J. H. Shumaker will deliver a lecture on "Manliness" in the Court House
                    on January 4th. The Young Men's Christian Association is sponsoring the event.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flack</ln>
                        <fn>W. Scott</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weagly</ln>
                        <fn>Emma V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Magee</ln>
                        <fn>Irving</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>W. Scott Flack and Miss Emma V. Weagly, both of Chambersburg, were married
                    at the residence of the bride's mother on December 22nd by the Rev. Irving
                    Magee.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gaibl</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hock</ln>
                        <fn>H. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Magee</ln>
                        <fn>Irving</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George W. Gaibl and Miss H. J. Hock were married on December 17th by the
                    Rev. Irving Magee.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spotts</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carothers</ln>
                        <fn>Minnie E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Magee</ln>
                        <fn>Irving</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William H. Spotts and Miss Minnie E. Carothers were married on December
                    24th by the Rev. Irving Magee.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Glass</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rinehart</ln>
                        <fn>Hannah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Magee</ln>
                        <fn>Irving</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Glass and Mrs. Hannah Rinehart were married on December 24th by the
                    Rev. Irving Magee.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Forbes</ln>
                        <fn>David S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rhodes</ln>
                        <fn>Mary A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houck</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>David S. Forbes and Miss Mary A. Rhodes, both of Chambersburg, were married
                    in Shippensburg on December 2nd by the Rev. W. H. Houck.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sollenberger</ln>
                        <fn>John S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rinehart</ln>
                        <fn>Martha M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tripner</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John S. Sollenberger and Miss Martha M. Rinehart, both of Franklin, were
                    married at Boyd's Hotel on December 22nd by the Rev. A. Tripner.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sollenberger</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brandt</ln>
                        <fn>Nancy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tripner</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Daniel W. Sollenberger and Miss Nancy Brandt, both of Franklin, were
                    married on December 24th at the residence of the bride by the Rev. A. Tripner.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stover</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snively</ln>
                        <fn>Annie E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snively</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bishop</ln>
                        <fn>J. Philip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Andrew S. Stover and Miss Annie E. Snively, daughter of Samuel Snively, all
                    of Greencastle, were married at the U. B. Parsonage in Mechanicsburg on December
                    22nd by the Rev. J. Philip Bishop.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schellhase</ln>
                        <fn>Conrad</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nickolas</ln>
                        <fn>Annie E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bishop</ln>
                        <fn>James M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Conrad Schellhase and Miss Annie E. Nickolas, both of Chambersburg, were
                    married on December 24th by the Rev. James M. Bishop.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Speer</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bechtel</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>P. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>David Speer of Martinsburg and Miss Rebecca V. Bechtel of Chambersburg were
                    married in Chambersburg on December 24th by the Rev. P. S. Davis.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kuhn</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swank</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie Louisa</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn>J. Smith</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Henry Kuhn and Miss Maggie Louisa Swank, all of Fannettsburg, were married
                    on December 23rd by the Rev. J. Smith Gordon.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Magee</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Vitty</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Vitty</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>West</ln>
                        <fn>W. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William A. Magee and Miss Maggie A. M'Vitty, daughter of Robert M'Vitty,
                    all of Amberson's Valley, were married on December 22nd by the Rev. W. A. West.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hengardner</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Tillie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dyson</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Hengardner and Mrs. Tillie Miller, both of Chambersburg, were married
                    on December 24th by the Rev. F. Dyson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shatzer</ln>
                        <fn>Hiram</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamilton</ln>
                        <fn>Alice R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamilton</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Creigh</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitstone</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Hiram Shatzer and Miss Alice R. Hamilton, daughter of Benjamin Hamilton,
                    were married in Mercersburg on December 22nd by the Rev. Thomas Creigh and J. H.
                    Whitstone.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitmer</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitmer</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Susan Whitmer, wife of Jacob S. Whitmer, died near Welsh Run on
                    December 18th. She was 39 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spencer</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Spencer died near Orrstown on December 23rd. He was 22 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.12.30.04" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

    </paperBody>
</hwp>
