
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1868/pa.fr.fr.1868.05.06">

    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>

        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>05/12/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>

        <address>
<city>Chambersburg</city>
<county>Franklin</county>
<state>Pennsylvania</state>
</address>

        <date n="1868-05-06">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day>06</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
    </header>

    <paperBody>

        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.05.06.01" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.05.06.02" exists="no">

            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>A. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>Jere</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>S. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A. K. McClure announces he will be retiring from editing the Franklin
                    Repository. Jere Cook and S. W. Hays will take over with his endorsement.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>From the above the readers of the REPOSITORY will perceive that the
                        undersigned have taken charge of its editorial department and its business.
                        Our introduction to the readers of the REPOSITORY, and the public generally,
                        having already been effected by the retiring Editor, we are spared the
                        annoyance of introducing ourselves, always an irksome duty.</p>

                    <p>The newspaper to which we succeed is itself, to all those familiar with its
                        long and interesting history, a sufficient guaranty as to the political
                        principles of Freedom and Justice, and the equal Rights of all Men, is to
                        say that it is no longer the REPOSITORY. However feeble then its advocacy of
                        these principles may in the future, as in the past, it will utter no
                        uncertain sound. Under the direction of HON. A. K. M'CLURE, the retiring
                        editor, this journal has attained a position for ability and political
                        sagacity which few others in the State have reached and none surpassed.
                        First of all to foresee the apostasy of Andrew Johnson, it fearlessly
                        predicted his betrayal of his party and his sacrifice of his principles,
                        boldly charged him with treasonable designs, and earnestly warned the loyal
                        people against him. We need but add, today, that in no single particular,
                        save in the degree of his political depravity, has it been mistaken. In view
                        of this past honorable and useful record, we assume the editorial chair with
                        genuine diffidence, and wherein we fail, as we sometimes must, beseech the
                        consideration and charity of its patrons and friends.</p>

                    <p>The Agricultural interests of this community are greater and more general
                        than all others. We propose, therefore, to give to Agriculture a prominence
                        in this journal commensurate with its interests. A department will always be
                        devoted to recording the experiments made in this branch of science
                        throughout the country, and original articles will appear from time to time
                        from the pens and gentlemen of practical experience and liberal education.
                        The result of the "Experimental Farm" of George A. Deitz, Esq., who has the
                        only private enterprise of the kind in the county, will be regularly
                        reported. This alone, to all those engaged in agricultural pursuits, will be
                        worth the subscription.</p>

                    <p>Hoping to retain the friendly relations which have heretofore existed between
                        this journal and our neighbor - the <emph rend="italics">Spirit</emph> - we
                        subscribe ourselves,</p>

                    <p>JERE. COOK,<lb/> S. W. HAYS.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Clure</ln>
                        <fn>A. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deitz</ln>
                        <fn>George A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>Jere</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>S. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Two new editors take over the Repository, asserting that the paper has been
                    consistently accurate in its political arguments, including being against
                    President Johnson. They further add that since agriculture is so important for
                    the general community, they will work to include extensive coverage of all
                    innovations in this area.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>A Bit of History</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Mr. Evarts, the last but one of the never ceasing talkers now defending the
                        President, refines even upon the thin arguments of those who have preceded
                        him. He asserts, as one of his remarkable propositions, that the Senate have
                        no authority to convict the President, for the astonishing reason that the
                        former are elected by the States, while the latter is elected by the people.
                        That as the Executive elected by the people, Johnson can be removed only by
                        the people. It is difficult to believe that the speaker hoped to convince
                        any of that body of the correctness of his proposition, but as his four days
                        speech was made for the people, he may have expected to deceive some of
                        these. As Johnson was impeached by the House of Representatives before he
                        was arraigned before the bar of the Senate for trial, and as the
                        constitution provides for his trial by the Senate upon the finding of a bill
                        of impeachment by the House; and as the members of the House are the
                        immediate representatives of the people, Mr. Evarts argument that the Senate
                        is incroaching upon the sacred rights of the people, is not well taken and
                        falls to the ground. But if it serve no other purpose, this pointless point
                        of the speaker suggests some of the strange circumstances in the career of
                        Johnson which at last resulted in his impeachment, and may help to answer
                        the inquiry whether the House of Representatives really represents the
                        people in this matter.</p>

                    <p>The present Congress was elected in the fall of 1866. Like it, that which
                        preceeded it was largely Republican in politics. It had carried the country
                        safely through a long and bloody war, begun in the interests of slavery and
                        ending in the final destruction of that unchristian institution, and the
                        overwhelming defeat of its champions. It had been throughout the war warmly
                        sustained by the people. With a view to the speedy reconstruction of the
                        rebellious States, Congress submitted to the States an amendment to the
                        constitution, providing, mainly, that no State should count any class as a
                        basis of representation to which it refused political rights. Johnson who
                        had already appointed provisional Governors of these States, from the number
                        of those who had been active traitors, and had directed them to call
                        Conventions to elect legislatures and members of the House and Senate,
                        strongly and openly urged upon them to reject this amendment. The lurking
                        treason of the South, defeated but not eradicated, under the coddling and
                        nursing of Johnson, soon grew bold and defiant, and contemptuously rejected
                        the generous propositions of Congress. The President was flattered and
                        pleased by this demonstration. He saw in it the success of his disloyal
                        schemes. He believed that with the defeated traitors of the South and the
                        fawning Democracy of the North he could defeat Congress, defeat the declared
                        wishes of the loyal people and subvert the Government. He flung discretion
                        to the winds, made drunken, disgusting journeys and speeches throughout the
                        land, and denounced Congress as an unlawful and unconstitutional body, whose
                        most patriotic and beloved members should be hanged. In his drunken madness
                        he bandied epithets and oaths with the mobs who at once cheered, and hissed,
                        and scoffed him, debasing his high office and humiliating the people before
                        the whole world.</p>

                    <p>This was the exact condition when the present Congress was elected. The issue
                        was openly and boldly made by the Democracy, and as freely accepted by the
                        Republican party. Johnson and the Democracy against the reconstruction
                        measures of Congress was their watchword, and never was a campaign more
                        vigorously contested, or discussion more general. Every one knows that the
                        election resulted in a complete Republican triumph and the vindication of
                        the policy of Congress. The President, who claims to come directly from the
                        people, was by this result unmistakably informed that the people would have
                        none of his policy. Now who, or what body has impeached Andrew Johnson of
                        high crimes and misdemeanors? the Congress elected upon the reconstruction
                        issue. Dare any one assert that they are not the representatives of the
                        people?</p>

                    <p>Again, it was not the intention of Congress to impeach the President, but it
                        was the bounden duty of that body to guard against his disloyal and
                        unconstitutional measures. To do this it became necessary to hold special
                        sessions. Because a traitor presided in the White House, Congress must
                        continue to sit and watch him. The Freedmen's Bureau bill was passed, vetoed
                        by him, and made a law over his head; the Reconstruction act passed through
                        exactly the same experience. By virtue of the constitutional authority
                        lodged in Congress, they became laws in spite of him, and if he refused to
                        execute them, he had no alternative but to resign. True, he could disobey
                        the laws, but like any other law breaker, he did it at his own peril.</p>

                    <p>From this time what does he do? The full and free execution of the Freedmen's
                        Bureau is obstructed and impeded by him on every occasion. The
                        Reconstruction measures are made a nulity by his removal of Department
                        commanders because they refused to disobey the laws. The gallant and courtly
                        Sickles was removed even when South Carolina wished him to be retained. Pope
                        was true and had to go. Sheridan would not quietly suffer the loyal people
                        of Louisiana to be butchered at Johnson's instigation, and Hancock - let us
                        pity him for his blindness - took his place. Though now apparent to the
                        simplest that Johnson was determined to prevent the practical Reconstruction
                        of the States lately in rebellion, still Congress acting only on the
                        defensive would not impeach him. As a further preventive the Tenure of
                        Office act was passed. Of course it too was vetoed, but by a two-thirds vote
                        became the law. As such it was duly recognized by the President in his
                        suspension of Secretary Stanton from the War office and appointment of
                        General Grant <emph rend="italics">ad interim</emph>, with a report of his
                        reasons for so doing to the Senate. Not satisfied with these the Senate
                        restored Stanton, whereupon Johnson, let us hope to his own confusion, but
                        the everlasting good of the whole country, deliberately violated the laws he
                        had sworn to support and maintain, and <emph rend="italics">removed
                        him.</emph></p>

                    <p>At last Congress was aroused. Its members had been elected to watch Johnson,
                        to stand between the people and his unholy policy. He had virtually violated
                        and nulified the laws for years, now he had actually disobeyed them, and
                        they promptly impeached him.</p>

                    <p>His trial will soon end, and whatever the result, it is at the same time the
                        trial of Congress and the country. If Johnson be acquitted, Congress and the
                        people stand convicted of high crimes and misdemeanors; all his unlawful
                        acts will be approved and commended; the Reconstruction of the States in
                        Rebellion will be a nullity, and they who opposed him will have broken the
                        laws. His acquittal will be the triumph of Copperheads in the past and
                        insure their triumph in the coming election, because this Congress does
                        represent the people, and if they are wrong Johnson is right.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The author argues that though detractors claim that Johnson cannot be
                    removed by the Senate because Senators were appointed by states and Presidents
                    elected by the people, this is untrue, and provides this version of the events
                    leading up to the impeachment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Gen. Grant's Intemperance</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper defends General Grant against charges of intemperance.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.05.06.03" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Great Victory! Democracy Defeated! Chambersburg Won't Stand the Ku-Klux Klan!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On Monday last the annual spring election for Borough Officers was held,
                        under the late law passed by the Legislature. For some time past the
                        Democracy have been actively at work, and succeeded in forming a thorough
                        organization. They not only placed their very best men on their ticket, but
                        they also induced one who had always acted with us to allow himself to be
                        sacrificed. A few weeks since we warned members of our party not to form any
                        political affiliations with the Copperheads, and predicted the consequences.
                        The election on Monday only affirms our position, and is but another warning
                        to those who forsake their party on account of disappointment of personal
                        ambitions. The polls were opened on Monday at 12 M, and closed at 6 P. M.
                        More than 800 votes were polled. Both parties were busy, but it was soon
                        discovered that the Democracy had been preparing for the conflict, and all
                        their available material was brought out. This only aroused the Republicans,
                        and although their strength was not out by several hundred they still
                        believed that victory was on their side. During the entire evening the Court
                        House pavement was crowded, and anxious groups were awaiting to hear the
                        result. Democrats and Republicans were discussing the effect on the Borough,
                        should their favorite candidates be elected or defeated. The former
                        especially felt jubilant until it "leaked out" that "their case was all
                        dough," when they<lb/> "Folded their tents like the Arabs,<lb/> And silently
                        stole away."</p>

                    <p>We must not fail to note that our political opponents gracefully yielded, and
                        are fully satisfied that no "ring" can give control of this Borough to their
                        party, and Republicans who "scratched" their tickets have been taught<lb/>
                        "That the best laid plans of mice and men,<lb/> Gang aft agee."</p>

                    <p>In the short space of six hours the vote polled was not quite 400 hundred
                        short of last October's vote, and 75 more than the spring election of '67.
                        We print below the names of the candidates and the votes each received.</p>

                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>
                                <emph rend="italics">Republican</emph>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <emph rend="italics">Democrat</emph>
                            </cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>

                    <p>BURGESS.</p>

                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Lyman S. Clarke......436 </cell>
                            <cell>A. H. Seuseny........409</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell> Clarke's majority, 27.</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>

                    <p>TOWN COUNCIL.</p>

                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Samuel F. Greenawait..486 </cell>
                            <cell>P. Henry Peiffer......392</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Theodore B. Wood......471 </cell>
                            <cell>James King............392</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Jacob L. Suesserolt...486 </cell>
                            <cell>Josiah Allen..........382</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Peter Kreichbaum......460 </cell>
                            <cell>James Logan...........379</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Franklin S. Gillespie 486 </cell>
                            <cell>Jacob Smith...........371</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>

                    <p>AUDITOR</p>

                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Abraham D. Canfman....461 </cell>
                            <cell>William C. Finney.....385</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell> Caufman's majority, 79.</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>

                    <p>HIGH CONSTABLE</p>

                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Michael W. Houser.....487 </cell>
                            <cell>Henry C. Koontz.......364</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell> Houser's majority, 123.</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This election report describes Democratic efforts in Chambersburg, their
                    subsequent defeat, and contains vote records for each candidate.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Temperance</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We publish, by request, the following extracts from the report of N. W.
                        Pratt, Esq., Grand Worthy Patriarch of the Grand Division of Sons of
                        Temperance of Pennsylvania, made at the quarterly session of that body
                        lately held in this place:</p>

                    <p> Chambersburg, April 22, 1868<lb/>
                        <emph rend="italics">To the Officers and Members of the Grand Division, Sons
                            of Temperance of Pennsylvania</emph></p>

                    <p>Worthy Brothers:-In presenting to you this, my second quarterly report,
                        permit me to say that, assembled for thanksgiving to God, that the horrors
                        of war have passed away, we hope no more to desolate the beautiful towns,
                        villages, and cities of our noble Commonwealth, of our fair land of freedom.
                        Where we are now assembled, the evils of war have been fully realized. The
                        torch of ruthless invaders here was applied, and in a short space of time
                        laid waste what had been the result of many years of patient toil and labor
                        and reduced this rich and beautiful borough to an unsightly mass of ruins.
                        Yet, notwithstanding all the past unfortunate desolations of war,
                        Chambersburg has risen Phoenixlike from its ashes, to more than its former
                        beauty. We are here, my brothers, to do business, not that which make our
                        fellowmen miserable and unhappy, or to dart the incendiary torch into the
                        midst of their homes and peaceful firesides, but we are here waving the
                        beautiful Olive Branch of peace and goodwill to all mankind. We are here as
                        Philanthropists, and we should be here as christians, to labor for the
                        happiness of our fellowmen here and hereafter. If the great evil against
                        which we are contending had never been permitted in our land. I believe we
                        should have been saved from a large portion, if not all, of the desolations
                        of war, bloodshed, crime and misery, that is such a fearful curse upon our
                        land.</p>

                    <p>I am glad to be able to say on this occasion, that so far as our Order is
                        concerned, our star is in the ascendant. In our own jurisdiction there is
                        evidently an uprising in the work, and if the feeling manifested is only
                        cherished as it should be, we would soon see our number largely increased,
                        and our influence bearing down with tremendous weight upon the evils against
                        which we are contending, and we would give way before us, and the sacred
                        Banner of Temperance wave in holy triumph throughout the length and breadth
                        of our land. But this, my brothers, cannot be done without the use of means.
                        It is not for me to say it shall be done, but this much I will say, I will
                        do all in my power with my small means and feeble efforts to bring this
                        great work to a successful completion. It is the word of Holy Writ "That he
                        that soweth sparingly shall reap sparingly, but he that soweth bountifully
                        shall reap bountifully." Let us, my brothers, be of the latter class, that
                        in the great day we may come rejoicing, bringing our sheaves with
                        application to duty, that our own city, town, village or borough is to be
                        the limit of our foil and labor; nay, rather let us feel that we must work
                        and toil on, both at home and away from home, until the sacred principles of
                        total abstinence shall be embraced by the entire brotherhood of man.</p>

                    <p>I take the liberty of appealing to you of our State, and in doing so I feel
                        that I am but fulfilling a duty, the demand of which is imperative.
                        Comparatively speaking, but little has been done for the protection of the
                        youth of our Commonwealth, from the snares that beset them in the youthful
                        paths of life. I ask, does not duty call in thunder tones, "save the youth,"
                        and yet how little we heed the call. A few faithful brothers are faithful to
                        the call, and are laboring with untiring zeal in sustaining the Order of the
                        Cadets of Temperance. They call for help, but they call in vain. Our
                        Divisions do not respond to the call as they should, and I think sometimes
                        they seem almost lost to a sense of their duty to their God, their country
                        and the youth of our State, forgetting how much easier it is to mould and
                        restrain the young minds than it is to correct long cherished habits of
                        disipation. I have on a former occasion called the attention of this Grand
                        Division to this important subject, but I fear with little or no effect, but
                        I am determined to press the subject at every opportunity. Will you not take
                        hold of the matter at once, and take decisive measures to encourage those
                        who [several words obscured] Philanthropic work. I am well assured that
                        there is not a Division in our jurisdiction but might with proper effect get
                        up and sustain a section of Cadets, which would not only be a powerful
                        shield to the youth from the evils of intemperance, but a fruitful source of
                        strength and prosperity to themselves.</p>

                    <p>I am happy to announce to you that the committee on lectures and public
                        meetings have secured the services of P. G., W. A., A. E. Bradley, of New
                        York, and he is now lecturing with great success in our State, and he had
                        already succeeded in organizing eight Divisions of our Order, although he
                        has been but two weeks at the work. I hope the committee will be enabled to
                        continue him in the field until he has canvassed our entire Commonwealth,
                        and until our Order has been planted in every town and village in our
                        jurisdiction. Eleven new Divisions have been chartered by the Charter
                        Committee since our last Quarterly Session.</p>

                    <p>Finally brothers, in concluding my imperfect report, allow me to invoke you
                        to a more earnest effort in carrying forward our glorious work; let us raise
                        high our banners and let our battle cry be <emph rend="italics"
                        >onward</emph>. I am with you in every measure you may see fit or judge
                        expedient to adopt to promote the advancement of the work God has thus
                        committed to our charge. I feel desirous that we all work in harmony, love
                        and zeal together so that when our own "Star shall set at life's close, it
                        may get as se's the Morning Star, which goeth not down behind the darkened
                        West, but melts away into the brightness of heaven."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This open letter from the head of a Pennsylvania temperance organization
                    urges temperance advocates to recruit children into the campaign, among more
                    general comments about the status of the state organization.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Improvements</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clever</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Dowell</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Culloh</ln>
                        <fn>A. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echart</ln>
                        <fn>Edward</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stepler</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Horne</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gelwicks</ln>
                        <fn>D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pickle</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Monks</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneck</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Besser</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henneberger</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Householder</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Charles F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Monath</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper lists the many Chambersburg property owners who have made
                    improvements to their homes or erected new buildings.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>J. H. Shumaker, A. M.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shumaker</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper endorses J. H. Shumaker as an excellent teacher and calls
                    attention to his advertisement.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Religious</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>J. Agnew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barclay</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hawkins</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Presbyterian Church did not hold services the past weekend due to the
                    absence of Rev. J. Agnew Crawford. Episcopal services were held in the lower
                    story of the Masonic Hall, Rev. Hawkins presiding. Rev. J. H. Barclay of New
                    York will preach in the Lutheran Church on Sunday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Huntingdon, Fulton and Franklin Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The citizens of Huntingdon County have been working to promote the
                    construction of a railroad to join the Cumberland Valley line. They invite the
                    citizens of Franklin to participate in their efforts.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Cuckoo</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dittman</ln>
                        <fn>F. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The citizens of Chambersburg have been entertained with the cuckoo clock
                    that jeweler F. G. Dittman has in his store.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>I. O. G. T.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roney</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilmore</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Over</ln>
                        <fn>Jennie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brad</ln>
                        <fn>Charles W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Black</ln>
                        <fn>Harper</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seiders</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keagy</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheets</ln>
                        <fn>Levi</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mason</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Welsh</ln>
                        <fn>Lide P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tolbert</ln>
                        <fn>Lide</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hazelet</ln>
                        <fn>N. Gehr</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stratten</ln>
                        <fn>Albert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sloan</ln>
                        <fn>Rachel A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilmore</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>W. S. Roney installed a number of officers of McMurray Lodge No. 119, I. O.
                    G. T. Mrs. Rachel A. Sloan and John Gilmore were elected as representatives to
                    the grand lodge, and William H. Wanamaker was chosen lodge deputy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>A Handsome Donation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>I. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The ladies of the Middle Spring Church presented the pastor's wife, Mrs. I.
                    N. Hays, with a silver and china tea set.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Y. M. C. A.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Young Men's Christian Association secured rooms above Gelwicks and
                    Burkhardt's store where they will hold meetings. They hope to open a reading
                    room, and invite all young men to attend an upcoming meeting.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hershberger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Maj. Hershberger's panorama of the burning of Chambersburg will be on
                    display in Repository Hall. The major will also play a violin solo. Those who,
                    due to crowds, did not see the painting last time are now afforded a chance.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Trustees Elected</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Lellan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chambers</ln>
                        <fn>William L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Dowell</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolff</ln>
                        <fn>B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chambers</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>T. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>W. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wunderlich</ln>
                        <fn>D. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Messersmith</ln>
                        <fn>G. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heyser</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Culbertson</ln>
                        <fn>Edmund</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Chambersburg Academy elected trustees at a recent meeting.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>New Buildings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Greencastle Building Association recently purchased ten acres on which
                    it plans to erect dwelling houses.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Dissolved</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>Charles G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The pastoral relation between Rev. Charles G. Fisher and the Grindstone
                    Hill congregation was dissolved at a recent meeting of the Mercersburg Classis
                    of the German Reformed Church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spielman</ln>
                        <fn>Clinton D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henderson</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnes</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel </fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Clinton D. Spielman and Miss Sarah Henderson, both of Chambersburg, were
                    married on May 5th at the residence of the bride's parents by the Rev. Samuel
                    Barnes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stinger</ln>
                        <fn>W. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anthony</ln>
                        <fn>J. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>W. A. Stinger and Miss E. Miller, both of Metal, were married on April 24th
                    by the Rev. J. P. Anthony.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Leiston</ln>
                        <fn>Matilda</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Matilda Leiston died in Fannett on April 21st. She was 52 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Knight</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Knight</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Margaret C. M'Knight, a native and long-time resident of Chambersburg,
                    died in Philadelphia on April 30th at the age of 77. She was the widow of the
                    late Rev. John M'Knight, former pastor of Rocky Spring and St. Thomas
                    Presbyterian Churches.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph Zarman</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn>Lemuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn>Rosean</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Joseph Zarman King, infant son of Lemuel and Rosean King, died on April
                    23rd. He was 8 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.05.06.04" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

    </paperBody>
</hwp>
