
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1868/pa.fr.fr.1868.05.20">

    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>

        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>05/12/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>

        <address>
<city>Chambersburg</city>
<county>Franklin</county>
<state>Pennsylvania</state>
</address>

        <date n="1868-05-20">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day>20</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
    </header>

    <paperBody>

        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.05.20.01" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.05.20.02" exists="no">

            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>What Was Done, What to Do</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>When the U.S. Senate on Tuesday of last week postponed the vote on the
                        impeachment articles until Saturday, the 16th, it was feared that Johnson
                        had bought and debauched enough of Republican Senators to secure his
                        acquittal. It was hoped that by this delay the loyal masses might by a
                        universal appeal recall the recreant Senators from the infamy of voting to
                        sustain the President. True, Republican Conventions and Republican State
                        Committees from every State had declared in firm and unmistakable tones
                        their conviction that Johnson was guilty of the charge preferred against
                        him, and demanded his removal. The entire Republican Press had joined in the
                        same demand. But since Tuesday, the 12th instant, the voice of the people in
                        every State from Maine to California has steadily demanded the conviction
                        and removal of the President. Through the journals, by mass meetings,
                        through conventions and committees, and through their Representatives in
                        Congress there has been but one cry. Maine, Illinois, Iowa and Missouri
                        besought their mercenary Senators not to betray them, by acquitting the
                        President, and thus bring upon themselves everlasting shame and reproach. In
                        all the land there was not one dissenting voice, but with marvelous
                        unanimity from a thousand different places at the same time, the same
                        unmistakable messages flashed over the wires to those men holding the grand
                        council of the nation. It cannot then be said that the people did not demand
                        his conviction.</p>

                    <p>It is not a question wherein the consideration of the Party, as a mere
                        political organization can have a place. Parties may rise and flourish and
                        sink to decay, and the cause of justice and freedom still goes on. But if
                        the loyal people of the United States demanded Johnson's conviction and
                        removal for flagrant violations of the law, and it is resisted only by those
                        who have proved themselves the enemies of the country, we do say the safety
                        of the country demands his conviction. It is a matter of history and needs
                        no proof that the Republican Party has for years been the salvation of the
                        country. It resisted the encroachments of the Slave Power of the South, and
                        when it rebelled and tried to overthrow the Government, it defeated the most
                        gigantic effort treason has ever made to destroy Republican Institutions.
                        Whatever honest and patriotic Democrats may have done, and they did much to
                        save the country, nevertheless the Democratic party by its leaders and its
                        organization voted and labored wholly in the interests of the rebellion.
                        They encouraged the Confederates, they resisted the draft, and always voted
                        in the National Councils and in the legislature of every State to withhold
                        the necessary means and measures to prosecute the war. The party of loyalty
                        and liberty, the Republican party, after treason had been defeated on every
                        battlefield, and the chains of slavery had been stricken from four millions
                        of bondmen, and freedom had been declared the birthright of all men, is
                        guilty of no idle boast when it claims that the loyal country demands the
                        conviction and removal of Johnson. It is too late now to recapitulate how
                        the President usurped the powers of Congress, how he took in his own hands
                        the Reconstruction of the Rebellious States, how he dictated terms of peace,
                        how he converted the federal patronage into a corruption fund to buy
                        renegade Republicans to support his policy, how he pardoned thieves, and
                        counterfeiters, and murderers, to make his party, how he arbitrarily removed
                        loyal Generals for obeying the laws of Congress, how he instigated the
                        bloody massacres of Memphis and New Orleans, how he vetoed the laws of
                        Congress, and how at last he assumed judicial as well as executive powers,
                        declared himself a despot, and violated the laws. All this the people know
                        he has done, and they have labored to secure his removal. But the voice of
                        Avarice and Greed has been louder than the still small voice of conscience,
                        and seven Senators have sold their manhood that they might share his
                        everlasting infamy and shame, while they enjoy none of his power.</p>

                    <p>To Republicans throughout the land, we say, you have been betrayed and
                        deceived. The steward in whose charge you placed your treasure have proved
                        false to the trust. When your liberties were invaded by the despot, they
                        proved cowards and deserted to the enemy. When your principles were
                        assailed, they did not resist. But principles are eternal, and will live
                        whether you are victor or vanquished.</p>

                    <p>Hundred of thousand of the best lives of the land died fighting for these
                        same principles. Their graves are found on every battlefield and their
                        vacant places are still felt at every hearthstone. Their silent appeals you
                        cannot resist. The liberties rescued from the hands of traitors, by the
                        sacrifice of their blood you must again rescue from the hands of the tyrant
                        at Washington. Unless you do, they fought in vain; the liberty for which
                        they died is a mockery, and the Constitution, the charter of Freedom which
                        they won from unholy hands, will prove to be an engine of power in the hands
                        of an unscrupulous tyrant to wrest our liberties from us.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper bemoans the "betrayal" of the people by the politicians of the
                    country through Johnson's acquittal, laying out a long history of what they see
                    as Democratic evils.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Dead</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Died, on the 14th instant, in Washington City, Senators Fessenden, of Maine,
                        Trumbull, of Illinois, Henderson, of Missouri, Grimes, of Iowa. Their
                        memories will be buried in a graveyard whose only occupants hitherto have
                        been Benedict Arnold, Aaron Burr, and Jeff. Davis. They died of weakness,
                        meanness, betrayal of their country and violation of their oaths. They died
                        because they had not the manhood to live. They aspired to be champions of
                        Freedom, they were only the tools of Despotism. They had well nigh made the
                        people believe that they were freemen, free in thought, speech and action.
                        They were but the cringing slaves of a Tennessee Tailor, and when he snapped
                        his whip they bowed their faces to the earth and licked the dust.</p>

                    <p>Now there is none so lowly that to gaze upon them he must not look down, none
                        so despised that he may not fervently give thanks that between him and them
                        there is an infinite distance. Let American youth look on Grimes and pray
                        that they be spared the imbecility of second childhood. Let them behold
                        Fessenden and learn the lesson, how the fairest temple of a lifetime,
                        wrought with infinite care and skill, may in an evil moment be dashed to the
                        ground, an unsightly mass. Let them learn that disappointed ambition and
                        envy could accomplish in a day what the enemies of his country failed to
                        effect in a lifetime - his political death.</p>

                    <p>If disappointed ambition made Fessenden mad; and doting senility would not
                        surrender Grimes to kindlier Death, what can be said in extenuation of the
                        conduct of Trumbull and Henderson? They can plead neither the one nor the
                        other. Old age has not dethroned their reason, nor disappointment burned his
                        mark upon their brows. But they too have fallen in the moment of the
                        crowning glory of their lives; and if their hands be not full of burning
                        gold they have but surrendered themselves to the Despot at their real worth.</p>

                    <p>"Weep for the dead' Not those who claim<lb/> Immortal life on the scroll of
                        Fame;<lb/> Not for the soul that feared but shame;<lb/> Not for the life
                        that reached its aim;<lb/> Not for the step that marked in flame<lb/> Print
                        of a hero's tread.<lb/> Weep for the dead that breathe and speak!<lb/> Dead
                        with a life-bloom on the cheek!<lb/> Dead for they have no aim to seek!<lb/>
                        Dead to the core - dead!<lb/> Dead as the use of a wasted hour!<lb/> Dead as
                        the dew on a poison flower!<lb/> Dead as the Soul's crime-palsied
                        power!<lb/> Dead!</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This tirade against the Republican Senators who voted for Johnson's
                    acquittal casts them as traitors, weak men, and many other unfortunate things.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Old Grimes</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p><emph rend="italics">Old</emph> Grimes is dead. Faithless to his
                        constituents, faithless to his high and sacred trusts, and faithless to his
                        country, he buried himself deep in the mire of Andrew Johnson's infamy. Old
                            <emph rend="italics">Grimes</emph> is dead. "With repenting hand he had
                        abolished his own works," slavishly connived with traitors, and to-day,
                        alone, and separated from those with whom he has stood shoulder to shoulder
                        in many a hard fought contest against those who mourn treason's fall, he
                        wanders without friends, and despised by his new found associates. Old
                        Grimes <emph rend="italics">is</emph> dead. He has fallen from his high
                        estate as a gallant standard bearer of the party of Freedom and Humanity. By
                        one fool deed he has blotted out his fair fame. A victim to his own
                        ambition, a betrayer of those who elevated him to his present position, the
                        Judas Iscariot of the U. S. Senate, he has dug his own political grave, and
                        in it let him be buried. It would be charity to suppose that it was an error
                        of judgment that led him astray, were the fact not against him mountain
                        high. Old Grimes is <emph rend="italics">dead</emph>. What his price was no
                        man knows, how great his ruin time alone can tell. Iowa has already forsaken
                        him, in the streets of the capitol he is met by no congratulating friends,
                        and when he returns to his home, he will not be received with any
                        manifestations of joy by the true men of his State, for in sadness and
                        sorrow have they seen him surrender his manhood. He will retire into
                        obscurity "not only doomed but damned," never to be thought of, save when it
                        is necessary to warn men who, in violation of the will of the people, would
                        sacrifice their party principles and others to gratify selfish purposes.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article comments on the so-called political death of Senator Grimes
                    after his vote to acquit President Johnson in the impeachment trial. It attacks
                    his character and predicts a dire fate for Grimes. </summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On Saturday at noon the Senate met and voted on the eleventh article of
                        Impeachment. The vote stood 35 for conviction and 19 for acquittal. Among
                        the latter were Republicans Grimes, Fessenden, Trumbull, Henderson, Fowler,
                        Van Winkle and Ross. The Senate then adjourned to Tuesday, the 26th inst.
                        This is virtually the end of Impeachment. If, indeed, a vote be taken at
                        all, upon the reassembling of the Senate, on the remaining articles, they
                        will likewise be defeated. The eleventh article charged that the President
                        violated the Tenure of Office Act, by attempting to remove Secretary
                        Stanton, and appointing Gen. Thomas to fill the office of Secretary of War,
                        without the advice and consent of the Senate. The Senate made the Tenure of
                        Office Act a law of the land over the President's veto, for the especial
                        purpose of restraining him in his unlawful removals of loyal men from
                        office. All but one of the Republican Senators who voted for his acquittal
                        on Saturday, voted also to make his law. That he attempted to remove Stanton
                        and appoint Thomas are record facts. On Saturday seven Republican Senators
                        were made to say, no matter how, that the President had a right to remove
                        Stanton and appoint Thomas, and, as a legitimate result of their vote, that
                        he has a right to turn their miserable carcasses out of the Senate Chamber,
                        and if he wishes, turn the government upside down. Why not? If the Senate
                        and House cannot make laws which Johnson is bound to respect, and if he can
                        remove and appoint without their advice and consent, they are without use,
                        and to retain them as a matter of ornament, why tastes differ, besides it is
                        too costly.</p>

                    <p>Of course Johnson cannot be convicted on any of the remaining articles.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article reports that the impeachment has failed and names the
                    Republican Senators who voted for acquittal. It questions the implications of
                    this acquittal on the government as a structure and reiterates the arguments for
                    impeachment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>To-day the Chicago Convention meets for the nomination of candidates for
                        President and Vice President on the Republican ticket. The first office in
                        the gift of the nation is universally conceded to the gallant military
                        chieftain who conquered treason's forces, and scattered them like leaves of
                        the forest throughout a land redeemed from the bondage of slavery. There
                        will be a contest for the Vice Presidency, with the chances now strongly in
                        favor of Wade. The most important part of the proceedings will be the making
                        of a platform for the next campaign. It is certain that none of the
                        principles that have already been sustained by the people will be
                        surrendered, and if the Convention determines to occupy still higher ground
                        on the great questions of Humanity and Freedom, they will be still further
                        supported by the masses. But on no account whatever should Trumbull, or
                        Grime, or Fessenden, or Ross, or Fowler, or Van Winkle, or Henderson, or the
                        great Chief Devil, Chase - whose only aim and ambition now is to cause the
                        rupture of the party that gave him the highest place in his profession, not
                        only because he differs from us in principle, but for the purpose of
                        gratifying bitter animosities - be permitted to appear on the floor or in
                        any way exercise any influence on any question that may be brought before
                        the body. Let these renegades no longer enjoy the confidence of the men they
                        have sold for the money of the "whiskey ring," and let them clearly
                        understand that they must cling to the idols of treason and associate with
                        the enemies of free government, to which they have deserted. Whether Johnson
                        is convicted or not, Grimes and Trumbull must be removed from the committees
                        of which they are chairmen, and honest and reliable men, who can withstand
                        the subtle charms of treason and treason's money, be immediately substituted
                        in their place. Let them be denounced in no gentle terms, let their conduct
                        be shown in its true and proper light, let their deep and damning guilt be
                        condemned by the great Union party in convention assembled, and the people
                        will say, amen.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper discusses the Chicago Convention to nominate the Republican
                    candidates for President and Vice President. President, the author says, is
                    universally accepted as going to Grant, but there is discussion about the VP.
                    The author further attacks the Republican Senators who voted for acquittal of
                    the President.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper denounces the seven Republican senators who voted to acquit
                    Johnson as having "betrayed their confiding constituents and dug their own
                    political graves." The only explanation the paper can find is that many had
                    terms expiring in 1869.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Hon. Simon Cameron</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper applauds Simon Cameron for voting to remove Andrew Johnson.
                    "Thoroughly alive to the jeopardy in which Andrew Johnson had brought the
                    country by his treachery, his reckless violation of law, his betrayal of the
                    Southern loyalists and of his party, he has labored earnestly and with a
                    singleness of purpose to effect his removal."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper charges that Senator Trumbull's "moral character" has been
                    destroyed by his vote to acquit Andrew Johnson. The paper suggests that the
                    explanation lies in Trumbull's son's alleged bet of $5,000 that Johnson would
                    not be removed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="l">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Teachers' Examinations</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"One of the Com" writes the Repository to defend the new law that requires
                    teachers holding professional certificates, who had previously been exempt, to
                    take the yearly examination. The correspondent argues that this will ensure that
                    all teachers are up to current standards. A committee on permanent certificates
                    will meet applicants and administer a general examination on June 6th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.05.20.03" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Impeachment Excitement</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It having been made known by the Harrisonburg morning papers that telegraphic
                        despatches would be sent throughout the country, in regard to the action of
                        the U. S. Senate, on the conviction or acquittal of Andrew Johnson, on
                        Tuesday, the 12th inst., many of our Republican friends came to the office
                        of the Repository for the purpose of hearing the news. The New York and
                        Philadelphia dailies of the evening previous having regarded the conviction
                        of the President as certain, there was of course but one conclusion formed
                        throughout the country, as to the result. The Copperheads were prepared for
                        the removal of this great obstruction to the execution of our laws, and the
                        reconstruction of the late rebel states, on a loyal basis. Some of our
                        merchants had received letters from men of the Democratic persuasion,
                        telling them that business would enliven and money would become plenty as
                        soon as Wade occupied the White House. Everybody felt satisfied that his
                        Accidency would be found guilty on some of the charges, at least, that had
                        been presented for the consideration of the high court of impeachment. No
                        one, of either party, seemed to have taken into account that the proposition
                        of the New York <emph rend="italics">World</emph> to raise millions of
                        dollars to buy Senators would or could be successful, and regarded it only
                        as an insult to our great Statesmen. But when a telegram was received
                        announcing the adjournment of the Senate until the 16th, suspicions of foul
                        play were at once aroused, and with one voice the recreant Senators were
                        denounced. Had Trumbull, or Fessenden, or poor old Grimes, or the traitor
                        from Missouri been about, they would have been roughly handled by their
                        former party friends. The failure was regarded as a Bull Run disaster. The
                        same countenances were full of grief and the same hearts were sad on
                        Tuesday, that mourned over our fallen braves on the bloody field of
                        Manassas, while on the other hand smiles and congratulations were everywhere
                        extended by joyful "Cops," who never rejoiced save when Union troops were
                        defeated, or never lamented, unless some Gettysburg disaster was the fate of
                        their traitor friends.</p>

                    <p>Brave veterans, who had gone through storms of lead and shell, and seen many
                        a comrade murdered by Southern bullets, that the "Stars and Stripes" might
                        be the flag of our nation; old men, who sent forth the idols of their
                        household to die for Liberty and Union, and mothers and maidens, who had
                        laid upon the altar of their country their heart's choicest offering,
                        bitterly deplored the evils that had been brought upon us by the vile
                        apostates. It was but the rehearsal of the woe and grief that hallowed
                        Fredericksburg and Chancellorsville. The vote on Saturday made the prospect
                        no brighter. The Senate met and virtually acquitted the Executive on the
                        eleventh article, and again adjourned, until the 26th of May. It is hard to
                        tell what may be done then. The betrayers may retrace their footsteps, but
                        it is not probable. The prayers of a Christian people can alone save us, as
                        they have in days gone by, from the ruin staring us in the face, and avert
                        the calamities that now overwhelm us.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article recounts the shift from certainty that the President would be
                    convicted to a shift, upon hearing of the adjournment of the Senate, to
                    questions of foul play and later disappointment and unhappiness.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Our Dead Heroes</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Gen. Logan, the Commander in Chief of the society of the Grand Army of the
                        Republic, has issued a general order designating the 30th of the present
                        month of May, as the day for "strewing with flowers or otherwise decorating
                        the graves of Comrades who died in defense of their country during the great
                        rebellion, and whose bodies now lie in almost every city, village, and
                        hamlet church yard in the land. In this observance no form of ceremony is
                        prescribed, but Posts and Comrades will in their own way arrange such
                        fitting services and testimonials of respect as circumstances may permit.
                        "Let us, then, at the time appointed gather around their sacred remains and
                        garland the passionless mounds above them with the choicest flowers of
                        springtime; let us raise above them the dear old flag they saved from
                        dishonor; let us in this solemn presence renew our pledge to aid and assist
                        those whom they have left among us a sacred charge upon a nation's
                        gratitude, the soldier's and sailor's widow and orphan."</p>

                    <p>It is not necessary to ask the gallant soldiers of Franklin County to comply
                        with the above order. There is no better way of keeping green the memories
                        of the sainted dead, than by these sad demonstrations of our appreciation of
                        their services. They nobly fought, nobly lived, and nobly died, that our
                        Republic might exist, and let us not now forget their services or their
                        names. Let each post of the G. A. R. make such arrangements as they may see
                        proper, let our citizens assist them in carrying out their plans and let us
                        all without regard to party or politics, meet over the silent mounds of our
                        slain patriots and then do homage to their remains. We can then refer to May
                        30th with pleasure, feeling confident that we have done our duty. Our ladies
                        can procure the <emph rend="italics">boquets</emph>, and we know they will
                        not hesitate to join in so noble a work. We hope to record a general
                        observance of Gen. Logan's request by all the good people of Cumberland
                        Valley.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>General Logan, Commander of the Grand Army of the Republic, declared the
                    30th of May a day of remembrance for fallen troops. The article encourages the
                    populace to observe this day.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Labor</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper publishes for the benefit of employers and laborers an act of the
                    legislature establishing a fair day's work as "eight hours of labor, between the
                    rising and the setting of the sun." The law does not apply to contracts made by
                    the "year, month, or week," nor does it prevent workers from working overtime if
                    they desire.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>I. O. G. T.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lego</ln>
                        <fn>Charles W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolf</ln>
                        <fn>Levi J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richards</ln>
                        <fn>Kate</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Black</ln>
                        <fn>Sue M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>H. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henderson</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mahon</ln>
                        <fn>N. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rodrock</ln>
                        <fn>Ida</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bittinger</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Black</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Downey</ln>
                        <fn>Emma</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Elroy</ln>
                        <fn>R. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Charles W. Lego, lodge deputy, installed a number of new officers at
                    Gilmore Lodge No. 385, I. O. G. T. of Fayetteville. This lodge has enjoyed "more
                    than usual success" since its organization. It opened with 20 members and now
                    boasts more than 60 in a town of 400. The success "shows what energy and
                    perseverance in a good cause will accomplish in despite of the open and covert
                    animosity of the friends and abettors of that giant evil of our favored
                    land--whiskey." The lodge will hold a picnic on May 29th. </summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>What Becomes of All the Butter</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An estimated 30 tons of butter per month is produced and shipped from
                    Franklin County. At 20 cents per pound, this brings in $140,000 per year.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>J. Madison Bell, an African American orator and poet from California, spoke
                    to a "small but appreciative audience" in Chambersburg's Repository Hall. He
                    plans two more lectures in town.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The New Law Judge</head>
                <origin>Bedford Inquirer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rowe</ln>
                        <fn>D. Watson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Judge D. Watson Rowe, the recent appointment as additional law judge for
                    the 16th Judicial District, won many compliments for the discharge of his duty
                    in Bedford. He is reportedly the youngest judge in the state.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>


            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>An Assault</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brooks</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bard</ln>
                        <fn>C. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel Brooks, an "American citizen of African descent" who works at the
                    quarry near Chambersburg, had his temple artery cut when a men with whom he was
                    arguing struck him with a rock. The quick action of Dr. C. L. Bard stopped the
                    bleeding, and Brooks seems to be recovering.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hawkins</ln>
                        <fn>William George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Rev. William George Hawkins of the Episcopal Church declined an offer
                    of chair of National Sciences at Bethany College in order to devote his energies
                    to building up his Chambersburg congregation. He also has plans of opening a
                    female seminary.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Refugees</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A man named Carpenter passed through Chambersburg with his wife and family
                    on his way to Chester County. He claims he was a loyal Union man driven from his
                    home in Kentucky by "the persecutions of rebels." The loyal citizens of
                    Chambersburg raised money to help him with his travel expenses. "His tale was
                    but the repetition of the outrages and wrongs inflicted on loyal men in the
                    South."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>June Court</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doebler</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sheriff</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sheriff Doebler announces to the people of Chambersburg that a special
                    session of the court will be held the first week of June.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Postponement</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The railroad committee postponed the public meeting, but are hard at work.
                    They have set the price of shares at $25.06 "thus bringing the enterprise within
                    the reach of all our citizens who take an interest in the prosperity of
                    Chambersburg."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Updyke</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Buchanan</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnes</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Updyke of Philadelphia and Miss Sarah Jane Buchanan of Franklin were
                    married at the American Hotel in Chambersburg on May 12th by the Rev. S. Barnes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Millhose</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Martha Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnes</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Henry Millhose and Miss Martha Jane Stumbaugh, both of Franklin, were
                    married on May 14th at the Methodist Parsonage in Chambersburg by the Rev. S.
                    Barnes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houghtelin</ln>
                        <fn>William H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McFetridge</ln>
                        <fn>Jennie L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McFetridge</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McElwee</ln>
                        <fn>William </fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William H. H. Houghtelin of Chambersburg and Jennie L. McFetridge, daughter
                    of Samuel L. McFetridge of Philadelphia, were married on May 7th by the Rev.
                    William McElwee.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eakle</ln>
                        <fn>Christian</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Christian Eakle died at his Chambersburg residence on May 10th. He was 55
                    years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Uglow</ln>
                        <fn>Annie B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Uglow</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Uglow</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Annie B. Uglow, daughter of Benjamin and Elizabeth Uglow, died on May 13th.
                    She was 3 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stahl</ln>
                        <fn>Anna Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stahl</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heintzelman</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Anna Mary Stahl, wife of Joseph Stahl, died suddenly in Guilford at
                    the residence of Andrew Heintzelman. She was 72 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingert</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brechbill</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Mary Wingert died in Green township on May 12th at the residence of
                    Jacob Brechbill. She was 23 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.05.20.04" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

    </paperBody>
</hwp>
