
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1868/pa.fr.fr.1868.05.13">

     <header>
          <title>Franklin Repository</title>

          <tagger>
               <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
               <tagDate>05/12/06</tagDate>
               <tagNote/>
          </tagger>

          <address>
<city>Chambersburg</city>
<county>Franklin</county>
<state>Pennsylvania</state>
</address>

          <date n="1868-05-13">
               <year>1868</year>
               <month norm="05">May</month>
               <day>13</day>
               <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
          </date>
     </header>

     <paperBody>

          <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.05.13.01" exists="no">


               <pageNote/>
          </page>

          <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.05.13.02" exists="no">

               <div type="e">
                    <column>01</column>
                    <head>The Franklin Repository for 1868. Seventy-Fifth Volume.</head>
                    <origin/>
                    <commentary/>
                    <transcript>
                         <p>The Franklin Repository, now in its seventy-fifth year, is more widely
                              read and more liberally supported than any other journal in the State,
                              out of the leading cities. It is unrivalled by any other rural journal
                              in its expenditures for reliable Correspondence, Editorial and other
                              contributions, telegraphing and everything necessary to make a
                              complete General and Local Newspaper.</p>

                         <p>The Repository gives a cordial and earnest support to Congress in all
                              its measures for the Reconstruction of the States lately in rebellion,
                              and urges the speedy and just re-admission of these States to all
                              their rights and privileges under the Constitution. It advocates, as
                              the surest and speediest, and only just road to this end, the broad
                              and comprehensive measures of Congress, which know no personal or
                              class distinctions, but concede to both white and black the rights,
                              and impose upon them the duties of citizens.</p>

                         <p>The Repository is not unmindful that to those who imperiled their lives
                              in defense of their country, when assailed by the hordes of treason,
                              belong the lasting gratitude, as well as the more substantial rewards
                              of the Government; that maimed and disabled soldiers should ever be
                              the cherished charge of a grateful people, and should in preference to
                              all others receive appointments and offices of trust under the people.</p>

                         <p>The Repository seeks neither patronage nor support as a matter of favor.
                              It aims to render a full return to its patrons and readers, and amply
                              remunerate them for the outlay of its subscription price. To the
                              citizens of Franklin and adjoining counties it is especially valuable
                              for its complete Local Reports, Correspondence, Markets, &amp;c,
                              and we firmly believe that the increase of its circulation will be no
                              less advantageous to the cause of the Republican Party and to the
                              success of its candidates, than remunerative to its publishers. To
                              those who seek a newspaper wedded in its belief to the principles of
                              the Republican Party, which believes them to be the Principles of
                              Eternal Right and Justice; which is ready and willing at all times to
                              give a reason for the faith that is in it, but which is ever
                              independent and untrammeled. We appeal with confidence for sympathy
                              and aid in extending our already large circulation.</p>

                         <p><emph rend="italics">There are few if any subscribers to the</emph>
                              Repository <emph rend="italics">who could not add but one new,
                                   responsible subscriber to its list within a month. Let the true
                                   friends of the country, in view of the importance of the coming
                                   Presidential Election, make an effort.</emph></p>

                         <p>Under the management of the present proprietors, the Repository will be
                              especially valuable to Farmers. An Agricultural Department will be
                              regularly sustained, under the management of gentlemen of experience
                              and learning. Experiments in Agriculture, Horticulture, the
                              improvements of Cereals for Seed, and improvement of Stock, will be
                              regularly recorded for the benefit of its readers.</p>

                         <p>Business Men of all classes will find the Repository and best
                              advertising medium in the State, outside of the cities. We believe
                              that no country journal reaches so large a class of intelligent,
                              progressive and thrifty men as does the Repository, and it is
                              invaluable to advertisers.</p>

                         <p>The Repository is furnished to subscribers at $2.50 per annum in
                              advance.</p>

                         <p>All subscription accounts must be settled annually. - No paper sent out
                              of the State unless paid for in advance. Subscriptions and
                              Advertisements may be sent directly to the Publishers or to any
                              responsible Agency.</p>

                         <p>Address. Cook &amp; Hays,<lb/> Successors to McClure &amp;
                              Stocer.</p>
                    </transcript>
                    <trailer/>
                    <names/>
                    <summary>The Repository, in this self-focused article, ties itself to the
                         Republican party, and thus calls upon all Republicans to spread its
                         circulation.</summary>
                    <note/>
                    <look/>
               </div>

               <div type="e">
                    <column>01</column>
                    <head>A Glance at Impeachment</head>
                    <origin/>
                    <commentary/>
                    <transcript>
                         <p>I have for three days been among the intensely interested spectators of
                              the great State trial of the first officer of the government, before
                              the first tribunal of the nation. I heard the profound argument and
                              matchless eloquence of Mr. Bingham, closing the case in behalf of the
                              outraged people and violated laws. While his argument was mainly over
                              beaten ground, his exordium and peroration were master specimens of
                              eloquence. The last half hour of his speech was listened to by every
                              Senator and by the thousands of spectators in breathless silence, and
                              when he closed the audience broke out in a thunder of applause. It was
                              not intended to be disrespectful to the high court, but it was the
                              spontaneous outburst of emotions which refused obedience to orderly
                              rules. In vain did Chief Justice Chase call for order, and follow it
                              with a turbulent demand that the galleries be cleared. It was an
                              expression that could not be stilled. As a thousand hands were wildly
                              clapped, nearly as many handkerchiefs waved in the ladies' gallery;
                              and when the order to clear the galleries was enforced in ill
                              concealed passion by Mr. Chase, a torrent of hisses answered back his
                              petulance as the tide of people streamed out of the door. Thus the
                              great trial closed, and it now only remains for the Senate to render
                              its verdict and pass sentence in pursuance thereof.</p>

                         <p>I will not attempt to speak of the merits of impeachment. It is needless
                              to do so after the able statesmen of the country have so completely
                              exhausted it. Not only every Senator, but every intelligent citizen of
                              the country, has made up his convictions on the subject, and the
                              nation now waits with deepest interest the verdict of the jurors. What
                              will it be? is the inquiry on every hand. Correspondents have given
                              the widest latitude to speculation in reference to the vote of the
                              Senate. More than enough of Republican Senators have been paraded
                              before the public as certain to vote for acquittal, and it has been
                              persisted in from the first day of the trial until now. I do not, of
                              course, have channels of information unknown to others, and do not
                              claim to be able to judge of the future action of Senators better than
                              others, but I feel that I hazard nothing in saying that the President
                              will be convicted in one or more of the articles by a vote of not less
                              than 40 out of the 54 senators; and I think it more than probable that
                              on the Stevens article, for conspiring to prevent the execution of the
                              civil tenure bill, the vote will embrace every Republican Senator. I
                              regard Grimes, Van Winkle and Fowler as the only Senators at all
                              doubtful on that vote, and it is at least probable that they will vote
                              with their Republican brethren. Messrs. Fessenden, Trumbull,
                              Frelinghuysen, Henderson, Sprague, Anthony and Sherman may vote "not
                              guilty" on several of the articles; but on the vital issue between
                              Congress and the President they will pronounce him a criminal and
                              depose him from his high trust. After the most careful inquiry, I do
                              not to day entertain the shadow of a doubt as to the result. The
                              President will be convicted, and one week from today Mr. Wade will be
                              in the Presidential office.</p>

                         <p>The country little knows how and why the success of impeachment has been
                              imperiled. While papers in sympathy with the President have been
                              holding up certain Senators as too conscientious and enlightened to
                              vote for conviction, they well knew that their only hope was in the
                              disappointed ambition of the Senators named. No Republican Senator who
                              has not political or personal grievances to avenge, has at any time
                              been doubtful on the question. "The last infirmity of noble minds" has
                              been most painfully visible throughout the trial; and but for the
                              united voice of the faithful people of the nation, demanding the
                              highest measure of integrity at the hands of their Senators,
                              impeachment would have ended in failure and the utter overthrow of
                              Republican rule. Mr. Chase was implacably hostile. It came just when
                              he had learned the bitter lesson that he could not be President, and
                              it added to his own disappointed ambition the still keener sting of
                              the success of his rival, Mr. Wade. He loves not Wade, for each has
                              shadowed the hopes and aspirations of the other. He envies Grant, for
                              gaining without a struggle what Chase has sought in vain for a quarter
                              of a century, forgetful that "whoever envies another confesses his
                              superiority?" Sprague is the son-in-law of Chase, and naturally in
                              sympathy with him. Grimes is an upright but disappointed and
                              embittered man. He is about to retire from public life, and would see
                              disaster take a wider sweep than his own oblivion. Van Winkle has
                              lingering sympathy with the South, as has Fowler, and they follow
                              radical domination reluctantly. Fessenden and Trumbull are great
                              leaders, but they have not led in impeachment, and they chafe like
                              caged eagles in subordinate positions. - With all their greatness they
                              cannot appreciate the popular sentiment, or governmental accidents,
                              which pass them by and fling others into the Presidency.- They are,
                              however, conscientious, and will vote in accordance with their
                              convictions, but they have moved reluctantly, and would be glad to
                              find good grounds for acquittal. As they cannot, they will vote to
                              convict. Anthony and Henderson sympathize with them, and would select
                              a thousand other men for President before Wade; they have not hastened
                              to remove Andrew Johnson. Ross has been esteemed doubtful - no matter
                              why.</p>

                         <p>Nor did the embarrassments in the way of impeachment stop with the mere
                              personal prejudices of Senators. There are not less then four Senators
                              who think it quite probable that the Chicago convention would take
                              them for Vice President, but for the fact that Mr. Wade will be in the
                              Presidency with vast patronage to dispense. They do not, of course,
                              wish impetuously to place Wade to vote to effect conviction, knowing
                              that he would at once resign and allow Mr. Colfax to take the prize;
                              but when detected it was soon abandoned. No man could be a party to
                              such a combination and have a future, and it was frowned out of
                              existence. Another interest looks to the nomination of Mr. Colfax for
                              Vice President, and it is more jealous of Mr. Wade's accession to the
                              Presidency, because it is presumed that it may nominate him for the
                              Vice Presidency. Mr. Colfax has not allowed his ambition to retard
                              impeachment for a moment, but there are half a score of Congressmen,
                              each of whom believes that he would certainly become Speaker if Mr.
                              Colfax should be promoted, and they have striven to delay impeachment,
                              and to make combinations and adverse interests have failed, simply
                              because impeachment is the cause of the people, and no man, or set of
                              men, was strong enough to resist it, or to defeat it by perfidious
                              machinations within the loyal ranks. It is a sublime triumph, before
                              which no ambition or prejudice has been able to stand, and I most
                              earnestly hope and believe that it will bring peace to our long
                              distracted nationality.</p>

                         <p>On Tuesday next the vote will be taken, and on Wednesday the judgment of
                              the court will be rendered and Mr. Wade qualified as President. He
                              will find a peaceful path to the White House, and there will not be a
                              ripple upon the wave of public sentiment. Beyond deposing Mr. Johnson,
                              I hope that sentence will not go. Ours is a government of the people,
                              and it is in their name that Andrew Johnson is to be deposed. Let him
                              be their ruler hereafter if they desire him. Let there be no obstacle
                              thrown in the way of Andrew Johnson's appealing from the Senate to the
                              supreme tribunal of the nation - the American People, and if he has
                              been wronged he can be vindicated, Deposed just when the people are
                              about to select a new Executive, there is especial fitness and
                              propriety in leaving every channel open to him to reverse the verdict
                              against him, for, if he shall not be chosen, he will retire with a
                              double condemnation. He merits this to complete the measure of popular
                              judgment, and seal in flaming and ineffaceable characters, his
                              matchless infamy. A. K. M.</p>

                         <p>Washington, May 7, 1868.</p>

                    </transcript>
                    <trailer/>
                    <names/>
                    <summary>The author analyzes the politics behind the impeachment trial,
                         including what will happen in the case of conviction and how this affects
                         individual Senators' votes.</summary>
                    <note/>
                    <look/>
               </div>

               <div type="e">
                    <column>03</column>
                    <head>The Railroad</head>
                    <origin/>
                    <commentary/>
                    <transcript>
                         <p>Unless the citizens of Chambersburg are willing to allow a golden
                              opportunity to pass; unless they are desirous of aiding foreign
                              localities from the wealth of our county, they should at once act in
                              this matter. Never has such an opportunity offered itself to our
                              Borough to build up its business; to make this the centre of trade for
                              Southern Pennsylvania; and to give employment to hundreds of laboring
                              men. In our local column we give a long and interesting account of a
                              meeting held in the Court House, on the 5th inst.- There was not a man
                              present who was not firmly convinced of the feasibility of the plan.
                              The large and wealthy Townships of Quincy and Washington, the richest
                              portion of this county, would contribute to our wealth, multiply our
                              commercial enterprises, double our population, and greatly enhance the
                              value of our property. Should this road connect with the Cumberland
                              Valley railroad below Scotland instead of at this point, we forever
                              will lose the advantages that are now within our grasp. Our people, to
                              be sure, would be compelled to come here once in a while at a Session
                              of Court, but on all other occasions they would pass us by and supply
                              their wants at some other place. And more than this, as all know, a
                              charter has been granted for a railroad from here to Gettysburg.
                              Suppose this Mont Alto road is extended from Fayetteville to Scotland,
                              the Gettysburg road will meet it there and go to Scotland, whilst, if
                              we build our portion of the road, this will be the terminus of the
                              Gettysburg Railroad. Seven miles of Gettysburg Railroad are graded in
                              Adams county, and we can make our six miles, only leaving twelve miles
                              to be completed through a pass in the South mountain, not requiring a
                              heavy grade. We have already discussed this question in previous
                              issues and must leave it entirely to those who have the financial
                              ability to say whether we shall become a live active town, or look
                              with wonder and astonishment at the chances we have missed, when
                              neighboring communities are prospering and our business is dull and
                              unprofitable.</p>
                    </transcript>
                    <trailer/>
                    <names/>
                    <summary>This article strongly encourages the proposed railroad terminating in
                         Chambersburg.</summary>
                    <note/>
                    <look/>
               </div>

               <div type="e">
                    <column>03</column>
                    <head/>
                    <origin/>
                    <commentary/>
                    <transcript>
                         <p>"North, South, East, or West,<lb/> Take the one that you love best." -
                              Old Song</p>

                         <p>The extreme flexibility of the Democratic party and policy has always
                              been a source of wonder and admiration to the uninitiated. The ease
                              with which it is "off with the old" and "on with the new," and the
                              cleverness with which opposites and even inconsistencies are merged
                              and woven with each other, are facts thoroughly established, but
                              peculiarly Democratic. In ancient days the good old Whig party - peace
                              to its ashes - stood amazed to find its favorite thunder, the
                              Protective tariff, stolen by an avowed free trade party, and its
                              biggest guns turned with terrific effect upon itself! And though
                              without spoils or power for years, it still shifts its scenes with all
                              the facility of the dissolving and appearing views of the diorama. To
                              illustrate: The last Democratic State Convention of Ohio, resolved
                              "that we are opposed both in principle and policy to negro suffrage."
                              This is view No. 1. The stage manager raises his hands, and No. 2
                              slowly rises out of the swamps of South Carolina: "Resolved, that we
                              declare our willingness, <emph rend="italics">when we have the
                              power</emph>, to grant the colored citizens, with proper
                              qualifications as to property and intelligence, the right of
                              suffrage." Another wave and another scene. It emerged out of the tall
                              grass of the Illinois prairies: "Resolved, that the right of suffrage
                              shall be limited to the white race in this country." One more wave and
                              the show closes with a scene from Georgia, painted by B. H. Hill, a
                              leading Democratic artist: "A very large torchlight procession of
                              Democratic Niggers are marching through the streets. Proclaim it
                              throughout upper Georgia, that everything is safe."</p>

                         <p>Now, taken by the four corners, this seems to unsophisticated Republican
                              eyes simply a mass of contradictions, from which only confusion worse
                              confounded could come. Democratic spectacles see through it at a
                              glance. "Democratic niggers" in Georgia are an excellent institution,
                              and should be encouraged.- "Democratic niggers" even in Illinois, if
                              there were any, with votes in their hands, would grow as comely as the
                              most perfectly fashioned Anglo Saxon. Democratic thunder against the
                              "nigger" would tone down into the gentle roar of the sucking dove;
                              thick lips would recede, projecting heels would shorten, flat feet
                              would assume the aristocratic curve - unfailing sign of gentle blood -
                              and the "horrible stink," by this little bit of paper, this unfailing
                              badge of manhood, would fall upon the Democratic olfactories with all
                              the grateful, delicious, sweetness of the balm of a thousand flowers.</p>

                         <p>We are glad that the Democracy of the South, with <emph rend="italics"
                                   >War Democracy</emph>, are in favor of Negro Suffrage, and we
                              take it that they are, otherwise they would hardly care to herald it
                              that "Democratic niggers" were marching through the streets burning
                              pine-knots, and thereby "everything was safe." But we protest against
                              the Democracy of Ohio and Illinois undertaking to deceive innocent
                              Republicans into the belief that they are opposed to "Democratic
                              niggers" voting.</p>
                    </transcript>
                    <trailer/>
                    <names/>
                    <summary>This article attacks what it calls inconsistencies in the Democratic
                         party's platform, as well as its poor treatment of the freedmen.</summary>
                    <note/>
                    <look/>
               </div>

               <pageNote/>
          </page>

          <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.05.13.03" exists="no">

               <div type="a">
                    <column>01</column>
                    <head>Railroad Meeting</head>
                    <origin/>
                    <commentary/>
                    <transcript>
                         <p>On Tuesday, the 5th inst, a large audience assembled in the Court House
                              for the purpose of listening to a statement of Col. Wiestling in
                              regard to the projected Railroad from Waynesboro to this point. Many
                              were conjectures we heard concerning the number of persons that would
                              be in attendance, but on entering the room it was manifest that our
                              citizens were aroused to the necessity of exerting themselves, and had
                              determined to gain all possible information on the subject. Some of
                              our wealthiest business men were present, and we think were convinced
                              of the feasibility of the route.</p>

                         <p>There are no great reasons why the citizens of Waynesboro, Washington
                              and Quincy townships should bring this road to this place, as it can
                              be built at much less expense to Scotland, yet the good people of the
                              Eastern portion of this county are willing to put themselves to some
                              inconvenience to enlarge and improve their county town.</p>

                         <p>We have gone to some trouble to give an accurate and lengthy account of
                              the proceedings, and would invite the attention of our readers to a
                              careful perusal of the able and practical remarks of the eloquent
                              gentlemen who addressed the meeting.</p>

                         <p>On motion of Col. M'Gowan, the meeting was organized by choosing Col.
                              James C. Austin President, and Calvin M. Duncan, Esq., Vice President.</p>

                         <p>Col. George B. Wiestling then being introduced by the Chairman, spoke as
                              follows:</p>

                         <p><emph rend="italics">Mr. President and Gentlemen:</emph> - I suppose
                              that all present are aware that I am not here to appeal to you for
                              favorable action in making this place the Northern terminus of the
                              Mont Alto Railroad, but merely to advise you of the origin and
                              progress of the enterprise - of the motives which prompted the wishes
                              of the citizens of the Eastern portion of the county, to extend the
                              road to Waynesboro, and of its general condition and prospects at
                              present. The propriety of confining myself to this, will be manifest
                              to you, when you consider that a connection with the Cumberland Valley
                              Railroad, at or near Scotland, will not only cost less in the
                              construction of our road and from the favorable alignments and
                              gradients to that point, be quite as cheaply operated when built, but
                              that the mileage to the Susquehanna river for all the tonnage of
                              Quincy and Washington townships will be at least six miles less, than
                              it will be with this place as our connecting point. If in what I have
                              to say, I refer frequently to the Mt. Alto Iron company and their
                              works, I trust it will not be attributed to egoism or selfishness, but
                              simply to the fact that under the circumstances it is necessary and
                              unavoidable. * * * * He then proceeded to give a history of the
                              enterprise from its commencement, during which he read extracts from
                              the "Report of Prof. J. Peter Lesley, Topographical Geologist, to the
                              President and Directors of the Cumberland Valley Railroad company;"
                              demonstrating the feasibility of a railroad to Mont Alto, with the
                              certainty of obtaining in sufficient quantity to support the road. He
                              explained the cause which delayed the construction of the road thus
                              long, and stated that the time had now arrived, when some of the
                              manufactories in the South eastern portion of the county, were
                              compelled to have railroad facilities by the exigencies of their
                              business, either by a connection with the Cumberland Valley or the
                              Western Maryland road; or as an alternative remove their
                              establishments elsewhere, to other counties, where such facilities
                              could be enjoyed. He drew attention to the fact that the road was not
                              only perfectly feasible, at exceedingly low cost of construction, and
                              could be operated very cheaply in consequence of its favorable
                              location; but that the amount of business which could be furnished to
                              it would in all human probability make it paying stock.</p>

                         <p>He brought into comparison roads in operations in other portions of the
                              State, carriers of ore, which had not nearly the territory tributary
                              to them which this would have, which had little or no passenger
                              travel, which all knew this would have considerable; which carried
                              little or no agricultural products, or implements or merchandise while
                              a knowledge of the <emph rend="italics">section through which the
                              road</emph> was to pass, was a guarantee of the amount of the
                              character of tonnage it would enjoy; which were dependent on no richer
                              or more extensive deposits of iron ore than this road would penetrate,
                              and which were expensive in their construction and yet were divided
                              paying roads. He stated that the citizens of Washington and Quincy
                              townships had awakened to a lively appreciation of these advantages -
                              had taken prompt and vigorous action, and had already subscribed
                              $100,000 to the capital stock, and believed that with the expected
                              assistance of the Cumberland Valley Railroad company and Mont Alto
                              Iron company, the early completion of the road was a fixed fact. That
                              the road with Scotland the Waynesboro as termini (about 18 miles in
                              length.) was estimated to cost about $360,000; and that with
                              Chambersburg as the Northern terminus, it would be upwards of one mile
                              longer, and cost probably somewhat more per mile for a portion of it.
                              He stated that while the South-eastern section of the county realized
                              the advantages which Scotland offered as a connecting point, they
                              still felt a lively interest in their shiretown, and he believed there
                              were none who would not prefer making Chambersburg the terminus,
                              provided it was made equally advantageous. He closed by reminding the
                              audience that the investment not only provided ample, direct,
                              legitimate compensation, but by it the whole community would be
                              benefited, and take another step forward in material progress.</p>

                         <p>We have given but the substance of the Colonel's speech, owing to a want
                              of room to publish it all. He was followed by I. H. M'Cauley, Esq.,
                              who said:</p>

                         <p><emph rend="italics">Mr. Chairman:</emph> - I had no thought of saying
                              anything when I came into this meeting, but after what has been stated
                              by my friend, Col. Wiestling, I am more deeply than ever impressed
                              with the importance to our town and people of the matter under
                              consideration. That we will shortly have a railroad built from
                              Waynesboro to connect with the Cumberland Valley road, is now a fixed
                              fact. Shall the point of connection be below Scotland, five or six
                              miles from us - or shall it be <emph rend="italics">here</emph>. Shall
                              we lose the benefit of the large amount of travel and business it will
                              necessarily create, or shall we make an effort and have it brought
                              into our midst. You have been shown by my friend, Col. Wiestling that
                              railroads much more costly than this will be, built through mining
                              district's, are <emph rend="italics">paying</emph>, and why not this
                              one. The people of our county do not, in my opinion, have any adequate
                              conception of the immense wealth that lies buried in our soil. We are
                              generally regarded as an <emph rend="italics">Agricultural</emph>
                              community, with but few large manufacturing establishments. Our county
                              is yet undeveloped, so far as its mineral wealth is concerned. I have
                              been told by a gentleman who <emph rend="italics">knows</emph>, and
                              who has been through all the large iron mining regions of this State -
                              upon the Ironton railroad, and the Catasaqua and Fogelsville railroad
                              - roads built to bring out iron ore exclusively - and who has also
                              been through the large ore producing districts of the Eastern States -
                              that he knows from a careful examination, that there is nowhere in the
                              United States a body of <emph rend="italics">Hematite</emph> ore
                              comparable in extent in richness, and in value, with that lying along
                              the base of the mountains which bound the Eastern side of our county.
                              The value of the iron made at "Hughes' Works" is well known
                              everywhere. It owes its quantity to the peculiar character of the ore
                              out of which it is made. Open a railroad through that immensely
                              valuable ore region and in five years from that time it is opened, you
                              will see twenty furnaces in full blast, with their immense
                              expenditures where there is now one. All that is wanted is an outlet
                              for the ore there lying buried out of sight in the bowels of the
                              earth. It is sought for even as far West as Central Ohio - the largest
                              establishments in the richest iron regions of our own State need and
                              would gladly use it, if they could get it. And as an evidence of its
                              importance and value, I will simply state that I have it from good
                              authority, that an iron establishment in the centre of our own State,
                              that could only procure 200 tons per week with the ore they are
                              compelled to use was by buying this hematite ore to mix with theirs,
                              enabled to produce 300 tons in the same time. Any one can see the
                              immense importance that the development of this ore alone will be to
                              our country. Large sums of money will at once be invested, upon the
                              making of the road. Our population must necessarily be largely
                              increased. Our agricultural products will have a home market, at good
                              prices, and all to whom this trade and money shall come cannot fail to
                              be largely benefited by it.</p>

                         <p>Now shall we let this trade do by us, never to return or benefit us, or
                              shall we seek by a generous effort to bring it to our town, its
                              natural centre. Chambersburg, I tell you, Mr. Chairman cannot afford
                              to lose this trade. The people of Waynesboro, we are informed have
                              already raised over $50,000 to build this road and say that they will
                              make it $100,000. All honor to them! They deserve to have a first
                              class railroad to their rich agricultural and mineral lands. The
                              people along the route have pledged themselves for $50,000 more - and
                              we are only asked to give as much as will pay the increased cost of
                              coming here, over going to Scotland. I tell you, my friends, that if
                              this effort fails, there is a great danger that the people of Quincy
                              and Washington townships will turn around and seek an outlet by the
                              Western Maryland road, which will be finished to Baltimore within a
                              year and which they can reach in four or five miles, at a much less
                              expense than they are willing to put into the road to this place, and
                              where will Chambersburg lie then? The trade of the richest part of her
                              territory will have gone from her <emph rend="italics">forever</emph>,
                              and thousands of dollars will be spent elsewhere which would be spent
                              here if the proper facilities for trade and travel were only offered.</p>

                         <p>Our town should earnestly <emph rend="italics">seek</emph> the opening
                              of arteries of trade and travel such as this. We should invest in them
                              to the extent of our means. They will <emph rend="italics">pay</emph>,
                              if not in dividends, yet in the increased value of real estate, and
                              through the business they will bring to our merchants and mechanics.
                              The day is not far distant when we will have a railway East over the
                              mountains and westward to the coal fields of Broadtop, and on to the
                              Ohio. Nor is the day far distant when the great line of travel from
                              the North to the South will be through this valley and town. We have
                              now a direct and continuous line from New York to within a few miles
                              of the Potomac and but few lines are wanting, and they will soon be
                              made, to complete the chain to New Orleans. <emph rend="italics"
                              >Then</emph> instead of one line of rails over the Cumberland Valley,
                              you will soon see two or more and where we have now one train of cars,
                              we will then have twenty, bearing along their rich fruits of goods,
                              and their thousands of idle pleasure-seekers, and hurrying, busy men.</p>

                         <p>Therefore, entreat the business men of Chambersburg to arouse themselves
                              to their true interests, and take such immediate measures as will aid
                              the construction of this road to this point and thus secure that which
                              there is great danger to fear they will never lose, if they let the
                              present opportunity pass.</p>

                         <p>C. M. Duncan, Esq., then addresses the meeting as follows:</p>

                         <p><emph rend="italics">Mr. President and Fellow Citizens:</emph> - This is
                              a practical question, it concerns every citizen of this borough. The
                              rich and the poor, the merchant, mechanic, the tradesman and laborer -
                              all are directly interested in the construction of this proposed road
                              between Waynesboro and Chambersburg.</p>

                         <p>After the remarks and discussion of the gentlemen who preceded me, I
                              presume no one present will doubt for a moment the vital importance of
                              this question and the necessity of one immediate action. Mr.
                              President, time, in my judgment, Sir, is an essential thing in this
                              matter. Now the people of Waynesboro, Quincy, Mont Alto and
                              Fayetteville, though joined to us by ties of common interest, already
                              propose by their liberal subscriptions to this road, to bind
                              themselves to us in bands of steel. Now they stretch forth their hands
                              towards us; and will we, the citizens of Chambersburg, shrink back?
                              Will we spurn their generous proffer? Can we do so without peril to
                              the vital interest of our town?</p>

                         <p>We should at once accept the proposition made to us by the citizens
                              along the proposed route, for if not now accepted, that wealthy and
                              enterprising people in Washington and Quincy township will not rest
                              until they have railroad communication with some other point. It may
                              be a branch road connection with the Western Maryland road - when it
                              will be too late for us here to bestir ourselves. With such a road
                              running South, we would lose all the trade and commerce of that
                              portion of our county, which is by far the wealthiest portion in
                              agricultural products and mineral ores. Lose it, and lose it forever!</p>

                         <p>Look at the advantages and benefits that would flow to us and to our
                              town, by a railroad running from Waynesboro to this point. Along the
                              route are located the best farms, mills, and live there most wealthy
                              and enterprising citizens to be found in this whole valley. Their
                              farms, mills, factories, furnaces and shops will pour their products
                              over this road. And along the route, nature has hid in her bosom
                              treasures of untold millions, in belts and veins, beds and strata of
                              iron ore. A railroad will compel dame nature to yield up to man her
                              treasures. She will pour her wealth into the pockets and coffers of
                              all our citizens. To the development of these vast beds of ore the
                              Iron Company of Mont Alto has already done much, but they need and
                              will have the facilities of a railroad, to operate more extensively
                              and satisfactory.</p>

                         <p>This energetic Iron Company of Mont Alto at first contemplated building
                              merely a freight railroad, to connect their works with Scotland; but,
                              encouraged in this railroad enterprise by citizens along the route,
                              and by the people of Waynesboro and vicinity, and requested to build a
                              first class road terminating at Chambersburg - they have finally
                              consented to do so. This will of course cost more money; and now, we
                              the citizens of Chambersburg are asked to contribute something.</p>

                         <p>We will contribute! We can't afford to let this railroad pass around our
                              town, with the terminus at Scotland - Chambersburg can't allow
                              Scotland to rival her in this matter. Let this proposition be at once
                              accepted - let us act at once, promptly and energetically. Let us all
                              join in an enterprise which cannot fail to be of interest and
                              advantage. And let a little of the energy and zeal of Col. Wiestling
                              be infused into our slumbering energies. Let us build this road, and a
                              new energy will be awakened along the whole route - new mills and
                              factories will arise and shake the hills with the hum and buzz of
                              whirling wheels and whistling spindles, new furnaces will arise,
                              forges be built, and from a hundred chimnies and stacks clouds of
                              smoke will darken the very heavens. A few years since, I visited the
                              Iron Mountains in Missouri, then some ten or twelve furnaces were
                              built there - now, Sirs, hundreds of furnaces and forges are
                              converting the iron ore into greenbacks, at no small rate. The Iron
                              Mountain railroad has done wonders there. This projected road will do
                              wonders for us here.</p>

                         <p>Now, Mr. President, this Iron Company of Mont Alto will have a railroad,
                              and if we fail at this time to move in the matter, we may waken to our
                              true interests too late. When they once have a freight road to
                              Scotland directly from their works, it might afterwards be converted
                              into a first-class road, but then we shall have lost, and lost
                              forever, the most favorable opportunity to have the terminus here.
                              Then we will have lost all that vast trade and travel of the whole
                              Eastern section of our county, with Scotland rivaling Chambersburg.
                              Sir, if we fail to act, and act promptly in this matter, we shall
                              prove ourselves blind to a project which is of vital importance to our
                              town - blind to our highest interests. If we fail to encourage this
                              enterprise now, we may never have another opportunity so favorable.
                              These proffers by parties along the route are made <emph
                                   rend="italics">now</emph> - six months, twelve months hence they
                              may change their minds. Let us then all join in this work now, and
                              there will be no failure.</p>

                         <p>Col. F. S. Stumbaugh made a few brief remarks, telling the audience how
                              in other days Chambersburg had permitted the Penna. Railroad to pass
                              us by when our town might have been along its route.</p>

                         <p>On motion of Col. McGowan, the following well known gentlemen were
                              appointed a committee to solicit subscriptions: - J. A. Eyster, C. M.
                              Duncan, Wm L. Chambers, H. M. White, T. B. Wood.</p>

                         <p>On motion of Col. Stumbaugh, it was resolved that the committee be
                              requested to report on Tuesday evening, the 19th of May. On motion of
                              John Stewart, Esq., the meeting adjourned. We hope this committee will
                              meet with success.</p>
                    </transcript>
                    <trailer/>
                    <names>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Wiestling</ln>
                              <fn>George B.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf>Col.</pf>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>M'Gowan</ln>
                              <fn/>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf>Col.</pf>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Austin</ln>
                              <fn>James C.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf>Col.</pf>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Duncan</ln>
                              <fn>Calvin M.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                              <fn>F. S.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf>Col.</pf>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Eyster</ln>
                              <fn>J. A.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Duncan</ln>
                              <fn>C. M.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Chambers</ln>
                              <fn>William L.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>White</ln>
                              <fn>H. M.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Wood</ln>
                              <fn>T. B.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                    </names>
                    <summary>This article contains several full speeches from a recent meeting
                         concerning whether the town of Chambersburg should strive to work with
                         neighboring communities to create a first-class railroad with a terminus in
                         Chambersburg. Each of the speeches is strongly in favor of the idea.</summary>
                    <note/>
                    <look/>
               </div>

               <div type="a">
                    <column>02</column>
                    <head>Improvements</head>
                    <origin/>
                    <commentary/>
                    <trailer/>
                    <names>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Hetrick</ln>
                              <fn>George</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Chambers</ln>
                              <fn/>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf>Ms.</pf>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Chambers</ln>
                              <fn>William L.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Beatty</ln>
                              <fn>Walter</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Doebler</ln>
                              <fn/>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf>Sheriff</pf>
                         </name>
                    </names>
                    <summary>George Hetrick improved the appearance of his house on South Front
                         Street by painting it. The Misses Chambers have erected a mansion on the
                         grounds formerly owned by William L. Chambers, and Walter Beatty and
                         Sheriff Doebler have both had houses built. The Town Council is discussing
                         building a bridge across the spring on King Street.</summary>
                    <note/>
                    <look/>
               </div>

               <div type="a">
                    <column>02</column>
                    <head/>
                    <origin/>
                    <commentary/>
                    <trailer/>
                    <names>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Crawford</ln>
                              <fn>John R.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Greenawalt</ln>
                              <fn>D. B.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Greenawalt</ln>
                              <fn>H. C.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Hartzel</ln>
                              <fn>E.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf>Dr.</pf>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Cook</ln>
                              <fn>Jacob B.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>M'Elroy</ln>
                              <fn>Robert T. M.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Long</ln>
                              <fn>D. W.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                    </names>
                    <summary>The citizens of Fayetteville constructed a building that will house a
                         new town hall and village school. The stockholders of the association
                         elected officers.</summary>
                    <note/>
                    <look/>
               </div>

               <div type="a">
                    <column>02</column>
                    <head/>
                    <origin/>
                    <commentary/>
                    <trailer/>
                    <names>
                         <name>
                              <ln>M'Clure</ln>
                              <fn>J. M.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                    </names>
                    <summary>J. M. M'Clure has opened a law office in Ludwig's building opposite the
                         Chambersburg court house. He is a Yale graduate who studied law with
                         M'Clure and Stewart and was admitted to the bar in 1867. He carries the
                         endorsement of the paper.</summary>
                    <note/>
                    <look/>
               </div>

               <div type="a">
                    <column>03</column>
                    <head>Appointments</head>
                    <origin/>
                    <commentary/>
                    <trailer/>
                    <names>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Clarke</ln>
                              <fn>Lyman S.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Seiders</ln>
                              <fn>John A.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Fahnestock</ln>
                              <fn>Daniel S.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Lippy</ln>
                              <fn>Levi P.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Greenawalt</ln>
                              <fn>John</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Snyder</ln>
                              <fn>Nicholas</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Dittman</ln>
                              <fn>John</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Leisher</ln>
                              <fn>David F.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                    </names>
                    <summary>The following have been appointed to Chambersburg town council posts:
                         Lyman S. Clarke, attorney for council; John A. Seiders, secretary for
                         council; Daniel S. Fahnestock, borough treasurer; Levi P. Lippy, lamp
                         lighter, N.W.; John Greenawalt, lamp lighter, S.W.; Nicholas Snyder, wood
                         inspector, N.W.; John Dittman, wood inspector, S.W.; David F. Leisher, tax
                         collector.</summary>
                    <note/>
                    <look/>
               </div>

               <div type="a">
                    <column>03</column>
                    <head/>
                    <origin/>
                    <commentary/>
                    <trailer/>
                    <names>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Eby</ln>
                              <fn>J. S.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                              <fn>T. B.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                    </names>
                    <summary>J. S. Eby moved his office to the second floor of Ludwig's Building on
                         the Diamond opposite the Court House. Mr. Eby was admitted to the bar in
                         1865 after studying with T. B. Kennedy. He then worked for a time with Mr.
                         Kennedy.</summary>
                    <note/>
                    <look/>
               </div>

               <div type="a">
                    <column>03</column>
                    <head/>
                    <origin/>
                    <commentary/>
                    <trailer/>
                    <names>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Ashcom</ln>
                              <fn>C. W.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Deitrich</ln>
                              <fn>J. L. P.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                    </names>
                    <summary>C. W. Ashcom, collector of the district, will be at the office of J. L.
                         P. Deitrich on Second Street between the 19th and 21st of May.</summary>
                    <note/>
                    <look/>
               </div>

               <div type="a">
                    <column>03</column>
                    <head/>
                    <origin/>
                    <commentary/>
                    <trailer/>
                    <names/>
                    <summary>Chambersburg's newest band played in front of Repository Hall. They
                         promise to become "first-class" musicians.</summary>
                    <note/>
                    <look/>
               </div>

               <div type="a">
                    <column>03</column>
                    <head>Law Partnership</head>
                    <origin/>
                    <commentary/>
                    <trailer/>
                    <names>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Cook</ln>
                              <fn>Jere</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Hays</ln>
                              <fn>S. W.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                    </names>
                    <summary>Jere Cook and S. W. Hays have formed a law partnership. They have taken
                         up an office in the Repository Building.</summary>
                    <note/>
                    <look/>
               </div>

               <div type="a">
                    <column>03</column>
                    <head>Notary Public Appointed</head>
                    <origin/>
                    <commentary/>
                    <trailer/>
                    <names>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Hostetter</ln>
                              <fn>Jacob</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                    </names>
                    <summary>Gov. Geary has re-appointed Jacob Hostetter a notary public for
                         Greencastle.</summary>
                    <note/>
                    <look/>
               </div>

               <div type="s">
                    <column>04</column>
                    <head>Married</head>
                    <origin/>
                    <commentary/>
                    <trailer/>
                    <names>
                         <name>
                              <ln>M'Kimm</ln>
                              <fn>Edward N.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Creamer</ln>
                              <fn>Catharine E.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Hummelbaugh</ln>
                              <fn>H. Y.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf>Rev.</pf>
                         </name>
                    </names>
                    <summary>Edward N. M'Kimm of Adams County and Mrs. Catharine E. Creamer of
                         Marion, Franklin County, were married at the U. B. Parsonage on May 5th by
                         the Rev. H. Y. Hummelbaugh.</summary>
                    <note/>
                    <look/>
               </div>

               <div type="o">
                    <column>04</column>
                    <head>Died</head>
                    <origin/>
                    <commentary/>
                    <trailer/>
                    <names>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Crider</ln>
                              <fn>Tobias</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                    </names>
                    <summary>Tobias Crider died in Letterkenny on May 9th. He was 70 years old.</summary>
                    <note/>
                    <look/>
               </div>

               <div type="o">
                    <column>04</column>
                    <head>Died</head>
                    <origin/>
                    <commentary/>
                    <trailer/>
                    <names>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Aldridge</ln>
                              <fn>Willie</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Aldridge</ln>
                              <fn>William H.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Aldridge</ln>
                              <fn>Lucy</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                    </names>
                    <summary>Willie Aldridge, infant son of William H. and Lucy Aldridge, died on
                         April 9th. He was 10 months old.</summary>
                    <note/>
                    <look/>
               </div>

               <div type="o">
                    <column>04</column>
                    <head>Died</head>
                    <origin/>
                    <commentary/>
                    <trailer/>
                    <names>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Blair</ln>
                              <fn>Nancy Jane</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Blair</ln>
                              <fn>W. H.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Smith</ln>
                              <fn>W. L.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                    </names>
                    <summary>Nancy Jane Blair, wife of W. H. Blair and daughter of W. L. Smith, died
                         in Orrstown on April 29th. She was 37 years old.</summary>
                    <note/>
                    <look/>
               </div>

               <div type="o">
                    <column>04</column>
                    <head>Died</head>
                    <origin/>
                    <commentary/>
                    <trailer/>
                    <names>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Mains</ln>
                              <fn>Marshall</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                    </names>
                    <summary>Marshall Mains of Southampton died on May 5th. He was 40 years old.</summary>
                    <note/>
                    <look/>
               </div>

               <pageNote/>
          </page>

          <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.05.13.04" exists="no">


               <pageNote/>
          </page>

     </paperBody>
</hwp>
