
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1868/pa.fr.fr.1868.03.18">

    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>

        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>05/09/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>

        <address>
<city>Chambersburg</city>
<county>Franklin</county>
<state>Pennsylvania</state>
</address>

        <date n="1868-03-18">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day>18</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
    </header>

    <paperBody>

        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.03.18.01" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.03.18.02" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Clure</ln>
                        <fn>A. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A. K. M'Clure will lecture in Repository Hall on "Life in the Rocky
                    Mountains." Tickets are 25 cents. Proceeds will go to benefit the Mission
                    School.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Our Standard-Bearers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Republicans of Pennsylvania have, with marked unanimity, presented their
                        standard-bearers and their platform of principles, to the world, and with
                        them they are prepared to buckle on their armors and carry their cause
                        before the great tribunal of the people.</p>
                    <p>Gen. Ulysses S. Grant is the choice of the Republicans of the whole Union for
                        the Presidency. There are individuals in the Republican party who prefer
                        others, but the sentiment of the party in all sections, is overwhelmingly
                        for him as our candidate. He is preferred not merely because he is
                        invincible before the people as he was in war, and thus certain to carry our
                        banner victoriously; but he is chosen mainly because the nation has
                        unbounded confidence in his integrity, patriotism and enlightened
                        statesmanship. No man in the country has manifested a clearer appreciation
                        of our internal political troubles than Gen. Grant, and his acts show that
                        he can and will administer the government wisely and well, and command for
                        his policy the largest measure of public confidence. He has been tested not
                        only on the field, but also in the cabinet, and in the whole administration
                        of public affairs in the lately insurgent States, and he has proven himself
                        a master man to grapple with the great issues to be decided and the
                        principles to be enforced in restoring the whole Union to peace and
                        prosperity. While Gen. Grant is available as the most heroic and successful
                        of our military chieftains, we rejoice that he is not untried in the
                        intricate paths of statesmanship.--As a candidate he will, therefore,
                        commend himself to the sober judgment of patriotic people, as well as to the
                        gratitude of the nation for his battles won, and his defeat is not within
                        the range of possibility. He will receive the largest popular vote, and the
                        largest vote in the electoral college, ever received by any candidate for
                        the Presidency. Kentucky, Maryland and Delaware may vote against him, but
                        all the northern States, with the ten rebellious States soon to be admitted,
                        will cast their votes for him, and by unprecedented majorities.</p>
                    <p>Gov. Andrew G. Curtin is presented for the Vice Presidency as the choice of
                        the Republicans of the State, and the enthusiasm with which his nomination
                        was greeted in the Convention was conclusive as to the earnestness of the
                        Republicans of Pennsylvania in presenting his name. At the largest
                        ratification meeting ever held in Philadelphia, on the evening after the
                        convention, his reception was the most enthusiastic we have ever seen given
                        to any public man in our State. He is not without competitors for the Vice
                        Presidency. Ohio presents Mr. Wade; Illinois has instructed for Colfax; New
                        York for Gov. Fenton and Massachusetts for Senator Wilson; but we feel
                        assured that, with the candidate for the Presidency in the west, the united
                        and earnest appeal of Pennsylvania will not be disregarded. Her delegation
                        will present no common name to the Chicago Convention to gild it with
                        unmeaning compliments. They will present one whose record is second only to
                        the great Chieftain Grant in subduing treason and giving victory to our
                        brave soldiers and to the Republic. First among our representative men in
                        point of ability and statesmanship, and endeared to the loyal people
                        everywhere for his ceaseless effort in behalf of our soldiers, his name will
                        be a tower of strength even to Gen. Grant in Pennsylvania, where the great
                        battle is to be fought. He has not only left his impress indelibly upon the
                        history of our State by his wise, economical, and eminently successful
                        administrations as Governor, but his name and his noble deeds are enshrined
                        in every heart that beats in unison with the loyal cause. There is not a
                        soldier of Pennsylvania who does not lisp his name with pride and affection,
                        and his nomination would inspire the liveliest personal enthusiasm in the
                        coming contest. We confidently trust that the claim of Pennsylvania, to be
                        made with such an enthusiastic and united sentiment, will be accepted by the
                        national convention, and that the magic names of GRANT and CURTIN will rally
                        the Republicans to their most decisive victory in 1868.</p>
                    <p>Of Gen. Hartranft, the candidate for Auditor General, and Col. Campbell, for
                        Surveyor General, we need not speak in detail. Both are gallant soldiers,
                        and blameless officers. Gen. Hartranft was the brave leader who re-captured
                        Fort Steadman after the rebels had stormed it, and he assaulted the
                        Democratic lines with equal success in Pennsylvania in 1865, when he was
                        elected to the office for which he has been re-nominated. He is a soldier
                        who has never lost a battle, and he will achieve another signal triumph in
                        October next. Both these gallant men have discharged their official duties
                        so satisfactorily that malignant partizanship has yet to accuse them of
                        wrong, and they will be triumphantly re-elected next fall.</p>
                    <p>--Such is the Republican ticket of Pennsylvania. It is headed with the name
                        of the first soldier of the Republic. Next is presented the name of the
                        great War Governor--the Soldiers' Friend, and the names of two heroic
                        soldiers complete the list of Republican candidates. This ticket means Loyal
                        Reconstruction, National Faith, Universal Freedom, Impartial Justice,
                        Victory, Peace! Who can doubt its overwhelming success!</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper presents the Republican candidates for President, Vice President,
                    Auditor General and Surveyor General nominated by Pennsylvania. The editors laud
                    the exploits of Grant, push heavily for Curtin's nomination for Vice President,
                    and put in good words for Hartranft and Campbell for the other two offices.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper gloats that Andrew Johnson, now that impeachment is looming, is
                    treating congress with respect, a body he once denounced as "revolutionary,
                    tyrannical, and unconstitutional."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.03.18.03" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Metal Township Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolff</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Devor</ln>
                        <fn>Amos</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>William S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>John D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elliot</ln>
                        <fn>F. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flickinger</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Typer</ln>
                        <fn>A. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilhelm</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flagel</ln>
                        <fn>Adam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Welker</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Ginley</ln>
                        <fn>A. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Jeremiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Curdy</ln>
                        <fn>S. O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Montgomery</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Republicans of Metal nominated the following for town offices: John
                    Wolff for judge; Amos Devor for inspector; William S. Harris, John D. Walker,
                    and F. W. Elliot for school directors; Jacob Flickinger for supervisor; A. C.
                    Typer for assessor; J. M. Wilhelm for auditor; Adam Flagel for constable. John
                    Walker bought the farm that had been the property of Rev. A. A. M'Ginley for 75
                    dollars an acre. Jeremiah Miller bought the farm of the late Joseph Brown for
                    $9,000. S. O. M'Curdy bought the property of Jere Miller at $100 per acre. Dr.
                    Montgomery gave a lecture at the lyceum on "Quackery" in which he denounced
                    quacks in the medical profession.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>I. O. of G. T.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Noble</ln>
                        <fn>William R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCurdy</ln>
                        <fn>S. O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hill</ln>
                        <fn>James M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>A. Calvin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Ellen</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Espy S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Montgomery</ln>
                        <fn>Annie E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kell</ln>
                        <fn>Emma V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>George A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reeder</ln>
                        <fn>Cynthia A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swank</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kegerries</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gallagher</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>James M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>At a meeting of Fannettsburg Lodge No. 226 of the I. O. of G. T., William
                    R. Noble, S. O. McCurdy, and James M. Hill installed the following officers: A.
                    Calvin Wilson, Ellen Miller, Espy S. Miller, Annie E. Montgomery, Emma V. Kell,
                    George A. Miller, Thomas J. Campbell, Cynthia A. Reeder, Benjamin F. Jones,
                    Maggie L. Swank, Rebecca E. Kegerries, Mary E. Gallagher, James M. Miller. This
                    lodge was organized one year ago with 24 members. I now boasts 45 members and is
                    becoming "one of the best Lodges in the county."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Ward Nominations</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Caufman</ln>
                        <fn>A. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eby</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamman</ln>
                        <fn>Philip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Forbes</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Frey</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Clellan</ln>
                        <fn>Rufus K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Republicans of the North Ward met at the Union Hotel and nominated the
                    following: A. D. Caufman for judge; Jacob S. Eby for inspector; and Philip
                    Hamman for constable. The Republicans of the South Ward met at the Indian Queen
                    Hotel and nominated the following: John Forbes for judge; Joseph Frey for
                    inspector; and Rufus K. M'Clellan for constable.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Public Schools</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Examinations of the public schools have begun in Chambersburg. The Board of
                    Directors and Teachers ask that parents and guardians be present to witness the
                    examinations.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>An Old Citizen Gone</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitmore</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Joseph Whitmore died at his residence near Shady Grove. He was 73 years old
                    and a native of Antrim. Many friends and neighbors attended the funeral at the
                    Lutheran cemetery.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Religious</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>S. H. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Rev. S. H. C. Smith will preach in the Methodist Church on Sunday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Royer</ln>
                        <fn>Morris</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bosserman</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Callendar</ln>
                        <fn>S. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Morris Royer and Miss Sarah Bosserman, both of Waynesboro, were married on
                    February 5th by the Rev. S. N. Callendar.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hussong</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schultz</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Callendar</ln>
                        <fn>S. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Hussong and Miss Catharine Schultz, both of Antrim, were married on
                    February 27th by the Rev. S. N. Callendar.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burger</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shook</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>W. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Burger of Maryland and Miss Mary Ann Shook of Middleburg were married
                    on February 27th by the Rev. W. F. Eyster.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hahn</ln>
                        <fn>John E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mayhugh</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>W. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John E. Hahn of Waynesboro and Miss Catharine Mayhugh of Maryland were
                    married on March 4th by the Rev. W. F. Eyster.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nikerk</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ruthrauff</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>W. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel Nikerk of Franklin and Miss Mary E. Ruthrauff of Maryland were
                    married on March 5th by the Rev. W. F. Eyster.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Charles H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beebe</ln>
                        <fn>Nettie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beebe</ln>
                        <fn>O. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Warner</ln>
                        <fn>E. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Charles H. Smith of Montrose and Miss Nettie Beebe, daughter of O. S.
                    Beebe, were married in Montrose at the residence of the bride's father on March
                    2nd by the Rev. E. A. Warner.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Benedict</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>E. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J. Keller</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. Jacob Benedict of Peters and Miss E. A. Reed of New Franklin were
                    married on March 10th in New Franklin at the residence of Mr. Reed by the Rev.
                    J. Keller Miller.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gamble</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shearer</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>West</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>David Gamble and Mrs. Mary Shearer, both of Spring Run, were married on
                    March 12th by the Rev. William A. West.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McAfee</ln>
                        <fn>Louisa</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McAfee</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craig</ln>
                        <fn>Jesse</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Louisa McAfee, wife of Rev. John McAfee and daughter of Jesse Craig of
                    Welsh Run, died suddenly in Bedford on March 6th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harvey</ln>
                        <fn>Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Jane Harvey died in Spring Run on February 29th. She was 64 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fleming</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Mary Fleming died near Dry Run on March 3rd. She was 81 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keller</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>David Keller died near Grindstone Hill Church on March 11th. He was 66
                    years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.03.18.04" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

    </paperBody>
</hwp>
