
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1868/pa.fr.fr.1868.06.03">

    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>

        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>05/12/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>

        <address>
<city>Chambersburg</city>
<county>Franklin</county>
<state>Pennsylvania</state>
</address>

        <date n="1868-06-03">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="06">June</month>
            <day>03</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
    </header>

    <paperBody>

        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.06.03.01" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.06.03.02" exists="no">

            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Why did Impeachment Fail?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Impeachment has failed. On Tuesday of last week the closing act of the
                        imposing drama was performed, and the verdict of the Senate clothes the
                        President with unbridled power to accept or nullify the laws at his
                        pleasure. I do not regret that the motion for further delay was defeated.
                        There was fitness in disposing of the case--to delay still longer would have
                        been to belittle and demoralize the whole proceeding. From the day that the
                        eleventh article was lost, impeachment became a running sore on the body
                        politic, and there was but one remedy for it--the prompt dismissal of the
                        case. That the verdict was honestly obtained I do not believe, but however
                        attained, it has all sanction and ceremony of law, and had to be obeyed. To
                        delay with the hope of intimidating or purchasing back those who had been
                        purchased for acquittal was to sacrifice all the moral effect of conviction
                        upon the altar of corruption and plunder, and it was, therefore, wise to
                        dismiss the case and let the responsibility of the verdict abide with those
                        who have violated their records and teachings to make it.</p>
                    <p>Why did impeachment fail?</p>
                    <p>The people of the Union will always obey the laws, and bow to the decision of
                        their properly constituted tribunals; but under out theory of government
                        they have reserved to themselves the final adjudication of all questions of
                        political law. If those who are clothed with the power of decision do
                        violence to the convictions of the people, they bow to the verdict until
                        they can constitutionally reverse their own appointed tribunals. Revolution
                        or rebellion is, therefore, without excuse in our government, for their are
                        peaceful remedies for all public wrongs. There is direct accountability to
                        the supreme power from every department of authority, and Senators, as well
                        as Congressmen and Presidents, must answer before the high court of the
                        people, and abide its solemn verdict.</p>
                    <p>Seven Senators must answer to the nation and to posterity for the unexpected
                        failure of impeachment. The twelve Democratic Senators were expected to
                        sustain the President in all things; but the forty-two Republican Senators
                        had convulsed the country for three years by a struggle against what they,
                        with one accord, pronounced the flagrant usurpations of the President; and
                        only when the laws they had enacted had been openly defied, in the face of
                        their repeated and most solemn records, did the House resort to impeachment
                        as the last hope of government and law. Had Messrs. Fessenden, Trumbull,
                        Grimes, Henderson, Fowler, Rose and Van Winkle then said, or even intimated,
                        that the case against the President did not warrant this expulsion from
                        office, the nation would have been saved a formal approval of the
                        lawlessness of Andrew Johnson. But they had repeatedly declared by their
                        votes, under oath, that he was a usurper; they had declared his reasons for
                        the suspension of Mr. Stanton as insufficient, and finally declared the
                        attempted removal of the same officer was without authority of law. Upon
                        this record, in obedience to this teaching, the President was impeached, and
                        there was not a particle of evidence expected in the case that was not known
                        to every Senator before the trial began. They were wrong either in enacting,
                        re-enacting and maintaining the civil tenure bill, or they were wrong in
                        acquitting the President. Both records were made under an oath equally
                        solemn. Under which oath are they to be charged as perjured? Under which
                        trial did venality or disappointed ambition compass a victory? This question
                        the people will decide--this problem history will solve and preserve in the
                        list of the trials and triumphs of the Republic.</p>
                    <p>But two of the seven recreant Republican Senators escaped the imputation of
                        venality. I have not heard any one intimate that Senators Fessenden and
                        Grimes were debauched by money. Grimes is rich and honest; but fretful,
                        morose, and disappointed to despair. He clouded his public career by an
                        insane effort to defeat the re-election of his colleague, Mr. Harlan, and
                        failed. In that failure he was not merely defeated--he was overthrown, and
                        he became an easy prey to faction. He hates Harlan and Wade, and his hate is
                        now his strongest passion, stronger even than himself. Bowed by his physical
                        infirmities and stung to madness by disappointments, he was open in his
                        declarations from the beginning that Mr. Wade should not attain the
                        Presidency. He had no love for Johnson, "D--n Johnson" said he to the writer
                        hereof, when the trial was about to close. "I have not spoken to him for two
                        years, and never will. He deserves every punishment the people can inflict
                        upon him, but impeachment is a folly and a farce." He seemed like a comet
                        that had been flung from its sphere and in pitiable mortification and
                        melancholy he wandered about, shunned by his old associates and heartily
                        despising his new friends, until paralysis wrecked him both mentally and
                        physically. He has cast his last vote in the Senate, and goes home, with
                        bitter maledictions against those who trusted and honored him, to die in the
                        fulness of his infamy.</p>
                    <p>Wm. Pitt Fessenden is the ablest of the Republican Senators, and I believe
                        the oldest in service in the body. He is esteemed a pure and most sensitive
                        gentleman--sensitive to a degree approaching a disease. With this element of
                        his organization, his birth has had much to do. He is the natural son of his
                        father, who is still a prominent citizen of Maine. His mother was an
                        accomplished member of the Greene family of New Hampshire--a sister of the
                        able editor of the Boston <emph rend="italic">Post</emph>. Both his parents
                        subsequently married different parties, and the father recognized and raised
                        the son with a family of ten children, all of whom have attained a high
                        measure of usefulness and popular respect in their different spheres. Ever
                        since the organization of the Republican party, Mr. Fessenden has hoped to
                        become President. He was recognized as the Republican leader in the Senate,
                        as its ablest and most honored champion, and why should he not be President?
                        While hope of advancement inspired him, he was ever true, but when Wade was
                        made President of the Senate, he felt most keenly the mark of distrust
                        thereby put upon him. From that hour dates his decline and fall. Too
                        sensitive to confide his mortification to the most trusted friends, he
                        brooded over his crushed hopes until "the last infirmity of noble minds"
                        added another of its many sad triumphs. It is the old story. Like thousands
                        of others, he tried to master fate, and he fell as had all such before him.
                        Where Lucifer had failed, Wm. Pitt Fessenden hoped to triumph, and he is but
                        "one more unfortunate" to mark the desolation of ambitious tread. Trumbull
                        is a compound of cupidity and ambition--an able disputant, a subtle lawyer,
                        an unscrupulous politician, and the victim of inordinate selfishness and
                        greed. Why he fell amidst the plaudits of the whiskey ring, with his
                        ever-burning words against Johnson's usurpations still ringing in the public
                        ear, the public can judge.</p>
                    <p>Of Henderson, Ross, Fowler and Van Winkle, one brief story tells all. They
                        were all corrupted--some by contracts in the Indian department--more by
                        money. They had their price and they were paid it. Henderson was one of the
                        most earnest in resisting the encroachments of the President, the most
                        bitter accuser he had before the people. Fowler declared, but few months
                        ago, that "if we refuse to depose Andrew Johnson, the blood of the loyal men
                        in the South will rest upon our souls." Van Winkle wrote an opinion in favor
                        of conviction to be filed in case after the testimony had been concluded,
                        and Ross voluntarily assured the Governor of his State, who had given him
                        his place in the Senate, on Friday before the first vote was had, that he
                        would vote to convict. There can be but one explanation of such changes, and
                        the public will adjudge, and history will record, that they imitated Judas
                        in all but the single virtue that made him hang himself. A. K. M.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article asserts that impeachment failed because of corruption and
                    personal and petty feuding within the Republican Party.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Democratic Morals and Religion</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We had occasion in a former issue to say that the Democratic party and a
                        general intelligence were antagonistic to each other, and that the Democracy
                        of Ohio recognized the fact by disfranchising her students. We now assert
                        with due regard for the gravity of the charge, that it is likewise opposed
                        to the christian religion, and true morality. Here are the proofs: During
                        the progress of the impeachment trial, and shortly before the vote was
                        taken, the <emph rend="italic">New York World</emph> urged in its columns
                        the importance of buying enough Republican Senators to secure Johnson's
                        acquittal. "If," said the <emph rend="italic">World</emph>, "ten millions be
                        needed to buy a verdict of acquittal let it be raised." The humiliating
                        spectacle of debauched Senators when a week later a vote was taken upon the
                        eleventh article, left no doubt that the suggestion had been heeded, that
                        the tempting bride had been offered, that cupidity was stronger than
                        integrity, and love of greed had mastered love of country. The <emph
                            rend="italic">World</emph> is the acknowledged leading Democratic
                        journal in the East. It is believed to speak with authority and to reflect
                        truly the feeling and sentiments of the party. Did any Democratic newspapers
                        repudiate this invitation of its leading organ to commit the party to the
                        doctrine of buying fraudulent verdicts, even in the Senate of the United
                        States? Did any, aroused to honest indignation, deny its right to do so? Has
                        there been a Democratic organization of any kind or name to raise its voice
                        in protest against this unparalleled outrage upon a free people? If so we
                        have not heard of it, nor have we seen it, but on the contrary have observed
                        a wonderful acquiescence that even in the corrupt Democracy was unexpected.</p>
                    <p>But we do not rest here. <emph rend="italic">The LaCrosse Democrat</emph>,
                        the most prominent journal of the party in the West, and more widely read
                        than the <emph rend="italic">New York World</emph>, scorning the indifferent
                        success of its party journals at sinning, mocks the Deity and shocks mankind
                        with its blasphemy.</p>
                    <p>The following appeared in this journal a few weeks ago, on the assembling of
                        the Quadrennial Conference of the Methodist Church at Chicago:</p>
                    <p>"There is now in session in the city of Chicago a nondescript, black-and-tan,
                        rump Radical, politico-religious mob, known as the Quadrennial Conference of
                        the Methodist Church. It is convened nominally in the interests of the
                        Methodist denomination, but really in the interest of the mongrel party, and
                        with an eye to the interest of Grant, who is a candidate of the Methodists.
                        It will remain in session until after the Chicago Convention, and will add
                        its nasal whine to the chorus of damnable discords that will hail the
                        nomination of the azure-backed butcher. It is engineered by the infamous
                        Simpson, Methodist Bishop of Philadelphia, who in collusion with Gen.
                        Howard, the other reverend ruffian of the Freedmen's Bureau, took possession
                        of twelve hundred churches belonging to the Methodist Church South, and
                        turned them over to the niggers and convict preachers of the North.</p>
                    <p> * * * * * * * * * *</p>
                    <p>Roost high, oh ye feathered beasts, for the chicken eaters are coming up to
                        that great city.</p>
                    <p>Guard well your back doors to your gin mills oh ye dispensers of benzine, for
                        the throats that are enveloped in white chokers are oft athirst.</p>
                    <p>Look well to your four-footed beasts, ye that keep livery stables, for horse
                        flesh hath ever a powerful attraction for the Methodist deacon.</p>
                    <p>Look well to your wallets, oh ye who travel in the street cars, lest you lose
                        the lovely patches of ragged paper that have symbolized money ever since the
                        time these nice shepherds have furnished the inspiration for the political
                        machine.</p>
                    <p>Look well to your mustard cups and spoons of shoddy silver, oh ye maidens who
                        doth dispense the juice of the hop, for the bible banger doth delight to
                        labor with the nymphs, who are profanely called beer-jerkers, and the
                        pockets of the brethren are capacious.</p>
                    <p>Mount a two-barrel gun within range of your clothes line, oh ye who have much
                        raiment, for the colporteurs have a weakness for square tailed shirts and
                        embroidered under clothes.</p>
                    <p>Place none but tried men on guard to-night, oh ye who set up free lunches for
                        your patrons, for the hymn squawkers do go for all things which are free.</p>
                    <p>Guard well your watch tower, oh ye publicans of high and low degree, for in
                        beating landlords a Methodist circuit-rider can double discount the 'eldest
                        inhabitants.'</p>
                    <p>And, oh ye unsuspecting Methodist brethren of Chicago, hearken to our
                        warning, and go mighty slow on your itinerant brethren from the country, for
                        they will renege on the first deal.</p>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">Brethren, let us pray.</emph>
                    </p>" <p>Comment upon this is unnecessary. It speaks for itself. The sheet is
                        weekly read by hundreds of thousands of persons. Many copies are regularly
                        received and read in this town, where we are free to admit that the
                        Democracy are now no worse than in other places. Nor is the extract above an
                        isolated case. There is not a single number issued by this blasphemer that
                        does not contain articles equally unholy. There is no family relation too
                        sacred for its polluting touch. The very pillars of society, the institution
                        of marriage and the church are made the themes of its lewd, profane and
                        disgusting comments. And yet this is one of the first, if not <emph
                            rend="italic">the first</emph> Democratic journal in the land, and gives
                        tone and sentiment to the party. It is not discountenanced by those organs
                        of the party that profess decency. Its claim to authority as a leading and
                        controlling Democratic sheet is not denied, and the conclusion is
                        irresistible that its mockery of God and His holy religion, and its libels
                        upon His servants, the ministers of the gospel, are sanctioned by the high
                        authority of the Democratic party. It is the logical result of the facts we
                        have stated, and of their truthfulness there cannot be a doubt.</p>
                    <p>To the people of Pennsylvania we present these facts, and ask for them a
                        mature and calm consideration. The Democratic party is making another effort
                        for supremacy and power. To secure them at any sacrifice to the country, no
                        matter how great, has been fully resolved. Shall they have the aid and
                        assistance of christian churches, whom they mock and defame, to put the
                        control of the government in their hands? Shall Young Men's Christian
                        Associations, which they despise, assist and encourage them? Shall the
                        institutions of learning, which they fear, vote to give them a lease of
                        power? Shall the people whom they openly and shamefully seek to prostitute
                        and debauch by the unlawful use of money, tamely allow themselves to be
                        deceived and sold? It may be so that they will, but we have too much faith
                        in their intelligence and integrity to fear such a result. A bloody
                        rebellion lasting four years, the sacrifice of countless treasure and
                        hecatombs of precious lives, are the heritage of this party to the people;
                        but out of all was evolved freedom from the course of human bondage and an
                        acknowledgement of the equal rights of all men under the law. These the
                        people will never deliver into the hands of their old enemies.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper accuses the Democratic Party of buying Johnson's acquittal with
                    bribes, and denounces a recent attack on the Methodist Church. The editors
                    conclude with a plea to defeat the party of the rebellion.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The nomination of Gen. Grant for the Presidency must fill the hearts of the
                        Democracy with unalloyed satisfaction, since it enables their allies to
                        fight their battles over again. When the war closed, chiefly as believed,
                        because the rebels had no more armies which had not been throughly thrashed
                        and well nigh annihilated, and no more material from which to organize
                        others, and no more provisions to feed them, nor clothes to put upon their
                        naked bodies, certainly from no willingness of the leaders to concede the
                        point in dispute, their sympathizers in the North could see to their entire
                        satisfaction that Grant was a miserable bungler, a mere empiric in war,
                        whose soldiers were defeated on every occasion, and that Lee was the
                        complete incarnation of Napoleonic strategy and skill and his soldiers
                        perfect centaurs in battle. It was a little difficult to square this theory
                        with the facts, and the obstinate facts were ready to pop in the mind if
                        every man to whom it was addressed, but with that sublime indifference to
                        facts peculiar to great and chivalric souls, these heroes who had snuffed
                        the battle afar off stuck to their theory and left the facts to take care of
                        themselves. It was true Grant captured Fort Donalson, including Buckner and
                        his greasy and <emph rend="italic">animated</emph> brigades; Vicksburg with
                        Pemberton and his large army were forced to succumb to his matchless skill
                        and the wonderful bravery of his troops, and when called to the chief
                        command of our armies victory perched on our banners everywhere, and even
                        Lee, the Ajax of the Confederacy, laid down his arms a conquered and
                        captured foe. Briefly stated, that is about the way the thing looks to those
                        who in sympathy or in arms were fighting the rebellion. Now that Grant is a
                        candidate for the Presidency, his successes in the field must necessarily
                        give him vantage ground to his campaign. To prove that these were only
                        apparent, and that Lee, and Johnson, and <sic>Beuregard,</sic> and Hood, and
                        Early, and such were the real victors, would pluck all the feathers from his
                        cap, and take all the strength of his great name from the cause he has
                        espoused and perhaps secure his defeat.</p>
                    <p>Let them try their hands at it, and an excellent idea, if we be allowed to
                        suggest, would be to begin with the soldiers.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors gloat that the outcome of the war demolished the Democrat's pet
                    "theory" that Grant was a bungler and Lee was a genius. The paper warns that the
                    Democrats will again try to tarnish Grant's military skill in the upcoming
                    campaign.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper pays tribute to Edwin M. Stanton who has resigned from the War
                    Department. "Few nations have ever had, our own has never before had, a chief of
                    the War Department who possessed such wonderful fitness for its responsibilities
                    and intricate duties. During the rebellion his great genius in marshaling troops
                    and organizing victory was only equalled by his sublime patriotism and his
                    unyielding integrity."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>No efforts will be spared by the Northern Copperheads--the last and only hope
                        of the conquered traitors and treason--to make this the fiercest and most
                        bitter political campaign that was ever carried on in this country. It had
                        almost become a mutual arrangement among politicians that the private
                        character of our Presidential candidates should be passed over in silence,
                        and their official acts alone be discussed; but as the foes of free
                        government and the friends of slavery have no argument to make, they must
                        appeal to the prejudices of the ignorant. We must expect to have Grant and
                        Colfax abused as men never were before, but the base fabrications of their
                        vile traducers will be harmless and do no injury. Loyal men should be
                        thoroughly organized and be prepared for the bushwhacking warfare of their
                        political foes. We have the power in our hands, and posterity will hold us
                        accountable for the proper use of it.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper warns Republicans to be prepared to endure negative campaigning
                    and personal attacks from the Democrats during the upcoming campaign.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.06.03.03" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The 30th of May</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Gen. Logan's order, requesting the decorating of the "passionless mounds" of
                        our dead heroes was complied with by all good citizens of Chambersburg. On
                        Thursday evening, previous, a meeting of our war worn veterans was held in
                        the Register's office, at which Leiut. Josiah W. Fletcher, Deputy-Sheriff,
                        presided and Sergt. John A. Seiders acted as Secretary. A committee of
                        arrangements was appointed, who were authorized to transact all business, as
                        well as solicit <sic>boquets</sic> and floral wreaths from our patriotic
                        ladies. The following circular was issued:</p>
                    <p>IN MEMORIAM<lb/> Chambersburg, May 28, 1868.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">To the Ladies of Chambersburg</emph>:--At a meeting of
                        the Soldiers of the Borough of Chambersburg, held at the Court House, on
                        Wednesday evening, May 27, to make arrangements for decorating the graves of
                        our fallen comrades with flowers, the Ladies were invited to furnish
                        Boquets, Wreaths, &amp;c., for that purpose. Feeling that their
                        co-operation is necessary to make it a success, they are earnestly invited
                        to give it their attention.</p>
                    <p>The ceremonies will take place <emph rend="italic">on Saturday morning, May
                            30, at 7 o'clock</emph>.</p>
                    <p>All contributions should be sent to Repository Hall, <emph rend="italic">on
                            Friday evening</emph>, between the hours of 6 and 8 P.M.<lb/> John A.
                        Seiders, <emph rend="italic">Secretary</emph>.</p>
                    <p>Prompted by the same spirit that sustained the army of the Union whilst
                        struggling for liberty and a free government, with an increased love for our
                        dear old "Stars and Stripes," and many a hallowed recollection of those who
                        offered up their lives for their country, our ladies heartily responded to
                        the request of the surviving soldiers. Repository Hall was opened on Friday
                        evening, and the contributions were generous, and continued until a late
                        hour of the night. One little girl remarked "here is a boquet for brother's
                        grave." Another one, "father, who was a soldier, always told me to love my
                        country, and I'm still going to do it." A little boy of twelve years said,
                        just wait till I become a man, and I'll fight for Liberty, too." Many
                        interesting incidents occurred that we have not the space to relate. The
                        Executive Committee visited the Cemetery and different grave yards on
                        Friday, and placed small flags over the grave of each soldier.</p>
                    <p>On Saturday a large crowd of our most respectable citizens assembled in front
                        of the Court House. Our business houses were not opened until ten o'clock.
                        At eight, A.M., the soldiers were formed in line, and in the rear of them
                        "home guards" and citizens. Without regard to party or politics, all were
                        assembled. This was one of the most pleasing features of the day. It showed
                        that all, equally well, loved the memories of those who had stood between
                        them and danger, who had offered their lives upon the altar of their
                        country, as a sacrifice for Humanity and Freedom, who had died in defence of
                        the principles of our fathers. Everybody rejoiced that the arrangements had
                        been so successful, for it established the fact, that not only that day but
                        on other days to come, when many a soldier who was present would be lying
                        with his departed comrades, the 30th of May would still be observed, and the
                        graves of the conquerors in the war against treason, would still receive
                        that homage due them. This day will go down to posterity, and will be
                        classed with the 4th of July, 22d of February, and other patriotic occasions
                        that are now in existence, and may hereafter be created. The procession
                        marched to the Cemetery under the command of Col. F. S. Stumbaugh who had as
                        aids Col. J. G. Elder, Capt. John Doebler, Segt. H. Strickler and Sergt.
                        David Hyssong. The pavements were covered with out patriotic citizens, and
                        the number that accompanied the soldiers, in addition to those who had
                        previously gone to the Cemetery, must have numbered several thousand. On the
                        arrival at the Cemetery, one soldier was placed at each grave. A prayer was
                        offered to the God of battles, who had given us the victory; whilst a dirge
                        was played by the band, the boquets and flowers were strewn over the mounds
                        of our heroes. Col. F. S. Stumbaugh, repeated the soldiers vow, and was
                        joined by the vast multitude in the solemn utterance. "In this solemn
                        presence, I renew my pledge, to aid and assist those whom that, (pointing to
                        Col. Peter B. Housum's grave), and the other heroic dead left among us, a
                        sacred charge upon a Nation gratitude, the widows and orphans. A blessing
                        was then pronounced and the vast multitude departed for the Presbyterian
                        grave yard. The following soldiers are buried in</p>
                    <p>CEDAR GROVE CEMETERY</p>
                    <p>Col. Peter B. Housum, 77th Reg. Penna. Vols.<lb/> Capt. William Stouffer, Co.
                        C, 92d Reg. Ill. Vols.<lb/> Rev. Wm. H. Maxwell, Chaplain<lb/> Jacob Lortz,
                        Co. A, 77th Reg. Penna. Vols.<lb/> Thomas J. Richter, 100th Reg. Penna.
                        Vols.<lb/> D. Augustus Houser, Co. A, 126th Penna. Vols.<lb/> Lieut. Wm. L.
                        Martin, 55th Reg. Penna. Vols.<lb/> Robert S. Martin, 111th Reg. Penna.
                        Vols.<lb/> Jacob Householder, 210th Penna. Vols.<lb/> James U. Palmer, Co.
                        L, 21st Penna. Cav.<lb/> Jacob B. Shaffer, Co. A, 126th Penna. Vols.<lb/>
                        William H. Seiders, Co. D, 11th Penna. Cav.<lb/> T. J. C. M'Grath, Co. A,
                        126th Penna. Vols.<lb/> William B. Leisher, Co. D, 210th Reg. Penna.
                        Vols.<lb/> Andrew M'Kean, Co. D, 21st Penna. Cav.<lb/> William M'Kean, 2d
                        Penna. Art.<lb/> Benjamin F. Suter, Co. D, 210th Reg. Penna. Vols.<lb/>
                        James M'Geehen, Co. K, 107th Reg. Penna Vols.<lb/> John Liggett, Co. K,
                        107th Penna. Vols.<lb/> Charles W. Kline, Co. K, 107th Penna. Vols.<lb/>
                        Dewitt C. Piper, 18th Reg. U.S. Infantry<lb/> John Caseman, Co. K, 107th
                        Reg. Penna. Vols.<lb/> David W. Hummelslue, Co. D, 11th Penna. Cav.<lb/>
                        Jacob H. Butler, Co. D, 11th Penna. Cav.<lb/> John K. Simmers, Co. D, 210th
                        Reg. Penna. Vols.<lb/> George Nolan, 2d Penna. Art.<lb/> Thomas M.
                        Dunkinson, Co. K, 107th Reg. Penna. Vols.<lb/> Capt. Samuel R. M'Kesson, Co.
                        A, 77th Penna. Vols.<lb/> George S. Shinefield, Co. D, 126th Reg. Penna.
                        Vols.<lb/> James S. Shuman, Co. D, 11th Penna. Cav.<lb/> William E. Shuman,
                        Co. K, 107th Reg. Penna. Vols.<lb/> John N. Heckerman, 13th Penna. Cav.<lb/>
                        Lieut. Thos. L. Fletcher, Co. K, 12th Penna. Reserves<lb/> John S. Oaks, Co.
                        A, 126th Reg. Penna. Vols.<lb/> Emanuel Dietrich, Co. H, 213th Reg. Penna.
                        Vols.<lb/> Martin Huber, Co. C, 149th Reg. Penna. Vols.<lb/> Casper Hug, Co.
                        E, 21st Penna. Cav.<lb/> Robert Cunningham, Penna. Reserves<lb/> C. Allen,
                        1st Michigan Cav.<lb/> Calvin Johnston<lb/> S. H. Ellis, Co. H, 137th Reg.
                        Penna. Vols.<lb/> Henry M'Cloud, New York Vols.<lb/> Dr. John R. Clippinger,
                        Co. D, 126th Penna. Vols.<lb/> Hugh Brotherton, Co. D, 11th Penna. Cav.<lb/>
                        Samuel Armbuster, Penna. Infantry.<lb/> Jeremiah Bufort, 14th Penna.
                        Cav.<lb/> -- Carr, 30th Reg. Penna. Vols.<lb/> George W. Crivinger, Penna.
                        Vols.<lb/> Jeremiah Dakens, 10th Reg. Penna. Infantry<lb/> Charles A.
                        Frank<lb/> George W. Gale<lb/> Andrew Hoffman, 20th Penna. Cav.<lb/>
                        Christian Helfrich, 5th U. S. Artillery<lb/> William W. James<lb/> Jonas
                        Nixon<lb/> Peter Obhoff, 1st New York Cav.<lb/> George W. Robertson<lb/>
                        Adam Weir<lb/> C. H. Wellington</p>
                    <p>The same services were held in the various Grave Yards, as at the Cemetery.
                        We give below the names of the soldiers interred in grounds attached to the
                        Churches.</p>
                    <p>PRESBYTERIAN</p>
                    <p>Dr. Stewart Kennedy, Surgeon U. S. Navy<lb/> George W. Wallace, Anderson Body
                        Guard<lb/> Samuel D. C. Reed, Co. A, 126th Reg. Penna. Vols.</p>
                    <p>CATHOLIC</p>
                    <p>Patrick Curran, Co. H, 69th New York Vols.<lb/> Joseph Yeager, Independent
                        Penna. Battery<lb/> Thos. Curran, Co. H, 69th New York Vols</p>
                    <p>SECOND LUTHERAN</p>
                    <p>Henry M. Fennel, Co. M, 21st Penna. Cav.</p>
                    <p>UNITED BRETHREN</p>
                    <p>Chas. E. Rapp, Co. C, 2d Penna. Artillery<lb/> Jacob M'Gowan, Co. A, 126th
                        Reg. Penna. Vols.<lb/> Lieut. J. Wesley Jones, 58th Penna. Infantry</p>
                    <p>GERMAN REFORMED</p>
                    <p>Lieut. Robert Earley, Quarter Master Indiana Vols.<lb/> Lieut. Matthew
                        Gillan, 2d Penna. Infantry<lb/> R. Bard Fisher, Co. A, 126th Penna. Vols.</p>
                    <p>After the services in the German Reformed Cemetery, the procession marched to
                        the Court House pavement, where they were dismissed by Col. F. S.
                    Stumbaugh.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fletcher</ln>
                        <fn>Josiah W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seiders</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sgt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>F. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elder</ln>
                        <fn>J. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doebler</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strickler</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sgt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hyssong</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sgt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Housom</ln>
                        <fn>Peter B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stouffer</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maxwell</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lortz</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richter</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houser</ln>
                        <fn>D. Augustus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn>William L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn>Robert S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Householder</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palmer</ln>
                        <fn>James U.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shaffer</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seiders</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Grath</ln>
                        <fn>T. J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Leisher</ln>
                        <fn>William B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Kean </ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Kean</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Suter</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Geehen</ln>
                        <fn>James M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Liggett</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kline</ln>
                        <fn>Charles W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Piper</ln>
                        <fn>Dewitt C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Caseman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hummelsine</ln>
                        <fn>David W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Butler</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Simmers</ln>
                        <fn>John K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nolan</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dunkinson</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Kesson</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel R. </fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shinefield</ln>
                        <fn>George S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shuman</ln>
                        <fn>James S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shuman</ln>
                        <fn>William E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heckerman</ln>
                        <fn>John N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fletcher</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Oaks</ln>
                        <fn>John S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dietrich</ln>
                        <fn>Emanuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huber</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hug</ln>
                        <fn>Casper</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cunningham</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allen</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnston</ln>
                        <fn>Calvin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ellis</ln>
                        <fn>S. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Cloud</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clippinger</ln>
                        <fn>John R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brotherton</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armbuster</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burfort</ln>
                        <fn>Jeremiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carr</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crivinger</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dakens</ln>
                        <fn>Jeremiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Frank</ln>
                        <fn>Charles A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gale</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoffman</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Helfrich</ln>
                        <fn>Christian</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>James </ln>
                        <fn>William M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nixon</ln>
                        <fn>Jonas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Obhoff</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robertson</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weir</ln>
                        <fn>Adam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wellington</ln>
                        <fn>C. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>Stewart</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wallace</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel D. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Curran</ln>
                        <fn>Patrick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yeager</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Curran</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fennel</ln>
                        <fn>Henry M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rapp</ln>
                        <fn>Charles E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Gowan</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>J. Wesley</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Earley</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillan</ln>
                        <fn>Matthew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>R. Bard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper prints an account of Memorial Day observances in Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shoemaker</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Shoemaker will soon be opening the Chambersburg Academy in his position
                    as principal. The paper endorses the school and the teacher.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>DeMott and Ward's United Menagerie and Circus</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>DeMott and Ward's circus will perform in Chambersburg on June 12th. They
                    are famous for their equestrian acts and wide variety of animals.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>An Act of True Heroism</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Major Henry T. Lee, of the 4th New York Artillery, in an address
                        commemorative of the services of the alumni and former students of Lafayette
                        College, in the war for the Union, relates the following interesting account
                        of the noble and truly christian conduct of one of Franklin county's sons:</p>
                    <p>"At the battle of Fredericksburg, the fortunes of the day left a large number
                        of wounded men belonging to the Pennsylvania Reserves between the contending
                        lines of skirmishers. They lay there, poor fellows, from the afternoon of
                        Saturday, and all through the long December night their agonizing cries were
                        heard as in hunger and thirst and cold, in darkness and alone they bled
                        their lives away. All attempts to aid them seemed unavailing, for the rebel
                        skirmishers remorselessly picked off all who went to their aid.</p>
                    <p>"On Monday night, strict orders were issued against the lighting of fires
                        along the line, and the officer detailed to enforce obedience, as he rode
                        along, came upon a fire kindled in the rear of the line, in a little hollow
                        hidden by trees, and there he found a chaplain with his contraband servant,
                        playing the good Samaritan to a group of poor wounded men, whom they had
                        dragged from between the contending skirmish lines at the imminent risk of
                        their lives. This practical application of gospel principles the men most
                        thoroughly appreciated, and the result was that on the return of the
                        division to camp, they built a huge log church for their plucky Chaplain,
                        who had stuck to them through the brunt of the fight, and had perilled his
                        life for them; and, what was better, every man in the regiment made it a
                        point of honor to attend service once on Sunday. As the officers told me, no
                        one in the regiment had more influence with the men than their Chaplain, for
                        they honored and loved him as a man, as well as respected him as their
                        superior officer.</p>
                    <p>"That man was John M. Pomeroy, Chaplain of the 3d Pennsylvania Reserves, and
                        after its disbanding, by a unanimous call, Chaplain also of the 198th
                        Pennsylvania, recruited by the officers of his first charge."</p>
                    <p>Hon. Thomas Pomeroy, of Roxbury, is the father of this patriotic minister,
                        who now has a charge in Chester county, Pa.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Account of the heroism of a Franklin County native at the battle of
                    Fredericksburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The 30th of May was observed in our neighboring town of Shippensburg. There
                        was a large procession, under the charge of Capt. Alex Stewart, who had as
                        aids Capt. Wm. Baughman, Capt. A. C. Landis, and Lieut. John Snow. We have
                        been furnished with a list of the deceased soldiers buried in that vicinity,
                        which we give below:</p>
                    <p>Richard Moore, Co. K, 201st Regt. Penna. Vols.<lb/> Samuel Golden<lb/> Wm.
                        Culp, 7th Penna. Reserves<lb/> Geo. Breniser, Co. D, 130th Regt. Penna.
                        Vols.<lb/> Geo. McLean, Co. D, 130th Regt. Penna. Vols.<lb/> Henry Miller,
                        Co. D, 130th Regt. Penna. Vols.<lb/> Jos. Matthews, Co. D, 130th Regt.
                        Penna. Vols.<lb/> Lieut. Wm. Harper, 7th Penna. Reserves<lb/> Capt. David
                        Harper, 4th Iowa<lb/> Jos. Gambel, Co. H, 3d Penna. Cav.<lb/> William
                        Grabill, Co. D, 130th Regt. Penna. Vols.<lb/> Capt. Samuel Speese, 13th
                        Penna. Cav.<lb/> Capt. Samuel Speese, Jr., 21st Penna. Cav.<lb/> W. S.
                        Severs, Co. F, 17th Penna. Cav.<lb/> Abner Trone, Co. H, 3d Penna. Cav.<lb/>
                        Geo. Koser, Co. B, 107th Regt. Penna. Vols.<lb/> Geo. Frey, Co. B, 107th
                        Regt. Penna. Vols.<lb/> Jacob Coover, Co. D, 130th Regt. Penna. Vols.<lb/>
                        Wm. Duncan, 13th Penna. Cav.<lb/> Nicholas Lenhar, Co. D, 130th Regt. Penna.
                        Vols.<lb/> David Shugars, Co. D, 107th Regt. Penna. Vols.<lb/> Lieut. Samuel
                        Patchel, Co. D, 130th Penna. Vols.<lb/> Wm. Mortner, 71st Regt. Penna.
                    Vols.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stewart</ln>
                        <fn>Alex</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baughman</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Landis</ln>
                        <fn>A. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snow</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moore</ln>
                        <fn>Richard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Golden</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Culp</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Breniser</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLean</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Matthews</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harper</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harper</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gambel</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grabill</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Speese</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Severs</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trone</ln>
                        <fn>Abner</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koser</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Frey</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coover</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duncan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lenhar</ln>
                        <fn>Nicholas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shugars</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patchel</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mortner</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Account of Memorial Day observances in Shippensburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The ceremony of decorating the graves of the Union Soldiers of Greencastle,
                        who fell in defence of their country, was duly observed on the afternoon of
                        the 30th ult. Business places were generally closed. There was a large turn
                        out of soldiers. The procession was formed in Centre Square, where the
                            <sic>boquets</sic> were distributed by the patriot ladies of that town;
                        after which the procession, composed of soldiers and citizens, moved
                        <sic>of</sic> to the different burying places, proceeded by the Antrim
                        Silver Cornet Band. Appropriate eulogies were delivered by Cols. D. Watson
                        Rowe and B. F. Winger. The church bells were tolled during the exercises,
                        and altogether the scene was solemn and imposing. Capt. George H. Miller
                        acted as marshal, and had as aids Lieut. J. G. Rowe, Sergt. Frank
                        Wunderlich, Sergt. John R. Allison, Corporal Isaiah Illginfritz and Corporal
                        Geo. L. Benner. Capt. W. H. Davison was master of ceremonies.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rowe</ln>
                        <fn>D. Watson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Winger</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>George H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rowe</ln>
                        <fn>J. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wunderlich</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sgt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allison</ln>
                        <fn>John R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sgt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Illginfritz</ln>
                        <fn>Isaiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Cpl.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Benner</ln>
                        <fn>George L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Cpl.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davison</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Account of Memorial Day observances in Greencastle.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Sad Death</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Speck</ln>
                        <fn>Edward</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Speck</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burkholder</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Frantz</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snively</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Edward Speck, son of Frederick Speck, died at Mt. Hope on May 22nd from the
                    effects of lock jaw contracted from a wound received from a cog wheel in his
                    father's mill. The best efforts of Drs. Burkholder, Frantz, and Snively could
                    not save him. He was 17 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>At a meeting of the soldiers of the borough of Chambersburg and vicinity,
                        held on the 30th of May last, for the purpose of decorating the graves of
                        their lost comrades, who fell in the late war in defence of their country,
                        the following resolutions were passed by unanimous vote:</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That we tender our thanks to the clergy
                        for their presence and services at the decoration.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That we tender out thanks to the members
                        of the Silver Cornet Band for their kindness in furnishing us with their
                        excellent music during the exercises.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That we tender our thanks to the ladies
                        for furnishing us with flowers, and for the interest they manifested in the
                        cause of doing honor to our fallen comrades.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That we tender our thanks to Messrs.
                        Cook &amp; Hays, for the use of the Repository Hall.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That we tender our thanks to the editors
                        of the REPOSITORY and <emph rend="italic">Valley Spirit</emph>, for their
                        kindness in helping us to do honor to our sacred dead, through their
                        respective journals.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That we tender our thanks to the
                        citizens in general, for the interest they manifested in the holy work, and
                        for a due observance of the day.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The soldiers of Chambersburg issue resolutions of thanks in honor of the
                    various groups that participated in Memorial Day observances.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>


            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Two Hours with the Poets</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Mr. and Mrs. F. A. Tannehill, the two well-known poets from the Cumberland
                    Valley, will give a performance in Repository Hall on June 5th consisting of
                    dramatic readings, recitations, songs, and dances. They have not appeared in
                    Chambersburg for some time, and all citizens are encouraged to attend.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>I. O. G. T.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Noble</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McWilhelm</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J. Campbell</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Espy S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kuhn</ln>
                        <fn>Henry X.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kell</ln>
                        <fn>Emma V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Montgomery</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heeter</ln>
                        <fn>John F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kegerreis</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swank</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reeder</ln>
                        <fn>Cynthia A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Noble installed a number of officers at Fannettsburg Lodge No. 226,
                    I. O. G. T. The paper reports that the lodge is in a "flourishing condition,"
                    and boasts 81 members.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>West</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The congregation of Rev. William A. West's Spring Run Presbyterian Church,
                    including many of the ladies, decorated the graves of the soldiers buried in
                    their church yard on the 30th. "The monument erected by this church, to the
                    memory of her sons who had fallen fighting for their God, their Country, and
                    Humanity, was decked and covered with boquets and floral wreaths."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scott</ln>
                        <fn>Nip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>An African American man named Nip Scott was recently arrested for
                    drunkenness and "corner lounging." The paper pleads that "no distinction of race
                    or color should be made in this matter. There are a number of white persons who
                    crowd up our pavements, not only on Saturday, but on all other evenings and
                    often prevent ladies from promenading. Let the borough ordinances be enforced by
                    our police and our streets cleared of loungers."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Strawberry and Floral Festival</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The ladies of Chambersburg will meet in the Lutheran Lecture Room on
                    Thursday to make plans to hold a Strawberry and Floral Festival to raise money
                    to erect a Soldiers' Monument.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A Union meeting for the benefit of the Young Men's Christian Association
                    will be held in the Lutheran Church on Sunday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The citizens of Waynesboro have plans to raise a cavalry company.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wigfall</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chambers</ln>
                        <fn>Mary A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mowery</ln>
                        <fn>Philip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Thomas B. Wigfall of Philadelphia and Mary A. Chambers of Chambersburg were
                    married in Chambersburg's Presbyterian Church on June 2nd by the Rev. Philip
                    Mowery.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fikes</ln>
                        <fn>D. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robinson</ln>
                        <fn>Carrie F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robinson</ln>
                        <fn>C. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lacy</ln>
                        <fn>E. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>D. D. Fikes of Orrstown and Miss Carrie F. Robinson, daughter of C. H.
                    Robinson of West Virginia, were married in Martinsburg, West Virginia, on May
                    21st by the Rev. E. S. Lacy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ferguson</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elder</ln>
                        <fn>Maria</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elder</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>West</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James Ferguson and Miss Maria Elder, daughter of William Elder, both of Dry
                    Run, were married on May 20th by the Rev. William A. West.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kyle</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dinning</ln>
                        <fn>Louisa</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hummelbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>H. Y.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Benjamin Kyle and Miss Louisa Dinning, both of Chambersburg, were married
                    at the U. B. Parsonage on May 14th by the Rev. H. Y. Hummelbaugh.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Danforth</ln>
                        <fn>Charles H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greenawalt</ln>
                        <fn>Ellie M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roth</ln>
                        <fn>G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Charles H. Danforth of Vermont and Miss Ellie M. Greenawalt of Chambersburg
                    were married in Chambersburg at the residence of the bride's mother on April
                    19th by the Rev. G. Roth.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Herring</ln>
                        <fn>G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roth</ln>
                        <fn>G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>G. Herring and Miss K. Wilson, both of Chambersburg, were married on May
                    7th by the Rev. G. Roth.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yost</ln>
                        <fn>Philip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burket</ln>
                        <fn>Anna</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roth</ln>
                        <fn>G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Philip Yost and Miss Anna Burket, both of Chambersburg, were married on May
                    18th by the Rev. G. Roth.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flickinger</ln>
                        <fn>Hetty S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Hetty S. Flickinger died at Fannettsburg on May 22nd. She was 51 years
                    old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.06.03.04" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

    </paperBody>
</hwp>
