<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="sd1862/pa.fr.sd.1862.02.21">
    <header>
        <title>Semi-Weekly Dispatch</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sarah Roth</taggerName>
            <tagDate>7/11/98</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1862-02-21">
            <year>1862</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day>21</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>bi-weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.sd.1862.02.21.01">
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 1-3; details on the Union victory at Fort Donelson,
                columns 4 and 5, continued on page 2</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.sd.1862.02.21.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Paying Dearly for Their Whistle</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that the British Government has spent about 20 million dollars in
                    preparation for possible hostilities due to the Trent affair.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>"Let Us Be Consistent"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"When James Buchanan transfered [sic] the Government over to Abraham
                    Lincoln, there was scarcely a particle of soundness in it."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In an article in the <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> of last week, under
                        the above caption, appears the following shameless falsehood, by way of
                        showing, we presume, that its new editor may be relied on to be as "<emph
                            rend="italic">consistent</emph>" in uttering unblushing falsehoods, with
                        reference to political opponents, in the future, as any of his predecessors
                        have been in the past. The <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> says--</p>
                    <p>"When the Republican party came into power the country was prosperous and at
                        peace. Now, one half is in the full blaze of rebellion, while the other half
                        is in a fair way of becoming bankrupted in putting it down."</p>
                    <p>Comment upon the above is, indeed, unnecessary, but we cannot refrain from
                        making a few remarks. A specious of madness must certainly revel in the
                        brain of the man who can recklessly assert, in the face of a reading,
                        intelligent public, at this early day of the rebellion, that "<emph
                            rend="italic">when the Republican party came into power</emph> [the 4th
                        of March, last,] <emph rend="italic">the country was prosperous and at
                            peace"!</emph> when it is so well known to all who are not wilfully
                        ignorant, that at least seven or eight States had passed Secession
                        ordinances--had seized national forts, arsenals, vessels, and mints--had
                        planted batteries, and were in open rebellion against the government long
                        before Mr. Lincoln was inaugurated.</p>
                    <p>Screen the faithless and guilty parties as much as you can--blink the
                        question as you may, the country will hold those leaders of the Democratic
                        party who adhered to the Buchanan Administration, and who afterwards
                        followed the fortunes of the rebel, John C. Breckinridge, to the very verge
                        of the pit into which he plunged, as responsible for the rebellion and its
                        attendant horrors and impoverishing results, and not the Republican party,
                        which was not in power when the house was fired by the incendiary's torch.</p>
                    <p>When James Buchanan transfered [sic] the Government over to Abraham Lincoln,
                        there was scarcely a particle of soundness in it. From the crown of the head
                        to the soles of the feet the whole body politic presented nothing but a mass
                        of reeking corruption, treason and infidelity--the whole head was sick and
                        the whole heart faint. Such being the almost hopeless condition of the
                        patient when given up by the Democratic quack Doctors to the Republican
                        party, the most active and powerful remedial prescriptions had to be
                        resorted to immediately, to revive and restore the wasted and almost ruined
                        health of the Government, brought about by the mal-practice of those who had
                        the charge of it. It was a case of life or death, and a halting,
                        equivocating cowardly policy, (such as had been practiced by the Buchanans,
                        the Brights the Guins, and other Democrats like them,) was altogether
                        inadmissable [sic].--"An ounce of preventive," we are told, "is worth a
                        pound of cure," and as James Buchanan failed to administer the "ounce of
                        preventative," thus permitting the disease to obtain such a fearful headway
                        as to throw the patient into almost a collapsed condition, it became the
                        duty of Abraham Lincoln and the Republican party to administer the "pound of
                        cure," and if it is a terrible dose, the country has James Buchanan, and the
                        Democratic leaders who surround him, to thank for it.</p>
                    <p>The Rebellion at once assumed the most threatening and gigantic proportions,
                        to meet which</p>
                    <p>The People looked to Mr. Lincoln to preserve the Union and the Constitution,
                        and no mincing or milk and water measures would do it. An army, in numbers
                        altogether unlike anything known in our history, had to be thrown into the
                        field, armed, equipped and fed; a navy had also to be provided and put
                        afloat; arms of every description had to be manufactured and procured from
                        abroad, in a word, the exigencies were such, that the most extraordinary
                        expenditures had to be made in haste, and without that consideration and
                        attention which the public interests would have demanded in ordinary times.
                        But the Buchanan Administration having left the Government in such a
                        terrible condition, that if the life of the patient was to be saved,
                        movements had to be made quickly. There was no time left for a higgling
                        [sic] policy. The expenditures for the public service amounted to hundreds
                        of millions, and that frauds were perpetrated upon the Government by Army
                        Contractors, in every shape and form, for the purpose of enriching
                        themselves, and, to that extent, depleting the Treasury, there is not a
                        doubt; but that any party that ever existed in this country has shown a more
                        fixed determination to put an end to corruption by ferreting out and
                        punishing offenders than the one now in power, we do not believe. If there
                        ever was, it is very evident it is not the modern Democracy.</p>
                    <p>In view, then, of the foregoing facts, what must be the regard for truth of
                        the man who can assert that.</p>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">"When the Republican party came into power, the country
                            was prosperous and at peace."</emph>
                    </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Disputes the Valley Spirit's claim that the country was prosperous and at
                    peace when the Republicans took office by arguing that Lincoln was forced to
                    wage war against the seceded states because James Buchanan did not put a halt to
                    secession during his administration.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Offer of Mason and Slidell to Abolish Slavery</head>
                <origin>Forney's Press</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"But, whether made in good or bad faith, it shows what sacrifices the
                    leading rebels are ready to make to destroy our Union. Much as they love
                    slavery, it seems they love Secession (or political power) still more."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Mason and Slidell have indicated that the South would be
                    willing to abolish slavery as a condition for England and France agreeing to
                    recognize the Confederacy. Questions whether this gesture is made in good faith
                    and whether the Confederacy would in fact follow through with abolition. Also
                    points out that this action suggests that disunion is more important to the
                    rebels than is slavery and questions whether the ordinary people of the South
                    would go along with such a proposition.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Savannah Captured</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports information learned from naval dispatches stating that Savannah has
                    been taken by Union forces.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Cotton Declining</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Among the significant signs of the times in commercial circles is the rapid
                        decline in the price of several kinds of cotton goods. The day is rapidly
                        approaching, when, instead of cotton-ing to King Cotton, the sovereign
                        people of the United States will find him one of their most humble and
                        submissive subjects.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that the price of cotton goods is decreasing and suggests that the
                    United States will no longer bow to King Cotton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Lebanon Courier</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Asserts that the Republican party, more than "any party ever existing in
                    the country," has investigated charges of corruption within the government, even
                    if those who were found out turned out to be Republicans.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Continuation of the article from page 1 that contains the details of the Union
                victory at Fort Donelson, column 1; repeat of information about Fort Donelson,
                report that France will not support the Confederacy, column 3; news from Fort
                Donalson, Cairo, Washington, column 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.02.21.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Suspension of Business</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges that no business be conducted or work done in Chambersburg on
                    February 22 on the occasion of George Washington's birthday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Promotion</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that Private Edward E. Brennand, a member of the Scott Rifles
                    Company of Pittsburg when they were stationed at Camp Slifer, has been promoted
                    to a Master mateship on the gunboat Carondolet for his bravery in the Belmont
                    engagement.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Too Fast</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The community would be hard up for news if it had to rely upon the columns
                    of the Spirit for it. This is probably the reason for its bad humor."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On the strength of what appeared to be reliable news, we announced, by an
                        extra, on the 14th inst., that Fort Donelson had fallen into the hands of
                        the Federal troops, with a large number of prisoners. It turned out
                        afterwards that we were a day or two too fast, and upon this the <emph
                            rend="italic">Spirit</emph> "gives a ghastly grin." We were not the only
                        party, however, that were premature in making such an announcement, as we
                        see that at other points, and especially at Cincinnati, a similar
                        announcement had been made on the same day. As it turns out, however, the
                        capitulation of the enemy took place on the 16th, so that we were not so far
                        out of the way.</p>
                    <p>The community would be hard up for news if it had to rely upon the columns of
                        the <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> for it. This is probably the reason
                        for its bad humor. An examination of its columns will show that the reader,
                        who depends upon the <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> for information with
                        regard to passing events, is from a week to ten days behind the times; but
                        doubtless, if the Federal arms should meet with a Bull Run reverse at
                        Columbus, or some other point on the Mississippi river, its readers would be
                        informed speedily by an extra. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Acknowledges that the Dispatch reported the fall of Fort Donelson to the
                    Union two days before it actually occurred. Points out, in response to the
                    Valley Spirit's chiding, that the Spirit perpetually prints news a week or ten
                    days after it has occurred.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Found</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that a newborn was found dead in a cesspool on the property of a
                    citizen residing in the upper part of Chambersburg. The alleged mother of the
                    child has been arrested.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The 22d of February</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Remarks that the birthday of George Washington will be an occasion that
                    calls for an even more joyous celebration than during previous years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Order of Procession</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Committee to make Arrangements for the proper Celebration of the 22d of
                        February, by our citizens, have adopted the following Order of Procession:</p>
                    <p>The Procession will be under the Marshalship of Capt. John Jeffries.</p>
                    <p>The Procession will form at 11 1/2 o'clock, on South Main Street; the Right
                        resting on the Diamond.</p>
                    <p>The Three Months' Volunteers--Capt. Doebler--with martial music.
                        <lb/>Friendship Fire Co. <lb/>Brass Band. <lb/>Hope Fire Company.</p>
                    <p>The Procession will move up Market St. to Franklin; counter-march to Main; up
                        Main, to Catherine; down Catherine, to Second; down Second to the North
                        Point; then up Main to the Diamond, where arrangements will be made for the
                        raising of the Flag, under the following Order:</p>
                    <p>1. Raising the Stars and Stripes, by Geo. W. Snider. <lb/>2. Firing by the
                        Three Months' Men. <lb/>3. Star Spangled Banner. - - - - Band. <lb/>4.
                        America. - - - - - - - - - - - Ladies. <lb/>5. Washington's Farewell
                        Address, Reve. Harden. <lb/>6. Music. - - - - - - Brass Band. <lb/>7.
                        Address. - - - - W. S. Everett. <lb/>8. Star Spangled Banner. - - Ladies.</p>
                    <p>The Procession will form in line again down Market St. to Second, and there
                        dismiss.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Outlines the order in which those involved in the procession will appear
                    and lists the order of events that will comprise the flag-raising ceremony on
                    the Diamond.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Capture of Fort Donelson</head>
                <origin>Philadelphia Press</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"This is one of the grandest military achievements of ancient or modern
                    times."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Commends the Union army and its troops for the victory at Fort Donelson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We may rejoice that we have a nation as powerful as it is wealthy; a Union
                    as inseparable as it is grand and extensive; a people as brave and patriotic as
                    they are intelligent and free."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Echoes the Philadelphia Press's commendation of the Union forces for the
                    most recent victory.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Frey</ln>
                        <fn>P. Dock</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scheible</ln>
                        <fn>Emma E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. P. Dock Frey and Miss Emma E. Scheible, both of Chambersburg, were
                    married on February 19.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boggs</ln>
                        <fn>John D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baughman</ln>
                        <fn>Susan E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. John D. Boggs and Miss Susan E. Baughman, both of Fayettville, were
                    married on February 6.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Plough</ln>
                        <fn>Hannah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Plough</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Hannah Plough, aged 42 years, died in Chambersburg of consumption on
                    February 16. She was the wife of Mr. John Plough of Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Mr. Samuel Radebaugh, aged about 68, died in Chambersburg on February 19
                    following a brief but painful illness.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eagle</ln>
                        <fn>Fanny</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eagle</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Fanny Eagle, aged 70 years, died in Hamilton township on February 16.
                    She was the consort of the late Peter Eagle.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>advertisements, columns 3-5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.02.21.04">
            <pageNote>Proceedings of Congress, column 1; prices current, column 2; advertisements,
                columns 2-5</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
