<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="sd1862/pa.fr.sd.1862.01.24">
    <header>
        <title>Semi-Weekly Dispatch</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sarah Roth</taggerName>
            <tagDate>7/8/98</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1862-01-24">
            <year>1862</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day>24</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>bi-weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.sd.1862.01.24.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Our Government a Success</head>
                <origin>Exchange</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Defends the republican form of government from the criticism of European
                    nations who argue that the Civil War in the United States is evidence of the
                    ineffectiveness of a state based on republican principles. Argues that the
                    mobilization of troops and supplies on a large scale in the U.S. actually proves
                    the effective operation of republican government in this country.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Weather Against Us</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that mud, snow, sleet, and ice have slowed down Union efforts.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>A Virginia Snow Storm</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The first snow storm has at last come. Saturday I gathered tea roses and
                        other flowers blooming in the open air at Hampton, but to-day the storm king
                        has come in all his fury, and adieu to lingering summer and her sweet
                        flowers. It is the North visiting Virginia with fearful vengeance. Well he
                        comes to cover her stains and nakedness and shame with a pure white robe.
                        May this North king, triumphing today so sternly but so beneficently, be but
                        an omen and pressage of a triumph till all Southland shall be covered with a
                        robe of righteousness and purity, and her present shame and nakedness no
                        longer disgrace America.--<emph rend="italic">Letter from Fortress
                        Monroe.</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A letter from Fortress Monroe reports the first snow storm of the season in
                    Virginia. Expresses the hope that the snow from the North that has descended on
                    Virginia will portend the conquering of the state and the South by the North.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Contrast</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The loyal States pay twenty millions of dollars for schools annually, and
                        have five millions of children at school, while the disloyal do not expend
                        one fifth of that sum, and have but six hundred thousand children in Ohio,
                        in school, than in all of the eleven disloyal states.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Points out that the states fighting for the Union cause spend much more to
                    send a much larger proportion of their children to school than do the disloyal
                    states of the South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 1-3; poem, anecdote, column 4; news from Ship Island,
                column 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.sd.1862.01.24.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>What Is an Abolitionist?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"An abolitionist, judging from the manner in which the fears of the Spirit
                    are wrought upon , cannot be anything less than a monstrous, hideous hobgoblin,
                    the sight of which would not only frighten children into spasms, but would make
                    ignorant men--such as the Spirit only can influence--tremble with mortal fear."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>What is there so hideous, so odious or so terrible in the term <emph
                            rend="italic">Abolitionist</emph>, when applied to an individual or a
                        party, to distinguish it from another party, that induces the new editor of
                        the <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> to howl so terribly about it? He
                        cackles more over it than would a pullet over her first egg. There must be
                        something terrible in it--perhaps it does mean more than we have any idea
                        of. An <emph rend="italic">Abolitionist</emph>, judging from the manner in
                        which the fears of the <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> are wrought upon,
                        cannot be anything less than a monstrous, hideous hobgoblin, the sight of
                        which would not only frighten children into spasms, but would make ignorant
                        men--such as the <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> only can
                        influence--tremble with mortal fear.</p>
                    <p>Every body pretends to know what a man means when he says he is a <emph
                            rend="italic">Whig</emph>, a <emph rend="italic">Democrat</emph>, or an
                            <emph rend="italic">American;</emph> that is, every body knows how to
                        classify a man who claims to be designated by one or other of these
                        destinctive [sic] appellations--but to the term <emph rend="italic"
                            >Abolitionist</emph>, our neighbor wishes to attach a more than ordinary
                        degree of political sin and deformity, and whose policy, if adopted by the
                        Government, would be the greatest monstrosity ever imposed upon any people.
                        So delighted does that pitiable journal seem to be with the frightfulness of
                        the term, that it has altogether dropped its former favorite epithet of
                            <emph rend="italic">Federalist</emph>, with which it used to designate
                        all opponents, and now rolls <emph rend="italic">Abolitionist</emph>, "like
                        a sweet morsel under its tongue." It has given the term <emph rend="italic"
                            >Federalist</emph> the go-by, probably, out of consideration for the
                        feelings of the "favorite son of Pennsylvania," who, in his retirement, is
                        now contemplating the exquisite horrors that he was mainly instrumental in
                        permitting to obtain headway in our country, and who was such a terrible
                        Federalist that it is said he boasted of not having even a drop of
                        Democratic blood in his veins. We say, it may be out of respect for the
                        feelings of James Buchanan, that prince of the Federalists, that it has
                        dropped the one and adopted the other.</p>
                    <p>But what is an Abolitionist? According to the <emph rend="italic"
                        >Spirit</emph>, an Abolitionist is a <emph rend="italic">fiend!</emph> and a
                        fiend, Webster says, is "an infernal being"--"the devil." Well, we will
                        again refer to Webster to see what his definition of the word Abolitionist
                        is one who favors "the immediate emancipation of slaves." A person, then,
                        who favors the emancipation of slaves, or who wishes to carry out God's
                        command to "let the oppressed go free," is a <emph rend="italic"
                        >fiend!</emph> To comply, therefore, with God's direct command, the <emph
                            rend="italic">Spirit</emph> argues, is to become a fiend! We cannot
                        refrain from saying, just here, that such fiends have multiplied enormously,
                        fearfully, since the bombardment of Fort Sumpter, and among them may be
                        enumerated such sterling Democrats as Gen. Bulter, Gen. Dickinson, Hon. John
                        Cochran, M. C., of New York, and a host of others we might name, if it were
                        necessary.</p>
                    <p>As a general thing, ninety-nine out of every hundred men, who profess to be
                        Abolitionists, are the most upright, moral, pious men of the community in
                        which they dwell, and they have naturally become Abolitionists in their
                        endeavors to carry out Christ's injunction: "Whatsoever ye would that men
                        should do to you, do ye even so to them,"--but to follow this rule, the
                            <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> argues, makes man a <emph
                            rend="italic">fiend</emph>, and instead of advancing his spiritual life,
                        it tends to death!</p>
                    <p>We are not now, nor were we ever an Abolitionist; not because we believe
                        there is anything intrinsically wrong in the doctrine, but from prudential
                        motives. The time has passed when odium can be attached to a man for being
                        an Abolitionist. We are for the preservation of our Constitution and Union,
                        at all hazards, and if Slavery stands in the way of their preservation, then
                        we are for striking down Slavery--or, in other words, we then become an
                        Abolitionist. If it is the Jonah, to save the ship let it be thrown
                        overboard. But it is that very thing which gives our neighbor so much grief
                        and trouble. He does not want Jonah thrown into the sea of oblivion--and to
                        save Jonah, he is willing to run the risk of losing the ship and cargo.</p>
                    <p>If all right-thinking men in the North are not Abolitionists, they are at
                        least antislavery in sentiment, and it is no credit to a Free State man'
                        head or heart to say that he is not anti-slavery in his views.</p>
                    <p>Or as John Randolph, of Va., said, in reply to a Northern dough-face who
                        attempted to justify Slavery in a speech in Congress, "I envy neither the
                        head or the heart of the Northern man who can stand up here and attempt to
                        justify Slavery on principle."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Protests the Valley Spirit's characterization of abolitionists as "fiends."
                    The editor of the Dispatch argues that the paper is not abolitionist in
                    sentiment, but asserts that any person who upholds the institution of slavery to
                    the detriment of the Union, as the Spirit seems to do, is at best misguided.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Death of John Tyler</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Briefly outlines the life of John Tyler, after suggesting that the nation
                    would not likely mourn the recent death of the ex-President.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Heart of the Confederacy</head>
                <origin>Philadelphia Inquirer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that the recent Union victory in Kentucky against General
                    Zollicoffer will be extremely important for the Union to get at the "military,
                    as well as geographical heart of the Confederacy."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>State Treasurer</head>
                <origin>Harrisburg Telegraph</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Expresses great satisfaction at the election of Henry D. Moore, Esq., as
                    state treasurer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Our Relations with England</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Gleans from a letter by a "New York letter writer" that it is likely peace
                    will be upheld between the United States and England.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Acts of the Last Legislature</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Speculates that the "House resolution calling for the investigation of the
                    acts of the last Legislature" is part of an attempt to impeach Governor Curtin.
                    Notes that a committee will soon be appointed to carry out the investigation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Particulars of the battle at Somerset, Kentucky, column 3; news from
                Washington, column 4; brief items of news, including a proclamation by Secretary of
                War Stanton ordering the War Department be closed Tuesdays through Fridays to all
                business unrelated to "active military operations in the field," column 5;
                advertisements, column 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.sd.1862.01.24.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Franklin County Bible Society</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that a celebration will be held the following Sabbath evening in
                    the Presbyterian church to commemorate the 49th anniversary of the Franklin
                    County Bible Society.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Glorious Victory</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"There was no Pennsylvania troops in the engagement; but if there had been,
                    the result would have been the same or perhaps, 'a little more so.'"</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that the recent victory for the Union will cause the "Rebels" as much
                    discouragement as it will bring confidence and hope to the Union forces.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Regiments Consolidated</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that all the unattached companies at Camp Curtin have been
                    transferred to Colonel Meredith's Regiment. That regiment along with the 101st
                    will move this week to Philadelphia to join a Southern expedition to be composed
                    only of Pennsylvania troops.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Taking Cold</head>
                <origin>Scientific American</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"A person may go directly from a hot bath into a cold one, or into snow,
                    even, and not take cold as he would by pouring a couple of table spoonsfull of
                    water upon some part of his dress or by standing in a door, or by opening
                    another, where one part of the body is colder than another."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Advises that colds can be prevented by maintaining a uniformity of
                    temperature throughout the body.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Poem and Concert</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports favorable on the reading of "The Times" by Mr. Seilhamer and on the
                    musical performances presented the previous Tuesday night.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>An Important Work</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Philadelphia Inquirer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates the progress of the telegraph line between Wilmington, Delaware,
                    and Fortress Monroe.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Reports involving Colonel Garfield's victory in Kentucky, the possibility of
                an attack on Norfolk, and a letter from the Petersubrg Express, column 3;
                advertisements, columns 4 and 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.sd.1862.01.24.04">
            <pageNote>Proceedings of Congress, column 1; prices current, column 1; advertisements,
                columns 2-5</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
