<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="sd1862/pa.fr.sd.1862.03.28">
    <header>
        <title>Semi-Weekly Dispatch</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sarah Roth</taggerName>
            <tagDate>7/14/98</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1862-03-28">
            <year>1862</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day>28</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>bi-weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.sd.1862.03.28.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Speech of Parson Brownlow</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Gentlemen, I am no Abolitionist! . . . Let me insure you that the South
                    have suffered no infringement on her institutions; the slavery question was
                    actually no pretext for this unholy, unrighteous conflict."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prints the speech made in Nashville on March 17 by Parson Brownlow,
                    describing his time as a captive of the Confederacy and bemoaning the path that
                    the "treasonous" Senators from the South have chosen, to reject the federal
                    government to which, not long before, they had pledged their allegiance.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 1-3; poem, column 3</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.sd.1862.03.28.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Words Fitly Spoken</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The existence of Slavery in any part of our country is a damning blotch
                    upon our national reputation as a free people; but that the presence of the
                    hideous monster should be permitted longer to disgrace the Federal Capital, is
                    without excuse or palliation."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Slavery in the District of Columbia has engaged the attention of Congress for
                        some time past, and during a debate in the Senate, the other day, upon the
                        subject, Mr. Davis, of Ky., and other Southern men, in opposition to this
                        righteous and desirable measure, as though it conflicted with the rights of
                        the Slave States, remarked, that the South would resist any measure of
                        emancipation," and that Kentuckians would die in defence of their rights."
                        In reply to this "dying in the last ditch" bombast, Senator Wilson, of
                        Mass., said:--</p>
                    <p>He would tell the Senators that the day for threats and menaces from the
                        champions for threats and menaces from the champions of slavery had passed
                        by in the Senate, and the Representatives of freemen are not cowardly enough
                        to shrink from the performance of their duty by the dogmatic avowals what
                        Southern men and women would do.</p>
                    <p>The existence of Slavery in any part of our country is a damning blotch upon
                        our national reputation as a free people; but that the presence of the
                        hideous monster should be permitted longer to disgrace the Federal Capital,
                        is without excuse or palliation. Congress legislates for the District, and
                        can control the whole matter. If the present Congress should, therefore,
                        adjourn without signifying to the world that Slavery is condemned by the
                        American people, by its abolition in the District, regardless of puerile
                        threats from any quarter, as a people, we must stand before the nations of
                        the earth condemned as approvers and supporters of the monstrous crime.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates part of a debate in the Senate concerning the abolition of slavery
                    in the District of Columbia. Prints the words of Senator Wilson of
                    Massachusetts, who replied to Kentucky Senator Mr. Davis's assertion that
                    emancipation of any kind would infringe on Southern rights and that Southern
                    states would resist such measures. Senator Wilson said that "the day for threats
                    and menaces from the champions of slavery had passed by in the Senate."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Catholic on the Slavery Question</head>
                <origin>Pittsburgh Catholic</origin>
                <commentary>"The Pittsburgh Catholic, in an article in this week's issue, takes
                    decided grounds on the slavery question."</commentary>
                <excerpt>"We can, however, remove the dung that is at our doors, no matter who put
                    it there; and, accordingly, we want slavery removed from the gates of the
                    capitol of this free republic."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Pittsburgh <emph rend="italic">Catholic</emph>, in an article in this
                        week's issue, takes decided grounds on the slavery question. It says: "We
                        are glad to perceive that there is much likelihood of the speedy abolition
                        of slavery in the District of Columbia. We believe there is no
                        constitutional difficulty in the way of such a measure. If it can be done
                        without infringing on the constitutional rights of Southerners, it ought to
                        be done. Slavery always was a disgrace to the national capital, but the
                        reasons that justified its toleration there, exist no longer. Negro slavery,
                        as it exists in this country, has no rights, for a wrong can have no rights.
                        I must, however, be tolerated by the general government, and by us, simply
                        because it is not our business to interfere with it. It is strictly a State
                        institution, or, we should rather say, a State sin. After stating that we
                        must bear with it in those States where it exists, however we may bewail its
                        existence," it adds: "We can, however, remove the dung that is at our doors,
                        no matter who put it there; and, accordingly, we want slavery removed from
                        the gates of the capitol of this free republic." </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Catholic argues that slavery is wrong, but that it is an issue that
                    each state must decide for itself. Approves of the abolition of slavery in the
                    District of Columbia, where Congress has jurisdiction.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>A Battle at Winchester on Sunday!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Recounts a battle at Winchester, Virginia, in which the Union forces were
                    victorious.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Glorious Victory near Winchester</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The details of the fight on Sunday record more deeds of personal heroism
                    and daring than any battle in history."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports incidents of heroism among Union soldiers at the recent battle at
                    Winchester, Virginia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Important News from Gen. Burnside</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports the capture of Beaufort, North Carolina, by General Burnside's
                    forces.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Wendell Phillips Mobbed at Cincinnati</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Cincinnati, March 24.--Wendell Phillips attempted to lecture at Pike's Opera
                        House to-night.</p>
                    <p>He commenced by avowing himself as Abolitionist and a Disunionist. Persons in
                        the galleries then hissed, yelled and throw eggs and stones at him, many of
                        which hit him. The hissing was kept up for some time.</p>
                    <p>Finally Phillips made himself heard, and he proceeded until something again
                        objectionable was said, when the storm of eggs was renewed. The aim, in many
                        cases, was good. Still Phillips persevered, and a third time was hissed, and
                        a third time egged and stoned.</p>
                    <p>The crowd from the galleries then moved down stairs, crying "put him out,"
                        "tar and feather him!" with groans for the "nigger Wendell Phillips." While
                        proceeding down the middle aisle towards the stage, they were met by the
                        friends of Phillips, when a fight ensued.</p>
                    <p>A scene of indescribable confusion occurred. The ladies in the audience were
                        screaming, crying, jumping over chairs and falling in all directions during
                        the skirmish.</p>
                    <p>Finally Phillips was taken off the stage by his friends, and the audience
                        moved out.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates that Wendell Phillips, after declaring himself an abolitionist and
                    a disunionist was pelted with eggs and stones by a crowd at Pike's Opera House,
                    which also hissed and yelled at him. After the lecture, a fight ensued.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Complaint by the Dispatch about editors who malign each other in a personal
                manner in their newspapers, column 1; further reports from Island No. 10 in the
                Mississippi River, off the coast of Kentucky, columns 4 and 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.sd.1862.03.28.03">
            <div type="l">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Contrast</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A friend has permitted us to publish the following extract of a letter
                        written by a brother in Philadelphia, who has, within a few days past,
                        returned from a visit to Kentucky. The desolation and suffering that he
                        refers to within the vast theatre of Rebel barbarism, must be truly
                        heartrending, presenting a striking contrast of the condition of the people
                        in the desolated region in Kentucky with that of our own highly favored
                        inhabitants of Southern Pennsylvania:</p>
                    <p>Philadelphia, March 22.</p>
                    <p>Dear Brother--I arrived home on last Monday, and, taking all things into
                        consideration, my trip to Kentucky was much more successful than I
                        anticipated. I got down as low as Bowling Green. The Rebels, after holding
                        that town or five months, with the strongest fortifications I ever saw, and
                        between fifty to sixty thousand troops under the generalship of Johnson,
                        Hardee and Buckner, were obliged to evacuate their strong fortifications and
                        the town, not without, however, destroying forty per cent. of the houses,
                        burning the bridges, stealing horses, mules and wagons. Of their army, some
                        four thousand died, and were indifferently buried, littering the deserted
                        places of their encampments with a large accumulation of animal and
                        vegetable offal. The stench from these sure sources of disease is absolutely
                        sickening, and will produce typhoid or some other malignant fever. The
                        country is devastated for fifty miles around, and not a fence or bridge is
                        to be seen. The vandalism of these scoundrels cannot be exaggerated, and you
                        have only to see the picture of desolation to be convinced of their
                        thieving, rascally and destructive policy.</p>
                    <p>The feeling among the people is growing daily, and the hatred is intense
                        between the loyal Union men and women and the Southern rights people, as the
                        secessionists call themselves. Families are broken up, and no intercourse is
                        had between loyal and disunion neighbors. Even the Church is being divided,
                        preacher against older, member against member, and a general disposition
                        among congregations to quarrel over our nation's troubles, although
                        two-thirds of the population of Kentucky are Union without an if or a but,
                        the balance, one-third, being strong secessionists.</p>
                    <p>In view of the destructive Rebel policy referred to in the above extract,
                        would any citizen of Franklin county, who has thus far enjoyed security of
                        life and property, listen to the croaking of the <emph rend="italic"
                        >Spirit</emph>, and murmur at the prospect of future taxation which will
                        enable our Government to crush out this monstrous Rebellion? </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prints an excerpt from a letter that was written by a man from Philadelphia
                    who recently returned from a visit to Kentucky and describes the suffering that
                    the people are experiencing there.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Fron Tennessee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes the situation in Nashville, where Governor Johnson has issued a
                    proclamation of "a conciliatory character," expressing a desire to win the
                    people back into the Union, but to suppress every sign of treason.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Another Speech from Train</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prints a portion of a speech given in London by George Francis Train in
                    which Train argues that the South has no "elements of civilization," as is
                    evidenced by their lack of financial, commercial, artistic, manufacturing, or
                    inventive greats.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flickinger</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCurdy</ln>
                        <fn>Lizzie J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCurdy</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Major</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. David Flickinger and Miss Lizzie J. McCurdy were married on March 20 at
                    the house of the bride's father, Major James McCurdy, all of Metal township.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Rumors and news items concerning Tennessee, New Orleans, Washington, and
                Chicago, column 2; advertisements, columns 4 and 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.sd.1862.03.28.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Campaign Opened</head>
                <origin>Philadelphia Press</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Applauds General McClellan for beginning the upcoming campaign against the
                    South. Predicts victory for his forces.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Prices current, column 2; advertisements, columns 2-5</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
