<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="sd1862/pa.fr.sd.1862.04.25">
    <header>
        <title>Semi-Weekly Dispatch</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sarah Roth</taggerName>
            <tagDate>7/16/98</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1862-04-25">
            <year>1862</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day>25</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>bi-weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.sd.1862.04.25.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Freedom in the District</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Echoes the answer given by the Washington National Republican and the Press
                    to those who have denounced the abolition of slavery in the District of
                    Columbia. Reprints several paragraphs from a petition submitted to Congress in
                    1828 by residents of the District asking that a scheme for gradual emancipation
                    be implemented.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Parson Brownlow at the Methodist Book Concern, Cincinnati</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Summarizes Parson Brownlow's speech, in which he outlined the position and
                    actions of the clergy in the South that he had encountered. The parson stated
                    that most of them were secessionists, and that the few who were not could do
                    little more than denounce secession, or they would be hung, regardless of their
                    age.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Movements at Yorktown</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"It is evident that all the appliances of modern warfare will be called
                    into requisition, and, if the battle soon expected occurs, it will probably
                    prove one of the most desperate that has ever taken place in any age or
                    country."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Predicts that the next great battle of the war will take place at Yorktown,
                    and that if the Union forces are able to defeat a Southern force that appears to
                    be well prepared and well led, the victory would be of the utmost importance for
                    the North.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Memorial from the Colored People</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the African-American people of Washington have presented a
                    memorial to Congress in which they express their gratitude for the recent action
                    by which they were able to secure their freedom. In the memorial, however, they
                    also requested a place to which they might emigrate and suggested Central
                    America for the purpose.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Prisoner Shot at the Old Capitol Prison</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates that a prisoner who refused to follow an order to remove his head
                    from his window was shot by a guard at the Old Capitol Prison in Hagerstown.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 1 and 2</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.sd.1862.04.25.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Junior Indignant</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Indeed, teachers should caution their intelligent pupils to beware of the
                    error abounding Spirit, for a too frequent perusal of it might vitiate their
                    English, in which they are striving to become proficient, as well as their
                    morals."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Berates the Valley Spirit for its grammatical and typographical errors and
                    suggests that they employ "more experienced writers."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Another Disloyal Democrat</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the committee investigating the alleged disloyalty of Senator
                    Starke from Oregon has determined that he offered support to the Confederacy and
                    therefore was indeed disloyal to the government of the United States.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The True Reason</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Slavery has grown powerful, defiant, domineering and dictatorial, and
                    because it cannot rule the Republic for its own interest, it seeks to sink both
                    it and freedom in a common ruin."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Refutes the claim made by the Valley Spirit that it is the existence of
                    abolitionists and not of slavery that is to blame for the war. Argues that the
                    Spirit is not condemning the crime but the attempt to get rid of the crime as
                    the evil.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Spirit and the Workingmen</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Points out that the Valley Spirit has attempted to deny the Dispatch's
                    charge that by ridiculing what the Spirit calls "small politicians" it has
                    "sneered" at the workingmen of Chambersburg. The Dispatch again defends the
                    artisans of the town from ill treatment in the press by the Spirit.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>From Memphis</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the South still claims the battle at Pittsburg Landing as a
                    victory, allegedly because more Union men were killed, wounded, or taken
                    prisoner than were Confederate men.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements for political candidates, column 1; news of a skirmish on
                Wilmington Island, news from General Bank's column that all is calm, official
                dispatch from General Banks, news of the continuing bombardment of Fort Wright,
                column 3; report that Governor Harvey of Wisconsin has drowned, that Fort Pillow has
                not been fired on in three days, and that a shipment of cotton and tobacco from the
                Tennessee River arrived in Pittsburgh, column 4; news of a murder in York County and
                other brief items and advertisements, column 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.sd.1862.04.25.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Maj. George Stetzel</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"He looks remarkable well, and reports the boys in good health, fine
                    spirits and anxious to be led against the enemies of their country and of
                    freedom."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Major George Stetzel, of Harlan's Pennsylvania Cavalry,
                    visited friends in Chambersburg a few days prior.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Died from Wounds</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that a member of Captain Wishart's Company who comes from Fulton
                    County died from wounds received at the battle of Pittsburg Landing. His name
                    was not given.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Death of a Soldier</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Essom</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that John Essom, a young man from Chambersburg whose parents live
                    on East Queen street, died of chronic diarrhea in the hospital at Nashville,
                    Tennessee, on March 29. He was about 24 years of age and was a member of Company
                    A of the 77th Pennsylvania.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Contrabands</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that several escaped slaves arrived in Chambersburg the previous
                    Tuesday morning and have been "loitering" around town since. The Dispatch
                    remarks that the fugitives should maintain "eternal vigilance" while there are
                    still Breckinridge Democrats in town.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Promotion</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thomas</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces that Lieutenant Thomas of Chambersburg, who has been recruiting
                    for Company A of the 77th Pennsylvania, was promoted to Captain of Company H of
                    the same regiment. Like all other recruiters, Captain Thomas has been ordered to
                    rejoin his comrades in the field.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Game Laws</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reminds readers that it is unlawful to kill bluebirds, swallow, robins, or
                    any other birds that eat insects, at any season. Points out that the killing of
                    these birds has brought the destruction of fruit trees by insects.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>A Young Horse Thief</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stout</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walk</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Groosman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Relates that a boy of about fourteen, calling himself James Stout, was
                    looking for a place to live and was taken in by Mr. F. Walk of Guilford
                    township. Soon after taking up residence with Mr. Walk, the boy was caught
                    attempting to steal a horse from Mr. Groosman, while the latter was attending
                    church. The boy is now in prison.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Cut Worms</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Recommends a remedy for the cut worm, which destroys corn crops.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nicklas</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henneberger</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Peter Nicklas and Miss Margaret Henneberger, both of Chambersburg, were
                    married on April 15.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henneberger</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nicklas</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nicklas</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henneberger</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Samuel Henneberger and Miss Mary E. Nicklas, both of Chambersburg, were
                    married at the same time and place--April 15 in Chambersburg--as Mr. Peter
                    Nicklas and Miss Margaret Henneberger.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>John Henry, aged 5 years and 6 months, died of catarrh in Hamilton township
                    on April 19. He was the son of David and Maria Henry.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 3-5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.sd.1862.04.25.04">
            <pageNote>Prices current, column 1; advertisements, columns 1-5</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
