<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="sd1862/pa.fr.sd.1862.04.01">
    <header>
        <title>Semi-Weekly Dispatch</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sarah Roth</taggerName>
            <tagDate>7/15/98</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1862-04-01">
            <year>1862</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day>01</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>bi-weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.sd.1862.04.01.01">
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 1-3; letter sent by telegraph to Colonel Buford at
                Kentucky from the telegraphic operator at Hickman, Kentucky, column 4; story of a
                fight between a Southern regiment from Kentucky who were preparing to go home and an
                Alabama and Tennessee regiment that attempted to prevent them from doing so, column
                4; account of the battle at Winchester, Virginia, including a number of official
                circulars, column 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.sd.1862.04.01.02">
            <pageNote>Article tracing the use of reserves in history, column 1; reports of the
                appointment of General Caldwell as a Major-General of Volunteers, of the death of
                "noted rebel chief" Ben M'Culloch, and of a railroad accident involving a Wisconsin
                regiment, column 1; report of the explosion in Philadelphia of the building that
                housed Professor Samuel Jackson's fire works and cartridge factory, columns 2 and 3;
                further reports of the fight at Island No. 10, columns 3 and 4; news from Fortress
                Monroe, column 4; report that Union troops are advancing on Knoxville, columns 4 and
                5; news from Arkansas, column 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.sd.1862.04.01.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Thunder and Lightning</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that the previous Sunday, in the middle of the day, a storm came upon
                    Chambersburg that brought thunder, lightning, and a shower of hail.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Growing Grain Crop</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the present crop of grain in the county is perhaps the best
                    that has ever grown there.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Promotion</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Treher</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sergeant</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces the promotion of Sergeant Treher, of the 5th Ohio Regiment, to
                    First Sergeant. He comes from Franklin County and once worked in the Dispatch
                    office.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Rev. Alexandr [sic] Owen</head>
                <origin>New York Christian Advocate</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Owen</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports the death of the Reverend Alexander Owen, who served as an
                    itinerant minister in the Pennsylvania Conference. He was born in Franklin
                    County and learned the mason's trade in Chambersburg before being converted and
                    answering the call to preach.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Female Volunteers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The same love of country and desire for fame actuate our female
                    volunteers, who don male attire and present themselves at the various recruiting
                    stations in the North for enlistment."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates the story of a young woman who, disguised as a boy, joined Captain
                    A. J. Brand's regiment in Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="j">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>A List of Jurors</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heyser</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf>Sr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLanahan</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maurer</ln>
                        <fn>J. LaTrobe</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Piper</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Perry</ln>
                        <fn>Saml</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shively</ln>
                        <fn>J. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spangler</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>J. Boyd</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strock</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Metcalf</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lists the jurors drawn for the court session to be held in Chambersburg
                    beginning on Monday, April 14. William Heyser, Sr., of Chambersburg will serve
                    as a grand juror. John B. McLanahan, B. Latrobe Maurer, David Piper, Saml Perry,
                    J. G. Shively, Jacob Spangler, and J. Boyd Wright, all of Chambersburg, will
                    serve as traverse jurors during the first week. In the second week, Daniel
                    Strock and Thomas Metcalf of Chambersburg will serve as traverse jurors.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Exports in War Time</head>
                <origin>New York World</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the exports of the city of New York are greater than they were
                    at this time last year or the one before. Points out that the warnings of the
                    South that the trade of the United States would fall to "ruin" at the cessation
                    of the Southern trade proved mistaken.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>News from the Potomac, columns 3 and 4; article about the theft of two rings
                from the body of a woman who had been buried near Alexandria, Virginia, information
                about how mortars are discharged, news of an attempted assassination of Billy
                Wilson, column 4; advertisements, columns 4 and 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.sd.1862.04.01.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Terrible Weapon</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Thirty shots were fired in a minute and a third, at a distance of one
                    hundred yards, and the thirty bullet holes in the target could be covered by a
                    piece of paper six inches square."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes Henry's Patent Repeating Rile, which is being tested for the
                    first time.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Incidents of the battle at Pea Ridge, Arkansas, column 1; anecdotes, column 2;
                prices current, column 2; advertisements, columns 2-5;</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
