<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="sd1862/pa.fr.sd.1862.05.02">
    <header>
        <title>Semi-Weekly Dispatch</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sarah Roth</taggerName>
            <tagDate>7/16/98</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1862-05-02">
            <year>1862</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day>02</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>bi-weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.sd.1862.05.02.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Capture of New Orleans</head>
                <origin>Philadelphia Press</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Expresses the hope that the information that New Orleans has been taken,
                    which has been learned only from Southern sources, is correct. Also points out
                    that the taking of New Orleans would likely be the most important event of the
                    war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The President and Republicanism</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Let the American States, therefore, draw closer together and animate and
                    reassure each other, and thus prove to the world that, although we have
                    inherited some of the errors of ancient systems, we are nevertheless capable of
                    completing and establishing the new one which we have chosen."--President
                    Lincoln</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates that the President recently told the Minister of Salvador that if
                    the Union is preserved, the United States will have demonstrated that
                    Republicanism can preserve the state against factionalism.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Hon. A. H. Reeder</head>
                <origin>Erie Gazette</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Praises the party leadership and exceptional character of Governor Reeder.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Their Situation at Corinth</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Predicts that a battle at or near Corinth is inevitable.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Death of Mrs. Lincoln's Brother</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article of four lines in length that reports the death of Samuel B. Todd,
                    the brother of Mrs. Lincoln who fought for the South. He died from wounds he
                    incurred at Shiloh in the action of April 7. The Dispatch does not comment
                    further.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 1 and 2; letter from Parson Brownlow stating that he
                will never join the Democratic party column 3; note that Parson Brownlow has
                accepted the chaplaincy of the 69th Ohio, column 4</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.sd.1862.05.02.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Iron Is King</head>
                <origin>Philadelphia Bulletin</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Points out that iron will eclipse cotton in importance for the world, as
                    the Monitor and the Merrimac have demonstrated.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Navy Supplies</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lists the amount of supplies that is estimated will be needed by the navy
                    for the coming fiscal year. Includes three million pounds of biscuits; 600,000
                    pounds of rice; and 150,000 gallons of whiskey.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Latest from New Orleans</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Confirms the preliminary reports that New Orleans was captured by Union
                    troops under the command of Captain Porter. Also prints the dispatch from the
                    Southern force that fled the city.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>From Gen. Halleck's Army</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Offers further confirmation of the fall of New Orleans.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements for political candidates, column 1; account of President
                Lincoln's visit aboard the French frigate Gassendi, column 2; reports from General
                McClellan's army at Yorktown, news from Fortress Monroe, report of the death of
                General Johnston, column 4; advertisements, column 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.sd.1862.05.02.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The May Festival</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that the May Festival in Chambersburg, held the previous evening at
                    Franklin Hall, proved "a very pleasant and attractive entertainment."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Sudden Death</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weaver</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Regrets the death of Mr. Jacob Weaver, aged 67 years, who died suddenly on
                    the previous Monday night in his residence in St. Thomas township.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Flag of the Seventy-Seventh Pennsylvania</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Governor Curtin presented the flag of the 77th Pennsylvania,
                    which was torn from the bursting of a shell in the battle of Shiloh. The troops
                    then departed for Kentucky. Thirteen men in the regiment were wounded, and ten
                    are expected to recover.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Pennsylvanians at Pittsburg Landing</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Official Report.</p>
                    <p>Head-Quarters Fifth Brigade, <lb/>Battle-field near Pittsburg Landing, Tenn.
                        <lb/>April 12th, 1862.</p>
                    <p>Honored Sir:--I embrace the first moment of time allotted me since the
                        terrific battle of the 6th and 7th inst., to inform you that the old
                        Keystone was represented in the battle of the 7th inst., by the 77th
                        regiment.</p>
                    <p>We were 28 or 30 miles from the scene of action from the scene of action on
                        Sabbath morning the 6th inst., when we distinctly heard the cannonading,
                        and, of course, made all possible haste to reach the battle field. Leaving
                        our transportation we marched forward 22 or 23 miles, over roads almost
                        impassable, to Savannah on the Tennessee river, where we arrived at 7
                        o'clock P.M., and after standing in the street under a most drenching rain
                        for eight hours, we embarked on board a boat at 3 o'clock A. M., on the
                        morning of the 7th, and landed at Pittsburg Landing at 6 o'clock the same
                        day, when, after a hasty cup of coffee and a cracker had been disposed of,
                        we were ordered forward into battle. The 77th was held in reserve for the
                        5th Brigade from 6 o'clock to 11 o'clock A. M., under a galling fire,
                        without being allowed to fire a gun, when we were ordered to support the 4th
                        Brigade, commanded by Gen. Rosseau, which they did till about 12 o'clock,
                        when the Regiment was detached by order of Gen. M'Cook, for the purpose of
                        flanking three regiments of the enemy, which the 77th nobly did, and also in
                        the meantime fired upon and silenced one of the enemy's batteries by killing
                        all their horses and many of their men. Just here a considerable body of
                        rebel cavalry charged down upon us, but were repulsed with severe loss.
                        Again they came and again the 77th repulsed them, when they retreated in
                        confusion. Our Regiment took many prisoners that day, among whom was Colonel
                        Battles, of the 2d Tennessee infantry.</p>
                    <p>Suffice it to say that all the officers and men of the 77th fought cooly and
                        bravely that entire day. I am especially indebted to Lieut. Col. Housum and
                        Maj. Bradford for distinguished services during the battle.</p>
                    <p>Our loss is quite meagre--only two or three mortally wounded, and some five
                        or six seriously and slightly. This, I apprehend, is on account of our
                        loading and firing lying on the ground.</p>
                    <p>The loss on the Federal side is very heavy, but nothing to compare with the
                        loss of the Rebels.</p>
                    <p>The ranking officers of our brigade all being wounded, I find myself in
                        command of the Brigade, and I may add it was <emph rend="italic">the</emph>
                        Brigade on Monday.</p>
                    <p>Trusting that you will pardon this incomplete and badly written epistle,
                        written on a drum head,</p>
                    <p>I am, dear sir, <lb/>Your obedient servant, <lb/>F. S. Stumbaugh.</p>
                    <p>To his Excellency, A. G. Curtin, Governor of Pennsylvania.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Publishes the official report to Governor Curtin of the actions of
                    Pennsylvania troops in the battle at Pittsburg landing (aka Shiloh).</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Rebel Outrages at Manassas</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Washington, April 30.--The committee on the conduct of the war, made a report
                        today, on the subject of the barbarities committed by the rebels at
                        Manassas, on the bodies of the federal soldiers, who fell at that battle.</p>
                    <p>The committee give ample evidence to sustain all the previous allegations.
                        The report shows that the most inhuman acts were perpetrated by the rebels.
                        The committee say:</p>
                    <p>"The outrages on the bodies of our dead will revive recollections of the
                        cruelties to which savages subject their prisoners. Our soldiers were buried
                        in many cases naked, face downwards."</p>
                    <p>In other cases, the testimony shows that the bodies were left to decay in the
                        open air. Their bones were dug up and carried off as trophies. Drinking cups
                        were made of their skulls, &amp;c.</p>
                    <p>The testimony of Governor Sprague is extremely interesting.</p>
                    <p>One of our men, who was taken prisoner, testifies that five of his comrades
                        were shot by sentinels. The murders were prompted by other rebels.</p>
                    <p>Dr. Honiston, Surgeon of the New York Fourteenth regiment, testifies that the
                        rebels brutally refused him permission to aid the wounded who were under his
                        charge on the field. He avers that he saw rebel Surgeons unnecessarily and
                        inhumanly operate on our soldiers. Some of our wounded were left lying on
                        the field at Bull Run, through one rainy and one sultry day, and when they
                        were at last brought in, their wounds were completely alive with larvae
                        deposited by flies.</p>
                    <p>Gen. Richetts testifies that the rebels threatened to knock his brains out as
                        he lay on the ground, wounded: that they stripped his first lieutenant and
                        left him naked on the field. Also, that our soldiers who died at Richmond
                        were buried naked along with negro corpses.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prints several excerpts from the report made by the Committee on the
                    Conduct of the War that give examples of the "rebel outrages" that were
                    perpetrated at Manassas.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Highlands</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. John Highlands, aged 75 years and 11 months, died in St. Thomas
                    township on April 25 after a lingering illness.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Account of an incident at Pittsburg Landing involving Captain Terrill's
                battery, column 3; advertisements, columns 3-5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.sd.1862.05.02.04">
            <pageNote>Prices current, column 1; advertisements, columns 1-5;</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
