<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; --><!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1867/va.au.rv.1867.03.29">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>03/14</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1867-03-29">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day>29</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1867.03.29.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The President's Views of Military Republics</head>
                <origin>New York Herald</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>According to the correspondent, President Johnson is opposed to holding
                    elections in areas of the South under "military control" because it is in
                    "conflict with the spirit of republican institutions." Johnson justifies his
                    position by drawing upon the words of Daniel Webster.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1867.03.29.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We publish elsewhere the Bill supplementary to the Military Re-construction
                        Bill, which was passed over the President's veto by a vote of 40 to 7 in the
                        Senate and 114 to 25 in the House, and is, therefore, a law. In this bill,
                        together with the proposed Constitutional Amendment and Military
                        Re-construction bill, the South has the programme of re-construction, to the
                        completion of which the time and labors (we will no say wisdom) of Congress
                        has been devoted for the past two years. The best comment on the various
                        acts of Congress, on this subject, have been the veto message of the
                        President, which for clearness, conscience and critical analysis, and a
                        desire to preserve the Government of Fathers, are remarkable State
                        documents. The message vetoing the Supplemental Bill, which we publish in
                        connection with it, is an able paper and forcibly shows up this bill. Our
                        readers will, no doubt, read the message carefully, but we desire to call
                        their attention to a point made by the President that the present
                        Constitutions of the Southern States are, if possible, more republican than
                        when the Union was originally formed, and that Congress demands no change to
                        be made in their provisions, except those which confine the suffrage to
                        whites, and draws this patent conclusion, that, in the exercise of the
                        Constitutional provision to guarantee a republican form of government to
                        every State in the Union, if Congress makes (as seems to be the case) negro
                        suffrage a <emph rend="italic">sine qua non</emph>, then re-construction
                        might as well commence in Pennsylvania or Ohio (both having lately refused
                        to allow negroes to vote) as in Virginia or North Carolina.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors discuss the potential ramifications of the Supplementary
                    Reconstruction Bill, which passed over the president's veto, and argue that the
                    law, in combination with the Military Reconstruction Bill and the proposed
                    Constitutional Amendment, will make the South "more republican than when the
                    Union was originally formed."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In the wake of the passage of the S. S. S. Bill, which calls for a state
                    convention to be held, the editors refute the notion that all members of the
                    Virginia Senate who voted in favor of the measure based their decision on
                    nefarious motives. Sometimes, they explain, legislators, like editors, are
                    "liable to err."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Before adjourning, the General Assembly passed a bill "to pay 4 percent
                    interest on State debt."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Bill Supplementary to the Stevens-Sherman-Shellabarger Bill</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Contains a copy of the Supplementary bill as approved by Congress over
                    President Johnson's veto. The bill establishes regulations for voter
                    registration and state conventions.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>President's Message</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Andrew Johnson</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article includes President Johnson's Veto of the Supplementary
                    Reconstruction Bill, which Congress overrode.</summary>
                <note>To view a full transcript of the message see the 4/3/1867 edition of the
                    Valley Spirit.</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1867.03.29.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Proceedings of the County Court</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Breckenridge</ln>
                        <fn>A. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yount</ln>
                        <fn>W. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pilson</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>James M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Byers</ln>
                        <fn>R. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ryan</ln>
                        <fn>J. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shifflett</ln>
                        <fn>A. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Golliday</ln>
                        <fn>J. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Van Lear</ln>
                        <fn>A. G. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Varner</ln>
                        <fn>Washington</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hill</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hill</ln>
                        <fn>Reuben</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jackson</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pannel</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>Calvin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sutler</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McComick</ln>
                        <fn>William D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Marshall</ln>
                        <fn>James H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peck</ln>
                        <fn>H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickle</ln>
                        <fn>R. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>"An order of Court was made to enable A. N. Breckenridge, W. J. Yount, J.
                    A. Patterson, John Pilson, James M. Brown, R. G. Byers, J. N. Ryan, A. E.
                    Shifflet, J. F. Golliday, A. G. L. Van Lear and Washington Varner, each of whom
                    lost a limb in the Confederate service, to obtain artificial limbs. The Grand
                    Jury made indictments against Martin Hill, Reuben Hill, Samuel Jackson and Frank
                    Harris, colored, and David Hanger, white, for petit larceny, and Daniel Pannel
                    and Calvin Davis for assault and battery. G. W. Sutler renewed his bond as
                    Notary Public. James W. Baldwin qualified as Deputy Clerk. William D. McComick
                    and James H. Marshall were appointed surveyors of roads. An order was made to
                    summon the Justices to the next term for the purpose of granting licenses to
                    Hotel-keepers &amp;c. H. H. Peck and R. G. Bickle were appointed a committee
                    to have the secret gutter on the Court House removed and its place supplied by a
                    hanging gutter. The Court very wisely, on Monday last, on account of the roads
                    and the prospect of fair weather, dismissed jurors, witnesses &amp;c. "</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn>George L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces that George L. Peyton, "the present popular proprietor of the
                    Virginia Hotel," will operate the Greenbrier White Sulphur Springs this season.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>Bolivar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes that Col. Bolivar Christian will present a lecture at the Staunton
                    Lyceum next Monday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Warns that if the market laws are not amended, they "will drive our
                    enterprising butchers, who have opened fresh meat establishments on Main street,
                    back to the Market House." Sentiment in town, relates the article, is decidedly
                    in favor of this modification because residents prefer the convenience.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shirley</ln>
                        <fn>Jonathan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swoops</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Price</ln>
                        <fn>W. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On March 10 Jonathan Shirley, of Indiana, and Maggie E. Swoops were married
                    by Rev. W. T. Price.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Englemen</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Arehart</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Karacofe</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Howman</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On March 21 Jacob H. Englemen and Sarah J. Arehart were married at the
                    residence of Jacob Howman, by Rev. J. W. Karacofe.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Akens</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wiseman</ln>
                        <fn>Francis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J. I.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On March 21 Benjamin Akens and Francis Wiseman were married by Rev. J. I.
                    Miller.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scherer</ln>
                        <fn>George P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George P. Scherer, a member of the "old 'Stonewall Brigade,'" died at his
                    father's residence on March 27. He was 26 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hilbert</ln>
                        <fn>Kate</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hilbert</ln>
                        <fn>Johnny</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hilbert</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On March 23 Johnny, infant son of J. W. and Kate Hilbert, died in Staunton.
                    He was 27 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paris</ln>
                        <fn>Charles Wallace</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paris</ln>
                        <fn>James R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paris</ln>
                        <fn>Lucy J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On March 21 Charles Wallace, son of James R. and Lucy J. Paris, died of
                    consumption. He was 23 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Risk</ln>
                        <fn>Martha</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Risk</ln>
                        <fn>Harvey</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On March 21 Martha Risk, wife of Harvey Risk, died at home. She was 59
                    years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1867.03.29.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements and news snippets.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
