<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; --><!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1867/va.au.rv.1867.02.22">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>03/07</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1867-02-22">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day>22</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1867.02.22.01">
            <pageNote>Page contains advertisements and a variety of anecdotes.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1867.02.22.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In our last issue we gave the substance of the Stevens Military
                        Re-construction bill and the bill proposed by Elliott for the
                        re-organization of the Government of Louisiana, which was thought to be a
                        favorite and which would be used as a precedent and would be applied to all
                        the Southern States. Since that time, an amendment to the Stevens bill,
                        styled the Blaine amendment, has been the popular scheme for
                        re-construction, which in turn has given way to the Sherman substitute for
                        the Stevens bill, which has been adopted by a vote of 29 to 10 in the United
                        States Senate. We publish the tenor of this substitute elsewhere.</p>
                    <p>It is useless to speculate on the various bills offered in Congress, which
                        look to reconstructing the South, so various and in such rapid succession
                        are they offered. There is one thing, however, we can not fail to notice,
                        that no bill is offered which bears upon its face even a title of justice to
                        the brave though conquered South. It would naturally seem that a victorious
                        people should forget the malignity begotten by war, and the rather seek to
                        re-instate the prosperity and foster a tendency to unity of feeling and
                        interest among the whole people than to keep discovered vast sections,
                        which, under a united government, must necessarily rely on each other for
                        their financial prosperity. Our experience has taught us the reverse. The
                        endeavor of the victors in our late war, through their representatives, has
                        been to keep dissevered rather than unite the once hostile sections of our
                        country. Whether for the sake of party -- for the purpose of pandering to
                        fanatical Northern majorities, or pure malignity, or all combined, it is
                        nevertheless so. We must accept it as it is, having no voice in, much less
                        power to control the conduct of affairs, and wait with patience until a
                        malignant fanaticism shall, as it will, over-leap itself, and in the effort
                        to destroy our liberties, awaken the North to the dangers of its own and to
                        the necessity of preserving constitutional liberty on this continent,
                        whether it enures to the advantage of so-called "Rebels" or not. If this
                        result does not follow then indeed did the once boasted constitutional
                        liberty of this country expire with the dying throes of the Confederacy, and
                        has been forever buried by the self-styled defenders of a Constitutional
                        Union.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In Washington, say the editors, Congress is debating a number of amended
                    versions of Stevens's Reconstruction bill. Though it is "useless" to speculate
                    on the various proposals, since so many have been put forth, one thing is
                    certain: none of them bears "even a tittle of justice to the brave though
                    conquered South."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In the Senate of West Virginia on Tuesday last, Mr. Hoke, from the Judiciary
                        Committee "reported a substitute for Senate resolution No. 9, authorizing
                        the Governor to appoint Commissioners to treat with the authorities of
                        Virginia on the subject of the public debt, which says the Commissioners are
                        not to treat with the Virginia Commissioners until it is decided in the
                        Courts whether Virginia has a right to the counties of Berkeley and
                        Jefferson, or until Virginia relinquishes all claims on her part to the said
                        counties in dispute are turned over the rightful jurisdiction of Virginia,
                        when every white male, over 21 years of age, irrespective of past political
                        sentiments, is entitled to vote, and hence the substitute offered by him.
                        It's no use kicking. These counties must come back to the old fold and West
                        Virginia must pay her just share of the State debt.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Discussing the conflict between West Virginia and Virginia over the
                    creation of the former, the editors maintain the counties of Berkley and
                    Jefferson "must come back to the old fold and West Virginia must pay her just
                    share of the State debt."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is reported that Congress defeated the amendments to the Reconstruction
                    bill proposed by Stevens, Elliot, and Sherman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is reported that North Carolina "has virtually rejected" the
                    reconstruction compromise drafted by Governors Sharkey, Parsons, Marvin, and
                    Worth.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Another Charitable Association in Baltimore</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article discloses that another charitable organization to help
                    destitute southerners has been founded in the North. "'The Ladies Depository,'"
                    as it is known, joins the New York Southern Relief Association in the effort to
                    alleviate southern suffering.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Elements of the Fortieth Congress</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Although the radical presence in Congress is strong now, warns the article,
                    it is "going to get much more powerful." In upcoming session, which begins on
                    March 4, there will only be 5 Democrats in the Senate and 37 in the House.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>From Washington--A Substitute Adopted for Stevens' Bill</head>
                <origin>Washington</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>News from Washington indicates that the Reconstruction bill has held the
                    attention of Congress during the past week. The latest proposal to make headway
                    is Sherman's substitute, which grants the President the power to appoint
                    military commanders, rather than Congress, as in Stevens' bill.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>New York Times</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is reported that Gen. Grant is opposed to the Military Force bill
                    because he cannot endorse "the creation of a despotism, with himself as the
                    chief despot."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Is Virginia A State In The Union? -- The Question Before A New York Court</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Explains that a trial in New York over the alleged theft of a steamer
                    revolves around the question of whether Virginia is in fact part of the Union.
                    If, as the defendant claims, Virginia is not a state, then the indictment for
                    his arrest is invalid since it was issued by the Governor of Virginia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1867.02.22..03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wenger</ln>
                        <fn>Elliott</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The editors note the return of Dr. Elliott Wenger, who, like several other
                    former residents of Augusta, has come back to visit the "Old Dominion."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Veitch</ln>
                        <fn>E. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Laments the passing of Rev. E. R. Veitch, a former resident of Augusta and
                    Presiding Elder of the District in the M. E. Church, which he joined in 1831. At
                    his death, Rev. Veitch was the Presiding Elder in the Winchester District.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Arnell</ln>
                        <fn>C. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The article notes with satisfaction the latest trade statistics for the
                    county: last week, approximately "372,000 lbs of freight, consisting of Corn,
                    Flour, Butter, &amp; c.," was shipped from Staunton, with "50,000 lbs on
                    hand to be shipped by first trains."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woods</ln>
                        <fn>John K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>English</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>In recent real estate news, John K. Woods purchased the "'Old Market
                    House'" at the public auction last Saturday for $2,250. Woods recently sold his
                    residence near the Deaf, Dumb, and Blind Institute to J. A. English for $5,500.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Arnall</ln>
                        <fn>C. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces that the Ladies' Memorial Association will hold a fair and dinner
                    on March 4 to raise money.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates that the concert put on by the Presbyterian Church choir last
                    Friday was "a decided success."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The "ladies of the Lutheran Church" held "very nice Fair and Supper" last
                    Thursday, reports the article, which raised about $200.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kerr</ln>
                        <fn>Ephraim</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Feb. 9 Ephraim Kerr died at his residence near New Hope. He was 57 years
                    old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kerr</ln>
                        <fn>James Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kerr</ln>
                        <fn>Ephraim</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Feb. 11 James Alexander, infant son of Ephraim Kerr, died. He was 4
                    months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kerr</ln>
                        <fn>Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Feb 10 Jane Kerr died of dropsy. She was 66 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1867.02.22..04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements and brief news summaries.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
