<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1867/va.au.rv.1867.09.06">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>05/07</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1867-09-06">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day>06</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1867.09.06.01">
            <pageNote>Page contains advertisements and a variety of anecdotes.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1867.09.06.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Abolition party of the North set up a vast claim of friendship for the
                        colored man, in which there is no justice, but on the contrary the truth is
                        that their hatred to the colored man based upon extreme selfishness has
                        brought about the existing state of things. In earlier days there was a
                        considerable desire on the part of Southern men to bring about a gradual
                        emancipation, in the view of bettering the condition of the then slave,
                        without damaging the interests of owners and the country. This was too slow
                        a process for the North an was overshadowed by a desire there to abolish the
                        institution. The advocates of abolition, it is true, endeavored to increase
                        their numbers and power by sympathetic appeals, but they showed their hand
                        plainly in the effort to unite with them the white laboring classes. Then
                        they asserted that the labor of the colored man, as a slave, who, in that
                        condition, would ever be the preferred laborer in the South, stood in the
                        way of Northern labor finding renumerative employment here. Then the truth
                        exposed and the doctrine of the "irrepressible conflict" enunciated. There
                        was no love -- no real sympathy for the slave, but he stood in the way of
                        Northern white labor and must give way if extermination should follow. This
                        pet scheme was carried out but the white laborer found a competitor still in
                        the freedman, who, innocent of the change in his relation to his former
                        master, continued to find employment and a sustenance among his Southern
                        friends in preference to the white stranger. Old friendships were too strong
                        and a chasm must be made in them or the result so long desired would be lost
                        in the only "irrepressible conflict" possible -- between white and colored
                        labor. Then were words of friendship breathed into his confiding ear until
                        he was ready to believe the insidious doctrine that his interests were in
                        conflict with his late master's. There the seeds of distrust were sown on
                        the one side, to be nourished by that immense act of friendship (?) the
                        elevation to the right of suffrage, which, while intended to humiliate the
                        Southerners, would accomplish that other purpose, the alienation of the
                        master from his former slave. This accomplished, competition to white labor
                        would be destroyed and it would even be sought after. This result all can
                        plainly see stalking on to the ultimate detriment if not destruction of the
                        colored man. And this result, who can look at the facts and fail to see was
                        the object sough, and who can find therein one act of genuine friendship to
                        the colored man? But a friendship which gives the franchise to the ignorant
                        freedmen of the South as a right and yet withholds the suffrage from the
                        educated colored men of the North. A friendship that would, to-morrow,
                        reverse the tables and send the freedmen back to servitude had a purpose to
                        subserve. A friendship, the counsels of which, the colored man, when he
                        fully comprehends it, will disregard, if he values the perpetuity and
                        propriety of his race in this country.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Blaming the "Abolition party of the North" for the current predicament in
                    the South, the editors allege that Republicans sabotaged the bond between
                    masters and slaves to advance their own interests, not because they had any
                    "real sympathy" for blacks.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that support for the Chesapeake &amp; Ohio Railroad is growing
                    in West Virginia, Kentucky, and Ohio. In Virginia, however, the endeavor has
                    unfortunately received a tepid response.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Rockingham Register</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates that a number of robberies have taken place recently in Rockingham
                    County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>New York Evening Post</origin>
                <commentary>"A desperate effort has been made to show a breach between the President
                    and Gen. Grant. A difference of opinion did exist as to the authority conferred
                    upon Gen. Grant by the supplemental reconstruction act, and a correspondence on
                    the subject transpired but the President was in the right, as acknowledged by
                    the New York <emph rend="italic">Evening Post</emph> (Radical) which says:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article dismisses the rumored discord between President Johnson and
                    Gen. Grant. As proof, it points to Grant's order to remove Gen. Sheridan from
                    his command, as called for by the Chief Executive.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is reported that the effort to impeach President Johnson has "been more
                    talked of in the past few weeks than at any time since the adjournment of
                    Congress."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that businessmen in Richmond organized a Board of Trade on August
                    30; a draft of the association's constitution will be presented on September 6,
                    at which time permanent officers will be selected.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Important Proclamation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Andrew Johnson</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>In response to attempts to interfere with the "processes of United States
                    Courts in North and South Carolina," the President issued his proclamation,
                    warning people to refrain from any and all efforts to hinder "the faithful
                    execution of the Constitution and the laws" of the nation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>"What It Will Do"</head>
                <origin>Cincinnati Enquirer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article argues in favor of paying off the national debt in greenbacks.
                    By doing so, it will save the country millions of dollars in interest payments,
                    it will reduce the tax burden of the people, and it will "put new life into
                    business." The result "will add to the general wealth of the country."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Mongrels in Despair!</head>
                <origin>Circleville Democrat</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that Republicans in Ohio have failed in their efforts to pass
                    legislation granting blacks suffrage rights.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Yellow fever is ravaging parts of Louisiana and Texas, states the article.
                    In Galveston alone, 241 people died from the disease last week.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>More Developments</head>
                <origin>National Intelligencer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article contends that, despite the "high character and Christian
                    reputation of its chief," the Freedmen's Bureau is plagued by corruption and
                    "wholesale frauds."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1867.09.06.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoy</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes that William Hoy's stolen horse, which was advertised in the
                    Vindicator last week, has been returned.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smart</ln>
                        <fn>M. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lara</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Relates that the distilling firm of Lara &amp; Smart has dissolved. M.
                    B. Smart will continue the business at the distillery in Stuart's Draft.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>At the Staunton Building Association's monthly meeting last Saturday,
                    twelve shares of stock were redeemed at an average of 62 percent, says the
                    article.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the Directors of the Augusta County Fair selected a meadow
                    near old Crawford Woolen Factory, near the eastern suburbs of the town, as the
                    site for this year's fair grounds.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that John D. Morris returned to town after a fifteen year absence;
                    Morris departed with a group of young men to find his fortune in the "far West."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hotchkiss</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echols</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>At the Staunton Lyceum's next meeting, the question "Would it be expedient,
                    under certain circumstances, to establish a general Free School System in
                    Virginia?" will be debated. General Echols will argue in the affirmative and
                    Prof. Hotchkiss the negative.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ward</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowles</ln>
                        <fn>Primus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hill</ln>
                        <fn>Joshua</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The article states that the latest term of the County Court transacted more
                    business than any other in recent years. Among the cases tried, William Ward was
                    convicted of rape and sentenced to one year in the penitentiary and Primus
                    Bowles and Joshua Hill (colored) were acquitted of the charge of
                    "house-breaking." Ward appealed his conviction and will face a new trial.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Tribute of Respect</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn>William Sylvester</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stafford</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carter</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schmitt</ln>
                        <fn>P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fuller</ln>
                        <fn>G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>O'Brian</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The article contains a series of resolutions passed by the Augusta Fire
                    Company memorializing William Sylvester Grove's passing.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woodward</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel M.</fn>
                        <sf>Sr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Sept. 4 Samuel M. Woodward, Sr., died at his residence in Staunton. He
                    was 77 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1867.09.06.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements and brief news items.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
