<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1867/va.au.rv.1867.02.15">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>03/07</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1867-02-15">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day>15</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1867.02.15.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>The Mormon Girls</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"Richard Williams who delivered a lecture at Buffalo recently on the
                    Mormons, alluded as follows to one of the disturbing elements among the Saints:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article contains an extract from a speech delivered Richard Williams in
                    which he attests to the suffering of Mormon girls "disaffected" by the prospect
                    of entering into polygamous relationships. The "most effective way" to destroy
                    the "whole system," Williams states, would be to "send an army of 10,000
                    unmarried men there, and protect every man who married a Mormon woman and
                    brought her back to camp."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>A Negro Candidate For Mayor Of Washington</head>
                <origin>Washington Intelligencer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that blacks in Washington City are "unanimous" in their endorsement
                    of the President of the Freedmen's Bureau Relief Association, of Washington, for
                    mayor; according to the "Washington Intelligencer", the man is black.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1867.02.15.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The change throughout the country, wrought by the war, is greater than many
                        at first suppose. It is not confined to the great labor system of the South,
                        which was wont to furnish sufficient materials to keep the vast mills and
                        factories of the world in motion, but embraces within it a change of the
                        prospects of the whole country. In days gone by the Southern planter made
                        not only a sufficiency for the support of his laborers and dependants, but
                        had an abundant surplus to enable him to lead a comfortable and even
                        luxurious life. What cared he then to make his plantation self-sustaining
                        when his income was sufficient to supply his every need without it! To-day
                        and henceforth the tables are turned. Economy, unknown in the South in
                        former times, is now to be the great polar star of her pecuniary
                        advancement. She is no longer able to purchase, as she was accustomed, her
                        live stock, cereals, provisions, &amp;c., from the great North West, but
                        must needs, in her poverty raise these cereals and breed our own cattle. In
                        like manner, for want of the great staple to exchange for manufactures, she
                        must act to work and finally do her own manufacturing. This she is impelled
                        to by another incentive, the excessive duties on foreign manufactures. With
                        a free trade system she would have continued as formerly to till the soil,
                        and, with the rich harvests she would reap, been content to look on at New
                        England and the outer world in possession of the monopoly of manufactures.
                        But with the present duties, not likely to be decreased, she can illy afford
                        to pay the demands of New England monopoly, and will, as we said, be
                        compelled to turn her attention more particularly to manufacturing.--What
                        she has accomplished, already, gives evident promise, in the future, of her
                        independence of the rest of the world in this respect. With the goods now
                        upon her it can be delayed to no distant day.</p>
                    <p>The North West must ultimately be effected as is the South. No longer a
                        Southern market for her productions, she will likewise be unable to raise
                        the means to go abroad for her manufactures, and will in turn be driven to
                        the necessity of manufacturing to a greater extent than heretofore.</p>
                    <p>New England is also bound to feel this changes as the Southern and Western
                        demand for her manufactures grows less. Reveling in wealth, accumulated by a
                        long and well protected monopoly, she feels but slightly, as yet, the
                        running of her mills and factories on half and quarter time. It is however
                        but the "beginning of the end." The handwriting is on her walls. The sceptre
                        is slowly but surely departing from her. Another year, and we fear that half
                        and quarter time will not be all. Many of her factories will cease operation
                        and where was but just now the busy hum of industry will be the quiet of a
                        "deserted village." We do not write as we would wish, concerning that
                        domineering and self-laudatory section of the Union, but as we seem to see
                        the finger of fate unerringly pointing. We would not curse her with such a
                        fate as seems to us portending, but we can but feel that when all was quiet
                        -- when each section was but doing its allotted portion for the advancement
                        of the whole country, of which she was getting the lion's share, New England
                        was not content, but stirred up the cause of strife which has terminated in
                        the present unhappy condition of the country, and which will eventuate in
                        her own impoverishment. If such be her fate, who will say the punishment is
                        undeserved? Since she sowed the whirlwind must she not, in justice, reap the
                        storm?</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors note that the war has had devastating effect on the nation's
                    economy, and assert that the duties applied to imported goods have only
                    exacerbated the situation. Should the situation persist, the editors predict
                    dire consequences for northern manufacturers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>After acrimonious debate last Friday, says the article, the Reconstruction
                    Committee's Southern military government bill was defeated in Congress and
                    "'forever buried.'"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article reports that a "worthy colored man" named Henry Clay was
                    murdered in Warrenton, Va., on January 28. Soon after the crime, two black men
                    were arrested; it is believed the suspects' motive was robbery since Clay was
                    "known to have a considerable sum of money."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We published in our last issue the new plan of reconstruction which was said
                        to have met with favor from President Johnson, the Northern Democracy,
                        Conservative Republicans and a number of prominent Southern gentlemen, among
                        them the Governors of several Southern States. We read it hastily and
                        published it merely for the information of ourselves. We have since re-read
                        it several times and we can scarcely see any difference between the new plan
                        proposed Constitutional Amendment of Congress, which the Southern State
                        Legislatures, as far as they have acted upon it, have with a great degree of
                        unanimity refused to ratify. The difference between it and the new plan is
                        that the latter does away with the disability clause of the former. This was
                        one of the most objectionable feature. These have been discussed and the
                        mind of the South fully made up on the subject. The new plan then comes up
                        as nearly as possible to the proposed amendment, not to be one of the same.
                        If we have good reasons to refuse to offer the other as a plan of
                        re-construction on our part. Leaving aside the merits (as far as we are
                        concerned,) of the new plan, it is not likely to meet with the consent of
                        those who hold the balance of power in Congress. They meet it with decision,
                        as a step towards the Republican demands, but not quite far enough. If we
                        intend to maintain our Constitutional stand points and demand our rights in
                        the Union as Constitutional rights, and failing to get them, as we have thus
                        far, to quietly await the time when fanaticism shall be borne down by the
                        power of reason and justice, then it is a step too far for even
                        representative Southern men to have gone and will not be sanctioned by the
                        masses. But if the Union, at the sacrifice of the principles on which it was
                        established, and for the sake of union alone, in what we must obtain, with
                        the present feeling of the Northern people, we have truly made but a feeble
                        step and must, if we would succeed, swallow all the nauseating draughts the
                        fanatical quacks prepare, and ask no questions.</p>
                    <p>We hardly think the Southern people are ready for such panaceas for union,
                        whether prepared by Northern or Southern doctors, and believe that all such,
                        not in strict accord with the Constitution, will, as they should meet the
                        fate of the kindred Constitutional Amendment.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Denouncing the revised terms of the proposed constitutional amendment, the
                    editors call on southerners to continue their resistance to the imposition of
                    any radical-inspired scheme to re-admit the former rebel states.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Expressing little surprise at its findings, the editors rebuke the
                    Congressional Committee's majority report on the causes of the New Orleans riot.
                    By attaching blame for the incident on the "unreconstructed," the commissioners
                    overlooked the true source of the riot: the "Conventionists" who incited the
                    blacks.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>New York World</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article vilifies the Grand Army of the Republic as "a secret
                    organization" whose chief purpose is "to sustain the policy of the present
                    radical Congress, by force, if necessary, and especially if opposition is made
                    to the effort to impeach the President."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Impeachment--Suspension of the President</head>
                <origin>New York World</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates that the latest congressional debate over impeachment focuses on
                    whether Johnson should be suspended pending the outcome of the impeachment
                    hearing. Should that take place, the article contends, it would give Johnson
                    "'solid constitutional grounds for resistance.'"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Washington</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>States that the Committee on Ways and Means will introduce its Internal
                    Revenue bill shortly.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Indicates that the New York Southern Relief Association has voted to send
                    $10,000 worth of corn to Alabama immediately.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1867.02.15.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates that a freight train ran off the tracks at the western edge of the
                    Blue Ridge Tunnel, destroying one car and damaging several others.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges disabled soldiers to apply to William F. Taylor, Secretary of the
                    Board in charge of distributing artificial limbs to veterans injured in the late
                    war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the "'Staunton Thespians'" gave two "interesting" performances
                    last weekend.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woods</ln>
                        <fn>John K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Evans</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kerr</ln>
                        <fn>Herbert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waters</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peck</ln>
                        <fn>H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bruce</ln>
                        <fn>A. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cushing</ln>
                        <fn>E. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bagby</ln>
                        <fn>B. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nelson</ln>
                        <fn>W. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoge</ln>
                        <fn>P. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Catlett</ln>
                        <fn>N. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoshour</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The article notes that officers were selected at the last meeting of the
                    Building Association at the Firemen's Hall.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James Hanger, inventor of an artificial limb, recently made "a great
                    improvement" on his design. The latest model is on display at Trouts' Drug
                    Store.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that the proceeds from tonight's Grand Concert will go toward the
                    purchase of a new organ for the Presbyterian Church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates that reviews from Dr. C. R. Harris's lecture at the Staunton Lyceum
                    last Friday are highly complimentary.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palmer</ln>
                        <fn>Martin V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>Hettie E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stringer</ln>
                        <fn>W. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Feb. 7 Martin V. Palmer and Hettie E. Patterson were married by Rev. W.
                    R. Stringer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wall</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McMahon</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walters</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Jan. 29 Andrew H. Wall and Margaret McMahon were married by Rev.
                    Walters.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Berry</ln>
                        <fn>A. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hulvey</ln>
                        <fn>Nancy J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Engle</ln>
                        <fn>J. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Jan. 3 A. L. Berry and Nancy J. Hulvey were married by Rev. J. J. Engle.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>Eveline</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>F. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Feb. 8 Eveline Davis, consort of F. C. Davis, died. She was 38 years
                    old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1867.02.15.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements and brief news summaries.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
