<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; --><!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1867/va.au.rv.1867.05.31">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>03/26</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1867-05-31">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day>31</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1867.05.31.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Whiskey From Cornstalks</head>
                <origin>Richmond Times</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On the 28th of the present month letters patent will be issued at Washington
                        to Messrs. James Neely and --- Allen of Buckingham county, Virginia, for th
                        manufacture of alcoholic spirits from a material heretofore regarded as
                        worthless.</p>
                    <p>By this valuable and important addition to modern sciences, an immense
                        quantity of grain and potatoes, of which ardent spirits are now
                        manufactured, will be saved for the natural uses for which they were
                        intended.</p>
                    <p>The invention is no less beneficial than extraordinary and surprising, and is
                        destined to create a revolution in the manufacture of all kinds of
                        spirituous liquors. The simple and unpretending cornstalk, when shorn of its
                        ears and fodder, formerly rubbish and even beneath the notice of a hungry
                        horse or cow, has been found by the inventor to possess every necessary
                        qualification for the distillation of liquor of a superior quality and
                        flavor. To the genius of Mr. James Neely, of Buckingham, is the country
                        indebted for this wonderful discovery, and we are happy to say that both the
                        government officers in Washington and distillers in the North who tested his
                        samples, have not only given the most flattering assurances of the great
                        value and importance of his invention, but have also congratulated him as
                        the fortunate possessor of such a secret.</p>
                    <p>The usual process of distilling is all that will be required in the
                        manufacture of the new material into ardent spirits; no additional expense
                        is incurred, while, on the contrary, it will prove a source of great
                        revenue, and a blessing to the country--the evil will in future have this
                        much a modification. Added to this, the culture of corn will now become
                        doubly valuable, and the farmer will realize from the sale of his stalks
                        nearly an additional half of the usual proceeds from his corn crop.</p>
                    <p>The sample of the article we have seen, which was manufactured in October
                        last, is all that the inventor claims for it, and unlike some of our
                        expensive brands of whisky readily mixes with water--not evincing that oily
                        nature so often seen in fine liquors, and which has always precluded the
                        possibility of making what is generally known as "good grog." This quality,
                        we may add, most particularly recommended it to Commissioner Rollins and the
                        Executive Department at Washington. Several capitalists from the North have
                        already made propositions an extensive business next fall, but as yet no
                        plans of a definite nature have been agreed upon, though many are projected.
                        We expect to hear that some of our Richmond distillers will secure the right
                        for the use of this invention in this State.--<emph rend="italic">Richmond
                            Times</emph>.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article states that a Virginian has invented a still that makes whiskey
                    using corn stalks, which, as a consequence, will save an immense quantity of
                    grain and potatoes since those are the ingredients currently used to make
                    liquor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1867.05.31.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article discusses the deliberations at the Virginia Central Railroad
                    stockholders' meeting in Richmond last week. There are plans to extend several
                    lines in the state to access the natural resources of the interior.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>States that the Mayor of Richmond closed the investigation into the recent
                    riot in that city. Four men--two black and two white--were indicted as a result
                    of the findings.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is reported that Gen. Scholfield dispatched a company of soldiers from
                    Petersburg to Danville to "prevent the formation of military companies" by
                    blacks.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Reconstruction!!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article contains of a copy of the Attorney-General's opinion on the
                    question of disfranchisement.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1867.05.31.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Landes</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burner</ln>
                        <fn>George C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baber</ln>
                        <fn>William S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>Silas H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roler</ln>
                        <fn>Courtney A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shirey</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moury</ln>
                        <fn>John C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lilley</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Commissioner</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hogshead</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Commissioner</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pilson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Commissioner</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turke</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Commissioner</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>Chesley</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Byers</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Faucet</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bruffy</ln>
                        <fn>J. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harnsbarger</ln>
                        <fn>R. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pannel</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jackson</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>Richard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hill</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The article includes some of the proceedings of "general interest" from the
                    May term of the County Court, Justice William Chapman presiding. "William
                    Landes, George C. Burner, George Cochran, William S. Baber, Silas H. Walker,
                    Courtney A. Roler, William Shirey, and John C. Moury were appointed overseers of
                    the roads in several precincts of the county. Road Commissioner Lilley,
                    Hogshead, Pilson, and Turke were received and referred to one or more road
                    commissioners for action and report. The Court ordered that the road near
                    Stribling Springs, as petitioned by Chesley Kinney, be re-opened. Judge John
                    Kinney was allowed $90 land damages for road established on his land, on
                    petition of J. S. Byers and others. A. Faucet was allowed $40 and J. N. Bruffy
                    $25 land damages for opening of road on their lands, on petition of Chesley
                    Kinney. An appropriation of $70 was made to rebuild a bridge over mill race near
                    R. S. Harnsbarger's mill. Commonwealth vs. Daniel Pannel, for assault and
                    battery. Jury assessed his amercement at $5 and costs. Commonwealth vs. Richard
                    Taylor Smith (colored) indicted for felony. Examination waved and remanded to
                    Circuit Court for trial. Commonwealth vs. Samuel Jackson (colored) indictment
                    for petit larceny--quashed. Commonwealth vs. Martin Hill (colored) for petit
                    larceny. Jury brought in verdict of guilty and court sentenced him to 60 days
                    imprisonment in county jail."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>Bolivar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yost</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echols</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beill</ln>
                        <fn>H. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beill</ln>
                        <fn>J. Wayt</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that the Valley Railroad Company stockholders' annual meeting took
                    place last week at the Court House in Staunton. During the proceedings, the
                    Directors agreed to implement a number of changes to the company's charter, as
                    proposed by the last legislature. In addition, last year's officers were
                    unanimously re-elected.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Evangelical Lutheran General Synod in North America met in Staunton
                    last week, relates the article.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>Mattie J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dinwiddie</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On May 28 Col J. M. McCue and Mattie J., youngest daughter of the late
                    James W. McCue, of Nelson County, were married by Rev. W. S. Dinwiddie.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitman</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wise</ln>
                        <fn>Louise J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Neel</ln>
                        <fn>A. A. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On May 23 Daniel A. Whitman and Louise J. Wise were married by Rev. A. A.
                    P. Neel.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitmer</ln>
                        <fn>Martin S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bolton</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Alexander</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On May 14 Martin S. Whitmer and Susan Bolton, of Iowa, were married by J.
                    M. Alexander.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Morgan</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flournoy</ln>
                        <fn>P. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On May 16 John Hanger and Mary Morgan were married by Rev. P. P. Flournoy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Mary F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary F. Smith died at her mother's home on April 24. She was 18 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On April 19 Sarah L. Wilson died at her residence in Buffalo Creek. She was
                    62 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1867.05.31.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements and news briefs.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
