<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; --><!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1867/va.au.rv.1867.07.05">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>04/04</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1867-07-05">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day>05</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1867.07.05.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Immigration to Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article reports that the Virginia Immigration Board decided last week
                    to appoint Gen. G. Tochman as its agent in Europe.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1867.07.05.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We have heard that some, who have been spoken to in reference to a
                        subscription for the completion of the Covington &amp; Ohio Railroad, at
                        once reply that taxation is so high at present that they can not agree to
                        make it higher by voting a subscription to the completion of that railroad.
                        We respectfully submit that they have not reasoned correctly on the subject.
                        In the first place the interest for several years would have to be paid on
                        the amount subscribed, but then the stock to which they subscribe, is a
                        preferred stock with an interest of 8 per cent, guaranteed, which would
                        thereafter pay the interest without resorting to taxation. When the whole
                        road is completed the stock will be better than any railroad stock in the
                        country and will readily command a premium, and doubtless a large one, and
                        nothing surely can be lost in that transaction. The ultimate
                        advantages,however, are greater. By the completion of this road the rapid
                        development of our great mineral region will follow, a source of immense
                        wealth to the State, while, as we increase the facilities of communication
                        and transportation, our lands must appreciate in value rapidly. But say some
                        "We do not desire to sell our lands, and their appreciation in value will
                        not advantage us, but will rather be a detriment, as we must pay more taxes
                        on them than we do now." Of course as you grow more wealthy you must pay
                        more taxes, whether your wealth comes from the increased value of your
                        lands, or from any other source, but we opine that the man who would object
                        to receiving a present of $100,000, or a farm of 1,000 acres, because he
                        would have to pay more taxes than he does at present, would be considered,
                        by the very men who make the objection spoke of above, as a fit subject for
                        an Institution located near this place. What we work for is to advantage our
                        posterity. We desire to leave our heirs as much as possible with which to
                        begin and run the race of life. Whether we leave them a few dollars kept
                        back from the tax gatherer and a farm worth only a nominal price, for which
                        there is no demand, or leave them possessions of value, which will command
                        almost any price in reason, on account of the facilities of access and for
                        the transportation of their productions, is a question for each one, but
                        which we think will be generally answered by a willingness to risk a great
                        deal to increase the value of what we possess. In all probabilities this
                        question will shortly be presented to the people along the line of the
                        Central and Covington and Ohio Railroads.</p>
                    <p>How they will answer it remains to be seen, but if they fail to cast their
                        votes for the completion of this road we think they will have let slip a
                        golden opportunity to advantage themselves and posterity greatly, and at a
                        small cost, and will thus retard the progress of the "Old Dominion" at an
                        immeasurable extent.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors explain the logic behind their endorsement of the Covington and
                    Ohio Railroad plan. According to their estimation, the long-term benefits of
                    financing the enterprise far outweigh the short-term costs.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article relates some of Governor Pierpont's key arguments in favor of
                    completing the Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad. Pierpont asserts that the railroad
                    will bring profits that dwarf the outlay of capital necessary to finance its
                    construction.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>A Plain Defense</head>
                <origin>Examiner</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Since the end of the war, declares the article, the antebellum leadership
                    of the Democratic party in Virginia has "retired from public life." Moreover,
                    not "one of this class of able and brilliant men is using the slightest
                    influence 'to prevent reconstruction.'"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Negro Race</head>
                <origin>Petersburg Examiner</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>There is but one way for the negro race to continue on this continent, and
                        that is for them to make friends of the whites in these Southern States. it
                        is a law of population, which has always, and must forever attend the spread
                        of people over the earth's surface, that the most intellectual race will
                        drive off the inferior--the more civilized will take the place of the less
                        cultivated. These States will ultimately be peopled by white laborers in
                        place of the black race. The only question, is, <emph rend="italic">how long
                            and how best can this result be deferred?</emph> the white people in the
                        South, amongst whom the negroes have been raised, do now (and are disposed
                        for a long time to come,) to prefer the negro, now free, and to continue
                        free, for their field labors and domestics. To induce the whites to cherish
                        this desire, the blacks have only to be contented in that sphere. The less
                        eager the black race is to be elevated to an equality with the whites, to
                        which they never can attain, the longer will the whites be determined to do
                        all they can to prevent an influx of foreigners, which will when it must
                        come, crowd off the negroes to the gradual extinguishment of the race on
                        this continent. The sooner the negroes sees the yankees are deceiving him
                        the longer he will linger in Old Virginia and North Carolina and the border
                        States in the South.--<emph rend="italic">Petersburg Express</emph>.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Blacks, according to the article, have one chance for survival in post
                    bellum society--to "make friends of the whites" in the South. Ultimately, the
                    region will be "peopled by white laborers in place of the black race," but the
                    timing of this transformation is partially dependent upon blacks and their
                    behavior. Should blacks be willing to disabuse themselves of any desire to
                    achieve equality, whites in turn "will prevent an influx of foreigners" for as
                    long as possible, thus preserving blacks' place in the region.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Statistics of the Wheat Crop</head>
                <origin>Examiner</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Aided by statistics from the Agricultural Department, the article discusses
                    the prospects for this year's wheat harvest, which is predicted to be ten to
                    fifteen percent larger than last year.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>New York Convention</head>
                <origin>Dispatch</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>At a convention in New York, reports the article, two proposals for
                    suffrage were hotly contested: the first endorses "'manhood suffrage'"; the
                    second calls for a plebiscite on the question of extending voting rights to
                    blacks. Despite this division, convention delegates were able to agree on one
                    issue--they resoundingly opposed female suffrage.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1867.07.05.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article notes that the crowd at the commencement exercises for the
                    Deaf, Dumb, and Blind Institute, held on June 27, was at the "utmost capacity."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennerly</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Antrim</ln>
                        <fn>T. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wallace</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunt</ln>
                        <fn>S. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>J. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gibson</ln>
                        <fn>J. St. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deacon</ln>
                        <fn>Johnathan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newham</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stinger</ln>
                        <fn>W. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Relates that officers were selected for the upcoming year at the meeting of
                    the Lee Lodge No. 209, F. &amp; A. Masons on June 18.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richards</ln>
                        <fn>N. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Payne</ln>
                        <fn>J. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamilton</ln>
                        <fn>O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bryan</ln>
                        <fn>C. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn>W. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hughart</ln>
                        <fn>R. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cleek</ln>
                        <fn>A. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGuffin</ln>
                        <fn>A. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Relates that officers were selected for the upcoming year at the last
                    meeting of the Warm Springs Lodge, F. &amp; A. Masons.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Registration in Staunton</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article lists the results of the Poll of Registration for Staunton's
                    two districts. Thus far, the count is: Whites 746 and Blacks 442.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Registration in Bath</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In Bath, reports the piece, the outcome of the registration was as follows:
                    Whites 215 and Black 59.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gallaher</ln>
                        <fn>Dewitt C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Philips</ln>
                        <fn>S. Travers</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gallaher</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces that among the class of graduates from the University of Virginia
                    this year there are several young men from Augusta.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that members of Staunton's various churches have "united together and
                    inaugurated the Union Prayer Meetings," the first of which was held last Sunday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Holt</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Breckenridge</ln>
                        <fn>A. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eskridge</ln>
                        <fn>W. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eskridge</ln>
                        <fn>W. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Board of Directors of the Deaf and Dumb and Blind Institution named A.
                    N. Breckenridge to replace Mr. Holt, who resigned his position as Steward. The
                    board also appointed W. P. Eskridge, son of W. C. Eskridge, "Teacher of the Deaf
                    and Dumb."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that a "young freedman named Frank Smith," of Charleston, applied
                    to the Secretary of War for admission to West Point.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bartley</ln>
                        <fn>Henry B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Layton</ln>
                        <fn>Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clark</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On June 19 Henry B. Bartley and Jane Layton were married by Rev. John L.
                    Clark.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1867.07.05.04">
            <pageNote>Page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
