<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; --><!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1867/va.au.rv.1867.06.21">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>04/02</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1867-06-21">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="06">June</month>
            <day>21</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1867.06.21.01">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements and a variety of anecdotes.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1867.06.21.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>To-morrow the Registration of the voters in District No. 1 and 2, Staunton,
                        and No. 3, Middlebrook, will commence and be continued in these Districts
                        until the 29th inst. We have, heretofore, endeavored to place before our
                        people the necessity of their promptly register, <emph rend="italic">one and
                            all</emph>. We again appeal to them to come forward and register, to
                            "<emph rend="italic">the very last man</emph>." Many do not take the
                        papers and can not therefore form correct conclusions on the subject, whole
                        many express a great disinclination to Register. It is therefore not only
                        imperatively our duty to register, but also to prevail upon the uninformed
                        and disinclined to do so.</p>
                    <p>The <emph rend="italic">Enquirer</emph> pithily and pointedly on this subject
                        says:</p>
                    <p>"Let no man decline to register because he may, perchance, and <emph
                            rend="italic">not yet</emph> have made up his mind to vote in the
                        elections that may be ordered. The act of registering will not <emph
                            rend="italic">require</emph> him to vote; but it will secure him <emph
                            rend="italic">the option</emph> of voting or not, as may seem expedient
                        in the future. To refuse to register is to gag himself hereafter, whether he
                        may then wish to vote or not. No man is wise enough in these times to know
                        positively what it may be best to do months ahead. Hence it would be very
                        foolish to lose the liberty of choice hereafter, by refusing to register
                        now.</p>
                    <p>While those who are allowed registry, owe it as a duty to themselves and the
                        Commonwealth, to avail themselves of the privilege, they also owe it as a
                        peculiar duty to those of their fellow-citizens who are excluded. As one of
                        this latter class, we call upon those who <emph rend="italic">can</emph>
                        vote, to take care of us too! Disappoint the miserable conspiracy of hungry
                        demagogues and refuse party hacks, who are seeking to fasten themselves like
                        vampires on the State, to suck out its life, and destroy both you and us!</p>
                    <p>It will be a terrible evil, from the effects of which it will take many years
                        to recover to let the conduct of our State affairs pass into the hands of
                        the utterly incompetent and venal men who are now seeking it, for what they
                        hope to make out of it."</p>
                    <p>We would desire our readers to weigh well the subject and act from reason,
                        rather than passion and prejudice and they will see that the course we have
                        endeavored to point out to them is the right one.</p>
                    <p>Let each and all, who can, then do their duty, in this darkest hour of
                        Virginia's history, and come forward like men who have something still to
                        live and strive for and register themselves as voters. In no other way can
                        they fully perform the duty they owe to themselves, to their disfranchised
                        fellow Southrons, to their State and to posterity.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>With voter registration commencing tomorrow, the editors reiterate the need
                    for all white men to register to vote. Labeling the prospect of black rule as a
                    "terrible evil," the editors contend it would "take many years to recover" from
                    such a scandalous outcome.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Alexandria Gazette</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Alexandria Gazette gives a report of the proceedings of the Immigration
                        Convention recently held in that city, from which we learn that a series of
                        resolutions were passed urging upon Landholders the great advantage to
                        themselves of subdividing their lands into such sized parts as will meet the
                        demands of those who would desire to settle among us and have not the means
                        to buy and cultivate large tracts, and recommending the establishment of
                        Agencies in the leading cities of this and foreign countries, with the
                        belief that the proper information can thus be better spread before the
                        people, and that the advantages which Virginia offers, thus made, known,
                        will suffice to draw into our State a reliable voluntary immigration adopted
                        to our need.</p>
                    <p>It is Generally conceded that our tracts of land are too large and yet there
                        is a great indisposition among our people to divide up and sell in smaller
                        tracts, although they may desire to sell the whole. This course may induce
                        some little immigration, but not of a character to do a great deal of good.
                        Virginia has many advantages over the far West, but with her indisposition
                        to sell in tracts suited to the demands of immigrants, the 80 and 100 acre
                        tracts will continue to carry immigration in that direction. To benefit
                        ourselves and the State we must be willing to divide our lands and sell in
                        small tracts suited to the demand, yet though satisfied of this it will
                        require time to start our people on this progressive track.</p>
                    <p>There is one thing however which this convention recommends, which we think
                        is practicable, that is, the formation of an organization to be called the
                        "Virginia Land Company," to receive subscriptions of land at a fair
                        valuation, to be disposed of to immigrants as may be required. There would
                        be sufficient subscriptions of land, from every locality in the State, to
                        show the practical advantages of selling in small parcels, to suit the
                        demands of settlers, and the idea would thus be practically initiated, which
                        is all that is needed.</p>
                    <p>We trust therefore that such a company may be organized to foster, by
                        positive inducements, a healthy immigration which we so much need, but
                        which, by our present course, we are daily repelling from us.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates that several resolutions were passed at the Immigration Convention,
                    held recently in Alexandria, including one calling on landowners to divide their
                    holdings into smaller plots as a means to attract immigrants who may not have
                    enough money to buy large plots of land.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>At a meeting held last week in Richmond to mend the rift between the
                    Hunicutt and Botts factions of the state Republican party, participants passed a
                    resolution calling for a convention to be held on August 1 to settle the matter.
                    The article contends that the white participants who approved of the resolution
                    are hypocrites, and notes that several of them "anterior to, and even after the
                    war would have disdained the idea of affiliation with negroes as derogatory to
                    their character and standing." These same men "in all probability now will sit
                    in convention with them."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gray</ln>
                        <fn>C. Douglas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes that C. Douglas Gray, of Augusta, is on the Executive Committee of
                    the state Republican party.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that a meeting will be held in Staunton on June 24 to discuss
                    "the completion of the Covington &amp; Ohio Railroad, which is under
                    contract with the Va. Central Railroad Company. Completion of the railroad "is
                    of the first importance to Virginia."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In the time since registration began in Richmond last Monday, reports the
                    article, the ballots from only one ward have been collected. Thus far, votes
                    from 466 whites and 890 blacks have been tallied. It is believed that blacks
                    from the countryside surrounding Richmond are traveling to the city to register,
                    which may account for the high total.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Powers and Duties of Military Commanders in the South</head>
                <origin>Baltimore Sun</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article praises the Attorney General's "lucid and cogent" opinion on
                    the constitutionality of the Military Reconstruction Act, and notes that
                    military commanders in the South have over-reached their powers by involving
                    themselves in civil affairs.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Important Cabinet Meeting--Forthcoming Order to Restore Southern Civil
                    Officers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is reported that a Cabinet meeting convened last week to re-examine the
                    policy of allowing military district commanders to remove civil officers, in
                    light of the Attorney General's published opinion questioning the legality of
                    such actions.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1867.06.21.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Link</ln>
                        <fn>Nannie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gooch</ln>
                        <fn>Nannie I.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heiskell</ln>
                        <fn>Carrie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>Cornelia M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allen</ln>
                        <fn>Sue</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burr</ln>
                        <fn>Nellie S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scheffer</ln>
                        <fn>Lila</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Estell</ln>
                        <fn>Kitty</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hawkins</ln>
                        <fn>Mollie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weade</ln>
                        <fn>Cornelia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Montgomery</ln>
                        <fn>Agnes</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fulton</ln>
                        <fn>Annie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guy</ln>
                        <fn>Bettie K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gibson</ln>
                        <fn>Eliza</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Glendy</ln>
                        <fn>Mary L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tate</ln>
                        <fn>Mattie E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Howard</ln>
                        <fn>Laura</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn>Kate</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>Lizzie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gamble</ln>
                        <fn>Mary R.,</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Howard</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allen</ln>
                        <fn>Ella M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Preston</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thornton</ln>
                        <fn>Nannie T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smiley</ln>
                        <fn>Letitia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>Nannie D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>Lizzie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn>Lucy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>Bettie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes that the Augusta Female Seminary held its commencement exercises last
                    Wednesday and Thursday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces the Augusta Fire Company will hold a picnic on July 4 in Goshen.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harlan</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes that George Harlan, the town's "efficient Jailor," has made several
                    "improvements" to the jail, and jokes that his work has made it "a Boarding
                    House to be sought after rather than avoided."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dice</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>Fannie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn>John L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On June 12 George W. Dice, of Pendleton County, and Fannie Beard were
                    married by Rev. John L. Clarke.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>Reuben</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garber</ln>
                        <fn>Sallie Virginia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn>W. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On June 5 Reuben Davis, of Aberdeen, and Sallie Virginia Garber, late of
                    Staunton, were married in Houston, Miss., by Rev. W. A Clarke.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1867.06.21.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements and news briefs.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
