<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; --><!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1867/va.au.rv.1867.11.15">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>05/21</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1867-11-15">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="11"/>
            <day>15</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1867.11.15.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Has She a call to be a Wife?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Has she a call to be a wife, who thinks more of her silk dress than her
                        children, and visits her nursery no oftener than once a day?</p>
                    <p>Has the woman a call to be a wife, who sits reading the latest novel while
                        her husband stands before the glass trying to pin together a buttonless
                        shirt bosom?</p>
                    <p>Has that woman a call to be a wife, who cries for a cashmere shawl when her
                        husband's notes are protested?</p>
                    <p>Has that woman a call to be a wife, who expects her husband to swallow
                        diluted coffee soggy bread, smoky tea and watery potatoes six days out of
                        seven?</p>
                    <p>Has she a call to be a wife, who flirts with every man she meets, and
                        reserves the frowns for the home fireside?</p>
                    <p>Has she a call to be a wife, who comes down to breakfast in abominable curl
                        papers a soiled dress gown and shoes down at the heel?</p>
                    <p>Has she a call for a wife, who bores her husband when he comes into the house
                        with the history of a broken tea-cup, or the possible whereabouts of a
                        missing broom-handle?</p>
                    <p>Has she a call to be a wife, who "has the headach" when her husband wants her
                        to walk with him, but willingly wears out her gaiter boots promenading with
                        his male friends?</p>
                    <p>Has she a call to be a wife, who would take advantage of a moment of conjugal
                        weakness to extort money or exact a promise?</p>
                    <p>Has she a call to be a wife, who takes a journey for pleasure leaving her
                        husband to toil in a close office, and "have an eye" when at home, to the
                        servants?</p>
                    <p>Has she a call to be a wife, who listens to outside slanders against her
                        husband, and does not scorn the slanderer?</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Through a series of rhetorical questions, the author of the piece
                    identifies traits unbecoming of a wife.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1867.11.15.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Cincinnati Commercial</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Drawn from extracts of an interview with a correspondent of the Cincinnati
                    "Commercial," the article relates the views of Senator Ben Wade, of Ohio, on a
                    number of pertinent issues. Of particular importance was Wade's opinion that
                    confiscation is "d--d foolery." The time to have implemented a confiscation bill
                    has passed; its only purpose would have been to prevent southern men from
                    joining the rebellion, not to grant it to the ex-slaves. According to the
                    correspondent, Wade stated that if southern blacks want land, they should work
                    for it.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>At the lead of our Editorial columns we publish the suggestion of the
                        Executive committee of the Conservative party of Richmond to the
                        Conservatives of Virginia, to assemble in primary meetings, in the various
                        counties and cities, and appoint delegates to the Conservative Convention to
                        be held in the city of Richmond on December the 11th next, for the purpose
                        of affecting an organization of the Conservatives of the State. We heartily
                        endorse the timely suggestion of the above mentioned committee and earnestly
                        request our people to meet at the Court House, on the first day of November
                        County Court, to appoint delegates from Augusta to the proposed Conservative
                        Convention. It is a matter of the first importance to the people of
                        Virginia, that the whole Conservative strength of the State should be
                        organized -- thoroughly organized before the Constitution to be framed by
                        the Radical Convention is submitted to the people for ratification. We have
                        just realized the futility of a disorganized majority attempting to win
                        success over an organized minority. Without organization we will realize the
                        same result. Although their property may be taxed for every conceivable
                        purpose, amounting to a slow process of confiscation, yet many Conservatives
                        will again fail to cast their suffrages without organization. Hence it is
                        imperative that there should be a thorough organization and we earnestly
                        repeat our request to the Conservatives of Augusta to assemble on the first
                        day of our November County Court and appoint delegates to the Richmond
                        Conservative Convention. Let there be a rousing meeting. Let no imaginary
                        interests prevent attendance, for rest assured your interest in the future
                        wise Government of Virginia outweighs all merely private considerations.
                        Then "come one -- come all" and unite in selecting delegates to a
                        Conservative Convention of the State and take the first step towards
                        organizing the conservative cohorts of "Old Augusta."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors "heartily endorse" a suggestion made by the Executive Committee
                    of the Conservative Party of Richmond to appoint delegates at the local level to
                    attend a state Conservative Convention in Richmond on December 11. The editors
                    call on county conservatives to assemble on the first day of the November County
                    Court to select delegates to represent Augusta.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article reports that interest in soliciting European immigrants to
                    Virginia is growing, and suggests that residents of Augusta join the movement to
                    attract foreigners.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Chesapeake &amp; Ohio Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>According to an order issued by Gen. Scholfield, everyone "interested" in
                    the railroad, "whether registered or not, will be entitled to vote" on the
                    matter.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Quoting Ben Wade, the article claims the Senator from Ohio asserted that,
                    if nothing else, the late elections have shown that "the line between the white
                    man and colored man has been distinctly drawn and the white man has won."
                    According to his estimation, Republicans throughout the North suffered badly at
                    the polls after making black suffrage the key issue in the contest.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lindsey Lewis, a black delegate elected to the Convention from Richmond,
                    was arrested by the Military Commissioner of Richmond on November 12 for using
                    "incendiary language," states the article. The charge pertains to a speech Lewis
                    gave at Hunnicutt Hall, which was allegedly "calculated to incite the colored
                    people against the whites." Bail was set at $1,000.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that Gen. William Mahone was elected President of the Virginia
                    and Tennessee Railroads at a stockholders' meeting in Lynchburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that residents of Fluvanna voted in favor of the county
                    subscription to the Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>How The South Is To Be Saved</head>
                <origin>New York World</origin>
                <commentary>"In an able editorial upon the meaning of the late elections the New
                    York 'World' says:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In an able editorial upon the meaning of the late elections the New York
                        "World" says:</p>
                    <p>"The fact that negro governments are in process of organization, and that
                        Congress may admit their representatives, does not vary the case except to
                        render a degrading farce more contemptible. Certain it is that these bastard
                        government as having the slightest validity. Within four months after the
                        presidential election a heavy battering ram will tumble them into shapeless
                        rubbish. The Southern people will immediately re-organize, hold new
                        elections, oust the negroes, send their own representatives to Washington,
                        and the House will at once admit them. The southern senators <emph
                            rend="italic">plus</emph> the conservative senators from the North will
                        form a majority of that body, organize as such, and neither the House nor
                        the President will recognize any other Senate. This course is entirely
                        feasible, will be perfectly constitutional, and beyond question adopted if
                        the Radicals are insane or wayward enough to recognize the negro governments
                        after this great rebuke. The only thing that could prevent it would be
                        acquiescence by Southern whites in the Radical scheme. Whoever expects that,
                        is better entitled to a straight-jacket than a refutation."</p>
                    <p>If Northern Democrats will stand up to this programme the South is safe.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Four months after the upcoming presidential election, predicts the article,
                    the "negro governments" of the South will fall and be replaced by white
                    representatives who will immediately be admitted by Congress. The "only thing
                    that could prevent" this chain of events "would be acquiescence by Southern
                    whites" to the Radicals' program.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Owners of "Abandoned" Lands</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>U. S. Grant</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article includes a copy of Gen. Grant's circular to assistant
                    commissioners in the Freedmen's Bureau, instructing them to inform the owners of
                    abandoned land that the federal government will take formal possession of the
                    plots on January 1 should they fail to make an official application for return
                    of the land. If that should happen, the land will be rented to refugees and
                    freedmen.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>New York Post</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The piece suggests that the New York "Post," a Radical journal, has
                    expressed deep reservations with the Republicans' Reconstruction program,
                    asserting that it has "caused the recent uprising and rebuke of the people."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1867.11.15.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gruber</ln>
                        <fn>August</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scheffer</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes that August Gruber purchased Frederick Scheffer's "little brick house
                    and lot, opposite the Virginia Hotel" for $1,000, equivalent to cash.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Perrow</ln>
                        <fn>C. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mitchell</ln>
                        <fn>T. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Relates that Dr. C. H. Perrow, Medical adviser of the Piedmont Insurance
                    Company, suffered a broken nose and an "indentation of the frontal bone" when
                    his horse fell while he was riding. Currently, Perrow is recuperating at T. J.
                    Mitchell's residence.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lang</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>While drinking and carousing last Saturday night, two members of the Burial
                    Corps got into a slight altercation. During the dispute, one shot the other in
                    the "fleshy part of the thigh" with two balls. The wounds were not serious,
                    though one ball came close to severing the femoral artery. The wounded man was
                    taken to camp and "is doing well."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Important To Registering Officers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An announcement informing all Registering Officers owed money by the
                    government that they must forward all pertinent information to T. H. Stanton,
                    Paymaster of the First Military District, in order to be reimbursed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Staunton Lyceum</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Latane</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mauzy</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn>Y. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>W. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>C. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hotchkiss</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>At the last Staunton Lyceum meeting, notes the article, the discussion
                    whether mail should be delivered on Sundays was decided in the affirmative; the
                    question to be debated at the upcoming meeting is "Was the Noachian deluge
                    universal?"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Emswiler</ln>
                        <fn>Wesley</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Butler</ln>
                        <fn>Louisa</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stringer</ln>
                        <fn>W. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Nov. 3 Wesley Emswiler and Louisa M. Butler were married by Rev. W. R.
                    Stringer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lynn</ln>
                        <fn>Ferdinand</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Acliff</ln>
                        <fn>Caroline L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stringer</ln>
                        <fn>W. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Nov. 3 Ferdinand D. Lynn and Caroline L. Acliff were married by Rev. W.
                    R. Stringer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burton</ln>
                        <fn>Marshall</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huff</ln>
                        <fn>Mattie Clark</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stringer</ln>
                        <fn>W. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Nov. 7 Marshall F. Burton, of Henrico, and Mattie Clark Huff were
                    married by Rev. W. R. Stringer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Argenbright</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dotson</ln>
                        <fn>Eliza A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kiracofe</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Nov. 7 George W. Argenbright and Eliza A. Dotson were married by Rev. J.
                    W. Kiracofe.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Karicone</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skiles</ln>
                        <fn>Lydia Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bovey</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Oct. 31 William Karicone and Lydia Catharine Skiles were married by Rev.
                    Henry Bovey.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moss</ln>
                        <fn>M. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maupin</ln>
                        <fn>Jennie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>S. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Nov. 5 M. J. Moss, of Lee County, Va., and Jennie E. Maupin were married
                    by Rev. S. M. Crawford.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Opie</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>Sallie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Latane</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Nov. 13 Dr. Thomas Opie, of Baltimore, and Sallie Harman, daughter of
                    Col. M. G. Harman, were married by Rev. Latane.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shuey</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Oct. 31 Jacob Shuey, formerly of Augusta, died in Shueyville, Iowa. He
                    was 70 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1867.11.15.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements and brief news items.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
