<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1867/va.au.rv.1867.01.11">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>02/28</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1867-01-11">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day>11</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1867.01.11.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>A Primitive Region</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article notes that the county of McDowell, located in southwestern
                    Virginia, is so remote that it only has a handful of roads, no post-office,
                    doctors or lawyers, and a "low cabin" that serves as the court house.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>The Condition of the Freedmen at Arlington</head>
                <origin>National Intelligencer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>According to the article, the freedmen at the refugee camp on the outskirts
                    of Arlington are "destitute and desperate." Known locally as the "Freedmen's
                    Village," the camp contains a "thousand poor benighted creatures scattered in
                    their scanty clothing, freezing habitations" whose only source of food is
                    government rations. Though the article does not doubt the merciful motives that
                    lay behind the establishment of the camp, it contends the project was "a
                    mistake" because the refugees are "in a dreary spot, away from all civilized
                    habitations," thus "even those who are able to do something for a subsistence
                    cannot possibly find anything to do."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Votes on the Changes</head>
                <origin>Richmond Advocate</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Discusses the issues currently under consideration at the annual conference
                    of the Southern Methodist Church, and includes the results from the measures
                    voted upon thus far. The two topics being debated by church authorities are
                    whether to remove "Southern" from the name of the church and whether to admit
                    lay delegates.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1867.01.11.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors offer a positive assessment of the President's veto message of
                    the bill to grant suffrage rights to blacks in the District of Columbia, and
                    concur with the logic behind his decision.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Constitution, contend the editors, will be the first casualty if the
                    Radicals' rise to power. At present, it is the key obstacle blocking their
                    schemes, though they are seeking to overcome it through a "series of amendments
                    and unconstitutional acts." The nation, relate the editors, must remain vigilant
                    to check the Radicals' nefarious plans.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Kentucky</origin>
                <commentary>"The following extract from the Message of Gov. Bramlette, of Kentucky,
                    deserves to be printed in letters of gold and hung up in the Halls of our
                    National Legislature, as a perpetual reminder to the members of Congress of the
                    short sighted policy they seem determined to pursue, and warn them of the
                    results they may entail upon the country by their reckless course. He says:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Gov. Bramlette argues that amnesty is the only solution to the problems
                    facing the nation. Without forgiveness, he states, "there is no real peace."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A bill to organize a militia of all men between the ages of eighteen and
                    forty-five has been introduced in Congress, reports the article. The act also
                    calls for the creation of a national guard consisting of two regiments of
                    infantry for each district and territory represented in Congress, one of which
                    would be composed of blacks. Additionally, "more than one-third of the enrolled
                    militia" will be black. No participant of the late war will be commissioned as
                    officers or privates in the national guard, whose main functions would be to
                    "suppress insurrection" and "enforce the law."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Caucus of Radical Representatives--The Question of the Impeachment of the
                    President Discussed</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>According to the article, a caucus consisting of sixty Radical congressmen
                    was held on January 5 to discuss the prospect of impeaching President Johnson.
                    The participants came to few conclusions, but did decide to examine the matter
                    in greater detail before proceeding any further.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Telegraph Fac Similes</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The piece describes the latest in communication technology, a method of
                    telegraphing that produces "exact copies" of a message at either "extremity of
                    the line soley by mechanical means."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>General Assembly of Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Recounts the proceedings from the state legislature between January 4 and
                    7, and includes a copy of the amended Stay Law.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1867.01.11.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Contains the law regulating contracts between freedmen and employers, as
                    passed by the state legislature last year.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eubanks</ln>
                        <fn>John T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that Hanson Bumgardner, who was convicted of killing John T.
                    Eubanks, of Augusta County, was sentenced to death. Bumgardner's execution will
                    take place on February 15.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>For the Vindicator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>S******</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>The author of the letter praises Christmas Exercises at the Valley Home
                    School, which "reflected great credit upon the institution."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1867.01.11.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements and a column of news snippets.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
