<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; --><!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1867/va.au.rv.1867.09.27">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>05/13</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1867-09-27">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day>27</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1867.09.27.01">
            <pageNote>Page contains advertisement and a variety of anecdotes.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1867.09.27.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Our people will shortly be required to decide upon the question of a
                        Convention or no Convention, which is, perhaps, the most important question
                        over presented to them with less to guide them in the formation of a
                        rational, not to say a correct conclusion. The Reconstruction Acts leave
                        them the option of calling a Convention or not and the orders of the
                        Commandant of District No. 1 require them to vote "Convention" or "no
                        Convention." Their votes then will decide the question as to whether a
                        Convention to frame a Constitution for Virginia shall be called. It would
                        seem but just that, with the choice left them and required to make it, the
                        matter should be at rest, whether they decide in favor of or in opposition
                        to the call of a Convention. Those, however, who favor a Convention, claim
                        that a failure to call it will exhibit a contumacy and rebellious spirit,
                        which will occasion more stringent and oppressive legislation against our
                        unfortunate people and should not be thought of. Those who oppose it declare
                        that in voting for it we will be perjuring ourselves and helping to place
                        ignorance and vice in control of our State, at the expense of intelligence
                        and virtue. That no worse fate can befall our people than to call a
                        Convention under the present registration, which, while it exhibits a
                        majority of Whites in the whole State, yet, according to the apportionment
                        of representation, gives, probably, sixty or seventy local majorities to the
                        colored votes, who will vote for radicals, against thirty or forty white
                        local majorities, enough to give the radicals a preponderance in the
                        Convention, thus fixing before hand the character of the Constitution likely
                        to be framed.</p>
                    <p>According to this if they vote for a Convention they are likely to be
                        burdened with a proscriptive constitution, with its dire concomitants,
                        whereas if they vote against it punishment is to be meted out to them for
                        exercising the only choice left them by Congressional desire. We know,
                        however, honest and conscientious men who favor either horn of this dilemma.
                        With equal honesty of purpose we have long since formed our opinion, which
                        we did not deem proper to give our readers, preferring rather to keep them
                        posted on all points necessary for them to form an approximately correct
                        conclusion, and we have seen nothing to cause us to change our views and
                        much to confirm us in them. Believing the whole Reconstruction legislation
                        in conflict with the constitution and subversive of the principles upon
                        which the Government was founded and prospered for such a length of time,
                        and, that yielding to it is but a step further in the establishment of a
                        despotism on the ruins of our much vaunted "Model Republic," we are opposed
                        to the call of a Convention. We shall not, however, quarrel with those who
                        differ with us, but would desire that all should calmly consider the subject
                        and when called on to decide, vote, without bias, as their judgement
                        dictates is best for themselves, their State, the prosperity of their whole
                        country and the stability of her long cherished Constitution and
                    Government.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>After discussing the potential repercussions of the election, the editors
                    declare their opposition to the proposed constitutional convention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>From the fact that there are a number of the white voters in the State who
                        favor the calling of a Convention, it seems to be thought that a Convention
                        will be called and we think it altogether probable. In view of this fact it
                        behooves our people to select good men and act as a unit in support of
                        them.--There is a great probability that the Convention, if called, will
                        contain a majority of delegates committed to Radical theories and it is
                        therefore more important that there should be no division where there are
                        assured Conservative majorities, lest the Radicals may be strengthened
                        thereby. There is one consolation, however, in the event of Radical
                        predominance in the Convention and the framing of an ill advised and
                        proscriptive Constitution, that it has to be referred to the people of the
                        State, when, if unjust, it can readly be rejected by the large Conservative
                        majority in the State. Nevertheless, as delegates must be voted for, we
                        advise concert of action on the part of Conservatives and the selection of
                        the very best men who are eligible to seats.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>With the prospect of a constitutional convention becoming increasingly
                    likely, the editors advise readers to select only the "very best men" as
                    delegates to counter any attempt by the Radicals to draft an "ill advised and
                    proscriptive Constitution."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>New York Herald</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that an "immense" crowd attended a Democratic rally in Ohio last
                    week to hear C. L. Vallandigham speak.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article states that a "gang of colored desperadoes" wanted in
                    connection with a spate of highway robberies was captured last Monday near
                    Petersburg. The police arrested the six men with the help of a number of local
                    blacks, who were so irate at the behavior of the criminals that the authorities
                    had to restrain them from "inflicting Summary punishment."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that voters in Maryland rejected the state's Radical Constitution by
                    a margin of 23,000.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The brief piece asserts that Gen. Scholfield "has decided that the only
                    restriction upon eligibility to membership of the State Convention is having
                    taken an oath to the United States and afterwards having aided the rebellion."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Radical Programme</head>
                <origin>New Nation</origin>
                <commentary>"The following from the <emph rend="italic">New Nation</emph>,
                    Hunnicutt's paper seems to be the Radical programme, in view of the present
                    change in sentiment in the North. The Dispatch says if this does not damage
                    Radicalism in the Northern States, especially Pennsylvania and Ohio, it will be
                    greatly surprised. So say we:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>To counter the influence of Irish immigrants, who tend to support the
                    Democratic party, the article states that Radicals will encourage African
                    immigration, if they have to, to insure the ascent of "Republican principles."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Approaching Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article contains Gen. Scholfield's order "prescribing regulations for
                    the election"; the order requires black and white votes to be recorded
                    separately.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Polish Emigration To Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that Gen. J. E. Tochman, the agent for the Virginia Emigration
                    Society, arrived in Norfolk to investigate the possibility of making that city
                    the port of entry for the 1,200 Polish emigrants who are expected to arrive
                    shortly.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Illness of Mr. Stevens</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is reported that Thad Stevens is "dangerously ill."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1867.09.27.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Munsey</ln>
                        <fn>William E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. William E. Munsey will deliver a sermon at the Methodist Church on
                    Sunday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Getzendanner</ln>
                        <fn>Harrison</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>States that Rev. Harrison Getzendanner will preach at Cochran's Mill next
                    Sunday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echols</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Catlett</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hotchkiss</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that an acre lot located near the Richardson land, west of the
                    Green Street Railroad Bridge, was sold for $1,500 equivalent to cash.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Informs readers that the Directors of the Augusta County Fair will hold a
                    meeting on Oct. 4 to select grounds for this year's event.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lilly</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lilly</ln>
                        <fn>M. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that the little daughter of G. W. and M. S. Lilly drowned after she
                    fell into a spring near the family's home in Churchville. The girl was 2 years
                    old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Balthis</ln>
                        <fn>William L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yount</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>States that William L. Balthis bought Jacob Yount's farm for $1,700 cash.
                    It is believed Balthis intends to devote the land to the cultivation of fruits.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spicer</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The article reports that B. F. Spicer, of Burke's Mill, who has seven
                    children, eloped with a widow, who has four children of her own, on Wednesday
                    morning. Shortly after leaving, however, Spicer evidently had second thoughts
                    and contacted his wife to see if it "would be safe for him to return."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>O'Ferrall</ln>
                        <fn>C. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Augusta County resident Col. C. T. O'Ferrall and his partner, W. W. Majors,
                    of Rockbridge, purchased the Lexington Hotel in Lexington, Va., for $48,000,
                    relates the article.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kerr</ln>
                        <fn>Millard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kerr</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Millard Kerr, son of William Kerr, dec'd, was shot by his roommate at
                    Roanoke College last Saturday, but is expected to recover fully. Apparently,
                    Kerr suffered the wound when he tried to climb through the ventilator above the
                    door. The roommate fired his gun because he thought Kerr was an older student
                    who had teased him and threatened to break into their room at night to play a
                    prank on him.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paxton</ln>
                        <fn>J. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>H. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Watts</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>Bolivar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echols</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>George M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>James M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>At the Court House last Monday, local residents debated the question of
                    subscribing $300,000 to the stock of the Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad Company:
                    arguing in favor of the motion were Maj. J. G. Paxton, Maj. H. M. Bell, Maj. J.
                    H. Watts, Col. Bolivar Christian, and Gen. John Echols; opposed to the tax were
                    James Bumgardner, George M. Cochran, Jr., and James Hanger. The Court decided
                    unanimously to submit the matter to a vote on Nov. 21.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hendry</ln>
                        <fn>I. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hendry</ln>
                        <fn>N. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hotchkiss</ln>
                        <fn>Jed.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Relates that I. S. &amp; N. B. Hendry purchased Capt. Jed. Hotchkiss's
                    corner lot, near the upper R. R. bridge, for $850. The men plan to open a steam
                    operated sash, blind, and door factory as well as a lumber, coal, and wood yard.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>Stanley F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Calvert</ln>
                        <fn>Lucilla A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>William E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Sept. 21 Stanley F. Snyder and Lucilla A. Calvert were married by Rev.
                    William E. Baker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coiner</ln>
                        <fn>St. Clair</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mowry</ln>
                        <fn>Sallie M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Engle</ln>
                        <fn>J. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Sept. 15, St. Clair Coiner and Sallie M. Mowry were married by Rev. J.
                    J. Engle.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>James E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Sept. 13 James E. Crawford died near Deerfield. He was 79 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lilly</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lilly</ln>
                        <fn>M. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lilly</ln>
                        <fn>Anna Laura</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Sept. 13, Anna Laura, daughter of G. W. and M. S. Lilly, died. She was
                    13 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1867.09.27.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements and brief news items.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
