<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; --><!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1867/va.au.rv.1867.10.18">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>05/20</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1867-10-18">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="10"/>
            <day>18</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1867.10.18.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Ohio White Boys In Blue</head>
                <origin>New York Express</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article reports that a political organization named "Our Boys in Blue"
                    has been organized in Ohio. The group is composed of former soldiers who declare
                    themselves against "equalizing" and "fraternizing" with blacks. They declare
                    their motive for fighting in the late war was not to free the slaves, but to
                    "restore the Union." The piece contends that there are 30,000 other veterans in
                    New York and Brooklyn who share these sentiments.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1867.10.18.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>J. Addison</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Southall</ln>
                        <fn>James C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The editors endorse the Conservative ticket for the Convention -- J.
                    Addison Waddell and Powell Harrison for Augusta, and James C. Southall, of
                    Albemarle, for the District, which includes the counties of Augusta, Albemarle,
                    and Louisa.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>To the Voters of the County of Augusta</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In response to a call published in the Stanton papers, for a meeting to be
                        held in Staunton on the 12th of October, 1867, of the purpose of nominating
                        candidates for the Convention, a number of citizens, not large, but fairly
                        representing the people of all portions of Augusta county, assembled and
                        unanimously slected Joseph A. Waddell and Power Harrison to represent the
                        county, and James C. Southall, of Albemarle, to represent the District
                        compsed of Augusta, Albemarle and Louisa counties. The undersigned were also
                        appointed by said meeting a committee to prepare an adress to the voters of
                        Augusta.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Harrison and Mr. Waddell are both too well known, and their character adn
                        capacity too highly appreciated by our people, to need that the action of
                        the meeting, in choosing them, should be vindicated. As the white majority
                        in the counties of Augusta, Albermarle and Louisa is large enough to elect a
                        conservative delegate, by concentrating the entire white vote upon a single
                        candidate, who it was believed, would command the vote of Albemarle and
                        Louisa. Mr. James Southall, the Editor of the Charlottesvilee Chronicle, who
                        is efficiently using his great abilities in the interests of conservativism,
                        and who is extensively and favorably know in these counties, seemed most
                        available for ensuring their vote, and at the same time acceptable to the
                        people of Augusta.--It is believed that he will unite the entire
                        conservative vote of the District, and thus defeat the election of a
                        radical. It cannot be expected that each voter should have his first choice.
                        Concert of action is indispensable, and can only be secured in teh way
                        provided by the meeting -- the people <emph rend="italic">fairly
                        represented</emph> [unclear] held after <emph rend="italic">full</emph> and
                            <emph rend="italic">fair notice</emph>, men have been nominated who are
                        known to be good and <emph rend="italic">true</emph> and <emph rend="italic"
                            >suitable</emph>.</p>
                    <p>The election of good men can <emph rend="italic">now</emph> only be secured
                        by uniting upon those nominees.--Then let every conservative, every <emph
                            rend="italic">anti-radical</emph> come himself, and use all his
                        influence in inducing others to come, and vote for the conservative
                        nominees.</p>
                    <p>George M. Cochran, Jr.,</p>
                    <p>W. A. Burke,</p>
                    <p>H. M. Bell,</p>
                    <p>Marshall Hanger,</p>
                    <p>James Bumgardner, Jr.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>George M. Cochran, Jr.; W. A. Burke; H. M. Bell; Marshall Hanger; James
                    Bumgardner, Jr.</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>The letter relates that a group of conservative voters met in Staunton on
                    October 12 and unanimously nominated Joseph A. Waddell and Powell Harrison to
                    represent the county, and James C. Southall, of Albemarle, to represent the
                    district.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors acknowledge that the "preferences of all can not be satisfied
                    in the nomination" of Waddell, Harrison, and Southall, yet, in light of the
                    circumstances, they call on conservatives to support the three nominees,
                    nevertheless.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We learn that some villainous parties are endeavoring to impress it upon the
                        colored people that with the return fo the Democrats to power they will be
                        reverted to slavery.--This is perfectly fallacious and is resorted to by
                        mean white scoundrels and black ignoramuses to force the colored people, as
                        a body, to vote the radical ticket. When any one preaches such a doctrine to
                        you set him down as a scoundrel and avoid him as you would a plague. He
                        means to use you and then, as similar pretended friends in Ohio have just
                        done, to cast you aside. Your old masters never want you again as slaves,
                        and if the question were put to them on Tuesday next, it would be voted down
                        by a large majority. They are relieved of a burden by your emancipation and
                        they will never take up that burden again. Be satisfied of this truth an
                        kick out your presence the scoundrels, white or black, who believe you are
                        such fools as to be imposed upon and used by such idle trash.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Seeking to dispel the notion that a return to power by the Democrats would
                    result in the re-enslavement of blacks, the editors contend the "villainous
                    parties" responsible for this rumor are simply trying "to force the colored
                    people, as a body, to vote the radical ticket."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article reports that Democrats have made impressive gains in the recent
                    elections in Pennsylvania and Ohio. These victories, it relates, are indicative
                    of the vast changes taking place in the North since the end of the war. In light
                    of this "triumph of Conservatism and Reason over Fanaticism and Folly," the
                    piece urges readers to deliver another resounding blow against Radicalism by
                    voting against the convention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In Ohio, relates the article, voters elected a Republican governor but
                    defeated an amendment to confer suffrage on blacks. This result, it argues,
                    "should be a warning to our colored people not to cut loose from their only
                    friends, the Southern whites."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>New York Tribune; Commercial Advertiser; New York Times; Journal of Commerce</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article includes extracts from various northern newspapers attributing
                    the Republican party's decline in popularity to its advocacy of extreme
                    policies, particularly the promulgation of black suffrage.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that the prohibition against the consolidation of the Virginia
                    &amp; Tennessee, Southside &amp; Norfolk, and Petersburg Railroads under
                    the Presidency of General Mahone has been lifted.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that "a large meeting in Albemarle" has endorsed the nomination of
                    James C. Southall by the Augusta meeting.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Conservative Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Abney</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>George M.</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shuey</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>Lee R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hall</ln>
                        <fn>Clinton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harrison</ln>
                        <fn>Powell</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn>Y. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>Marshall</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Michie</ln>
                        <fn>H. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>H. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pierce</ln>
                        <fn>A. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strasburg</ln>
                        <fn>D. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Opie</ln>
                        <fn>H. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Abney</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The article chronicles the proceedings of the October 12 meeting in which
                    the county and district nominees for the convention were selected. In addition
                    to the political matters, a resolution was passed in support of advancing 100
                    bushels of seed wheat, five dollars, and two plows to the Polish emigrants in
                    Spotsylvania.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Convention, Jas. C. Southall's Acceptance of his Nomination as Candidate
                    of the District</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>Marshall</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Michie</ln>
                        <fn>H. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The piece contains the letter from a committee of Augusta citizens
                    notifying James C. Southall that he has been nominated to represent the district
                    at the upcoming convention, and Southall's letter of acceptance.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1867.10.18.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>At the Boards of Registration meeting held last week, the final revision of
                    the voting lists was compiled; fifty whites and six blacks were added to the
                    lists.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Last Saturday, reports the article, a black man from Richmond addressed a
                    meeting of blacks in Greenville and endeavored to lure the crowd to the "Radical
                    cause by stating that the Radical Congress had passed a confiscation bill and
                    that the lands in Eastern Virginia were now being parcelled out among the
                    colored people." Apparently, the speech provoked a dispute between Radical and
                    Conservative blacks, after members of the latter group disputed the speaker's
                    assertions.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Staunton Lyceum</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Caldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>Bolivar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guy</ln>
                        <fn>R. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>Marshall</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn>Y. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>At the Staunton Lyceum's last meeting, officers were selected for the
                    ensuing quarter and the question "Should the law secure to a married woman her
                    undivided property, free from the debts and control of her husband" was decided
                    in the affirmative. At the next meeting, members of the group will discuss
                    whether Roman Catholicism, based solely on its secular influence, has
                    ameliorated man's social and political condition.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Good News</head>
                <origin>Norfolk Virginian</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is reported that the first group of Polish emigrants, numbering between
                    300 and 400, should arrive in Virginia at the end of February.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fishburne</ln>
                        <fn>E. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Van Lear</ln>
                        <fn>E. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>See</ln>
                        <fn>C. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Oct. 10 E. G. Fishburne and E. L. Van Lear were married by Rev. C. S.
                    See.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mahaney</ln>
                        <fn>John T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Riley</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clark</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Oct. 10 John T. Mahaney and Sarah M. Riley were married by Rev. J. L.
                    Clark.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roler</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>Henrietta A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Engle</ln>
                        <fn>J. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Sept. 3 Jacob C. Roler and Henrietta A. White were married by Rev. J. J.
                    Engle.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>Hetty Amanda</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>G. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On July 23, Hetty Amanda, daughter of Dr. G. N. and Elizabeth Kinney, died
                    in Sherman, Texas. She was 6 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>Susan J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>Calvin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Black</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Oct. 9 Susan J. Cochran, "consort" of Calvin Cochran and daughter of
                    William Black, died near Newport. She was 28 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scott</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Sept. 28 Margaret C. Scott died at her home in Augusta. She was 64 years
                    old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1867.10.18.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements and brief news items.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
