<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; --><!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1867/va.au.rv.1867.10.04">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>05/13</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1867-10-04">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="10"/>
            <day>04</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1867.10.04.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Negro Candidate For Congress</head>
                <origin>New York Herald</origin>
                <commentary>"The New York <emph rend="italic">Herald</emph> of Saturday publishes
                    the following letter:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Ellick Mahaly</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article contains a letter from a black candidate for Congress in
                    Georgia who advocates a platform that includes support for the military
                    reconstruction bill and opposition to the "unGodly tax upon cotton and tobacco."
                    He also supports a measure that would divide the political positions in the
                    state: blacks would run for Congressional seats and whites would run for state
                    offices.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>A Negro Judge</head>
                <origin>Lancaster Intelligencer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>For the first time ever, a black judge presided over the First District
                    Recorder's Court in New Orleans, leaving the author of the article to ponder the
                    question: "How long will it be until we shall have negro Congressmen, negro
                    Governors and a negro President or Vice-President?"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1867.10.04.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We endeavored in our last to impress upon our people the necessity of unity
                        of action in the selection of delegates to the Convention, should it be
                        called, and we again urge it upon them. No matter whether favoring or
                        opposed to the Convention, it is the incumben duty of each one of us to vote
                        for delegates. It is equally incumbent upon us to unite in support of the
                        same men. For, without some concert of action on the part of conservatives
                        in the selection of suitable persons as delegates, each section of our
                        county may support some local favorite and result be the election of a
                        radical representation from "Old Augusta." This may seem improbable to soem,
                        yet we tell them it is probable if there be a division in the conservative
                        vote of the county. The object of this organization is to carry the
                        elections by a solide and united vote. This all understand, yet no concert
                        of action is taken by those well-meaning citizens who could but deplore such
                        a result.</p>
                    <p>This county will send a conservative delegation by a large majority if proper
                        action be taken. Then let us take this action.--Let us assemble at our Court
                        House, from every portion of our county, and, forgetting local favorites and
                        old political confreres, unite in selecting suitable and candidates to
                        represent us in the Convention. Having selected them, let us unite in their
                        support and thus ensure their election. The time is growing short and delay
                        is dangerous.--With the sole purpose of uniting our people in support of
                        good men, to be selected by themselves, we respectfully suggest to them to
                        meet in this place on Saturday the 12th inst. to select such men to
                        represent us in the Convention, should the voters of Virginia favor its
                        call. We suggest the above mentioned day as the latest day, before election,
                        on which our people could meet and have their action generally known in the
                        county, and trust our suggestions may meet with the concordant feeling among
                        our county people and that a large representation from every portion of the
                        county will be present to aid in selecting competent and in every way
                        suitabel men, for whom we can cast an united vote.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors urge conservatives to unite "in support of good men" in the
                    upcoming election rather than voting for "local" favorites. Should conservatives
                    fail to do so, the editors warn, it will dissipate the strength of the
                    conservative vote and result in the election of Radicals to represent "'Old
                    Augusta'" at the convention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors warn county conservatives to mobilize in order "to defeat the
                    machinations of Hunnicutt and his ilk" or, they remark, "you will regret your
                    supineness as long as you live."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is reported that Germans in Iowa are "rapidly" abandoning the Republican
                    party.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Important Movement By Southerners</head>
                <origin>N. Y. Tribune</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In the wake of President Johnson's latest amnesty proclamation, reports the
                    article, several Alabama residents, formerly excluded from voting, sought to
                    register their names, but were refused, on orders from Gen. Pope. As a
                    consequence, they appealed to the U. S. Commissioners and intend on bringing the
                    matter before the courts to test the constitutionality of the military
                    reconstruction laws.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Riotous Disturbances In Georgia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In Savannah, relates the article, a melee occurred at a political rally
                    after a northern "mulatto" named Bradley delivered a speech that included
                    "harangues against white men" and a demand that rebel land be distributed to
                    "conservative negroes." Police and troops were called to quell the violence and
                    confiscate the muskets brought in by "large band of country negroes."
                    Apparently, a "large proportion" of the black population "disapprove" of Bradley
                    and "threaten to assassinate him."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Disintegration of Union Leagues in Virginia</head>
                <origin>New York Herald</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports from Virginia indicate that "the Union Leagues formed by Radical
                    negropholists are disintegrating." The article attributes their demise to two
                    reasons: the fact that white men who joined the organization are now "ashamed"
                    of their actions and that blacks have begun to see that Radicals view them as
                    "tools of designing men, and nothing more."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1867.10.04.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that the Boards of Registration for Augusta will meet at the Court
                    House next Tuesday for the final revision of voter lists. They will remain is
                    session for five days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Staunton Musical Association has been re-organized for the winter and
                    will remain under the leadership of Dr. J. L. Brown, reports the article.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gladke</ln>
                        <fn>C. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rosenbaum</ln>
                        <fn>L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gray</ln>
                        <fn>C. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The article relates that C. D. Gray, Register in Bankruptcy, oversaw the
                    hearing of the creditors of C. A. Gladke &amp; L. Rosenbaum, who filed
                    bankruptcy on Sept. 26.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that members of the Augusta Fire Company and the Fire Company of
                    the D. D. &amp; D. Institution held a torch-light procession last Thursday
                    night.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Larew</ln>
                        <fn>John J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that a silver mine was discovered on John J. Larew's farm; judging
                    by surface specimens, the property promises a fine yield.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors relate that, last Sunday, Rev. William E. Munsey preached to
                    the "largest congregation we have ever seen assembled" in Staunton. His
                    performance "raised greatly the high estimate entertained of his analyptic and
                    elocutionary powers."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin>Spectator</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eubank</ln>
                        <fn>Robert P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The article reports that Robert P. Eubank, formerly of Augusta, suffered a
                    life-threatening injury on September 20, near his home in Clark County. The
                    injury occurred while Eubank was using a thresher; somehow his overshirt got
                    caught on the tumbling shaft of the machine and whirled him around with such
                    velocity that it tore off his clothes and dislocated his thigh, causing serious
                    internal injuries in the process. It is feared Eubank's wounds will leave him
                    susceptible to pneumonia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mayers</ln>
                        <fn>Cravis F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hailman</ln>
                        <fn>Augusta E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hailman</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shirey</ln>
                        <fn>J. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Sept. 17, Cravis F. Mayers and Augusta E. Hailman, daughter of B. F.
                    Hailman, were married by Rev. J. D. Shirey.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cooke</ln>
                        <fn>John Esten</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Page</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Page</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Francis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Sept. 18, Maj. John Esten Cooke and Mary Francis, daughter of the late
                    Dr. Robert Page, of Clarke County, Va., were married by Rev. Joseph Jones.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cox</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Sept. 19, Alexander H. Cox and Mary E. McClure were married by Rev. C.
                    Beard.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Root</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hizer</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Sept. 22, William Root and Margaret F. Hizer were married by Rev. C.
                    Beard.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shepherd</ln>
                        <fn>Ellen</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Sept. 5, Ellen Shepherd, formerly of Staunton, died in Shepherdstown.
                    She was 74 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1867.10.04.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements and brief news items.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
