<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1867/va.au.rv.1867.02.01">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>03/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1867-02-01">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day>01</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1867.02.01.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>A Chapter of Tragedies</head>
                <origin>Louisville Journal</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article provides a summary of the key events in the long and violent
                    feud between the Johnstone and Rogers clans in Carter County, Tennessee. The
                    conflict continued for twenty years before drawing to a close.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Scene in the Mayor's Court, Richmond</head>
                <origin>Richmond Dispatch</origin>
                <commentary>"The local of the Dispatch is very felicitous at times, in his
                    description of the trial of negroes before the Mayor's Court in that city. The
                    following is a specimen of his 'getting up.'"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Recounts the story of two black men who were arrested in Richmond for
                    fighting, and describes their courtroom antics.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Women at Work</head>
                <origin>Atlanta New Era; Mobile Register</origin>
                <commentary>"In the Atlanta New Era we find the little paragraph:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In Alabama, relates the article, there are several instances in which
                    destitute women have resorted to hard labor to maintain their livelihood. The
                    article describes one example in which two sisters "employ themselves in cutting
                    wood and hauling it to Mobile."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1867.02.01.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It is not unknown to our readers that an effort is being made in New York
                        City, by the concerted action of her people, without regard to political or
                        party bias, to afford pecuniary relief to the suffering of the South. This
                        is eminently praiseworthy on the part of the people of that great and
                        wealthy city. With the mere fact of an effort being made to extend a charity
                        to the suffering poor of the South, made so by the devastation and
                        destruction of the war, we do not propose to deal, save to express our
                        gratification thereat, and to return the thanks of those people of Gotham,
                        who, aroused by the reports of the destruction and want in various sections
                        of the South, and animated by a Christian philanthropy, from their
                        abundance, are about to extend that material aid, which will relieve many
                        innocent ones from suffering and want, for whom their friends and neighbors
                        can do but little, so destitute were all Southrous [sic] left by the late
                        war and its attendant results.</p>
                    <p>Another feature, we think claims not only our attention, but the attention of
                        the whole people of the country. this effort, as we stated above, excites
                        and interests the sympathy not of Conservatives alone, but finds cordial
                        supporters in the ranks of those from whom the South is led to expect but
                        little. Among those who appeal strongly for the greatest liberality on the
                        part of the people of the "Great Metropolis," are the editors of the radical
                        papers of that city, and, doubtless, heartily endorsed by their thousands of
                        radical patrons. From a Southern stand point we exclaim, "and is not most
                        incumbent upon them to exhibit the greatest liberality! for is it now due to
                        them that the present destitution and suffering in the South has been
                        brought about?" This they do not, or will not see, but they are astute
                        enough and sufficiently unprejudiced to see that the <emph rend="italic"
                            >continuation</emph> of the destitution in certain portions of our fair
                        land is not due to the war, but to the continued disturbed and unpacified
                        condition of the country so long after the cessation of actual hostilities.
                        That had <emph rend="italic">peace</emph> and pacification followed close on
                        the heels of war, want would have been but a name not a reality in the
                        fertile South. This they can readily and do understand, for they are brought
                        into daily contact with it in the diminished receipts of their ills, and
                        feel it in every throb of the commercial and financial pulse in that great
                        business mart. Indeed they not deny it. On the contrary, on this very
                        account, they profess a great desire to see the restoration of the Union
                        accomplished speedily. Yet we find these very journalists, who bespeak for
                        the Southern poor a bounteous donation, daily advocating plans of
                        restoration, introduced into Congress simply because they are believed
                        impossible, and not for the purpose of securing speedy restoration -- not
                        "to preserve the Union of our Father," but to preserve the life of a party
                        which can only live in turmoil and strife, and whose funeral client be the
                        plans [unclear] of peace. They do not cry out against the impeachment of
                        President Johnson, for observing his oath of office to support the
                        Constitution and Laws, as expounded by the Supreme Court, because it is
                        wrong <emph rend="italic">per se</emph>, but because it would hazard the
                        existence of a party. Party and party patronage with them is more weighty
                        than country and the prosperity of the people.</p>
                    <p>While the extending of relief to the suffering poor of the South, or of other
                        lands, is both magnanimous and christian-like, yet we say to our Northern
                        readers and exchanges, would you do away with its necessity in this <emph
                            rend="italic">once</emph> land of plenty -- would you "cast your bread
                        upon the waters" to "find it after many days," you must throw aside that
                        partizan feeling, which, for an act somewhat similar to that which made this
                        country a Free-Republic -- a proud monument of successful rebellion, would
                        continue in destitution twelve millions of people -- prevent the recovery of
                        the greatest resources of the country from the present crippled condition,
                        and send down a burden of debt never to be cancelled through coming time,
                        and all, that a <emph rend="italic">party</emph> may live. You must take a
                        national, not a partizan view of affairs, and dethrone from their positions
                        these men who would not only exercise the Legislative, but also the
                        Executive and Judicial functions of government, supplanting them by men who
                        will exercise the prerogatives of Legislation without infringing on those of
                        the Executive or Judicial Departments, and whose legislation will be for the
                        benefit of the whole country and not that of a party. When you of the North
                        rise equal to the occasion an act as becomes you, as lovers of your country
                        and the Constitution of your "rebel" Fathers, no longer will you hear the
                        cry of destitution and want from any portion of our land, but you will find
                        that her resources will spring forth to relieve her of debt and her progress
                        and prosperity move rapidly onward from where partizan fury brought them to
                        a sudden and shattering halt.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors commend philanthropic organizations in New York that have
                    collected money to provide relief for destitute southerners, yet they question
                    the logic of Radicals who have joined the effort since it was they, the
                    Radicals, who brought about the southerners' suffering in the first place.
                    Indeed, as a result of their reconstruction policies, the Radicals have stood as
                    the key obstacle to improving the southerners' conditions.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Lynchburg Republican</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The recent decision of Judge Meredith against the constitutionality of the
                        Stay Law seems to have attracted the attention of the Legislature, for in
                        the House, on Friday, we notice that the committee of Courts of Justice,
                        consisting of Messrs. Seawell, Marshall, Wilson, Goode, Crump, Herdon,
                        Dickenson, Cabell, Woodson, Wyatt, Beckein, Jones and Evans, submitted a
                        report on the constitutionality of the new law, is which the decision of
                        Judge Meredith is declared to be "erroneous." This committee is composed of
                        the first legal talents in the Legislature, if not in the State, and their
                        united opinions are certainly entitled to at least as much weight as the
                        decision of any one Judge. Indeed, no great legal talents are necessary to
                        show the utter fallacy of Judge Meredith's decision, for had the honorable
                        gentleman gone to sleep in the Katskill mountains with Rip Van Winkle, some
                        fifty years ago, and remained in a state of unconscious torpor until the
                        last gun of Lee had died away on the plains of Appomattox, he could not have
                        rendered an opinion more directly in conflict with the highest Judicial
                        decisions of the country, and the changed circumstances and necessities of
                        the people and the State.--<emph rend="italic">Lynchburg
                    Republican</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Judge Meredith's recent ruling against the constitutionality
                    of the Stay Law has prompted considerable debate in the legislature and is sure
                    to be challenged.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Amendment in Mississippi</head>
                <origin>New Orleans</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In defiance of Senator Alcorn's appeal to accept the proposed
                    constitutional amendment as the "least of Congressional evils," states the
                    article, both branches of the Mississippi Legislature unanimously rejected the
                    measure.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>General Assembly of Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that, during the proceedings at the capital last week, the
                    legislature approved a bill "incorporating the Southern Association for the
                    benefit of the widows and orphans of the Southern States."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Another Veto Message From the President</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that President Johnson recently vetoed two bills: in the first
                    instance, Johnson rejected the act admitting the territory of Colorado as a
                    state; in the second, he vetoed a bill conferring suffrage on all citizens by
                    legislative action.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1867.02.01.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bittinger</ln>
                        <fn>Joel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The piece praises the performance given by the "young ladies of the Augusta
                    Female Seminary" last Saturday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hewitt</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Drake</ln>
                        <fn>D. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guy</ln>
                        <fn>R. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunter</ln>
                        <fn>C. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ettinger</ln>
                        <fn>Joel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Alby</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nelson</ln>
                        <fn>W. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Berkeley</ln>
                        <fn>E. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Informs readers that Staunton residents formed a new "Musical Association"
                    at a meeting held on January 22nd. During the proceedings, a constitution was
                    adopted and the officers were elected.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wheat</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chandler</ln>
                        <fn>A. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dull</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paul</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Churchman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>Chesley</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kerr</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>Simon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>Jack</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zambro</ln>
                        <fn>Ella</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickle</ln>
                        <fn>R. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peck</ln>
                        <fn>H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shelton</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Earman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnhart</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parker</ln>
                        <fn>C. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Byers</ln>
                        <fn>John S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smart</ln>
                        <fn>M. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sullivan</ln>
                        <fn>T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn>John Bernard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The January Term of the County Court convened last Monday. J. C. Wheat and
                    J. W. Baldwin, renewed their bonds as Notaries Public. The estates of A. D.
                    Chandler and Jacob Dull were committed to Samuel Paul for administration. The
                    petitions of John Churchman, Chesley Kinney and others, for charges of public
                    roads, were referred. David Kerr, Simeon Koiner, James W. Patterson were
                    appointed surveyors of roads. The Hotel license of Chesley Kenney was
                    transferred to J. A. Hefelfinger. Jack and Rebecca Walker, (colored) and Ella
                    Zambro (white) were ordered to be bound out. R. G. Bickle and H. H. Peck were
                    appointed a committee to have the Jail floor repaired, and also to purchase coal
                    for furnace in the Jail. Thomas W. Shelton and James W. Cochran, were exempted
                    from Payment of erroneous taxes. Earman (white) vs. Barnhart (colored) case of
                    unlawful Detainer. Jury gave verdict for Barnhart. C. W. Parker's road
                    petition--writs of "ad quod damnum" were granted to John S. Byers, M. B. Smart,
                    T. Sullivan, to be executed on Monday next. John Bernard Peyton, qualified as an
                    Attorney-at-Law.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>States that Col. George Baylor, one of Augusta's delegates to the
                    legislature, is recovering from his illness and is expected return to the
                    capital shortly.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Munsey</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mauzy</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf>R.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>W. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes that tonight's debate at the Staunton Lyceum pits R. Mauzy against
                    Rev. W. A. Harris on the question "Would a judicious Bankrupt Law be beneficial
                    to the South?"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richardson</ln>
                        <fn>C. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strasburg</ln>
                        <fn>D. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Effinger</ln>
                        <fn>Fred</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>At the meeting of the Philomathesian Society last Saturday, participants
                    discussed whether fear of punishment or hope of reward was the greatest
                    incentive to exertion. At the next meeting, the question "'which is the most
                    desirable government--the Monarchical or Republican?" will be debated.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that Thomas Burke, of Newton, lost his house and its contents in a
                    fire last Tuesday. The source of the blaze was a kerosene lamp that exploded.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Editor of the Staunton Vindicator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Many Virginians</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Michie</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>In his letter, "Many Virginians" endorses Thomas J. Mitchie as "a fit and
                    suitable gentleman to fill the office of the Chief Magistrate" of Virginia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Labor Contracts</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Major General Howard commissioner of the Freedmen's Bureau, has issued the
                        following order to each assistant commissioner:</p>
                    <p>"Hereafter, and until further orders, no fees or charges will be exacted by
                        officers or agents of this bureau for services they may render in connection
                        with contracts between freed people and their employers, either in
                        examination, approval, witnessing or registry of such contracts, or
                        otherwise.--Please instruct your subordinates to comply with this
                        requirements. Labor contracts should be in writing. If possible, persuade
                        laborers and employers not in rely upon more verbal agreements; they
                        occasion much confusion. Bureau agents are required to do all in their power
                        to secure fair contracts for the freed people, and in offering their
                        services for that purpose they should let it be understood that they will be
                        rendered without charge to the parties concerned."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Contains a copy of Gen. O. O. Howard's order pertaining to labor contracts.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>G. Harvey</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>M. Virginia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stevenson</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Jan. 24 G. Harvey Brown, of Rockingham County, and M. Virginia Brown
                    were married by Rev. G. W. Stevenson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fifer</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickle</ln>
                        <fn>Carolina S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>W. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Jan. 24 Benjamin F. Fifer and Carolina S. Bickle were married by Rev. W.
                    E. Baker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Arnold</ln>
                        <fn>C. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>C. W. Arnold died near Brownsburg on Jan. 17. He was 56 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lindamood</ln>
                        <fn>Carrie Lee Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lindamood</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lindamood</ln>
                        <fn>Hannah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Carrie Lee Catharine, only daughter and child of Hugh and Hannah Lindamood,
                    died on Jan. 25. She was 6 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thornton</ln>
                        <fn>John S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Morris</ln>
                        <fn>William F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lowry</ln>
                        <fn>G. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. John S. Thornton, daughter of William F. Morris and former wife of G.
                    T. Lowry, died on Jan. 19. She was 22 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1867.02.01.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements and brief news summaries.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
