<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; --><!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1867/va.au.rv.1867.11.22">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>05/22</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1867-11-22">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="11"/>
            <day>22</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1867.11.22.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Woman's Mission</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article contains an extract of a speech delivered before the Board and
                    Members of the Synodical Female College in Florence, Alabama. The address is a
                    "tribute to the loveliness and power of female piety."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>"She Is A Working Girl"</head>
                <origin>Scranton Register</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article chastises those women who disparage "working girls" and
                    encourages men to end their relations with women who voice such sentiments.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1867.11.22.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On Monday next, Court-day, it is proposed to hold a meeting of the
                        Conservative citizens of Augusta County, to select delegates to represent
                        them in the Conservative Convention proposed to be held in Richmond on the
                        11th day of December next. The object of the Richmond Convention is to
                        organize thoroughly the Conservative voters of the State and adopt some
                        general plan of action to defeat, if possible, the attempted Radical
                        domination in this State. That any attempt of the Radicals to rule in the
                        "Old Dominion" can be defeated, needs only a reference to the re[unclear]
                        lists in the State, which exhibit a white majority of 13,000. The Statistics
                        also show that 14,000 whites failed to register. A small number of those who
                        failed to register, <emph rend="italic">may</emph> do so previous to the
                        election on the ratification of the Constitution. But the question is, how
                        can the whole known white majority of 27,000 be secured on the registered
                        lists? In no way save by a general Conservative organization throughout the
                        State, looking to that as well as to the casting of the entire Conservative
                        vote of the State on the question submitted by the Convention. Then will the
                        prominent men of the State canvass every county and district in the State,
                        on the issues presented and the people of Virginia will be aroused from that
                        apathy which has been so disastrous to them in the late election. This
                        Conservative organization can be secured if the counties will move promptly
                        in the matter. Already a number of counties have selected delegates. Let not
                        Old Augusta and her sister counties in the Valley be dilatory in the good
                        work.--The importance of thorough Conservative organization is conceded by
                        all. It is a matter that vitally interests every Conservative in the State.
                        Let our people respond generally to the call for a meeting in the Court
                        House on Monday next. Let us have no such sickly affair as that which made
                        nominations for the Convention, but let every good citizen, who can possibly
                        do so, be present. If we would have Virginia take her place along side of
                        her sister States of the North, who have so lately, and significantly,
                        declared in favor of upholding the Constitution and Laws [unclear]make our
                        county meeting one worthy of "Old Augusta" and the delegates selected such
                        as will meet the hearty approval of every Conservative in the county.</p>
                    <p>REMEMBER MONDAY NEXT <emph rend="italic">and let every good citizen be
                            present at the meeting of the Conservatives of Augusta on that
                        day</emph>.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors remind readers to attend a meeting of Conservative citizens in
                    Staunton next Monday, at which time delegates will be selected to attend the
                    State Conservative Convention in Richmond. It is imperative that all
                    conservatives voters "be aroused" from their "apathy" so as to deter "the
                    attempted Radical domination of this State."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>New York Herald</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The New York Herald quotes the Federal Constitution to show that no person is
                        eligible to a seat in the Lower House of Congress unless he has been a
                        citizen of the United States for seven years, or to the Senate unless he has
                        been a citizen for ten years. Assuming that, according to the decision in
                        the Dred Scott case, negroes were not citizens, at least until Mr. Lincoln's
                        proclamation in 1862, it concludes that they are not now eligible to seats
                        in Congress. We are surprised at the Herald quoting the Constitution on a
                        body which has ignored it. Does it no know that the only test of eligibility
                        is loyalty to Radicalism? Citizenship is out of question, and
                        negro-representation from the South is a fixed fact under the Congressional
                        Reconstruction.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>According to the Constitution, candidates for Congress must be U. S.
                    citizens for seven years before they are eligible to serve in the House and ten
                    years for the Senate. Consequently, relates the piece, blacks, who "were not
                    citizens, at least until Mr. Lincoln's proclamation in 1862," should be
                    ineligible to hold office. Since the Radicals came to power, however, the true
                    test for eligibility has become "loyalty to Radicalism."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In the late election in Minnesota, reports the article, a Radical governor
                    was elected but a measure to grant blacks the vote was defeated. "It is a
                    sufficient comment to state that Minnesota Republicans are willing to see negro
                    suffrage in the South," it notes, "yet at this late day refuse the 259 colored
                    men in that State the right to vote."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is reported that Thad Stevens's health is steadily declining, yet, even
                    on his death bed, "he still clings to his pet scheme of confiscation and
                    discusses, in a rambling way, political questions."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Senator Wilson On Reconstruction</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Contains an extract of a letter written by Senator Wilson to a black
                    candidate for the North Carolina Convention. In his correspondence, Wilson
                    offers words of encouragement and declares Congress' intent "to stand like a
                    rock in defense of its policy of reconstruction," though he states unequivocally
                    that confiscation will not occur.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>New York Herald</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>According to the New York "Herald's" Washington correspondent, Gen.
                    Scholfield, in his meeting with President Johnson, provided "a good deal of
                    information relative to the arming of blacks" in Virginia and intimated that
                    whites in the state "were at a great disadvantage." As a result, Scholfield
                    intends to implement a plan to "prevent" blacks from making use "of their
                    superiority in arms." It was also reported that Scholfield believes the
                    Convention "will prove a complete failure."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Baltimore Gazette</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>As a result of the ever-escalating cost of living in American cities, the
                    article contends, numbers of American emigrants are relocating to Germany where
                    living expenses are much cheaper.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Proposed Division Of The State Of Texas</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is reported that Thad Stevens plans to submit a bill to Congress
                    mandating a division of Texas into two or more states.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>What Should The South Do?</head>
                <origin>National Intelligencer</origin>
                <commentary>"The <emph rend="italic">National Intelligencer</emph> of Saturday has
                    an interesting editorial from which we take the following:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editorial maintains that the "only salvation for the South and the
                    whole country" is for southerners to reject the imposition of the new
                    constitutions and "the despotic rule of the Radical party." "It is absurd," the
                    editorial suggests, "to suppose that Congress, in this case, will revert to
                    positive measures--to confiscation, disfranchisement, &amp;c." because the
                    "people will not tolerate this."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1867.11.22.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snapp</ln>
                        <fn>George K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes that a man from South Carolina paid $3,000 cash for the residence of
                    the late George K. Snapp. The house, which includes seven acres of land, is
                    located about a mile out of town.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that the Staunton Musical Association will give its first
                    performance of the season on November 26 at the Deaf, Dumb, and Blind Institute.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Churchman</ln>
                        <fn>Willie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Churchman</ln>
                        <fn>John S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that John S. Churchman's son, Willie, was severely injured last
                    Tuesday in an accident involving a thresher. The boy's leg was "badly crushed"
                    when he tried to step off the machine while it was motion. It is feared the leg
                    may need to be amputated.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echols</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Catlett</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn>H. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The firm of Echols, Bell, Catlett, &amp; Co. sold Judge H. W. Sheffey's
                    farm, which contains 440 acres, to a man from Alabama for $25,000, half the
                    amount in cash and the remaining in three annual installments with interest.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pelter</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Branaman</ln>
                        <fn>Esteline</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Nov. 10 George Pelter and Esteline Branaman were married by Rev. C.
                    Beard.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clemmer</ln>
                        <fn>Henry C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armehart</ln>
                        <fn>Mary M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schreckhise</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Nov. 7 Henry C. Clemmer and Mary M. Armehart were married by Rev. J. M.
                    Schreckhise.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Masinoup</ln>
                        <fn>David V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fall</ln>
                        <fn>Mary M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Neel</ln>
                        <fn>A. A. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Nov. 14 David V. Masinoup and Mary M. Fall were married by Rev. A. A. P.
                    Neel.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heard</ln>
                        <fn>John F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grabbin</ln>
                        <fn>Emma T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burrows</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Nov. 14 John F. Heard and Emma T. Grabbin, of Richmond, were married by
                    Rev. Burrows.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dick</ln>
                        <fn>P. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rivercomb</ln>
                        <fn>R. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rivercomb</ln>
                        <fn>Johnathan C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stevenson</ln>
                        <fn>G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Oct. 14 P. H. Dick, of Rockingham, and R. A., daughter of Johnathan C.
                    Rivercomb, were married by Rev. G. Stevenson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1867.11.22.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements and brief news items.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
