<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1867/va.au.rv.1867.01.25">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>03</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1867-01-25">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day>25</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1867.01.25.01">
            <pageNote>Page contains advertisements and a variety of short news items and
            anecdotes.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1867.01.25.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>At no time perhaps has the subject of mining engaged the attention of
                        Virginians so extensively as at present. Daily important and valuable
                        additions are made to the great mineral wealth Virginia is know to possess.
                        These discoveries are inducing a disposition to engage in a new species of
                        manufacture in the Old Dominion. We herald this as a good omen. The success
                        of any kind of manufacturing establishment induces greater energy in that
                        line and tends to stimulate other branches. We have noticed with pleasure
                        that our Capital City is turning her attention to a greater degree than
                        heretofore to manufacturing. Richmond, with her vast water power, her
                        attention turned to manufacture, and with her facility to receive the raw
                        material, will take no second rate position among manufacturing cities. This
                        will but increase her importance as a commercial city. Her advantages in
                        this line are no mean order and manufactures will serve to stimulate her
                        commercial interests. To see Richmond turning her attention particularly to
                        manufacturing is a pleasing sight to Virginians. To this means alone, in her
                        changes circumstances, have we looked ultimately to see her take that proud
                        and prominent position among the cities of this country to which her
                        location and natural advantages justly entitle her.</p>
                    <p>Not only is manufactures destined to benefit Richmond, but it is to the
                        proper reduction of the raw material, in which Virginia abounds, into
                        marketable commodities, that we will have to look for restoration of the
                        former prosperity of the "Old Dominion." Every facility in this line will
                        ultimately be taken advantage of. Manufacturing establishments, adapted to
                        the wants, or super-induced by the facility of receiving and cheapness of
                        the raw material, will spring up in every community. They will furnish labor
                        with constant work, produce with a ready market at home, merchandise with
                        prompt and cash customers and indeed give a heretofore, unfelt impetus to
                        every branch of business. What we all have to do is to foster those which
                        have been erected in our communities by our patronage, and stimulate the
                        building up of other branches of manufacture by the success of those already
                        in operation. If we all but add out mite in this line, every city and town
                        will rise in importance, and Virginia be prosperous beyond any realization
                        of the past or the most sanguine anticipation of the future.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors herald the development of the manufacturing and mining
                    industries in Virginia. These advances will aid Virginia's return "to the former
                    prosperity of the 'Old Dominion.'"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>A. H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes that the message of Gov. Boreman, of West Virginia, contained several
                    topics of interest to the citizens of Virginia, including his contention that
                    any attempt to re-join Virginia "would be unanimously rejected" by the
                    legislators.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>"Virginia and West Virginia"</head>
                <origin>Wheeling Intelligencer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In response to a letter discussing the debate over where to place the
                    capital of West Virginia, the editors offer a suggestion, but question the
                    relevance of the issue to residents of "'Old Virginny.'"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Informs readers that the snow fall in Augusta last Sunday "was the deepest
                    of the season."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that the legislative committee assigned the task of investigating
                    the plan to postpone the May 1867 elections until October has been discharged.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is reported that $1,530,000 worth of domestic goods, mostly flour and
                    tobacco, was exported from Richmond last year. Imports amounted to $37,300,
                    including $20,977 worth of salt.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Retaliatory Legislation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We clip the following from the proceedings of the Legislation of "West
                        Virginia" last Thursday:</p>
                    <p>"Mr. Ferguson, from the Judiciary Committee, reported a bill to protect the
                        people of the counties bordering on Virginia, in which State there is a stay
                        law. It provides, in brief, that the people of Virginia shall not collect
                        debts from citizens in West Virginia so long as the latter are prevented by
                        the Virginia stay law from collecting debts due from citizens of Virginia.
                        Read the first time."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates that a West Virginia legislator introduced a bill to protect people
                    on the border with Virginia. The new law stipulates that Virginians may not
                    collect debts from West Virginians so long as the latter are prevented from
                    collecting debts because of Virginia's Stay Law.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Impeachment--Exciting Statements</head>
                <origin>New York World; New York Herald</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Using extracts from two New York journals, the article contends the debate
                    over whether President Johnson should face impeachment hearings has polarized
                    the nation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>General Assembly</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Details the proceedings from the General Assembly last week, including the
                    penitentiary bill, which passed unanimously.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Effect of Impeachment on Five-Twenties</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Informs readers that Europeans have sent a flood of U. S securities back to
                    the United States for sale, and blames "the lack of confidence" on the
                    continuing crisis over Johnson's impeachment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The brief piece contains a passage from Rev. Henry Ward Beecher's lecture
                    on "'Universal Suffrage,'" in which he argues in favor of granting the ballot to
                    women.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The New York Southern Relief Association</head>
                <origin>New York World</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on the creation of a women's philanthropic organization in New
                    York, whose goal is to ease the "terrible destitution now prevailing" throughout
                    the South. The group has no political affiliation and has received support from
                    various city leaders.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1867.01.25.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>States that the U. S. Agricultural Commissioner has obtained a large
                    quantity of Spring wheat seed from Russia to distribute in areas of the country
                    where that variety can be grown, which includes Augusta County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Informs readers that S. R. Sterling, Collector of United States Internal
                    Revenue, will be in Staunton from Feb. 18 to Feb. 21. All taxes assessed through
                    January 1 are to be collected.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Cautions readers that counterfeit National Bank notes are circulating.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Giles</ln>
                        <fn>S. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ker</ln>
                        <fn>Heber</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wheat</ln>
                        <fn>C. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>Carrie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces the formation of another debating society in Staunton, the
                    "Philomathesian Society."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that "no business of general interest" was undertaken by the
                    Circuit Court during its session here last week.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tuner</ln>
                        <fn>A. J&gt;</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Proudly notes that the "'Stonewall Band'" will be organized next week,
                    under the leadership of Prof. A. J. Tuner.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>S. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces that Rev. S. D. Stuart will deliver a lecture at the Stanton
                    Lyceum next Friday. The subject of the lecture will be his recent trip to
                    England .</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Leonard</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yount</ln>
                        <fn>Nannie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yount</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Jan. 22 Jacob H. Leonard and Nannie Yount, daughter of David Yount, were
                    married by Rev. C. Beard.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cease</ln>
                        <fn>Erasmus P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swine</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Busey</ln>
                        <fn>E. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Erasmus P. Cease and Sarah A. Swine were married by Rev. E. F. Busey last
                    Tuesday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1867.01.25.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements and a column of news snippets.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
