<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1864/pa.fr.fr.1864.06.22">
    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Rachel Onuf</taggerName>
            <tagDate>11/24/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>1st Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1864-06-22">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="06">June</month>
            <day>22</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.06.22.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Davisegination</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>Jefferson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>"Instances are common of the most afflictive separation of family relations
                    by this unnatural war. Brothers, and even parents and children, are found in the
                    ranks of the hostile armies. One of the most touching cases of this kind is that
                    of a son of the Confederate President Jefferson Davis, who is serving in the
                    National cause on the gunboat Carondolet, fighting to crush the Rebellion which
                    his father is leader of. The Davis junior is the son of Eliza, late a slave to
                    the patriarchal Davis. An officer of the army of Vicksburg who had heard of the
                    fact, verified it from Eliza's lips. How sharper than a serpent's tooth must be
                    the grief of that parent whom unrelenting fate compels to take sides against his
                    own son in a war for freedom!"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Includes the latest army news, which highlights the Federal assaults on
                Petersburg, Virginia, and the Washington and "Political Intelligence" columns. There
                is also an engraving depicting the Sanitary Fair Buildings on Logan Square in
                Philadelphia.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.06.22.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>How I Escaped: A Soldier's Story</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <summary>A tale of a captured Federal Lieutenant "Hanson," who escapes with the
                    assistance of a Confederate Colonel who has grown fond of Hanson during his
                    genteel parole, and cannot bear to see him dragged off in irons to his death.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The New Marriage</head>
                <origin>From the Press.</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Let joy prevail throughout the land, for after many years of bitterness
                    between the radicals and Copperheads we are to have peace and union, and
                    felicity. The banns have been read -- the marriage settlements are being
                    prepared--the bride is blushing, and timid, and anxious -- the bridegroom looks
                    forward with impatience to the happy hour."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Come all men from the east and the west, and let us sing the new
                        epithalamium. Let joy prevail throughout the land, for after man years of
                        bitterness between the radicals and Copperheads we are to have peace and
                        union, and felicity. The banns have been read--the marriage settlements are
                        being prepared--the bride is blushing, and timid, and anxious--the
                        bridegroom looks forward with impatience to the happy hour. The day of the
                        wedding has been fixed, and prudish gossips bid us anticipate happy fruits
                        from the happy union. It is no family affair of ours, perhaps but let us all
                        be neighborly and kind, and go to church on the appointed morning. We then
                        may greet the new couple and wish them all manner of happiness, and many,
                        many returns of the day.</p>
                    <p>Who are to be the happy pair? Nay, do not laugh and turn away, and chide and
                        deride them; for if they are to love and cherish each other, what right have
                        we to interfere or pronounce impediments? Miss Radical Democracy, from
                        Cleveland, supported by Misses Fremont and Cochrane, to Mr. Copperhead
                        Democracy, of Chicago, Whose next best friends have not been named--these
                        are the happy beings, and may the sun shine brightly upon them on the
                        eventful morning. People do talk, of course, and say that Misses Fremont and
                        Cochrane are two old maids who have been a long time in the market, and
                        having tried all means to make a match of their own, find the chances
                        becoming desperate and their charms familiar. They can find no opportunity,
                        in any respectable family, and so try their fortunes with this new concern
                        in Cleveland, in the hope that all will be arranged at Chicago, with wine
                        and cake for every guest. We do not know the terms of the settlement, but
                        many good things are reserved for the deserving old maids; and if the affair
                        can be arranged, the balance of their lives, dear old souls, may be spent
                        over snuff and tea. What delightful stories they could tell! What varied
                        experiences they have had--and if they are old maids, it is not their fault,
                        for they have been all their lives true to themselves, and anxious for a
                        change--how Miss Fremont went to California, and the gold mines, and the
                        Rocky Mountains, and the Blairs, and the Benton family, and South Carolina,
                        and Missouri, and emancipation, and among the Germans--and how she might
                        have been fortunate but for that ugly Mr. Lincoln, who was jealous of her,
                        and made people believe that she was no better than she ought to be! But a
                        more interesting story we shall have from Miss Cochrane. The old lady is
                        somewhat garrulous, and rather eccentric of speech, like most old maids, and
                        has been in more families than one since her earlier life. How she went to
                        Buffalo after the Van Burens, and to Mr. Pierce after certain loaves and
                        fishes, and to Richmond after Jefferson Davis, and to Mr. Lincoln after
                        further loaves and fishes, and down into the army, where that envious fellow
                        Burnside worried her so that she got sick and had to come home. She has had
                        her own time tramping around, this poor Miss Cochrane; and now there is hope
                        that she will have peace and comfort, and cake and wine, and tea and snuff,
                        at Chicago.</p>
                    <p>This, of course, will be a happy union. Ill-natured people tell us that there
                        has been much ill-feeling between the families, and that great scandal will
                        ensue. But if they love each other now, what difference will it make? "I am
                        sure," says Mrs. Malaprop. "I hated your poor, dear uncle, before marriage
                        as if, as if he'd been a black-amour, and yet, Miss, you are sensible what a
                        wife I make." There are two intimate friends of the family, for instance,
                        Mr. Wendell Phillips and Mr. Fernando Wood. We all know that Phillips and
                        Wood have been as far apart as the antipodes, as different in their temper
                        as the cobra-di-capello and the dove. They have been the political Montagu
                        and Capulet, never meeting without a brawl. Phillips has been a high-priest
                        among the anti-slavery radicals, and for twenty years has swung the censor
                        in the anti-slavery temple. Wood has been a prince among Secessionists, as
                        consistent but hardly as courageous a rebel as Davis or toombs [sic]. All
                        these things will be forgotten at Chicago--and when the benediction is
                        pronounced over the newly-united Copperhead-Radicals, their glasses will
                        clink together in the joyous libation. We shall have McClellan and
                        McKinstry, Fitz John Porter and the staff-majors with unpronounceable names,
                        William B. Reed and Mrs. B. Cady Stanton, Charles Ingersoll and Mrs. Abby
                        Forster, Samuel S. Cox and Frederick Douglass, all surrounding the
                        newly-married pair and overwhelming them with congratulations. Charles
                        Mackay, with his Cockney Copperhead rhymes, will write the nuptial song; and
                        the "night-clerk" of the <emph rend="italic">World</emph>, with his German
                        friends of the <emph rend="italic">New Nation</emph>, will sing the chorus.</p>
                    <p>It is not for us to be too busy with our neighbors' affairs, or to ask
                        impertinent questions. The <emph rend="italic">New Nation</emph> tells us
                        that the main cause of this affectionate sympathy between the Copperheads
                        and Radicals is "the hatred of Lincoln." This controlling thought overrides
                        and surpasses all difference of principle, of record, of former association.
                        What are freedom and Union compared with the "hatred of Lincoln?" This is
                        the chain that links them all together. This "hatred of Lincoln" is so
                        engrossing, so intense, so all-pervading--so general in its application,
                        from Wendell Phillips to Jefferson Davis--that we venture to make a
                        suggestion. Why not transfer the marriage-ceremony from Chicago to Richmond?
                        If "hatred of Lincoln" is to be the motto of the new epithalamium, there
                        will be more singers in Richmond than in Cleveland, or Chicago, or the Five
                        Points. Let them all herd together, and go to the place of all places where
                        the "hared of Lincoln" is a virtue and a religion. They need not have any
                        hesitancy about getting through the lines. Vallandigham found it easy
                        enough, and if these people are really desirous of going Gen. Butler will be
                        happy to meet them at City Point, and escort them as far as the guns of Fort
                        Darling.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <summary>A sardonic celebration of the new "marriage" between Copperheads and
                    radicals, joined together by their mutual hatred of Lincoln.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Includes a poem, entitled, "The Song of the People," an optimistic article
                about the "waning" of the rebellion, and advertisements, with the following
                headings: Dry &amp; Fancy Goods; Educational; Publications; Medical.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.06.22.03">
            <pageNote>Entirely advertisements, with the following headings: Gutta-Percha Roofing;
                Medical; Groceries, &amp;c; Tobacco and Segars; Physicians; Hardware, Cutlery,
                &amp;c; Forwarding Houses; Attorneys at Law; Hats, Caps, and Straw Goods;
                Miscellaneous.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.06.22.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Vallandigham</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vallandigham</ln>
                        <fn>Clement C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Clement C. Vallandigham, who was banished from the country as a traitor in
                    1863, had recently returned to his home in Dayton, Ohio, where he was
                    immediately elected a delegate to the Democratic convention in Chicago. The
                    author wishes to dismiss "Val" as a non-entity, but can't resist such an easy
                    target: "the sorest punishment that can be inflicted upon him is to doom him to
                    live in the country he sought in vain to destroy, to be shunned, despised, and
                    scorned by every loyal heart."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>"Rev. Sam'l Kepler"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kepler</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Rev. Samuel Kepler, in Bedford, has "got up a little secession in the
                    Church," and has proposed founding "The Church of our Providence." The author
                    observes that Kepler was "fully justified in seceding from the Methodist Church,
                    as he had only 'Hobson's choice'--that is he had either to withdraw or be kicked
                    out, and he naturally prefered peaceful dismemberment to that style of
                    coercion."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>"The Military Telegraph Corps"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Wherever the army goes there goes the man of wires and lightning, ready to
                    improvise an office and annihilate space for the benefit of the service."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilmore</ln>
                        <fn>James R.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James R. Gilmore, Esq., of Chambersburg, is in charge of the telegraph
                    lines in and about Newburne, North Carolina, doing one of the "most useful and
                    least appreciated" jobs in the service.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>There are a couple articles about Grant's campaign and the likely siege of
                Petersburg, an account of Lincoln's visit to the Fair in Philadelphia, a report on
                the House defeat of the resolution providing for the abolition of slavery by an
                amendment of the Constitution, and more ridiculing of Clement
            Vallandigham.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.06.22.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Gossip with our Friends</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Door knobs rattle, chambermaids tattle, doors slam, ne'er a calm, boots
                    stamp, passing lamp, Irish porter, drunk exhorter."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <summary>A wry account of the difficulties of sleeping in a room fronting on
                    Broadway in New York City.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Fair--A Remarkable Success--The Results</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Couch</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs. Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Culloh</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nixon</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ayres</ln>
                        <fn>George B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Halm</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Halm</ln>
                        <fn>Julia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Ladies' Fair raised about $3,000 for the Christian Commission. Mrs.
                    Gen. Couch is the chief executive officer of the Ladies' Aid Society, and she
                    was assisted by many citizens, including Messrs. Reed, M'Culloh, and Nixon. Mr.
                    George B. Ayres conducted the Old Folks' Concerts. Mrs. Halm and her daughter
                    Miss Julia Halm from Hagerstown performed at these musical entertainments, which
                    netted nearly $700.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>A Good Record</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wood</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The editors had the pleasure of meeting Thomas Wood of Fannettsburg, who
                    had served as a private in the Pennsylvania Reserve Corps. Wood was in
                    thirty-two skirmishes and battles, and was unscathed except for a slight foot
                    wound: "He talks intelligently of the battles he has been in, is plain and
                    unassuming in his manners, and seems to have no other ambition than to serve his
                    country faithfully."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Death of Capt. S. R. M'Kesson</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Kesson</ln>
                        <fn>S. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strickler</ln>
                        <fn>Harry</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Capt. S. R. M'Kesson died of consumption at his home in Chambersburg last
                    Saturday. At one time he commanded Co. A of the 77th Regiment of Pennsylvania
                    Volunteers. He was also an "earnest" Democrat, and his party nominated him for
                    Register and Recorder, but he was defeated by the present incumbent, Harry
                    Strickler, Esq.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Liberal Contributions</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <summary>The Ladies' Aid Society of Mercersburg raised $219 at their Strawberry
                    Festival and $780 through contributions, all for the Christian Commission.
                    Antrim township has forwarded $1100 in cash and "liberal contributions" of
                    produce to the Sanitary Commission.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>A New Draft</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <summary>Another draft will be made on July 19th for Franklin and Somerset Counties.
                    Some districts, such as Guilford, Chambersburg, and Greencastle, have filled
                    their quotas and will not be subject to a draft until a new call is made.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Look for the Flag</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <summary>In addition to the usual long streamer, a large flag will fly from the new
                    Union pole whenever there is "cheering news" from the Union Armies.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Wounded</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Kibbin</ln>
                        <fn>Robert P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Kibbin</ln>
                        <fn>D. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Kibben</ln>
                        <fn>Chambers</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Kibbin</ln>
                        <fn>Chambers</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lieut. Robert P. M'Kibbin, formerly a resident of Chambersburg, is severely
                    wounded and now in Washington. His brother Capt. D. B. M'Kibbin, a former
                    Colonel of the 158th Regiment, is a prisoner in Richmond. Another brother,
                    Lieut. Chambers M'Kibben [sic], was wounded severely under M'Clellan on the
                    Peninsula, and Chambers M'Clellan Jr., his nephew, was wounded under Sherman at
                    Buzzard's Roost.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Remarkable Escape</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greenawalt</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>"Mr. John Greenawalt, Co. E, 21st Cavalry, of this place, was in the
                    engagement at Bethsada Church two weeks ago, and was wounded. The ball struck
                    him in the groin and passed through a testament in his pantaloons pocket, giving
                    him a severe wound in the thigh. But for the resistance offered by the book, his
                    thigh would have been broken. His parents have this testament, and will
                    naturally value it as a most sacred relic alike of his valor and safety."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Religious</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Cullom</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maher</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ham</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowles</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>"The religious exercises which commenced in the Catholic Church, of this
                    place, on Sunday, and ended yesterday, were of a very devotional and impressive
                    character. Besides the Rev. Mr. M'Cullom, pastor of the Church, the Rev. Messrs.
                    Maher, of Harrisburg, Ham, of York, and Bowles, of Gettysburg, were in
                    attendance. The very efficient choir was assisted by some fine talent from
                    abroad, and the music rendered was of the most superb description."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Collision</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"On Thursday last a collision occurred on the Cumberland Valley Railroad,
                    near Alterton, between the Accommodation Passenger Train going own and the
                    Freight Train coming in this direction. Several cars were considerably damaged,
                    and the Baggage-Master, Engineer, Fireman and one or two others were badly,
                    though not dangerously injured on the passenger train."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>"At the raising..."</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnhart</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reilly</ln>
                        <fn>Wilson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Couch</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Major General</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Clure</ln>
                        <fn>A. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>"At the raising of the great Union Pole in our Public Square, on Tuesday of
                    last week, a fervent and patriotic prayer was made by Rev. Thomas Barnhart, and
                    eloquent and impressive speeches made by Hon. Wilson Reilly, Major General Couch
                    and Col. A. K. M'Clure."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Col. Boyd</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyd</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Col. William H. Boyd is recovering from his wound but the bullet is still
                    lodged in the bone near his spine. The surgeons have twice tried to remove it
                    but have not been successful.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Sanford</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sanford</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>"Sanford, with his inimitable Troupe, gave two concerts in Franklin Hall,
                    on Monday and Tuesday evenings last, to crowded audiences."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Meyers</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Meyers</ln>
                        <fn>S. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Daniel W. Miller, of Green township, married Miss Susan Meyers, daughter of
                    S. B. Meyers of Fayetteville, on June 14, 1864. The Rev. Samuel R. Fisher
                    performed the ceremony.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brotherton</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stover</ln>
                        <fn>Sue</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bosserman</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Brotherton, formerly of Waynesboro, married Miss Sue Stover at the
                    home of her parents, near Springfield, Illinois, on May 31, 1864. Rev. Alexander
                    Bosserman performed the ceremony.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Kesson</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Capt. Samuel R. M'Kesson died in Chambersburg on June 18, 1864, after a
                    "severe and protracted illness." He was 42 years, 6 months, and 6 days old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Mary Kennedy died in Greencastle on June 9, 1864, aged 83.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bitner</ln>
                        <fn>Joshua</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bitner</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Joshua Bitner, son of Jacob Bitner, died on June 10, 1864, near
                    Greencastle. He was 9 years, 6 months, and 20 days old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.06.22.06">
            <pageNote>Entirely advertisements, with the following headings: Lines of Travel; Stoves
                and Tinware; Medical; Musical; Boots and Shoes; Dye-Colors; Drugs, Medicines,
                &amp;c; Co-partnership Notices; Dry &amp; Fancy Goods; Books and
            Stationery.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.06.22.07">
            <pageNote>Entirely advertisements, with the following headings: Clothing; Insurance;
                Coal, Lumber, &amp;c; Liquors; Dentistry; Agricultural; Trees, Plants and Vines;
                Saddlery, Harness, &amp;c; Confectioners, &amp;c; Seeds; Medical.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.06.22.08">
            <pageNote>Includes a transcript of a speech given by Gov. Johnson in Nashville earlier
                in the month, a plug for "The Old Flag," which is the campaign paper the editors
                will start publishing in July, and advertisements, with the following headings: Real
                Estate Sales; Financial; Wants; Hotels; Military Notices; Legal Notices.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
