<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1864/pa.fr.fr.1864.03.09">
    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Rachel Onuf</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/23/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>1st Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1864-03-09">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day norm="09">9</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.03.09.01">
            <pageNote>This page includes the weekly "Political Intelligence," "Personal,"
                "Financial," "Washington," and "Summary of War News" columns. The "Harrisburg"
                column describes the disorganization of the Senate as the Democrats and Union men
                continue their political struggles, even though the election of Dr. Thomas St. Clair
                as a Union Senator has broken the party deadlock.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.03.09.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Speech of J. M'D. Sharpe, Esq., In the House of Representatives of
                    Pennsylvania, on the Bill for the Adjudication and Payment of Military Damages.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"Delivered February 24, 1864."</commentary>
                <excerpt>"Go home to your constituents if you can, go home to them if you dare, and
                    tell them that Pennsylvania, the brightest star in the galaxy of States, the
                    cradle of American freedom, the nursing mother of the Declaration of
                    Independence, rich in the hallowed memories of Valley Forge and Germantown,
                    having within its limits the birth-place of our nation, and the grave of treason
                    close by the consecrated sepulchres of Gettysburg's heroes--on empire of three
                    millions of people, whose mountains milk the clouds, and whose valleys run with
                    fatness, having within her bowels coal enough to warm all her friends, and iron
                    enough to cool all her foes--a Commonwealth abounding in prosperity,
                    intelligence and civilization unknown elsewhere--tell your constituents, I
                    repeat it, that this State, as I have described it, through you as her
                    representative on this floor, has refused to be just to her citizens, and has
                    declared herself to be too weak and poor to protect them."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <summary>J. M'D. Sharpe exhorts the Senate to pass the bill for the adjudication and
                    payment of military damages, and offers a resolution that parties furnish
                    positive proofs of their loyalty when making claims. He also insists that "there
                    are no politics in this bill, and that there ought to be none in its
                    discussion."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>This page includes advertisements for Groceries, &amp;c.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.03.09.03">
            <pageNote>Entirely advertisements, with the following headings: Seeds; Saddlery,
                Harness, &amp;c.; Forwarding Houses; Agricultural; Medical; Trees, Plants and
                Vines.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.03.09.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Military Claim Bill</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <summary>The author expresses amazement that the bill for the payment of military
                    damages in the border counties continues to be subjected to fierce political
                    debate. The bill has finally been referred to the committee on Federal
                    Relations, "although it is clearly not within the legitimate province of that
                    committee," but in that committee it should find a refuge from the political
                    strife "aimed at its vitals."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Township Elections</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The coming Presidential election will be the most important in the history
                    of the government, and the friends of the administration cannot prepare for
                    action too soon."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The township elections for election and other local officers will take place
                        on Friday of next week, the 18th inst., and the Union men should be on their
                        guard against surprise by the well organized Democracy. Last Spring the
                        Democrats elected every Judge of election in the county but <emph
                            rend="italic">two</emph>, while thirteen of the twenty-two election
                        districts give Gov. Curtin a majority last fall. The North Ward and
                        Greenvillage were the only districts in which we had Union election
                        boards--all the rest, even Mercersburg, the Old Gibralter, chose Democratic
                        officers. We doubt not that very many Union votes were lost to the party
                        last fall by these adverse boards, and it is the imperative duty of Union
                        men to give timely attention to the elections now near at hand.</p>
                    <p>The coming Presidential election will be the most important in the history of
                        the government, and the friends of the administration cannot prepare for
                        action too soon. It is of the first importance that the local elections
                        should be carried wherever it is in the power of the Union voters to do so;
                        and we appeal to them to commence the work of organization at once.
                        Guilford, Antrim, Fayetteville, Washington, Peters, Montgomery, Loudon,
                        Fannettsburg, Dry Run, Sulphur Spring, Mount Rock, Warren and the South
                        Ward, should each reverse their present election boards and carry their
                        local tickets. It <emph rend="italic">can</emph> be done if the Union men
                        resolve to do it, and the time to begin the work is now. It would be
                        discreditable to our organization, and fearfully peril our cause, if by our
                        remis[s]ness we surrender to the foes of the government the control of our
                        election boards and the district offices. Union men! the place to begin the
                        good work for the great struggle of 1864 is at the township elections on
                        Friday of next week!</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <summary>The author urges Union men to come out for the elections for township and
                    other local officers in order to try to regain positions lost to the Democrats
                    in the election the previous spring, and as preparation for the national
                    election to come.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>(No Title)</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt> "What side of the question it [the <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph>] will
                    take in its next issue, we couldn't guess. As it has already been on both sides,
                    it will have the merit of consistency let it go as it may hereafter." </excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> of the 17th ult. protested against any
                        oath being applied to claimants for military damages. Mr. Kelly had offered
                        a resolution instructing the committee to require parties to "furnish
                        positive proofs of their loyalty," and the <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph>
                        called upon the Democratic members to "<emph rend="italic">oppose all
                            amendments to the bill and defeat the bill itself</emph>, rather than
                        have this odious provision in it." Mr. Sharpe <emph rend="italic">did</emph>
                        amend the bill so as to require claimants to furnish "positive proofs" of
                        loyalty by solemn oath, and now the <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> says
                        "there is not a Democrat in the county that objects to taking the oath
                        prescribed by the bill as reported by the committee." What side of the
                        question it will take in its next issue, we couldn't guess. As it has
                        already been on both sides, it will have the merit of consistency let it go
                        as it may hereafter.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary/>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Descendents of Ham</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clark</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Repository reprints from the Valley Spirit the comments of "C,"
                    presumed to be Rev. Joseph Clark, and supports his arguments against the
                    Spirit's assertions that "the Negroes are the descendents of Ham, and that they
                    are by God accused to perpetual Slavery."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sellers</ln>
                        <fn>James A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reamer</ln>
                        <fn>Charlotte C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coble</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thomas</ln>
                        <fn>R. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James A. Sellers, of the 20th Pennsylvania Cavalry and Miss Charlotte C.
                    Reamer, of Peters Township, were married at the house of Daniel Coble on March
                    6, 1864, by the Rev. R. P. Thomas.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Morrison</ln>
                        <fn>Hans</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Branthaver</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Creigh</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Sarah Jane Branthaver, of Mercersburg, married Hans Morrison, of
                    Mifflin County, on March 3, 1864. Rev. Thomas Creigh performed the ceremony in
                    Mercersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crilly</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thomas</ln>
                        <fn>R. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Daniel F. Crilly of Chicago and Miss Elizabeth Snyder of Loudon, were
                    married by Rev. R. P. Thomas on March 3, 1864.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orth</ln>
                        <fn>John Q. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Alleman</ln>
                        <fn>Lizzie C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Breidenbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Q. A. Orth, of Mercersburg, and Lizzie C. Alleman, of Montgomery
                    township, were married February 25, 1864, by Rev. E. Breidenbaugh.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Auld</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Auld</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Niccolls</ln>
                        <fn>S. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. Campbell and Miss Auld, both of Dark County, Ohio, were married at the
                    residence of Mr. Auld, of Chambersburg, on March 8, 1864, by Rev. S. J.
                    Niccolls.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowman</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowman</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowman</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sarah Jane Bowman, infant daughter of Mary E. and Jacob Bowman, died March
                    6, 1864 in Antrim township of Catarrh Fever. She was 11 months and 22 days old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Haynes</ln>
                        <fn>Laura Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Haynes</ln>
                        <fn>Isabella</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Haynes</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Laura Elizabeth Haynes, infant daughter of Isabella and Jacob Haynes, died
                    February 23, 1864, at Spring Run, aged 8 weeks and 2 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lohr</ln>
                        <fn>Anna M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lohr</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Anna M. Lohr, daughter of John Lohr, died near Chambersburg on February 26,
                    1864, aged 3 years, 4 months, and 26 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Horst</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Henry Horst died on February 28, 1864, in Southampton township, aged 71
                    years, 6 months, and 27 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beckner</ln>
                        <fn>Susanna</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beckner</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Susanna Beckner, "consort" of Daniel Beckner, deceased, died of Lung
                    Fever near Mt. Hope on February 24, 1864. She was 74 years, 10 months, and 4
                    days old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rook</ln>
                        <fn>Emma Rebecca</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rook</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rook</ln>
                        <fn>Christiana</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Emma Rebecca Rook,. daughter of David and Christiana Rook, died of Spotted
                    Fever on February 5, 1864, near Mt. Hope. She was 10 years, 10 months, and 6
                    days old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Geddes</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Noonan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Elizabeth Geddes died at the house of her son-in-law, William Noonan,
                    Esq., on February 29, 1864, aged 74 years and 9 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peters</ln>
                        <fn>Elmer Ellsworth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peters</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peters</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On March 1, 1864, Elmer Ellsworth Peters, son of Samuel B. and Margaret E.
                    Peters, died in Greenwood, aged 2 years, 8 months, and 18 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Elroy</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Elroy</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Elizabeth M'Elroy, a member of the Methodist Episcopal Church and wife
                    of Rev. William M'Elroy, died in Fayetteville on February 25, 1864, aged 68
                    years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>This page includes articles critical of the Democrats ("the disorganizers of
                the Senate"), the Valley Spirit, and Vallandigham. There is also a column of news
                about Pennsylvania newspapers.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.03.09.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Gossip With Our Friends</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <summary>The author chastises soldiers for swearing in the presence of women: "It is
                    not manly to use language before any lady that you would not employ in the
                    presence of your sweethearts."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Arrested</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <summary>"A negro named --- ---" was arrested in Martinsburg, Va. and charged with
                    the murder of the man found dead in Gabby's Lime Kiln. He will be tried at the
                    April Court.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Serious Charge</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Leidig</ln>
                        <fn>Levi</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>"Levi Leidig, a citizen of this place, was recently arrested in Harrisburg
                    charged with taking a satchel containing a large sum of money belonging to a U.
                    S. Paymaster, from the Cumberland Valley Cars. He was committed to prison for
                    trial, but subsequently released for his appearance by giving the required
                    security. Leidig formerly kept the 'Continental Restaurant' in this place, is
                    respectably connected and we learn always bore the reputation of an honest,
                    upright man."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Guilford Union Ticket</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Small</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strickler</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vanderaw</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoler</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKnight</ln>
                        <fn>C. Harry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Downey</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ebersole</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rutt</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hege</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sollenberger</ln>
                        <fn>Solomon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stouffer</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kiefer</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Union ticket of Guilford township: Constable, Henry Small, Jr.;
                    Assessor, Daniel Grove; Assistant Assessors, Henry Snyder (of J.), Jacob
                    Strickler; Judge, William Vanderaw; Inspector, Andrew Stoler; School Directors,
                    C. Harry McKnight, John Downey; Supervisors, Michael Ebersole, Samuel Rutt,
                    Henry Hege, William Harman; Treasurer, Solomon Sollenberger; Auditor, Jacob
                    Stouffer; Township Clerk, Isaac H. Kiefer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Our Citizen Prisoners</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <summary>The last letters from the prisoners at Salisbury, N.C. were dated February
                    19, 1864, and at that point all were in good health. Although some have applied
                    for 60 days of parole, it has not been granted, as the Valley Spirit falsely
                    reported.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Resigned</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sees</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lane</ln>
                        <fn>S. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. S. G. Lane will replace Dr. Sees as Surgeon to the Board of Enrollment
                    for the Chambersburg district.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Delegate Elected</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duncan</ln>
                        <fn>C. M.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>"C. M. Duncan, Esq., of this place, has been elected Delegate to the
                    Democratic State Convention, with instructions to vote for Gen. M'Clellan as the
                    choice of the Democracy for the Presidency."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>This page includes an article in favor of life insurance and another urging
                contributions to the Sanitary Commission. The stories of a traitor from York County
                and of a murderer from a New Jersey regiment are also related, as well as the
                "Report of the Markets" and new advertisement listings.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.03.09.06">
            <pageNote>This page is entirely filled with advertisements with the following headings:
                Lines of Travel; Medical; Coal, Lumber, &amp;c; Liquors; Physicians; Stoves and
                Tinware; Dye-Colors; Drugs, Medicines, &amp;c.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.03.09.07">
            <pageNote>This page is entirely filled with advertisements with the following headings:
                Clothing; Medical; Hotels; Dry and Fancy Goods; Gutta-Perch Roofing; Books and
                Stationery; Musical; Watches and Jewelry.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.03.09.08">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Gov. Curtin's Proclamation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"Gov. Curtin has issued an earnest and eloquent Proclamation against
                    Pennsylvania soldiers enlisting in other States. He truthfully and pointedly
                    says:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Curtin</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gov.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Governor urges men not to volunteer on behalf of other states, for they
                    would then deprive their families and themselves of the protection and
                    assistance Pennsylvania offers her citizens.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>This page includes commentary on a couple articles from other newspapers and
                advertisements with the following headings: Boots and Shoes; Painting, Glazing,
                &amp;c; Wants; Co-partnership Notices; Religious; Dentistry; Justices of the
                Peace; Lost, Stolen and Strayed; Insurance; Publications; Tobacco and Segars;
                Educational; Attorneys; Legal Notices; Personal Property Sales; Real Estate
            Sales.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
