<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1864/pa.fr.fr.1864.06.01">
    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Rachel Onuf</taggerName>
            <tagDate>11/18/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>1st Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1864-06-01">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="06">June</month>
            <day norm="01">1</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.06.01.01">
            <div type="l">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>From the 21st Cavalry</head>
                <origin>Camp Casey, Va.</origin>
                <commentary>"The 21st in Camp Casey--Temporarily Acting as Infantry--A Complimentary
                    Order--A Romantic Marriage--A Negro Regiment--Letters from Home."</commentary>
                <excerpt>"It was very hard for us to part with our horses, and I noticed many a
                    watery eye as the men took a final look or gave a parting caress to the noble
                    animals which they have cared for ever since the re-organization of the
                    Regiment, and which they expected to ride to victory or a patriot's grave."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The 21st in Camp Casey--Temporarily Acting as Infantry--A Complimentary
                        Order--A Romantic Marriage--A Negro Regiment--Letters from Home.</p>
                    <p>Correspondence of the Franklin Repository</p>
                    <p>Camp Casey, Va., May 21, 1864.</p>
                    <p>After a tiresome march and some disappointments, we have at last encamped in
                        this place. It is situated at the Virginia end of Long Bridge. The day after
                        our arrival at Washington City we were ordered to Belle-Plain and marched to
                        the wharf, anticipating a speedy trip and a chance of displaying our bravery
                        in the conflict now going on between the Union and Rebel armies. But all our
                        hopes were dispelled by the order being countermanded, and very reluctantly
                        we went into camp again--the men showing their disapprobation by giving vent
                        to language more expressive than refined. But he unkindest cut of all had
                        not come yet, and well may we cry "A horse! a horse! my kingdom for a
                        horse!"--for we have been dismounted, and have to act temporarily as
                        infantry. It was very hard for us to part with our horses, and I noticed
                        many a watery eye as the men took a final look or gave a parting caress to
                        the noble animals which they have cared for ever since the re-organization
                        of the Regiment, and which they expected to ride to victory or a patriot's
                        grave. But we know the Cavalry in the Army of the Potomac stand greatly in
                        need of horses, and must have them, so the men bore it manfully, and like
                        good soldiers--which truly they are--all of them will stand by our Country,
                        right or wrong. The Lieutenant Colonel issued an order congratulating the
                        officers and men upon the calm, patriotic and soldierly manner in which they
                        received the order dismounting the Regiment; that he observed with pride and
                        satisfaction that devotion to our cause which prompts them to do their duty
                        to their Country in whatever capacity the interest of the service may
                        require, and that he felt assured by their past and present conduct, their
                        future course will be characterized by the same soldierly bearing. We hope
                        to be mounted again in about six weeks and them you will hear a good report
                        of the gallant twenty-first.</p>
                    <p>We have had an addition to our Regiment since leaving Chambersburg---being no
                        less than a very pretty and intelligent young lady, who having a bold
                        soldier boy for a lover, put on the blue uniform and came to this place,
                        where they were married and are now living happy together in a shelter tent.
                        She says she will fight by the side of her husband as long as possible.</p>
                    <p>In the next field to our camp there is a negro regiment in barracks. I was
                        surprised to see with what proficiency they drill, and how well disciplined
                        they are. They handle their arms and march with the precision of veterans,
                        and I am happy to see that they receive all respect due them as United
                        States soldiers from the officers and privates of all ranks and regiments.</p>
                    <p>Those who have never experienced it can scarcely form an idea of how much
                        good it does a soldier to receive a letter from home, and by prevailing upon
                        those who have brothers and sons in the army to write to them often. I will
                        have to stop until I can find something of interest to communicate to you.</p>
                    <p>R.H.W.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>R. H. W.</trailer>
                <summary>A letter from the 21st Cavalry, which had been stationed in Chambersburg
                    for some time before marching to Virginia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>This page includes the latest war news and an article about the new Union
                League building on Broad Street in Philadelphia, accompanied by an engraving of the
                exterior.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.06.01.02">
            <pageNote>Includes a poem, "The Old Folks' Room," a humorous piece by Artemus Ward, Jr.
                on the presidency, and details about the new militia law. There are also
                advertisements, with the following headings: Dry and Fancy Goods; Educational;
                Watches and Jewelry; Co-Partnership Notices; Medical.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.06.01.03">
            <pageNote>Entirely advertisements, with the following headings: Gutta-Percha Roofing;
                Medical; Groceries, &amp;c; Tobacco and Segars; Physicians; Hardware, Cutlery,
                &amp;c; Forwarding Houses; Attorneys at Law; Hats, Caps &amp; Straw Goods;
                Dentistry.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.06.01.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nill</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The entire Bar of Chambersburg recommended to Governor Curtin that he
                    appoint Hon. Alexander King, of Bedford, as President Judge of the District, in
                    place of the recently deceased Judge Nill.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Death of Judge Nill</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nill</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kimmell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reilly</ln>
                        <fn>Wilson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>An obituary for the Hon. James Nill, a founder and prominent member of the
                    local Union party. He was chosen as Judge Kimmell's successor as President Judge
                    of the Franklin, Fulton, Bedford and Somerset judicial district, defeating Hon.
                    Wilson Reilly in the fall election of 1861.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <summary>There is confusion among the western counties about electing delegates for
                    the national convention: The Somerset paper complains that Adams and Franklin
                    counties unfairly elected a delegate, but the Repository editor asserts that
                    when citizens of Somerset and Fulton did not appear at the announced meeting, it
                    was assumed that they had decided to meet separately, as Bedford County did, and
                    were opting not to take part in the selection.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nill</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>"The late Judge Nill, who died childless, by a will executed some years
                    ago, made a liberal bequest to a relative who is a native of this county and
                    still resides on the State; but by his will admitted to probate on Monday last,
                    he revokes the legacy expressly on the ground that the legatee sympathises with
                    the traitors in arms against the government. Judge Nill was a War Democrat, and
                    he was as consistent in death as he was earnest in life, in his abhorrence of
                    faithlessness to our sacred Nationality."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Our Wounded in Washington</head>
                <origin>Washington City</origin>
                <commentary>"We learn from reliable sources that there are now some 6,000
                    Pennsylvania wounded soldiers in Washington, and from all the benevolent
                    associations we have calls for aid to mitigate the sufferings of these noble
                    heroes. The following letter from Hon. Jasper E. Brady is worthy of the
                    attention of our people. The association of which he speaks has done great
                    service to our wounded, and our ladies should forward the supplies he desires as
                    promptly as possible. Articles left at the REPOSITORY office will be
                    acknowledged in these columns and forwarded without delay."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>J. E. Brady</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brady</ln>
                        <fn>Jasper E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Hon. Jasper E. Brady, chairman of the Executive Committee of the
                    Pennsylvania Relief Association in Washington D.C. and a former resident of
                    Chambersburg, appeals to the patriotic ladies of the "Green Spot," (as he calls
                    Chambersburg), to send whatever supplies they can muster.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reilly</ln>
                        <fn>Wilson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nill</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The author corrects the Harrisburg Telegraph, which identified Hon. Wilson
                    Reilly as the "Breckinridge candidate" in the 1861 race against Judge Nill, the
                    Union candidate and winner of the election. Apparently Reilly was an ardent
                    Douglas supporter in 1860, and "never sanctioned Breckinridge or treason." His
                    military career is summarized as further proof of his decency: he volunteered in
                    1861 and raised a company for the 6th Reserves. When he resigned due to his
                    health, his two sons stepped in and have served gallantly.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Draft</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shank</ln>
                        <fn>Simon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoner</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hellman</ln>
                        <fn>Wash</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnhart</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Good</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Alexander</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Saylor</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bratz</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel L.</fn>
                        <sf>(col'd)</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Loose</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gearhart</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wyant</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ruthrauff</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf>of Jacob</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gearhart</ln>
                        <fn>Fred</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tolhelm</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gorman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Loy</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shoaff</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mordorff</ln>
                        <fn>Philip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garven</ln>
                        <fn>Hezekiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lear</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Briggs</ln>
                        <fn>Richard</fn>
                        <sf>(col'd)</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoner</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walk</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Horner</ln>
                        <fn>Francis T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dixon</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Latshaw</ln>
                        <fn>John L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lindsay</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Welsh</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Frovinger</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolff</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wistar</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf>of Jacob</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weagley</ln>
                        <fn>Jeremiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Renicker</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kuhn</ln>
                        <fn>Carlisle</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Helfrick</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn>Fred</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stouffer</ln>
                        <fn>Amos</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snively</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brenner</ln>
                        <fn>Luchen</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ward</ln>
                        <fn>Aaron</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf>(col'd)</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>John F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gearhart</ln>
                        <fn>Francis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jordon</ln>
                        <fn>Turner</fn>
                        <sf>(col'd)</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rummel</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nelson</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf>(col'd)</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Byers</ln>
                        <fn>Hiram</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Poper</ln>
                        <fn>Levi</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Conley</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn>James H.</fn>
                        <sf>(col'd)</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kelker</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burns</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Royer</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Middower</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hickus</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hokelander</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Powell</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elliott</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stribe(?)</ln>
                        <fn>Christopher</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grubb</ln>
                        <fn>Reuben</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Potter</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf>(col'd)</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burkholder</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoffman</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Kim</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>Amos A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coons</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Junkins</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rindersmith</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elliott</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brinly</ln>
                        <fn>Noah A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Vicky</ln>
                        <fn>Edward A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoubs</ln>
                        <fn>Martin L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bear</ln>
                        <fn>David W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Culbertson</ln>
                        <fn>James P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>W. H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamman</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolff</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Vitty</ln>
                        <fn>R. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nesbett</ln>
                        <fn>James A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shearer</ln>
                        <fn>Jonathan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>French</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eckenrode</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Haines</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roller</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Junkins</ln>
                        <fn>James S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Piper</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Obediah</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vansyock</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harvy</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Cartney</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Struble</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flack</ln>
                        <fn>John E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garton</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stake</ln>
                        <fn>Porter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Simon W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shearer</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kuhn</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harvey</ln>
                        <fn>M. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Conner</ln>
                        <fn>Barnabas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parson</ln>
                        <fn>F. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Saylor</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stake</ln>
                        <fn>A. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn>R. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shearer</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zeigler</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stanford</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Neil</ln>
                        <fn>Amos</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zimmerman</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLean</ln>
                        <fn>Gilbert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vansyoc</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Logan</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peiper</ln>
                        <fn>Solomon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Slaymaker</ln>
                        <fn>James D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Arnold</ln>
                        <fn>Nicholas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elder</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hudson</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf>(col'd)</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shields</ln>
                        <fn>Augustus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richenbach</ln>
                        <fn>Barnhart</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamman</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doyle</ln>
                        <fn>Dominick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn>R. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLaughlin</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Butts</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elder</ln>
                        <fn>James F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fagan</ln>
                        <fn>William Penn</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hockenberry</ln>
                        <fn>John S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Genaver</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elder</ln>
                        <fn>A. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Long</ln>
                        <fn>A. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donnelly</ln>
                        <fn>W. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Culbertson</ln>
                        <fn>B. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Evitts</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wallace</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doyle</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harvey</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLean</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ross</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fordney</ln>
                        <fn>Solomon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Henry C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fagan</ln>
                        <fn>William S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Jeremiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>Henry D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carter</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf>(col'd)</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hockenberry</ln>
                        <fn>Morrow</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Everett</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stover</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sechrist</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gill</ln>
                        <fn>W. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sweeny</ln>
                        <fn>Lucius R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garver</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ott</ln>
                        <fn>Jeremiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lehman</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reamer</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf>(col'd)</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bittinger</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shank</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fauble</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hull</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Freishour</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pugh</ln>
                        <fn>Bartly</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Evans</ln>
                        <fn>Barnet</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf>(col'd)</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fraker</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Picking</ln>
                        <fn>B. V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Poe</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reiser</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reiser</ln>
                        <fn>Jeremiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McAleer</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillan</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Oyer</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coll</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stizell</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ault</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Andrews</ln>
                        <fn>Robert B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Upperman</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kay</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunter</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palmer</ln>
                        <fn>Joshua</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strock</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hull</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGowan</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shettern</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strike</ln>
                        <fn>Reuben</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Diehl</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Steppler</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rife</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf>of J</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rosenbery</ln>
                        <fn>Keefer</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kauffman</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Speck</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Belts</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Root</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lingle</ln>
                        <fn>Christian</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shrader</ln>
                        <fn>Michael P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoner</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Slyder</ln>
                        <fn>James S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huber</ln>
                        <fn>Felix S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trayer</ln>
                        <fn>Adam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mear</ln>
                        <fn>Jeremiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Byers</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lane</ln>
                        <fn>William C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keefer</ln>
                        <fn>Moses J. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sleichter</ln>
                        <fn>Jere</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Byers</ln>
                        <fn>David S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sell</ln>
                        <fn>John R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gipe</ln>
                        <fn>Levi</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cramer</ln>
                        <fn>George G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mowry</ln>
                        <fn>George H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robuck</ln>
                        <fn>Abram</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hollar</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pumroy</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cashman</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gipe</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spear</ln>
                        <fn>John D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allaman</ln>
                        <fn>Leman</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dehaven</ln>
                        <fn>David S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Saltsman</ln>
                        <fn>Henry M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Worley</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heywood</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nead</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>John D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gamble</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolff</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Curdy</ln>
                        <fn>Anthony K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kegreis</ln>
                        <fn>M. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cowan</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyer</ln>
                        <fn>Elias</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guyer</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Steward</ln>
                        <fn>David D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brenize</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heeter</ln>
                        <fn>John F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Laughlin</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hasting</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kegreis</ln>
                        <fn>P. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gracey</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kent</ln>
                        <fn>Alfred</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kegreis</ln>
                        <fn>M. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>William M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rosenberry</ln>
                        <fn>Levi</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Williams</ln>
                        <fn>Robt</fn>
                        <sf>(col'd)</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Malone</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>West</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kyle</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gaukly</ln>
                        <fn>Aaron</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Montgomery</ln>
                        <fn>James C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ile</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>James B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richards</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Conrad</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyd</ln>
                        <fn>Robert J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strock</ln>
                        <fn>H. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blair</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn>Henry M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duffield</ln>
                        <fn>James B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Angle</ln>
                        <fn>H. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Felkill</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf>(col'd)</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lowebaker</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christy</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf>(col'd)</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eichelberger</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reisner</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dick</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heagy</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf>(col'd)</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitmore</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hornbreaker</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewer</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zimmerman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoffer</ln>
                        <fn>David B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bushey</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elliott</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carson</ln>
                        <fn>Mitchell</fn>
                        <sf>(col'd)</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hite</ln>
                        <fn>Top</fn>
                        <sf>(col'd)</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gutshaw</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bradley</ln>
                        <fn>John J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elliott</ln>
                        <fn>Maxwell</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brubaker</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Drury</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Christ</fn>
                        <sf>of John</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Laughlin</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cooper</ln>
                        <fn>R. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoner</ln>
                        <fn>Archibald</fn>
                        <sf>(col'd)</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Briggs</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wells</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf>(col'd)</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>There is a table showing the quotas of the several sub-districts of
                    Franklin County and a list of the men drafted, which is 50 percent more than the
                    deficiency. Antrim Township had 375 enrolled, a deficiency of 45, and 68 men
                    drafted: Simon Shank, Joseph Stoner, Wash Hellman, Henry Barnhart, David Good,
                    John M. Alexander, Daniel Saylor, Samuel L. Bratz (col'd), Joseph A. Loose,
                    George Gearhart, Samuel Wyant, Henry Ruthrauff, John Grove of Jacob, Fred
                    Gearhart, David Tolhelm, John Miller, John Gorman, Jacob Loy, Jacob G. Shoaff,
                    Philip Mordorff, Hezekiah Garven, Jacob Lear, Richard Briggs (col'd), David
                    Stoner, Henry Walk, Francis T. Horner, Jacob Dixon, John L. Latshaw, Hugh D.
                    Lindsay, Daniel Gordon, Jacob Welsh, Daniel Frovinger, Jacob Wolff, George
                    Wistar of Jacob, Jeremiah Weagley, John H. Renicker, Carlisle Kuhn, John
                    Helfrick, Fred Martin, Samuel Miller, Amos Stouffer, Joseph Snively Jr., Luchen
                    Brenner, Aaron Ward, John Anderson (col'd), John F. Miller, Francis Gearhart,
                    Turner Jordon (col'd), Henry Rummel, George Nelson (col'd), Hiram Byers, Levi
                    Poper, John Conley, James H. Martin, Jacob Kelker, John Burns, C. Royer Jr.,
                    George Middower, David Young, Daniel Hickus, J. Hokelander, Samuel Powell,
                    Alexander S. Elliott, Christopher Stribe (?), Reuben Grubb, R. Potter (col'd),
                    George Burkholder, Jacob Hoffman. Fannett Township had 222 enrolled, a
                    deficiency of 58 and 87 names drawn in the draft: John M'Kim, Amos A. Skinner,
                    Jacob Coons, Samuel Junkins, John A. Rindersmith, William Elliott, Noah A.
                    Brinly, Edward A. M'Vicky, Martin L. Stoubs, David W. Bear, James P. Culbertson,
                    James Crawford, W. H. H. Wilson, Martin Hamman, David Wolff, R. C. M'Vitty,
                    James A. Nesbett, Jonathan Shearer, Joseph French, Joseph Eckenrode, Jacob
                    Haines, Jacob Roller, James S. Junkins, Frank Piper, John Obediah, Benjamin
                    Vansyock, John A. Harvy, William M'Cartney, George Struble, John E. Flack,
                    Samuel H. Wilson, Thomas B. Garton, Porter Stake, Simon W. Miller, John M.
                    Shearer, John Kuhn, M. K. Harvey, Barnabas Conner, John A. Skinner, F. A.
                    Parson, James Saylor, A. W. Stake, R. B. Campbell, J. H. Shearer, Jacob Zeigler,
                    George Stanford, Henry McClure, Amos Neil, Daniel Zimmerman, Gilbert McLean,
                    Samuel Vansyoc, Andrew J. Logan, Solomon Peiper, James D. Slaymaker, Nicholas
                    Arnold, David Elder, James W. Skinner, Henry Hudson (col'd), Augustus Shields,
                    Barnhart Richenbach, Daniel D. Hamman, Dominick Doyle, R. J. Campbell, John
                    McLaughlin, William Butts, James F. Elder, William Penn Fagan, John S.
                    Hockenberry, John A. Genaver, A. M. Elder, A. D. Long, W. M. Donnelly, B. J.
                    Culbertson, John Evitts, Hugh Wallace, James Doyle, Robert Harvey, John A.
                    McLean, Thomas Ross, Solomon Fordney, Henry C. Miller, William S. Fagan,
                    Jeremiah Miller, Henry D. Skinner, Joseph Carter (col'd), Morrow Hockenberry,
                    John W. Everett. 288 have enrolled in Green township, with a deficiency of 8, so
                    twelve names were drawn: Henry Stover, Jacob B. Cook, Isaac Sechrist, W. B.
                    Gill, Lucius R. Sweeny, John Garver, Jeremiah Ott, Daniel Lehman, John Reamer
                    (col'd), John Grove, Jacob F. Bittinger, John Shank. In Hamilton township, 131
                    have enrolled, there is a deficiency of 20, so 30 names have been drawn for the
                    draft: Henry Fauble, Samuel Hull, Henry Freishour, Bartly Pugh, Barnet Evans,
                    John Newman (col'd), Andrew Fraker, B. V. Picking, Charles Brown, Samuel Poe,
                    Henry Reiser, Jeremiah Reiser, James McAleer, Samuel H. Gillan, Joseph G. Oyer,
                    Henry Cell, Daniel Stizell, John Ault, Robert B. Andrews, Isaac Upperman, James
                    Kay, Charles Hunter, Joshua Palmer, Daniel Strock, John Hull, Joseph McGowan,
                    William Shettern, Reuben Strike, Michael Diehl, William Steppler. In Letterkenny
                    Township, 196 men have enrolled, there is a deficiency of 16, and 24 names have
                    been drawn: John Rife of J, Keefer Rosenbery, Jacob H. Kauffman, George Speck,
                    Jacob Belts, John W. Root, Christian Lingle, Michael P. Shrader, Jacob M.
                    Stoner, John H. Carbaugh, James S. Slyder, Felix S. Huber, Adam Trayer, Jeremiah
                    Mear, Frederick Byers, William C. Lane, Michael Snyder, Henry Miller, Moses J.
                    G. Keefer, Jere Sleichter, David S. Byers, John R. Sell, Levi Gipe, George G.
                    Cramer. In Lurgan township, 103 men have enrolled, with a deficiency of 7, and
                    11 names to be drawn: George H. Mowry, Abram Robuck, Jacob C. Hollar, Isaac
                    Reed, Andrew A. Pumroy, Jacob S. Cashman, John Gipe, John D. Spear, Leman
                    Allaman, David S. Dehaven, Henry M. Saltsman. In Metal township, 123 men have
                    enrolled, there is a deficiency of 22, and 38 men have been drafted: Peter
                    Worley, Martin Heywood, John H. Walker, John Nead, John D. Jones, Samuel A.
                    Gamble, James Wolff, Anthony K. M'Curdy, M. C. Kegreis, John Cowan, Elias Eyer,
                    Jacob Guyer, David D. Steward, Andrew Brenize, John F. Heeter, Thomas J.
                    M'Laughlin, William Hasting, P. W. Kegreis, David Gracey, Alfred Kent, M. R.
                    Kegreis, William M. Wilson, Levi Rosenberry, Robt Williams (col'd), Benjamin
                    Malone, George West Jr., John B. Kyle, George Jones, Joseph Miller, Aaron
                    Gaukly, James C. Montgomery, John Ile, James B. Davis. In Montgomery township,
                    313 men enrolled, leaving a deficiency of 24, so 36 names were drawn: William
                    Richards, Benjamin Conrad, Robert J. Boyd, H. B. Strock, Martin Blair, Henry M.
                    Martin, James B. Duffield, H. B. Angle, David Felkill (col'd), John Lowebaker,
                    George Christy (col'd), Martin Eichelberger, Lewis Reisner, Joseph Dick, Daniel
                    Heagy (col'd), Abraham Whitmore, William Hornbreaker, Jacob Brewer, John
                    Zimmerman, David B. Hoffer, Henry Bushey, George Elliott, Daniel Myers, Mitchell
                    Carson (col'd), Top Hite (col'd), William Gutshaw, John J. Bradley, Maxwell
                    Elliott, Abraham C. Brubaker, William Drury, Christ Myers of John, Daniel
                    M'Laughlin, R. W. Cooper, Archibald Stoner (col'd), Joseph Briggs, David Wells
                    (col'd).</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>The draft list is continued on page 5.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.06.01.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>[The Draft, continued from page 4]</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Afee</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cromer</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snider</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Israel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hill</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dickey</ln>
                        <fn>Seth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Higgins</ln>
                        <fn>Isaiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lowers</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Teeter</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Potter</ln>
                        <fn>H. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brubaker</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kriner</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Lellan</ln>
                        <fn>Robt. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heagy</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rider</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Iser</ln>
                        <fn>Josiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cuff</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf>(col'd)</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rider</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>Edward</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Williams</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoover</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Friner</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Webster</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fulton</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roreabaugh</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rock</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Summers</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hicks</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nunemacher</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>D. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Poe</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zook</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mentzer</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf>of J</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stull</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Summers</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burger</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>West</fn>
                        <sf>(col'd)</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lowry</ln>
                        <fn>Curtis</fn>
                        <sf>of G</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Speelman</ln>
                        <fn>Calvin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Monn</ln>
                        <fn>A. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bittinger</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kine</ln>
                        <fn>Smith</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hellin</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hefner</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Null</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beaver</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Knepper</ln>
                        <fn>George L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bricker</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wertz</ln>
                        <fn>Hiram E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitmore</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf>Sr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lee</ln>
                        <fn>Edward</fn>
                        <sf>(col'd)</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keller</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newcomer</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pfoutz</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kohn</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reamer</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beatty</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shirk</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf>(col'd)</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Geise</ln>
                        <fn>Adam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnston</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Golden</ln>
                        <fn>William C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hull</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf>(col'd)</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hogan</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf>(col'd)</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rudolph</ln>
                        <fn>Val</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilbert</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lucket</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf>(col'd)</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoover</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hollar</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilbert</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garman</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hassler</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ford</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf>(col'd)</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Killinger</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reeside</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rowe</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>John C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kell</ln>
                        <fn>Sol. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Etter</ln>
                        <fn>Josiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn>George C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Starlipper</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shirk</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keefer</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCleary</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peck</ln>
                        <fn>Jerome</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Conner</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gross</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yeakle</ln>
                        <fn>Jonathan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seachrist</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCullough</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fritz</ln>
                        <fn>Leonard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ward</ln>
                        <fn>Aquilla</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thomas</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Jonathan S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>Calvin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shier</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cullar</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phinicie</ln>
                        <fn>William M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zimmerman</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stamy</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kuhns</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bouchet</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Masters</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Delf</ln>
                        <fn>M. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newcomer</ln>
                        <fn>M. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddle</ln>
                        <fn>Henry J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shank</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snowberger</ln>
                        <fn>Elias</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cunningham</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cully</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patton</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jackson</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tracy</ln>
                        <fn>David C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ditch</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mort</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bonebrake</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Oller</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Leashure</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boing</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fnnk[sic]</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hess</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burns</ln>
                        <fn>Morrow</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wiels</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Izer</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoke</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sollenberger</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Goff</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Resh</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Frantz</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lampkins</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cooper</ln>
                        <fn>Jeremiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Butler</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf>(col'd)</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bonner</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>W. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>French</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Philips</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bonebrake</ln>
                        <fn>David S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kline</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lokas</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Overfield</ln>
                        <fn>Patterson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Krebs</ln>
                        <fn>Walter E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Jeremiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zimmerman</ln>
                        <fn>Jeremiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bonebrake</ln>
                        <fn>H. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rohyual</ln>
                        <fn>Charles T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunter</ln>
                        <fn>W. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>Augustus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Honstine</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kuhns</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bakener</ln>
                        <fn>Josiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Forney</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>This is a continuation of the Draft article that started on page four.
                    Mercersburg borough had 105 men enrolled, and a deficiency of 2, so 3 names were
                    drawn: Thomas M'Afee, Michael Cromer, John H. Snider. In Peters township, 241
                    men enrolled, leaving a deficiency of 15, so 23 men were drafted: Israel Brown,
                    John Hill, Seth Dickey, Isaiah Higgins, David Lowers, John Teeter, H. J. Potter,
                    Henry Brubaker, Jacob Kriner, Robt. L. M'Lellan, Henry Heagy, Michael Rider,
                    Josiah Iser, Joseph Cuff (col'd), George Rider, Edward Fisher, William Williams,
                    Michael Hoover, John Friner, John Webster, Joseph Fulton, George Roreabaugh,
                    Thomas Rock. Quincy Township has enrolled 266, and has a deficiency of 18, so 27
                    names were drawn for the draft: Samuel Summers, John Hicks, Benjamin Nunemacher,
                    D. M. Miller, John Poe, John W. Zook, William Mentzer of J, William Stull, John
                    Summers, B. F. Burger, West Patterson (col'd), Curtis Lowry of G, Calvin
                    Speelman, A. S. Monn, Daniel Bittinger, Smith Kine, Daniel Miller, Daniel
                    Hellin, Samuel Hefner, Daniel Thompson, Jacob S. Null, David Beaver, George L.
                    Knepper, Daniel Bricker, Hiram E. Wertz, Peter Whitmore, Sr., Edward Lee
                    (col'd). In St. Thomas township, 163 men were enrolled, leaving a deficiency of
                    3, so 5 names were drawn: David Keller, Joseph Newcomer, Henry Pfoutz, Andrew M.
                    Kohn, Jacob F. Reamer. In Southampton township, 178 men enrolled, and there was
                    a deficiency of 15, so 23 names were drawn: John Beatty, William Shirk (col'd),
                    Adam Geise, Benjamin Johnston, John W. Martin, William C. Golden, John Hull
                    (col'd), Charles Hogan (col'd), Val Rudolph, Samuel Gilbert, George Lucket
                    (col'd), Samuel Hoover, David Hollar, Daniel F. Gilbert, David Garman, Michael
                    Hassler, Benjamin Ford (col'd), J. Killinger, William Reeside, John Rowe, John
                    C. Hays, Sol. D. Kell, Josiah Etter. In Warren township, 65 men enrolled, there
                    was a deficiency of 14, and 21 names were drawn: George C. Martin, Jacob
                    Starlipper, Jacob Myers Jr., Henry Shirk, Peter Keefer, George McCleary, Jerome
                    Peck, James Conner, John Gross, Jonathan Yeakle, Samuel Seachrist, J. C.
                    McCullough, Leonard Fritz, Aquilla Ward, Henry Thomas, Jonathan S. Myers, Calvin
                    Cook, David Shier, Abraham Cullar, William M. Phinicie, Jacob Zimmerman.
                    Washington township has 242 enrolled men and a deficiency of 22, so 33 names
                    were drawn: Abraham Stamy, W. S. Kuhns, Joseph Bouchet, Henry Masters, W. H.
                    Brown, M. F. Delf, Lewis F. Beard, Samuel H. Brown, M. S. Newcomer, Henry J.
                    Waddle, John Shank, Elias Snowberger, Thomas Cunningham, John H. Cully, W. H.
                    Patton, Charles Jackson, David C. Tracy, Lewis Ditch, William Mort, Daniel
                    Bonebrake, John Oller, Daniel Leashure, Daniel J. Boing, Jacob S. Fnnk [sic]
                    John Hess, Morrow Burns, John Wiels, David Izer, John Hoke, John Sollenberger,
                    B. F. Goff, Daniel Resh, Benjamin Frantz. In Waynesboro' borough, 138 men have
                    enrolled, leaving a deficiency of 15, so 23 names were drawn for the draft:
                    Benjamin Lampkins, Jeremiah Cooper, Thomas Butler (col'd), James Bonner, W. G.
                    Smith, W. H. French, Henry Bell, John Philips, David S. Bonebrake, John Kline,
                    William Lokas, Patterson Overfield, Walter E. Krebs, Jeremiah Miller, Jeremiah
                    Zimmerman, H. S. Bonebrake, Charles T. Rohyual, W. B. Hunter, Augustus Fisher,
                    George Honstine, Samuel Kuhns, Josiah Bakener, Jacob H. Forney. The schedule for
                    when and where the Board will sit and make the draft, hear claims for exemption
                    and receive commutation money and substitutes, is given after the list of men
                    drafted.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Another Supposed Spy Captured</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Funk</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Winchester</ln>
                        <fn>Mordaunt</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jacob M. Funk, of Mercersburg, "who has been devoting his attention
                    recently to the arrest of deserters," accosted a suspicious-looking man on South
                    Mountain. Funk was convinced that the man, who identified himself as Mordaunt
                    Winchester of Frederick, Maryland, was a spy, and took him to Sheriff Eyster.
                    Winchester appears to have been on a "tour of observation" for some time, and
                    might have been trying to find his way back to Virginia when he was captured.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Broke Jail</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"They had been locked inside of the Jail building in the evening, and when
                    they supposed the Sheriff to be out, they asked for a bucket of water. When the
                    servant girl opened the door to hand in the water, they struck the girl on the
                    arm with a stick, and rushed out of the Jail and made their escape."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On Wednesday night of last week, six prisoners effected their escape from the
                        Jail in this place. Their names are--Mac. Hamilton, (colored) awaiting trial
                        for murder, and John Helurg, Co. M, 22d Penna. Cavalry; Wm. Van Dyke, Jacob
                        Van Dyke, and Jacob H. Coons, of Co. B, 5th New York Artillery, and William
                        Sissom Co. G, 120th New York Vols.,--all arrested by the Provost Marshal as
                        deserters. They had been locked inside of the Jail building in the evening,
                        and when they supposed the Sheriff to be out, they asked for a bucket of
                        water. When the servant girl opened the door to hand in the water, they
                        struck the girl on the arm with a stick, and rushed out of the Jail and made
                        their escape. On Saturday morning last the negro returned to the Jail
                        voluntarily and gave himself up. What his motive was for doing so, can
                        scarcely be conjectured, as he is imprisoned on a charge that will demand
                        his life if he is found guilty. He reports that he left the deserters in
                        Amberson's Valley. Any citizen is entitled to a reward of $30 for the arrest
                        of a deserter, and we doubt not that the citizens of the Valley can, with a
                        little strategy, gather most of these deserters up. We learn that Capt.
                        Eyster has placed a special guard about the Jail to prevent the escape of
                        deserters and military prisoners hereafter.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamilton</ln>
                        <fn>Mac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Helurg</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Van Dyke</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Van Dyke</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coons</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sissom</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mac Hamilton, a "colored" man awaiting trial for murder, and five men
                    arrested as deserters--John Helurg of Co. M, 22nd Pennsylvania Cavalry, William
                    Van Dyke, Jacob Van Dyke, and Jacob H. Coons, all of Co. B, 5th New York
                    Artillery, and William Sissom of Co. G, 120th New York Vols.--escaped from the
                    Chambersburg jail last Wednesday. They asked for a pail of water, and struck the
                    girl who delivered it when she opened the door, rushing past her and making
                    their escape. Hamilton returned to the jail voluntarily on Saturday (a move the
                    author of the article cannot fathom, because Hamilton will die if he is found
                    guilty as charged). Hamilton reported that he had left the deserters in
                    Amberson's Valley, and citizens are urged to capture them and claim the $30.00
                    reward offered for the arrest of any deserter.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Special Court</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Piper</ln>
                        <fn>Polly</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dyarman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dyarman</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reilly</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharpe</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nill</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kimmell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewer</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Aughinbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Adam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Branthaver</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Branthaver</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beaver</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thomas</ln>
                        <fn>K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillespie</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stenger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Graham</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paxton</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A special term of the Court of Common Pleas was held by Judge Graham of
                    Carlisle, with Associates Carson and Paxton. Three cases were "disposed of"
                    before Judge Graham adjourned the court due to the extreme illness of Judge
                    Nill. Judges Reilly, Sharpe, Kennedy, Kimmell, Brewer, Orr, Clarke, and Stenger
                    were also present. Polly Piper won her case against Dyarman and his wife
                    Catharine, and was awarded $300.00; Adam Aughinbaugh won his case against Samuel
                    Branthaver and Michael Reed, executors of George Branthaver, dec'd, and gained
                    $25.00; and John Beaver et al won six cents in damages against K. Thomas and
                    Thomas L. Gillespie.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Identified</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dix</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamilton</ln>
                        <fn>Mac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>"The man who was founded murdered in Gabby's lime-kiln last fall, and for
                    which a negro named Mac Hamilton is now awaiting trial, has been identified" as
                    William Dix, a deserter from the 15th New York Cavalry.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Killed and Wounded</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowman</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowman</ln>
                        <fn>Calvin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowman</ln>
                        <fn>Franklin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowman</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowman</ln>
                        <fn>Upton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mowen</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>"Mr. David Bowman of this vicinity, says the Waynesboro Record, had four of
                    five sons wounded in the late battles. Calvin, we regret to learn, died from his
                    wounds in Washington. He had been shot in the hand, on the chin and through the
                    left breast. Franklin lost a finger and is now at home on furlough. David was
                    seriously injured from a fall in a charge. Upton had one of his legs broken from
                    a shot in the wilderness and is supposed to be a prisoner. David Mowen [sic], of
                    Waynesboro', was wounded in Sigel's late fight in the Valley, and is now in
                    Martinsburg."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Contribution</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flack</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>"We have received from Mr. George Flack $10 for the Sanitary Commission."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seirer</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carmany</ln>
                        <fn>Kate J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Colestock</ln>
                        <fn>Z. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Henry Seirer, of Chambersburg, married Miss Kate J. Carmany of
                    Mechanicsburg on May 19, 1864. The Rev. Z. A. Colestock performed the ceremony
                    at the bride's mother's residence.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Louchbaum</ln>
                        <fn>Levi</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>Amanda Virginia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Henry</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Levi Louchbaum and Miss Amanda Virginia Baker were married by Rev. S.
                    M'Henry at the residence of the bride's mother, near Fayetteville, on May 17,
                    1864.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blanchard</ln>
                        <fn>Elijah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deem</ln>
                        <fn>Mary C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dyson</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Elijah Blanchard and Miss Mary C. Deem were married by Rev. F. Dyson on May
                    2, 1864.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Graves</ln>
                        <fn>Thaddeus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hull</ln>
                        <fn>Hester E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dyson</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Hester E. Hull, of Chambersburg, married Thaddeus Graves on May 17, 1864.
                    Rev. F. Dyson performed the ceremony.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Coy</ln>
                        <fn>Lynda</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Coy</ln>
                        <fn>Smith V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Coy</ln>
                        <fn>George S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Coy</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Coy</ln>
                        <fn>Louis C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Coy</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Coy</ln>
                        <fn>Rachel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Five children of John A. and Rachel M'Coy, who moved from Cumberland Valley
                    to Clark County, Iowa five years ago, died of spotted fever. On April 8, 1864,
                    George S. died, aged 9 years and 5 months, and Sarah C. died, aged 7 years, 5
                    months, and 18 days. On April 17 Lynda died, aged 2 years, 4 months, and 5 days
                    and Smith V. died, aged 4 years, 4 months, and 5 days. On April 18, Louis C.
                    died, aged 11 years, 6 months, and 9 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Coy</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Coy</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary E. M'Coy, wife of William M'Coy of Clark County, Iowa, died on April
                    2, 1864, aged 31 years, 1 month, and 29 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blair</ln>
                        <fn>James F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blair</ln>
                        <fn>Mary C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blair</ln>
                        <fn>Wilbur F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blair</ln>
                        <fn>Elijah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blair</ln>
                        <fn>Agnes</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Three children of Elijah and Agnes Blair, who moved from Cumberland Valley
                    to Clark County, Iowa five years ago, died of spotted fever. James F. died on
                    March 25, 1864, Mary C. on March 27, and Wilbur F. on April 21.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Currey</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Witherspoon</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Rebecca Currey died at the home of her brother, David Witherspoon, in
                    Guilford township, on May 9, 1864, at the age of 73.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nill</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Hon. James Nill died in Chambersburg on May 27, 1864, at the age of about
                    62 years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.06.01.06">
            <pageNote>Entirely advertisements, with the following headings: Lines of Travel;
                Musical; Dye-Colors; Stoves and Tinware; Boots and Shoes; Drugs, Medicines,
                &amp;c; Dry and Fancy Goods; Books and Stationery; Medical.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.06.01.07">
            <pageNote>Entirely advertisements, with the following headings: Clothing; Insurance;
                Coal, Lumber, &amp;c; Liquors; Agricultural; Trees, Plants and Vines;
                Confectionery, &amp;c; Saddlery, Harness, &amp;c; Hotels;
            Medical.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.06.01.08">
            <pageNote>Includes the summary of war news, the "Political Intelligence" column, and
                advertisements, with the following headings: Seeds; Miscellaneous; Real Estate
                Sales; Financial; Military Notices; Justices of the Peace; Legal Notices;
            Wants.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
