<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1864/pa.fr.fr.1864.11.09">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sally Henninger, 1st pass; Susanna Michele Lee, 2nd pass, 1/16/99</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1864-11-09">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="11">November</month>
            <day norm="09">9</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.11.09.01">
            <pageNote>The page includes advertisements, a poem entitled "Chambersburg by Moonlight,"
                and a story called "The Professor Marrying a Cook."</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.11.09.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Struggle Ended</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"If Gen. McClellan is chosen President of the United States, he has a right
                    to demand the support and cooperation of every citizen in his efforts to
                    administer the government."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The great political struggle of 1864 belongs to history, and few there be who
                        do not rejoice that its passions and prejudices have fulfilled their
                        mission, or at least exhausted their efforts for evil. That their baneful
                        fruits must linger and survive the field of mad strife and phrenzied
                        political hatreds and hopes, is, we fear, but too true; but it is a welcome
                        hour to every faithful man that closes the contest and bids the conflicting
                        host to retire and yield the victory to those who have won it.</p>
                    <p>Never before have we struggled through a National contest with such a sense
                        of responsibility, and with such mingled hopes and fears, as in the one just
                        closed. We had no idols to consecrate with power; no shrine of personal
                        devotion that called out a Nation's overflowing love and enthusiasm, such as
                        wept in the train of the tall white plume of Harry Clary. Men and
                        men-worshippers were dwarfed in the colossal issues of the conflict, and
                        they faded into insignificance as a mighty Nationality struggled with deadly
                        treason in the field and subtle treachery at home, for its own life.
                        Candidates were but the representatives of ideas, around whom gathered their
                        supporters often with sullen, earnest, tireless effort rather than the
                        hearty shouts which have usually made the welkin ring in Presidential
                        contests.</p>
                    <p>Passion deepened into prejudice--prejudice into implacable hatred even of a
                        beneficent government; and there were thousands upon thousands who were
                        insensibly led, step by step, until they mourned our country's triumphs and
                        rejoiced at its misfortunes. Clouded by intensified political inclinations,
                        they forgot the holy duty of the citizen to law and order, and lawlessness
                        sprang million-tongued from one side of the contending lines, and spread the
                        seeds of anarchy among friend and foe. On the side of the Democratic party
                        there was an habitual teaching of disregard for law--a constant wearing out
                        of the sanctity with which all have been taught to regard it in better days;
                        and it culminated in thousands of skulking conscripts who, forgetful of
                        honor, shame and country, turn upon their own homes, upon their house-hold
                        gods and upon their Nationality, and peril the last hope of Free Government
                        by their perfidy. Equally, earnestly and persistently were the people taught
                        that our taxes are but needless oppression; that our debt but the fruits of
                        remorseless tyranny, and that the calls for troops to strengthen our brave
                        armies in the field, are but the steady strides of a grasping usurpation;
                        and resistance even to revolution was counseled, either in spirit or in
                        fact, until the last refuge of a free people--the majesty of law--was
                        threatened in the very house of its friends. Could such elements in a
                        National struggle fail to be fruitful or evil? Not alone within their own
                        chequered ranks did it lessen the sanctity for law; but its pestiferous
                        breath spread like a deadly miasma over friend and foe, and aimed at the
                        very vitals of the life of the Republic.</p>
                    <p>We write without knowledge as to the result of the great contest. We hope to
                        record in these columns the re-election of President Lincoln by a decisive
                        majority, but improbable as it is, a different result is remotely possible,
                        and we would have all men, of whatever political persuasion, prepare to
                        leave passion and lawlessness on the field so desperately contested, and
                        make common cause for the preservation of the government. If Gen. M'Clellan
                        is chosen President of the United States, he has a right to demand the
                        support and co-operation of every citizen in his effort to administer the
                        government. As its constitutional head, we should sustain him in all things
                        looking to the safety of our institutions. We should differ with him
                        doubtless in many of his measures and council against his policy; but
                        looking as we do to the majesty of law as the only safety to person,
                        property and our institutions, we should seek to strengthen rather than
                        weaken his power so long as he stood firmly for maintaining the unity of the
                        States and overthrowing treason. And equally sacred is the duty imposed upon
                        the opponents of Mr. Lincoln if he is our Chief Magistrate, chosen in
                        conformity with our laws. Mere political differences cannot justify an open,
                        desperate effort to defeat the measures of the government in a deadly
                        conflict with traitors. He who assumes that he is the best judge of what
                        measures the government should adopt to preserve it, and refuse assent or
                        support to any other, is himself either deceived or purposely faithless to
                        his country; and whatever may be the political affinities, of our chosen
                        rulers, let them be sustained with one voice until treason is overthrown,
                        and an honorable and enduring peace gained for ourselves and posterity. We
                        hope indeed that the torrent of partizan prejudice has spent its fury, and
                        that henceforth we shall make common cause to rescue the Republic from its
                        relentless foes, and give speedy and decisive triumph to Liberty and
                    Law!</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Repository describes the struggle between the Democrats and the Union
                    parties in the 1864 elections. In the improbable case of Democratic victory in
                    the presidency, the paper pledges to support McClellan as long as he maintains
                    the unity of the United States and overthrows treason.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Bold But Fruitless Fraud</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coffroth</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>General</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koontz</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>General</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Repository reveals that the Democratic judges' efforts to nullify army
                    votes did not work. Koontz defeated the Democratic candidate Coffroth.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Lawlessness</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Repository discusses the general lawlessness encouraged by the war. The
                    article mentions thievery and murder committed by soldiers and urges citizens to
                    promote harmony .</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Vote For Judge Official</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kimmell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Repository ponders a possible dispute over the election for judge.
                    Kimmell received the majority of the home vote, but the army vote gave King the
                    victory. The editors wonder whether Kimmell will challenge the vote or concede
                    graciously.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors criticize the Valley Spirit's suggestion of another draft to
                    dissuade citizens from voting for the Union presidential ticket. The editors
                    argue that the large number of Copperhead deserters provides the only possible
                    reason for another draft.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Manufacture Of Tar In Pennsylvania</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes the high quality tar manufactured in Cambria, Somerset, and
                    adjoining communities.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Great Central Fair</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Details the amount raised by the Central Fair last June as $1,071,343.30.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>The Republic Lives! President Lincoln Re-elected! Lincoln's Vote Nearly
                    Unanimous! 176 Majority In The Electoral College! The Greatest "Failure" Of The
                    War! The Thunders of the Loyal North!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The popular majority against McClellan will be the largest ever cast
                    against a Presidential Candidate!"</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>A. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Repository publishes the presidential election results from all states
                    except three not yet reported. The paper announces the almost unanimous
                    re-election of Lincoln. The editors describe the events of election night
                    including a speech by A. K. McClure.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>A large number of articles in columns 4 and 5 were illegible because of very
                faint print.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.11.09.03">
            <div type="j">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Court Proceedings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Andrew</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eberly</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Williams</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Troupman</ln>
                        <fn>Philip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hadebaugh</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yeager</ln>
                        <fn>Leonard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Caseman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoner</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>Caleb</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Butler</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weisgarver</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kissecker</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Needy</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitmore</ln>
                        <fn>Ann C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bohn</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heits</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Black</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zellers</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rale</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Philipy</ln>
                        <fn>Mathias</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ashway</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lochbaum</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lambert</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huber</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paxton</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Describes the court proceedings beginning October 31. Judge King, with
                    associates Judges Carson and Paxton, sat on the bench. In Com. vs. J. Andrew for
                    assault and battery (excessively whipping his son) with J. Eberly leading the
                    prosecution, the court found the defendant not guilty and ordered Eberly to pay
                    2/3 of costs of prosecution and Andrews the remaining. In Com. vs. W. Williams
                    for larceny, the court ruled not guilty. In Com. vs. P. Troupman for throwing
                    stones, with J. Hadebaugh as the prosecutor, the court ruled not guilty for the
                    reason of insanity and ordered the defendant sent to poor house. In Com. vs. L.
                    Yeager for assault and battery with J. Caseman as the prosecutor, the court
                    ruled not guilty and ordered each party to pay half the costs. In Com. vs. W.
                    Stoner for assault and battery with J. Harris as the prosecutor, the court ruled
                    guilty. In Com. vs. C. Harris for assault and battery, the court ruled not
                    guilty and ordered each party to pay half the costs. In Com. vs. W. Butler for
                    larceny with J. Weisgarver as the prosecutor, the court ruled guilty. The
                    Repository describes the defendant as "a colored boy about sixteen years of
                    age." The court sent Butler to the House of Refuge. In Com. vs. G. Smith for
                    horse stealing, with J. Kissecker as the prosecutor, the defendant pled guilty
                    and the court sentenced him to two years and nine months in the Eastern
                    Penitentiary. In Com. vs. J. Needy for assault and battery, with A. Whitmore as
                    the prosecutrix, the court ruled guilty and ordered each party to pay half of
                    the costs of prosecution. In the case of Com. vs. W. Stoner for assault and
                    battery, with J. Harris as the prosecutor, the court ruled guilty. In Com. vs.
                    J. Bohn and J. Heits for larceny, with R. Black as the prosecutor, the court
                    ruled guilty and sent the defendants, two orphan boys, to the House of Refuge.
                    In the court of common pleas: M. Zellers vs. J. Rale--Action in Assumpsit, for
                    the Plaintiff (sum is illegible); M. Philipy vs. J. Ashway--Action in Assumpsit,
                    for the Plaintiff of $10.19; A. Lochbaum vs. J. Lambert and J. Huber--Action in
                    Replevin; for the Plaintiff (sum is illegible). The Repository praises King's
                    execution of his office.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Praises Crawford's promotion to major general and provides a history of his
                    heroic efforts in various wars.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Important Order</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Repository reprints General Couch's request that Franklin County
                    citizens scrutinize the large numbers of refugees for potential spies.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>"The Burning Of Chambersburg."</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneck</ln>
                        <fn>B. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seibert</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes that the first edition of B. S. Schneck's "The Burning Of
                    Chambersburg" sold out. Schneck plans a new and enlarged edition. Dr. Seibert
                    writes a condensed German version.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Forney</ln>
                        <fn>C. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces the appointment of C. H. Forney by the Eldership of the Church of
                    God, meeting at Newburg, Cumberland County, on October 26.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lowe</ln>
                        <fn>C. G.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>M. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On October 13, by Rev. Brown, C. Lowe married M. Smith, both of
                    Mercersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hutton</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mahaffy</ln>
                        <fn>Anna M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On September 29, Mr. Hutton married A. Mahaffy, both of Chambersburg. (The
                    reverend's name is illegible.)</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gray</ln>
                        <fn>Mason</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Diggs</ln>
                        <fn>Rachel A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>M. Gray, of Mercersburg, married R. Diggs, of Hagerstown, Maryland.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hall</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lauck</ln>
                        <fn>Mary C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. Hall, of York County, married M. Lauck, of Franklin County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rogers</ln>
                        <fn>S. Emma</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rogers</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rogers</ln>
                        <fn>Matilda</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports the death of the infant daughter of Rogers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>The page includes advertisements. A portion of the page is illegible because
                of faint print.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.11.09.04">
            <pageNote>The page includes advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
