<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1864/pa.fr.fr.1864.06.08">
    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Rachel Onuf</taggerName>
            <tagDate>11/20/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>1st Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1864-06-08">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="06">June</month>
            <day norm="08">8</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.06.08.01">
            <pageNote>In the June 1st issue, the Repository printed the list of the men drafted in
                Franklin County, and this page lists the rest of the men drafted in the 16th
                District--Adams, Bedford, Fulton, and Somerset counties. There is also the latest
                army news, including accounts of Cold Harbor.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.06.08.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Day's March</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <summary>A sentimental tale of a small shy soldier named Joe who gives his last
                    water to his friend Tom and then, asking for a kiss, dies of thirst. Tom takes a
                    chain from his neck as a memento and discovers that "Joe" was really
                    "Josephene."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <summary>"Uneducated persons and even the rudest often succeed in illustration,
                    where the thoughtful and cultivated fail. A striking instance is given us in the
                    case of a negro, whose head was examined by a phrenologist. Said he: 'It am hard
                    to tell what meat is in de smoke-house by puttin' de hand on de roof!'"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>This page includes a poem, entitled, "A Mother's Love," as well as various
                anecdotes, statistics about Union Generals, and resolutions of the Lutheran Synod,
                recently adopted in New York. There are also advertisements, with the following
                headings: Dry and Fancy Goods; Educational; Watches and Jewelry; Medical.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.06.08.03">
            <pageNote>Entirely advertisements, with the following headings: Gutta-Percha Roofing;
                Medical; Groceries, &amp;c; Tobacco and Segars; Physicians; Hardware, Cutlery,
                &amp;c; Forwarding Houses; Attorneys at Law; Pension and Bounty
            Agencies.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.06.08.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Union Party--Its Issues</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"These acts of timidity instead of settling dangerous questions, produced
                    political disorder in all parties, from which we believe have grown up the
                    different factions of fanatics, whose extreme views have hurried on the fearful
                    bloody conflict that has deluged our land. When the gates of Janus were unlocked
                    and thrown open, and three years of fratricidal war like a besom of destruction,
                    have swept their way across the South, desolating the whole land, he was a bold
                    man who ventured to predict a harmonious order of things to be restored from
                    this tempestuous confusion."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It is interesting to observe how most of the leading politicians of our
                        country have failed in their prophecies relative to the position and
                        principles of the Union party during the terrible ordeal now pending. That
                        many prophesies should have been made is not at all singular. In the midst
                        of the life and death struggles, by which, during the last three years
                        densely populated States have confronted each other in bloody battle, and
                        the most peaceful of our citizens have been distracted, it would indeed have
                        been remarkable, if the spirit of prophecy had not become general, and if
                        the signs of the times had not prompted a general prediction of unexampled
                        confusion in our national politics.</p>
                    <p>The leading statesmen of the old Whig and Democratic parties despaired of the
                        perman[en]cy of the Union, and feared the collision of arms between the
                        North and South. In order to avert so sad a calamity, they were on several
                        occasions induced to yield to compromise when the measures then agitating
                        the public mind should have been fearlessly met and settled according to the
                        spirit, if not the letter of the constitution. These acts of timidity
                        instead of settling dangerous questions, produced political disorder in all
                        parties, from which we believe have grown up the different factions of
                        fanatics, whose extreme views have hurried on the fearful bloody conflict
                        that has deluged our land. When the gates of Janus were unlocked and thrown
                        open, and three years of fratricidal war like a besom of destruction, have
                        swept their way across the South, desolating the whole land, he was a bold
                        man who ventured to predict a harmonious order of things to be restored from
                        this tempestuous confusion.</p>
                    <p>How often have our ears been greeted with the intelligence that party lines
                        have been broken up, and that no party organizations were in existence, save
                        and alone for the purpose of vindicating the integrity of the Government and
                        restoring the Union. How often have we been told that the Democratic party
                        was national in its doctrines, conservative in its tendencies, and loyal in
                        its principles, and that whilst the dark cloud of war hung over our national
                        horizon, its power should be exercised for the preservation of National
                        life; and yet in the face of all this, influential journals, the oracles of
                        this party, have been found advocating a disruption of the Union, as the
                        only practicable method of extricating ourselves from the political
                        entanglements by which we have been overcome.</p>
                    <p>In the midst of our troubles the ultra organs of all parties have been busily
                        engaged in exerting their influences and disseminating their pernicious
                        doctrines. It was an easy matter for them to assert their claims to
                        attention and to wield an influence in public opinion for a time. this we
                        have all seen, and all are equally glad that their existence was brief, and
                        their death as sudden as their birth. The decay of factions is the greatest
                        proof of the stability of our government and its institutions. And now since
                        the rebellion has been stripped of its terrors, and the supremacy of the
                        government has been fully vindicated, the landmarks of duty and principle
                        have become more distinct to the minds of all, except those who are
                        constitutionally incapable of seeing.</p>
                    <p>Universal freedom, the light of the Constitution, that beacon of all true
                        American Statesmen, is now more than ever recognized as the guide through
                        our great national difficulties. The eye of the nation is directed to it,
                        and with one voice does the Union party, the party in power, proclaim its
                        advent. It should be a source of gratification to every Republican, every
                        well wisher of the nation, that the doctrines of our party have triumphed
                        through this terrible struggle; that factions have ceased their blatant
                        uproar, and that the Union party has again the opportunity, during the
                        approaching Presidential struggle, of confronting the disloyal elements of
                        the nation, upon the issues of social, political and national
                        aggrandizement. In the merits of our political creed we have full
                        confidence, relying as we do on the amount of truth we can bring to sustain
                        our cause.</p>
                    <p>Let no Union man be persuaded that the principles for which he has all along
                        contended are about to be abandoned by the party during the coming campaign.
                        The destiny of these principles has not yet been completed and to sacrifice
                        any of them at this time, would but be a step backwards and against the
                        interests of our country. The doctrines of the Union party are those of
                        equitable and peaceful progress. Neither by violence nor by stagnation will
                        they ever propose to succeed; but by a firm decided and steady course, amid
                        every variety of political and social circumstances. The institution of
                        slavery must be abolished, and the States in rebellion subdued and brought
                        back to their allegiance, upon the basis of the free States of the North. A
                        good and substantial circulating paper medium must be established. A tariff
                        sufficient to encourage and protect the free labor of the country must be
                        enacted. These are the doctrines of our party, and when we are found untrue
                        to these, untrue to American interests, we shall admit the claims of others
                        to the possession of a purer patriotism. Until then we shall not cease, with
                        all honesty of purpose, to propose for popular acceptance those great
                        measures in defense of which we are now arrayed, and with reference to which
                        we are not divided.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <summary/>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>From the Anderson Cavalry</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"From a private letter addressed to this office, from W. H. H. Newman,
                    of this county, a member of the Anderson Cavalry, at present detailed in the
                    Provost Marshall's Office at Chattanooga, we take the following:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newman</ln>
                        <fn>W. H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A cheery letter from the front, assuring the reader that "no fears need be
                    entertained for the final triumph of the ever victorious Army of the
                    Cumberland."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>This page includes a couple flaming editorials about Loyalty and "treacherous
                partizans," as well as a review of Union Party doctrine and the summary of war news
                and "Political Intelligence" columns.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.06.08.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seiders</ln>
                        <fn>Marian</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reynolds</ln>
                        <fn>Sade</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Culloh</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Kate</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Black</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stenger</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Coy</ln>
                        <fn>V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carlisle</ln>
                        <fn>Emma</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shyrock</ln>
                        <fn>J. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foster</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wunderlich</ln>
                        <fn>D. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stevenson</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mitchell</ln>
                        <fn>William G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fellows</ln>
                        <fn>B. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lane</ln>
                        <fn>S. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Platt</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bert</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lull</ln>
                        <fn>O. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Earley</ln>
                        <fn>T. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clark</ln>
                        <fn>L. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huber</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grier</ln>
                        <fn>J. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDowell</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nixon</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chambers</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chambers</ln>
                        <fn>L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sweringen</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wampler</ln>
                        <fn>Julia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoner</ln>
                        <fn>M. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duncan</ln>
                        <fn>C. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A list of the members of the committees in charge of each department of the
                    upcoming fair to benefit the Christian Commission. Fancy Tables--Misses Marian
                    Seiders, Sade Reynolds, Maggie M'Culloh, Kate Miller, Mary Black, Mrs. William
                    Stenger, Mrs. V. M'Coy, Mrs. Emma Carlisle. Toys and Books--Mrs. J. K. Shyrock,
                    Mrs. J. Foster. Ice Cream--Mrs. D. K. Wunderlich, Miss Maggie Stevenson.
                    Cake--Mrs. William G. Mitchell, Mrs. B. T. Fellows. Candy--Mrs. S. G. Lane, Mrs.
                    George Platt, Miss Sarah Wright, Maj. Bert. Restaurant: Mrs. O. N. Null, Mrs. T.
                    J. Earley, L. S. Clark. Coffee--Mrs. S. Huber, Mrs. J. D. Grier.
                    Strawberry--Mrs. William H. McDowell, Mrs. J. S. Nixon. Floral--Misses M. and L.
                    Chambers, Capt. Sweringen. Silver--Miss Julia Wampler, Mrs. M. J. Stoner.
                    Lemonade--Mr. and Mrs. Kinney, Mrs. C. M. Duncan.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Distressing Intelligence</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyd</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyd</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harmony</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>"Mrs. Colonel Boyd received a telegram from her husband, Col. W. H. Boyd,
                    commanding 21st Pa. Cavalry, dated at Yorktown, announcing that he had been
                    wounded. In what engagement this occurred we are at present unable to say, as we
                    have no intelligence of the whereabouts of the Regiment for some time past. Mrs.
                    Boyd proceeded to Washington on Monday. We have also intelligence of the death
                    of Captain John H. Harmony, of the same Regiment. It is stated that he was
                    killed on Tuesday of last week. His wife received a telegram conveying this
                    statement, yesterday. A telegram from Col. Boyd yesterday, states that he is
                    doing well, and that about forty of the 21st were killed and wounded."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Promotion</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nimmons</ln>
                        <fn>John S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>"Our friend Lieut. John S. Nimmons, of Fannettsburg, and a veteran of three
                    years' service, has been appointed Quarter Master of the 11th Penna. Cavalry. A
                    faithful, modest soldier is Lieut. Nimmons. He fully deserves the honor of which
                    he has been made the recipient."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Mr. John Buxton</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Buxton</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>"Mr. John Buxton, of the 7th Maryland Regiment, Infantry, was among the
                    killed in the eight days' fight in the Wilderness. He was from Hagerstown. For
                    many years he resided in this place, and for a long time was a Baggage Master on
                    the Cumberland Valley Railroad."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <summary>"One hundred and fifty-six dollars have been forwarded to the Sanitary
                    Commission in Philadelphia, the proceeds of a musical entertainment given in
                    Shippensburg, on Saturday evening of last week."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richard</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoner</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rohrer</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Elizabeth Stoner, of Waynesboro, married Jacob Richard, of Washington
                    County, Maryland, on May 24, 1864. The Rev. Joseph F. Rohrer performed the
                    ceremony.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bratten</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rorabaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Garvey</ln>
                        <fn>P.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On May 29, 1864, in St. Thomas, William Bratten married Mrs. Sarah
                    Rorabaugh. P. M'Garvey, also of St. Thomas, performed the ceremony.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Null</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Null died near Quincy on May 22, 1864, aged 21 years, 4 months, and
                    14 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kohn</ln>
                        <fn>Ida Bell</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kohn</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kohn</ln>
                        <fn>Milvinia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Ida Bell Kohn, youngest daughter of Benjamin and Milvinia Kohn, died on May
                    31, 1864, aged 3 years, 6 months, and 18 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bender</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Elizabeth Bender died near Welsh Run on May 23, 1864, aged 35 years, 4
                    months, and 20 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ludwig</ln>
                        <fn>John S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John S. Ludwig died in Chambersburg on June 3, 1864, aged 29 years, 6
                    months, and 23 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chariton</ln>
                        <fn>Annie E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chariton</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chariton</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Annie E. Chariton, daughter of James and Catharine Chariton, formerly of
                    Chambersburg, died at Columbus, Ohio, on May 11, 1864. She was 21 years, 3
                    months, and 11 days old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>This page includes another appeal for donations to the upcoming Ladies Aid
                Society Fair, the Report of the Markets and New Advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.06.08.06">
            <pageNote>Entirely advertisements, with the following headings: Lines of Travel;
                Musical; Dye-Colors; Stoves and Tinware; Confectionery, &amp;c; Drugs,
                Medicines, &amp;c; Boots and Shoes; Dry and Fancy Goods; Medical; Books and
                Stationery.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.06.08.07">
            <pageNote>Entirely advertisements, with the following headings: Clothing; Insurance;
                Coal, Lumber, &amp;c; Liquors; Dentistry; Agricultural; Trees, Plants and Vines;
                Saddlery, Harness, &amp;c; Medical.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.06.08.08">
            <pageNote>Continuation of war news from page one, and advertisements, with the following
                headings: Hats, Caps and Straw Goods; Military Notices; Justices of the Peace; Real
                Estate Sales; Financial; Co-Partnership Notices; Legal Notices; Hotels;
            Seeds.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
