<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1862/pa.fr.vs.1862.01.08">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andrew Morris</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1862-01-08">
            <year>1862</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day norm="08">8</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.01.08.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Remarks of Hon. Thaddeus Stevens</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"I ask this House if they are prepared to add to the burdens their
                    constituents now have upon them, and which they must bear, twenty or thirty
                    million dollars a year more, unless there is some imperative necessary for it? I
                    cannot. Unless such a necessity be shown, I cannot vote for this bill."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stevens</ln>
                        <fn>Thaddeus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Congressman Thaddeus Stevens speaks in opposition to a bill authorizing
                    raising new troops for the defense of Kentucky. Stevens argues that present
                    troop levels are adequate to defend the state, and that further defense
                    authorizations would further increase the deficit caused by the war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Mason and Slidell Given Up</head>
                <origin>National Intelligencer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprints of official correspondence between Secretary of State Seward and
                    British officials regarding the conditions of release of Confederate agents
                    Mason and Slidell.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>This Mason-Slidell article occupies over half of the front page and is
                continued to the next page.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.01.08.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Mason and Slidell Given Up (continued)</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Continuation of reprinted correspondence regarding the Trent affair.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>The Mason-Slidell story occupies 5 out of 6 of the columns on page 2. Also
                includes brief Congressional report.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.01.08.03">
            <pageNote>Fiction and humor</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.01.08.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Imbeciles</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Can any man say that this wicked rebellion is any nearer being crushed out
                    to-day than nine months ago, although millions upon million of dollars have been
                    expended and thousands of valuable lives lost in the unnatural conflict?"</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We ventured to remark, several months ago, that the Administration had shown
                        its entire incompetency to conduct the present war. We regret to be
                        compelled to reiterate this opinion, but the sad experience of every day has
                        not only confirmed it, but demands, in the name of our beloved Union, that
                        the Press of the country speak out and spare not. It is undeniable that
                        every move our army has made has been a blunder, our naval expeditions
                        proved failures, and our battles resulted in defeats; with the exception of
                        the brilliant little affair at Drainsville--the only bright spot in the dark
                        and bloody panorama before us. Can any man say that this wicked rebellion is
                        any nearer being crushed out today than nine months ago, although millions
                        upon millions of dollars have been expended and thousands of valuable lives
                        lost in the unnatural conflict. When this rebellion broke out we had the
                        respect and sympathy of the whole world on our side. We could procure loans
                        of money from the great powers of Europe, and buy up, in their markets, any
                        quantity of munitions of war our country might need. By the bad management
                        of the Administration all these advantages have been upset--we cannot now
                        obtain from Europe a dollar, a cannon, or a pound of saltpetre; and those
                        who we reckoned as friends have been made the allies of our enemies up in
                        arms against us. Canada, our nearest neighbor, that tendered a regiment of
                        lancers to fight in our behalf, have now eighty thousand men who have
                        volunteered to fight against us! We might overlook--nay, despise--all this
                        and still maintain our self-respect and restore the Union, had not the
                        Administration cast a fire-brand among the combustible material in the
                        country by agitating the nigger question in its councils, at a time it had
                        no business there, and thereby driving off its Union friends in the South
                        and border States, and injuriously dividing public sentiment in the North as
                        to the objects of the war. When we add to all this the peculations, and
                        downright robbery, by officials high and low under this Administration, we
                        have a gloomy picture from the contemplation of which every honest and loyal
                        man must turn with horror and dismay. Public opinion is every day demanding
                        in louder and louder tones that this Administration give up the ghost or the
                        Union is irretrievably lost. It has shown its incompetency to conduct the
                        war successfully so far, and gives no promise for any better results in the
                        future. We are not alone in expressing these opinions. Honest Republicans do
                        not hesitate to give vent to the same doubts and fears as to the ability of
                        this Administration to conduct the war. The Philadelphia <emph rend="italic"
                            >Daily News</emph> a rabid Republican paper, says, unless something is
                        done speedily to retrieve it, "<emph rend="italic">the administration of Mr.
                            Lincoln will prove to be the worst failure which the world has ever yet
                            witnessed</emph>." We republish the article from the <emph rend="italic"
                            >Daily News</emph>, of Saturday, which taken in connection with the
                        recent speech of HON. THADDEUS STEVENS, to be found in another part of our
                        paper, on the imbecility in the management of the war, indicates pretty
                        plainly that confidence, in LINCOLN'S Administration, even in its own
                        household, is about expiring. Mr. STEVENS concludes his remarks by begging
                            "<emph rend="italic">for Heaven's sake not to go on piling mountains
                            upon mountains of debt and taxation until the nation itself is destroyed
                            in the operations of this war</emph>." No people can, or will longer
                        stand Millions of Taxes and Hundreds of Millions of Debt without some
                        results for the honor and good of the country to show for it.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Editorial arguing that the Lincoln administration has consistently bungled
                    the prosecution of the war. Because of its incompetence and the mixing in of the
                    "nigger question"--i.e. abolition--the Lincoln administration has alienated
                    potential allies in foreign countries and sympathizers in the border states and
                    the south. The article also cites an article in the Philadelphia Daily News, a
                    Republican paper, questioning the military competence of the administration.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Slave Emancipation--A Precedent</head>
                <origin>Washington (PA) Examiner</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Points to Bacon's Rebellion in Virginia in 1676, where Governor Berkeley
                    freed the slaves of the rebels, as an example of the failure of emancipation to
                    procure military victory--since freeing the slaves did not noticeably alter the
                    course of the rebellion.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Taking Care of Pennsylvania and Her Interests</head>
                <origin>Chicago Tribune</origin>
                <commentary>"Simon Cameron is distinguished for his regard of Pennsylvania and her
                    interests. The latest instance of it we find in the Chicago Tribune, the leading
                    Republican paper of Illinois...."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cameron</ln>
                        <fn>Simon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Article describing contracts given to Pennsylvania firms (by Secretary of
                    War Cameron, the article implies) to supply lumber to Fort Leavenworth,
                    Missouri, though there was abundant lumber to be had on the Missouri River.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Connelsville Railroad!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>A Friend of the Road</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Follows up on the letter of the previous week, urging the construction of
                    the Connelsville Railroad from Gettysburg to Pittsburgh, and an "Air-line"
                    railroad from Gettysburg to Washington, to insure the supply of coal from the
                    west. The author argues that a delegation from Franklin and surrounding counties
                    should go to Washington to lobby for such a route.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Constitution and the Union Must Fall or Stand Together</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"That shows where Mr. Webster would have been found, if he had lived to
                    the present time. He would not belong to that school of politicians who believed
                    that the Union could be saved by destroying the Constitution."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Cites an 1851 speech by Daniel Webster arguing that the Constitution and
                    the Union are inseparable.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Includes miscellaneous war news and Congressional reports.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.01.08.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Camp Slifer</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The men quartered at Camp Slifer left for Camp Curtain, Harrisburg on
                    Tuesday morning, where they will be consolidated with regiments forming there.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Public Library</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heyser</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A meeting of the Public Library Association will be held at the residence
                    of William Heyser Esq. on Friday at 6 p.m.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Presentation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deatrich</ln>
                        <fn>W.H.R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The congregations served by Rev. W.H.R. Deatrich presented him with a horse
                    on New Years' Day.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Clark's Lecture</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The subject was handled in a masterly manner and afforded much
                    gratification to a large and respectable audience."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clark</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Rev. Joseph Clark delivered a lecture on the "History and Theory of
                    Revolutions" and related it to the "Southern Rebellion" at the Franklin Hall on
                    New Year's Eve.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A New Year Gift</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Messersmith</ln>
                        <fn>George R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The teachers of the Lutheran Sunday School presented George R. Messersmith,
                    superintendent of the School, with a Bible and hymnbook as a token of
                    appreciation for his services.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Death of a Soldier</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seiders</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stitzel</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Seiders of Chambersburg, age 19, a member of Capt. Stitzel's
                    company, died of typhoid fever last week at Fortress Monroe and was interred in
                    Chambersburg last Monday. He was a printer by trade.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Hero of Drainesville</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Easton</ln>
                        <fn>Hezekiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Capt. Hezekiah Easton, who distinguished himself at the engagement in
                    Drainesville, stopped in Chambersburg on his way to his home at Loudon and
                    displayed the saddle of a Confederate colonel taken at the battlefield.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Shakespearean</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClintock</ln>
                        <fn>J.B.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>At the request of the Chambersburg Bar, J.B. McClintock, Esq., gave a
                    biographical lecture on Shakespeare at the Court Hall on Friday evening and
                    concluded with recitations from several of Shakespeare's plays.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Cannonading</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The sounds of cannons heard in the valley on Saturday and Sunday were most
                    likely from the rebel shelling of Hancock.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Great Rise of Goods</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Our readers may expect in the future to pay 'war prices' for their store
                    goods."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>For several months past, Cotton Goods and Groceries have been tending upwards
                        in price, till now they have taken a sudden flight of thirty to fifty per
                        ct. Sheetings usually retailed at eight and ten cents cannot now be bought
                        in the cities at wholesale less than fifteen cts per yard, and shilling
                        prints are held at eighteen cents. Dealers in Teas, Coffee and Sugar have
                        withdrawn their stocks from the market waiting for a fancy price, and the
                        prospect is fair that they will eventually get all they choose to ask.
                        Country dealers are obliged to be governed in their sales by the wholesale
                        men of the cities, and our readers must expect in the future to pay "war
                        prices" for their store goods.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Discusses the increase in price of thirty to fifty percent of cotton goods
                    and groceries and implies that dealers in tea, coffee and sugar are withholding
                    their goods to wait for further price increases.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McHenry</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>W.F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>W.F. Smith and Catharine M. Miller, both of Guilford township, were married
                    on December 24 at the home of the bride's mother.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McHenry</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strike</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel R. Strike and Elizabeth Baker, both of Hamilton township, were
                    married on December 26.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McHenry</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henry</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Robert Patterson married Mary Ann Henry on December 26 at the home of the
                    bride's parents in St. Thomas township.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Colestock</ln>
                        <fn>T.A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cormony</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Isaac H. Thompson and Sarah A. Cormony, both of Letterkenny township, were
                    married by T.A. Colestock on December 31.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneck</ln>
                        <fn>B.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rider</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stouffer</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Joseph Rider married Elizabeth Stouffer, youngest daughter of Abraham
                    Stouffer (from near Chambersburg) on January 2.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Colestock</ln>
                        <fn>T.A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Forney</ln>
                        <fn>Emanuel H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dourty</ln>
                        <fn>Barbary C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Emanuel Forney and Barbary Dourty, both of Chambersburg, were married on
                    December 31 by T.A. Colestock.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneck</ln>
                        <fn>B.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kochenour</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hockman</ln>
                        <fn>Barbara</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Kochenour of California married Barbara Hockman, from the vicinity of
                    Chambersburg, on January 2.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deatrich</ln>
                        <fn>W.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heck</ln>
                        <fn>John P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>Charlotte</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John P. Heck of Carroll County, Maryland, was married to Charlotte Johnson
                    of Fayetteville, Pennsylvania on December 31 at the Chambersburg Hotel.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Colestock</ln>
                        <fn>T.A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coldsmith</ln>
                        <fn>Oliver D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burns</ln>
                        <fn>Harriet</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Oliver D. Coldsmith and Harriet Burns, both of Greene township, were
                    married on January 2.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bartels</ln>
                        <fn>A.J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McFarland</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kreighbaum</ln>
                        <fn>Mary A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John H. McFarland of Pittsburgh married Mary A. Kreighbaum of Shippensburg
                    on January 1.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fortna</ln>
                        <fn>Curtis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fortna</ln>
                        <fn>Fanny</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fortna</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Elizabeth Fortna, youngest daughter of Curtis and Fanny Fortna, died on
                    January 2 near Strasburg, aged 12 years, 10 months and 28 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Includes breakdown of party strength in Pennsylvania legislature, story of
                Spanish invasion of Mexico, market information, and advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.01.08.06">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.01.08.07">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.01.08.08">
            <pageNote>Advertisements and repeat of judicial notices from previous week</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
