<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1862/pa.fr.vs.1862.06.11">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andrew Morris</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1862-06-11">
            <year>1862</year>
            <month norm="06">June</month>
            <day>11</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.06.11.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Abolition Schemes of Negro Equality Exposed</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprints a speech in the U.S. House of Representatives by Cong. W. A.
                    Richardson of Illinois on May 19, 1862. In it Richardson cites a number of
                    documents which purport to demonstrate the efforts of the Lincoln administration
                    to place blacks on an equal social and economic footing as whites. Included
                    among these are the provision of rations for "contraband" blacks in Washington
                    D.C., the employment of blacks in D.C. as teamsters (to the exclusion of whites,
                    claims Richardson), and the employment of blacks in the Navy as laborers.
                    Richardson concludes by arguing that the superiority of the white race is a
                    God-given fact, and that any attempt to equalize them has "always degraded the
                    superior race."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.06.11.02">
            <pageNote>Literature</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.06.11.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Party Affiliation</head>
                <origin>Patriot and Union</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that the radical Republicans oppose the stated war goals of
                    "preserving the Constitution as it is and restoring the Union as it was," and
                    that if the Confederates were to surrender, the Republicans would refuse it.
                    This is because, argues the article, the Republicans fear losing power more than
                    they desire the restoration of the Union. The President is being driven toward
                    abolitionism by the need to keep the party together, and the authors argue that
                    he should disregard his party and spare himself embarrassments such as General
                    Hunter's abolition order.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Five columns of classified advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.06.11.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Notice to Subscribers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamsher</ln>
                        <fn>B. Y.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Alerts subscribers that their names are now printed on their papers, along
                    with the date from which they owe money for their subscription to B. Y. Hamsher
                    and Co. Subscriptions are $1.50 per year if paid in six months, and $1.75 if
                    paid thereafter.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Reign of Terror</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt> "Pennsylvania is experiencing another "Reign of Terror." Troopers in the
                    pay of the Federal government--but, to the credit of the President be it spoken,
                    not sent by him on their infamous errand--have been prowling around, cutting
                    down <emph rend="italic">Union Poles</emph> and attempting to murder peaceable
                    citizens." </excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>There was a period in the history of our country which has been very
                        appropriately called the "Reign of Terror." It was during the Presidency of
                        old John Adams, when <emph rend="italic">Federal troopers</emph> were sent
                        through Pennsylvania to chop down the <emph rend="italic">Liberty
                        Poles</emph> erected by the Jefferson Democrats.</p>
                    <p>Pennsylvania is experiencing another "Reign of Terror." Troopers in the pay
                        of the Federal government--but, to the credit of the President be it spoken,
                        not sent by him on their infamous errand--have been prowling around, cutting
                        down <emph rend="italic">Union Poles</emph> and attempting to murder
                        peaceable citizens.</p>
                    <p>We respectfully call the attention of the War Department to the fact that a
                        portion of Horner's Cavalry, led by a Lieutenant or other officer of the
                        company, have chopped down a pole erected expressly to bear the Flag of the
                        Union, and which had borne that flag, though it was not flying at the time
                        when the act was committed. These troopers still further disgraced the
                        uniform they wore, by attempting to murder Mr. Michael Hanstine, the owner
                        of the pole, who carried the "Stars and Stripes" in his hands at the time.</p>
                    <p>These outrages were perpetrated two weeks ago at the town of Waynesboro', in
                        this county. The civilians who participated in them will in due time be
                        looked after by the civil authorities, and it is to be hoped that the
                        troopers will receive their deserts from the War Department. Recent events
                        have proved conclusively that the government can get all the men it needs
                        for the suppression of the rebellion. It can therefore well afford to drum
                        out of its service those who run away from the enemy and exercise their
                        valor only against inoffensive poles and peaceable citizens.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanstine</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A number of Union cavalrymen, under the command of Horner, supposedly
                    chopped down a flagpole bearing a union flag in Waynesboro two weeks ago. These
                    same troopers assaulted the owner of the flagpole, Michael Hanstine. The editors
                    call for these men to be drummed out of the army.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Resolutions of the Lutheran General Synod--Another Test of Loyalty</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"If there is a word or sentence in our article that can be tortured into an
                    impeachment of the loyalty of either the resolutions or the members of the
                    Synod, it must have got there without our knowledge or consent and after the
                    paper left the office. We don't follow the business of impeaching men's
                    loyalty."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Valley Spirit responds to accusations by the Transcript that the
                    Spirit's criticisms of the resolution in support of abolition by the Lutheran
                    General Synod was aimed at impeaching the loyalty of the Synod. The editors
                    claim that their main argument was that the church should not meddle in
                    politics, and not that the Lutherans were disloyal. The Spirit attacks the
                    editor of the Transcript for his inability to discern the difference between the
                    two.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>How the Tribune Cheers Our Brave Troops</head>
                <origin>New York Tribune</origin>
                <commentary>"The whole design and scope of that article was to deprive the soldiers
                    of the Army of the Potomac of their blood-bought laurels, and to cheapen the
                    triumphs of its General because that General is one that the Tribune hates in
                    its heart of hearts...."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprints part of an article from the New York Tribune that declares the
                    battle at Chickahominy Creek outside of Richmond was a warning for the Union.
                    The editors of the Valley Spirit protest what they see as sneering at the
                    efforts of the Union troops and as an attempt to discredit General McClellan.
                    The Tribune admitted that overall the battle was a Union victory, but that it
                    had been poor planning to leave Union positions so exposed. The Valley Spirit
                    argues that the sole reason that the Tribune takes this position is that
                    McClellan is not an abolitionist, and they accuse the Tribune of demoralizing
                    people with that sort of coverage.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.06.11.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Minutes of County Committee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reilly</ln>
                        <fn>Wilson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Democratic County Committee met on May 27 at Montgomery's Hotel. Hon.
                    John Orr was chosen as the Senatorial Delegate, and Hon. Wilson Reilly as the
                    Representative Delegate, to the upcoming Democratic State Convention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Captain Wishart</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"That man must, indeed, be possessed of a mean spirit who would in such a
                    cowardly way rob a fellow soldier of his good name."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wishart</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Housum</ln>
                        <fn>P. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut. Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>This article follows up on one published several weeks ago regarding
                    Captain Wishart's behavior at Shiloh. The earlier editorial had emphasized that
                    Capt. Wishart had left his command unwillingly, when pressed into service as
                    regimental surgeon. In the current editorial, the writer notes that a member of
                    Wishart's company is circulating a letter claiming that Wishart left his post
                    willingly, and the editors print a letter from Lt. Col. P. B. Housum denying the
                    accusation made of Wishart</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Good Move</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"A meeting of citizens was held in the Court House on the 27th ult., for
                    the purpose of devising means for providing for the sick and wounded soldiers
                    who are daily passing through this place."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A meeting of citizens was held in the Court House on the 27th ult., for the
                        purpose of devising means for providing for the sick and wounded soldiers
                        who are daily passing through this place. A committee was appointed,
                        consisting of Capt. J.M. Brown, J.S. Brown, Esq., Mr. Jacob Hoke, B.F. Nead
                        and John Mull, Esqs., to take charge of them, and for that purpose they have
                        secured a large room in the lower part of the Masonic Hall which has been
                        fitted up with beds, &amp;c. Arrangements have been made with one of our
                        Hotel Keepers to furnish their meals. The expenses are to be paid by
                        contributions from our citizens who will, we are sure, as promptly and
                        generously respond to this call as they have to every other for the
                        maintenance and comfort of our brave soldiers.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoke</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nead</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mull</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A meeting of citizens was held at the Court House on May 27 to devise a
                    means of taking care of the sick and wounded soldiers passing through town. A
                    committee consisting of Capt. J. M. Brown, J. S. Brown, Jacob Hoke, B. F. Nead,
                    and John Mull, Esqs. was appointed. They have reserved a large room in the
                    Masonic Hall that has been filled with beds, and arrangements have been made
                    with local hotel keepers to provide meals for the patients. Expenses will be
                    paid by contributions from local citizens, "who will, we are sure, as promptly
                    and generously respond to this call as they have to every other for the
                    maintenance and comfort of our brave soldiers."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Meeting of the Presbytery</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas X.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Carlisle Presbytery met in the Presbyterian Church of Chambersburg on
                    June 3, and "our young friend" Thomas X. Orr was licensed as a preacher. The
                    editors went to listen to his trial sermon and pronounced their satisfaction.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Pennsylvanians at Shiloh</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The only Pennsylvania regiment on the field, it bore without reproach, the
                    banner of the Keystone State through the thickest of the fight, and won for her
                    a wreath which may, with pride, be placed beside those gathered upon the fields
                    of the Revolution in Mexico."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The following letter from Gen. McCook to Gov. Curtin was written soon after
                        the battle of Shiloh. It speaks well of the bravery of the Pennsylvanians in
                        that great battle, and must effectually silence the slanders in which some
                        of our <emph rend="italic">gallant</emph> Home Guards are so apt to indulge
                        in reference to Col. Stumbaugh, and the brave Franklin county boys, who are
                        now earning such proud laurels for our State in the South:</p>
                    <p>H.Q. 2d Division, Army of Ohio. <lb/>Field of Shiloh, Tenn., April 15.</p>
                    <p>Hon A.G. Curtin, Governor of Pennsylvania:</p>
                    <p>Sir: Both justice and inclination prompt me to bring to your notice the
                        bravery, coolness and discipline of the 77th regiment, Pennsylvania
                        Volunteers, (Col. Stumbaugh's) which was a part of the division I had the
                        honor to command in the battle of Shiloh. The only Pennsylvania regiment on
                        the field, it bore without reproach, the banner of the Keystone State
                        through the thickest of the fight, and won for her a wreath which may, with
                        pride, be placed beside those gathered upon the fields of the Revolution in
                        Mexico.</p>
                    <p>I am, sir, very respectfully,</p>
                    <p>Your obedient servant, <lb/>A.M.D. McCook, <lb/>Commanding Second
                    Division.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary/>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>War News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Several columns of war news, beginning with accounts of the "Victory Before
                    Richmond" at the Chickahominy River, as well as several report on the pursuit of
                    Stonewall Jackson's troops through the Shenandoah by Union forces.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Meeting of the Hope Fire Company</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGrath</ln>
                        <fn>A. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shelito</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn>P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snider</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mitchel</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Housholder</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lesher</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Montgomery</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGrath</ln>
                        <fn>A. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fleck</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinsler</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snider</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The following officers were elected at a meeting of the Hope Fire Company:
                    President, A. C. McGrath; Vice President, M. Shelito, P. Grove; Secretary, F.
                    Snider; Chief Director, J. Snider; Chief Engineer, A. Mitchel; Asst. Engineers,
                    H. Smith, P. Grove; Treasurer, W. Eyster; Directors, F. Housholder, J. Lesher,
                    J. Montgomery, A. C. McGrath, A. Fleck, M. Shelito; Standing Committee, W.
                    Eyster, C. Kinsler, A. Snider, B. Cook, P. Grove; Superintendent, A. Snider.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snider</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gabler</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shoemaker</ln>
                        <fn>Violet A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel Gabler of Letterkenny married Violet A. Shoemaker of Roxbury on May
                    27.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dickson</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rife</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brubecker</ln>
                        <fn>Fanny</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jacob Rife and Fanny Brubecker, both of Franklin County, were married on
                    May 5.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Died</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Evens</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Mary Evans of Chambersburg died on June 8 at age 76.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Died</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>John Stoler</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Stoler Cook, son of James and Catharine Cook, died near Mount Hope on
                    June 8, at age 2 years, 8 months and 11 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Died</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lein</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Elizabeth Lein died on May 29 in Hamilton Township at the age of 66
                    years, 5 months and 18 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Died</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Ellen</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary Ellen Brown died on June 1 near Fayetteville, age 3 years, 2 months
                    and 4 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Died</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shew</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Sarah Shew died on June 7 in Hamilton Township at the age of 58 years,
                    7 months and 1 day.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Died</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deihl</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf>Senior</sf>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel Deihl Senior died on June 2 at his residence near Marion at the age
                    of 89 years 9 months and 5 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.06.11.06">
            <pageNote>Literature and classifieds</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.06.11.07">
            <pageNote>Literature and classifieds</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.06.11.08">
            <pageNote>One column of war dispatches from Corinth, five columns of classified
                advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
