<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1862/pa.fr.vs.1862.02.26">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andrew Morris</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1862-02-26">
            <year>1862</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day>26</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.02.26.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>War News--Fort Donelson Victory</head>
                <origin>Chicago Tribune, St. Louis Republican, St. Louis Democrat</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The Federal and Rebel officers fraternize with the best feeling, and the
                    view expressed in my dispatch yesterday, respecting the Union sentiment
                    prevailing among the prisoners here, were much strengthened by subsequent
                    intercourse with them. The remark holds specially true of the Tennessee
                    regiments. The best officers among them are those who yielded to popular madness
                    at the eleventh hour."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Four different accounts of the final day of fighting at Fort Donelson in
                    Tennessee, where Union forces overran a strategic Confederate fort. Several
                    articles discuss the Unionist sympathies of many Confederate soldiers. The paper
                    also reprints the exchange of letters between Confederate General S.B. Buckner,
                    left in charge of Fort Donelson, and Union General U.S. Grant, commander of the
                    troops attacking the fort. Buckner proposes discussion of terms of surrender,
                    and Grant replied that "No terms except an unconditional and immediate surrender
                    can be accepted. I propose to move immediately on your works." Buckner
                    surrenders, though noting Grant's "ungenerous and unchivalrous terms."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>From Washington</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A short paragraph reprinting a letter from Lincoln's cabinet noting that
                    the President is in mourning over the death of a child.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Cheering News From Richmond</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The news of the Fort Donelson surrender had a most disheartening effect in
                    Richmond, but cheered the hopes of the Unionists, who say they want it to be
                    known that they are ready to welcome the old flag and fight for it."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A Union prisoner reports that Union sentiment is strong in Richmond and
                    that the Confederate capital is weakly defended.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Object of the War</head>
                <origin>National Intelligencer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A letter from Amos Kendall to President Lincoln, defending Northern
                    Democrats and attacking abolitionists. He argues that while Northern Democrats
                    were willing to compromise in the interests of peace, once war became inevitable
                    they rallied around President Lincoln's leadership, and will spare no sacrifice
                    to defend the Union. Abolitionists, on the other hand, sought to divert the
                    military strength of the country from a fight to save the Union to a fight to
                    free the slaves.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>5 out of 6 articles are filled with war-related news stories</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.02.26.02">
            <pageNote>Classified advertisements as well as reprint of county financial
            information.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.02.26.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Remarks of Mr. Cox of Ohio, in Defence of Gen. McClellan</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"He said there were hypocrites in religion, quacks in medicine,
                    pettifoggers in law, mushrooms in vegetation .... and military critics in
                    Congress."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Congressman Cox of Ohio replied to Congressman Gurley's criticisms of
                    General McClellan, noting that Gurley, a minister "whose thoughts have been more
                    on the dove than the eagle," was presumptuous in criticizing the military
                    strategy of McClellan. Rumors of McClellan's unpopularity with his troops were
                    unfounded, Cox went on to argue.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Fiction and classified advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.02.26.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Cameron and Wilmot</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"If we took merely a partisan view of this matter, we should be gratified
                    rather than displeased to see this new scheme of CAMERON'S carried out. It would
                    not shock our feelings to see the Republican party commit suicide."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports a rumor that Simon Cameron, former Secretary of War and now envoy
                    to Russia, and Senator David Wilmot, both of Pennsylvania, are discussing
                    switching positions if the Pennsylvania legislature approves. The Valley Spirit
                    on one hand thinks it might be a good idea to rid the country of a troublesome
                    political influence (Wilmot) and to prevent Cameron from tarnishing the
                    country's image through his corruption. But ultimately, even though they think
                    it would embarrass the Republicans, the editors decide that having Cameron in
                    the Senate would be even worse.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Spirit Vindicated</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The true Democracy alarmed at these attempts to overthrow all our
                    fraternal, social and commercial relations with the South, and burning with a
                    patriotic solicitude for the preservation of the Union, and the prosperity and
                    greatness of the whole people, endeavored to repel these delusions and slanders
                    against a portion of our common country which a sectional party seems so bent on
                    destroying."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors refer to a recent exchange in which "would-be Union sliders"
                    took issue with the Valley Spirit's publication of statistics showing the amount
                    of cotton produced in South Carolina--in an effort by the Spirit to argue that
                    the South was of vital economic importance and should be kept in the Union.
                    These opponents disputed the Spirit's statistics, but the editors in this piece
                    produce another report of South Carolina's produce, and use it to argue that the
                    abolitionists are deliberately distorting the truth.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>No Compromise With Traitors</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt> "Well, we got no compromise, and what is the result? We have five thousand
                    traitors now to every single traitor we had when the patriotic Crittenden plead
                    for compromise; and we have a war which, no matter how soon it may end, will
                    leave on our shoulders a debt of at least <emph rend="italic">one thousand
                        millions of dollars</emph>." </excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>This is the cry with which the Republican hungerers and thirsters after
                        plunder put down the Crittenden Compromise. They did not want our troubles
                        settled peaceably, for a peaceable settlement would not have filled their
                        pockets. Well, we got no compromise, and what is the result? We have five
                        thousand traitors now to every single traitor we had when the patriotic
                        Crittenden plead for compromise; and we have a war which, no matter how soon
                        it may end, will leave on our shoulders a debt of at least <emph
                            rend="italic">one thousand millions of dollars</emph>. This is the
                        lowest amount we can escape with. The interest on this debt, at 7.80, the
                        present treasury rate, will be seventy-three millions per annum. If the
                        country is kept together and the Southern States are made to pay their
                        proportion, Pennsylvania will have about one-tenth of this sum to raise--say
                        seven millions of dollars a year. If the South gets off, Pennsylvania will
                        have about one-sixth of it to make up--say twelve millions of dollars a
                        year. Can the people of this State stand the grinding of additional taxes
                        out of them to the amount of twelve millions per annum? Can they pay even
                        seven millions over and above their present State, County, School, Borough
                        and township taxes? We don't see how it is to be done. Perhaps those who
                        would have "no compromise with traitors" can tell us.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors wonder how those who decry any compromise with the South will
                    make up for lost federal tax revenues.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>No Quorum</head>
                <origin>Journal of Commerce</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"If a weary soldier, in the lonesome watches of the night, falls to sleep
                    upon his post, or shrinks from the faithful performance of his duty, he is
                    subjected to severe punishment; but men who hold high and honorable offices,
                    representing the interests of millions of the people, and the performance of
                    whose duties requires no exposure to danger or discomfort, shamefully sleep
                    while the nation is bleeding at every pore...."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that last week the Senate was unable to achieve a quorum with which
                    to conduct its business. The Journal attacks Congress for abandoning the
                    responsibilities of pressing the prosecution of the war and securing the
                    finances of the country.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Georgia Manifesto</head>
                <origin>Patriot and Union</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We believe they will not [spare rebel leaders] when they come to
                    understand that the mission of the army among them is not to interfere with
                    their rights or their property but to restore the rightful authority of the
                    Government."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A recent manifesto in Georgia attempting to steel the resolve of Georgians
                    demonstrates the fear of its authors more than the strength of the Confederacy.
                    When Georgians realize that the object of the war is to preserve the Union and
                    not to interfere with slavery, then they will realize the folly of secession.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.02.26.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Twenty Second</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"One hundred and thirty years have elapsed since the birth of Washington,
                    and the importance of commemorating his natal day, by every suitable evidence of
                    joy and congratulation, never seemed so forcibly felt, or the celebration so
                    generally participated in, as at the present time."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>One hundred and thirty years have elapsed since the birth of Washington, and
                        the importance of commemorating his natal day, by every suitable evidence of
                        joy and congratulation, never seemed so forcibly felt, or the celebration so
                        generally participated in, as at the present time. Every heart appeared
                        warmed anew with patriotic zeal, and fresh determination to merit, maintain
                        and improve the glorious legacy transmitted to his countrymen by the great
                        and good Washington. Our citizens were not behind in celebrating the day in
                        an appropriate manner. A Procession was formed in the Public Square,
                        composed of the Military and Firemen, under the Marshalship of Capt. John
                        Jeffries, which paraded through the principal streets of the town and made a
                        very fine display. The Military company was made up of the three months men
                        under command of Capt. John Doebler. They marched and maneuvered with great
                        regularity and precision, and their firing could not have been surpassed for
                        accuracy and rapidity. The Band accompanied the Procession and discoursed
                        its choicest music along the route. The apparatus of the respective fire
                        companies was decorated in the most tasteful manner with evergreens and
                        flowers. The scenic effect of the Procession was still further increased by
                        a handsome display of flags and Banners. After parading the streets the
                        Procession returned to the Public Square where a beautiful new flag--the
                        Stars and Stripes--was raised on the liberty pole erected in the centre of
                        the Diamond. Washington's Farewell Address was then read in a very
                        impressive manner, by Rev. Harden, to an immense crowd collected in front of
                        the Franklin House. This was followed by an eloquent and patriotic discourse
                        delivered by W.S. Everett, Esq. The programme for the day wound up with some
                        excellent music from the Band, and splendid singing by the ladies on the
                        veranda of the Hotel. In the evening a grand display of Fire Works was given
                        in the Diamond that afforded much gratification to all classes of our
                        citizens. The celebration of the day was conducted by our citizens in a
                        manner becoming freemen who are proud of their liberty and their country,
                        and who glory in the name of WASHINGTON who established for them the best
                        form of government the world ever beheld.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jeffries</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doebler</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harden</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Everett</ln>
                        <fn>W.S.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Describes the events celebrating Washington's Birthday in Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Old Folks Concert</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ayers</ln>
                        <fn>George B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The entertainment given in Franklin Hall last Friday raised $300 for
                    "benevolent purposes." The "Old Folks" of Franklin County dressed up in antique
                    clothing for the concert, and played to "immense" audiences. Special recognition
                    was given to George B. Ayers for his management of the occasion.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Gratifying</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rebaugh</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>An article preceding a letter of thanks from a soldier in the 46th Regiment
                    of Pennsylvania Volunteers for mittens brought by Rev. Rebaugh of Greencastle.
                    The editors had not heard of any boxes being sent to the 46th and ask if this
                    letter is correct.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Sad Casualty</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kuhns</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Isaac Kuhns from near Orrstown died on Saturday "under circumstances of the
                    most distressing character." He was quarrying stone near a lime kiln on Thursday
                    when the embankment fell in and covered him. He was not found until the next
                    morning, but was fatally injured and died soon after. He left a wife and two
                    small children.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Infanticide</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt> "If we keep on at this rate old Herod won't be a circumstance to some of
                    our modern <emph rend="italic">gals</emph> in the matter of slaughtering
                    infants." </excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We learn that another case of supposed infanticide has occurred in this <emph
                            rend="italic">moral</emph> community. A girl residing near the upper end
                        of Main Street gave birth to a child, a few days ago, and deposited it in
                        the vault of the privy. This is becoming a very fashionable way of disposing
                        of these little responsibilities, and unless an example is made of some of
                        the unnatural mothers, we may be shocked by hearing of crimes still more
                        horrible, if that were possible, being committed among us. If we keep on at
                        this rate old Herod won't be a circumstance to some of our modern <emph
                            rend="italic">gals</emph> in the matter of slaughtering infants.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A Chambersburg girl is accused of depositing her newborn child in a privy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>A Good Idea</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"After the Procession passed around town the rag was burnt in the Diamond,
                    and the "Stars and Bars" vanished into smoke in the same manner the
                    "Confederacy" of which it is the insignia is soon bound to disappear."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A feature worthy of note in the Fireman's Procession, on the 22nd inst., was
                        a rebel flag trailing in the dirt, attached to the Hope apparatus. After the
                        Procession passed around town the rag was burnt in the Diamond, and the
                        "Stars and Bars" vanished into smoke in the same manner the "Confederacy" of
                        which it is the insignia is soon bound to disappear.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Firemen in the Washington's Birthday parade dragged a Confederate flag
                    behind them and burned it at the end of the parade.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Democratic Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Democrats of Greene township will meet in Scotland on Saturday March 8
                    to nominate a ticket for the spring election. A meeting will also be held that
                    night in Fayetteville to complete the ticket.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Steck</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fry</ln>
                        <fn>P. Dock</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scheible</ln>
                        <fn>Emma C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scheible</ln>
                        <fn>J. G.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. P. Dock Fry and Emma C. Scheilbe (daughter of J. G. Scheible, Esq.), of
                    Chambersburg, were married on February 19th at the Lutheran Parsonage.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Z?ickarias</ln>
                        <fn>G. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heater</ln>
                        <fn>John F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ebert</ln>
                        <fn>Margarette</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John F. Heater and Margarette Ebert, both from the vicinity of Fanettsberg,
                    were married on February 13.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schlosser</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boggs</ln>
                        <fn>John D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baughman</ln>
                        <fn>Susan E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John D. Boggs and Susan E. Baughman, both of Fayetteville, were married on
                    February 6.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gotwalt</ln>
                        <fn>L. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>O'Neal</ln>
                        <fn>Salisbury</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barny</ln>
                        <fn>Maria</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Salisbury O'Neal and Maria Barny, both of Greenvillage, were married on
                    December 25 at the residence of the bride's aunt.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Good</ln>
                        <fn>D. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hefelman</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rosenberger</ln>
                        <fn>Abigail</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Henry Hefelman and Abigail Rosenberger, both of the vicinity of
                    Chambersburg, were married on February 13 at the home of Rev. D. F. Good.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lindeman</ln>
                        <fn>Casper</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn>J. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Siders</ln>
                        <fn>Martha</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Frantz</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Casper Lindeman and Martha Siders, both from the vicinity of Waynesboro,
                    were married on February 19 at the home of Abraham Frantz, Esq.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flood</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flood</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sarah Elizabeth Flood, "consort" of David Flood, died near Newton Hamilton,
                    Mifflin County, on December 20, age 28 years, 3 months and 7 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Plough</ln>
                        <fn>Hannah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Hannah Plough died in Chambersburg, on January 16th, age 43 years, 2 months
                    and 3 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.02.26.06">
            <pageNote>Classified advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.02.26.07">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Remarks of the Hon. John P. Hale in the Senate of the U.S.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Hon. John P. Hale spoke to the Senate on the subject of the Secretary of
                    the Navy's employment of his brother-in-law for five months at the rate of
                    $70,000. Hale accused Republican senators of hypocrisy, arguing that if it had
                    been a Democratic cabinet member, "the whole vocabulary of Grecian and Roman
                    classical invective would have been exhausted by the Senator from
                    Massachusetts."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.02.26.08">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Late Victories</head>
                <origin>Journal of Commerce</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article argues that on the strength of recent Union victories, and
                    with some evidence of counter-revolution in states like Tennessee, a well-timed
                    appeal from the Administration in the spirit of conciliation may be enough to
                    end the war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
