<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1862/pa.fr.vs.1862.01.29">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andrew Morris</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1862-01-29">
            <year>1862</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day>29</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.01.29.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Abolitionists Preparing to Abandon the Union</head>
                <origin>Patriot and Union</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We have little doubt that such influential men as Sumner, Wilson, and
                    others of like stamp, are again plotting disunion, and that when their plans are
                    ripe for execution they will be developed. Their hearts are not in this war for
                    the Union as it was. They cannot be counted upon. But Democrats and conservative
                    citizens must disregard their disloyal machinations and discourage the first
                    intimations that the Union can in any event be abandoned."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Cites a statement from an anonymous letter that supposedly represents the
                    views of an abolitionist. The article observes, on the basis of the letter, that
                    abolitionists would prefer to stay separate rather than recreating the Union on
                    any terms which accept the institution of slavery. It argues that abolitionists
                    believe that Northern Democrats are trying to engineer such a reunion. The
                    article emphasizes that Northern Democrats are in fact more loyal to the Union
                    than abolitionists are, despite accusations to the contrary.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Victory or Defeat</head>
                <origin>Journal of Commerce</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Victory to be followed by a long and desolating invasion can only be
                    wished for by those who hate slavery and slaveholders more than they love the
                    Union. It becomes the conservative men of the North to stand firm in their
                    principles, and be ready to welcome the first voice of allegiance from the
                    revolted States."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It is useless to attempt concealment or disguise of the fact that the
                        American Republic is approaching the most solemn moment of its history. We
                        all feel it, through the entire nation. The war which has now been nearly a
                        year in progress, must before long assume a more bloody aspect than
                        heretofore, and a half million of men, Americans--brothers, friends--must
                        grasp each others' throats in the conflict. It cannot be many months longer
                        before the dead of the war will be counted by scores of thousands, and the
                        question which has been referred to the arbitrament of the sword, will be in
                        process of settlement by the sword.</p>
                    <p>In view of the rapidity with which great battles are likely to occur, it is
                        eminently proper that the minds of men should be prepared for whatever is
                        before the country. The alternative of victory or defeat is mentioned in a
                        breath, but the results of one or the other are as diverse as human minds
                        can well imagine. We should be prepared to use the former with discretion,
                        and equally prepared to receive the latter with calmness.</p>
                    <p>Never, until now, have the people appreciated the magnitude of the struggle.
                        Unaccustomed to war, they were easily led to think it a matter of quick
                        decision, a little skirmishing, perhaps one great battle, and then one side
                        or the other was to abandon the contest. The present moment admits no such
                        ideas. If the half million men now called into the field are unable to
                        accomplish their work, if the five hundred millions of money already in the
                        war are not productive of success, it is very easy to say that we must raise
                        more men and expend more money, but it is difficult now to foresee what
                        result either increase will produce. If our present armies are defeated, the
                        nations of the world will probably at once recognise our enemies as a
                        nation, and we shall have double the work before us to do which we had when
                        the war commenced.</p>
                    <p>It is, therefore, necessary for the national cause that, in the struggles
                        about to take place, success should be assured. Let no man call for a hasty
                        advance. Let no man blame the Commander-in-Chief for wise and prudent
                        delays. Let every man reflect that the forces have been gathered, the means
                        have been provided, and present success with these men and these means is
                        the business of army and officers.</p>
                    <p>It is most emphatically the duty of every citizen, who has not gone to the
                        war in person, to submit the management of the army to the President and the
                        Commander-in-Chief. All agitation, all attempts to coerce them into
                        particular plans of warfare, or particular lines of "military necessity,"
                        are but disturbing and annoying forces, tending to the injury of the great
                        cause. We have undertaken war, we have raised our armies, and we have chosen
                        our leaders. We owe it to them, and we owe it to our own good sense, and
                        character for national prudence, to forbear all factious opposition to their
                        military plans.</p>
                    <p>A few weeks or a few months will decide the first great campaign. We do not
                        pause to consider what will be the results of defeat to the national cause.
                        We prefer rather to look on what ought to be the results of victory. It is
                        not remotely probable to-day that the Southern leaders or people would
                        accept any settlement of the differences except on the absolute
                        acknowledgement of their independence, and it is hardly probable that they
                        would accept that without also having the slave States, including the
                        District of Columbia, abandoned to their power. But the first great effect
                        of victory in this campaign for us must be considered the final decision of
                        the question of Union. If we are successful the South must abandon its
                        extravagant ideas, and at once yield to the conviction that they are
                        hopeless. We shall not have conquered the South, nor shall we have
                        accomplished the subjugation of the rebellion by victories in Kentucky or on
                        the Potomac. But we shall have settled forever the possibility of the
                        division of the Union.</p>
                    <p>Then follows the effect on Southern minds. If the victorious armies were
                        marching to the desolation of the Southern country, the abolition of slavery
                        and the overthrow of the rights of States, the war would be one of endless
                        duration. We see a remarkable feature of the contest in the fact that in
                        South Carolina, where the people are a unit, they abandon their homes to our
                        invading forces, and retire from our reach as we advance. This sight was
                        hardly ever before witnessed in any war, among civilized nations. It is an
                        indication of what we may expect as the results of victory where the enemy
                        believe us to be invaders for ruin, instead of the armies of a
                        constitutional government. When invasion is for punishment or for mere
                        conquest, every house becomes a fort, every stream a defensible position,
                        and the last intrenchment of the defenders must be reached and taken before
                        the end of the contest is attained. God forbid that such be the course to
                        which we are lead in victory by the principles of our war, or the cries with
                        which we send our men to the field.</p>
                    <p>On the other hand, victory, accompanied as it will be under the present
                        conservative management of Mr. Lincoln, with assurances of faith to the
                        Constitution and its provisions, while it results in settling the question
                        of the dissolution of the Union, may be followed by a speedy termination of
                        the war, if the South is not wholly given over to madness. The Union
                        sentiment, small though it be, may develop itself at once. The impossibility
                        of independence must become manifest to all, and the question will then be
                        asked how far the North designs conquest and interference with State
                        sovereignty. That question, answered by the voice of the conservative masses
                        at the North, East and West, may lead to a sudden revolution in the South,
                        which will overthrow the leaders of the rebellion and restore the power of
                        the Constitution. For such results every good man must earnestly hope.
                        Victory to be followed by a long and desolating invasion can only be wished
                        for by those who hate slavery and slaveholders more than they love the
                        Union. It becomes the conservative men of the North to stand firm in their
                        principles, and be ready to welcome the first voice of allegiance from the
                        revolted States.--<emph rend="italic">Journal of Commerce</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that, with the war nearly a year old, there does not appear to be a
                    speedy solution in sight. However, it warns, the war will be much longer and
                    deadlier if it is prosecuted on the terms of abolitionists, which require
                    emancipation and, in the eyes of this author, a complete surrender of the rights
                    of the state. A more conservative goal would be allowing the South to admit the
                    futility of its cause and working toward a quick reunion.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Also includes general war news.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.01.29.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Indiana Democratic State Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"There was gratifying evidence in the Convention of a willingness to
                    forget former divisions, and to unite for the sake of the Union, upon the
                    conservative and patriotic principles of true Democracy."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprint of selected resolutions passed by the Indiana State Democratic
                    Convention, most of which blame the Republican Party for bringing on the war and
                    for disregarding civil liberties in the prosecution of the war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.01.29.03">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.01.29.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Democracy and The President</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We can never hope to be of one sentiment--expect to subdue the rebellion,
                    or have a peaceful Union, while that question [emancipation] is being agitated.
                    We must put it down, peaceably if we can, forcibly if we must...."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We are glad to perceive that the Democracy, throughout the country are
                        supporting President LINCOLN in the grounds he has taken against the
                        emancipation policy of the Abolitionized portion of his party. The Democracy
                        will stand where they have always stood in regard to this question. They
                        have always opposed abolitionism in every form, and they will do so still
                        without caring whether it meets the approbation of the Republican or any
                        other party. If President LINCOLN sees fit, for the good of the country, to
                        adopt Democratic doctrines, we are with him, and will stand by him until
                        these principles triumph which they assuredly must. They are founded upon
                        constitutional grounds and have nothing whatever to do with the Chicago
                        platform, and if carried out by President LINCOLN, in good faith, will save
                        the country from the horrors which would undeniably be brought upon it by
                        the adoption of the policy recommended by the radical Republicans. The time
                        has fully arrived when something must be done to put a stop to the wild and
                        wicked designs of these crazy fanatics. These enemies of the Union are
                        continually prating about "slavery being the cause of the war"--"slavery
                        must be abolished before the war can stop"--"there can be no Union with
                        slave-holders" &amp;c. Men who talk this way have no regard for the
                        Constitution, and are as bad as armed Secessionists. The Government has no
                        authority to abolish negro-slavery in any State, and were it to do so it
                        would be an act of usurpation, alike despotic in character and ruinous in
                        its consequences. It would destroy the Union at one fell blow. Not a State
                        would be bound by that instrument, because its terms of union would be
                        abrogated. The Constitution is binding upon all, in all its parts, or it is
                        binding upon none. To urge the abolition of slavery by the Government, is,
                        therefore, to urge disunion, to advocate secession, to demand a permanent
                        separation of the States. Men who urge this suicidal policy upon the
                        Government, or defend it before the people, should be marked as
                        disunionists--as aiding and comforting the rebellion--as seeking to involve
                        the country in common anarchy and ruin. They are recreant to every principle
                        of constitutional liberty. Had there not been abolitionists in the North,
                        there would have been no secessionists in the South. It is only the terror
                        of Northern Abolitionism that makes the rebellion the solid column that it
                        now is.</p>
                    <p>The effect of this emancipation scheme upon the North would be most
                        disastrous and plunge us into utter dispair [sic]. We can never hope to be
                        of one sentiment--expect to subdue the rebellion, or have a peaceful Union
                        while that question is being agitated. We must put it down, peaceably if we
                        can, forcibly if we must, or we need not look for unity of action, on the
                        part of the Northern people, now at a time when it is so much needed. The
                        Democracy will never stand to see the Constitution trampled upon by the
                        Abolitionists of the North any more than by the Secessionists of the South.
                        They have shown their readiness to take up arms to subdue one set of
                        traitors and they will as promptly, if needs be, take them up to put down
                        the other. The recent course of the President has given the heartiest
                        satisfaction to the Democracy of the North, and the only other step needed
                        to quell the rebellion is to convince the people of the South that he is in
                        earnest. Every day brings us news that there is a strong Union feeling in
                        the South, and this must be cherished as the only hope of peace and sure
                        foundation upon which the Union can be restored. If the North is flooded
                        with Abolition petitions, and the emancipation of the negroes made the
                        object of the war in the eyes of the Southern people we wipe out the last
                        vestige of Union sentiment in the South. A cotemporary [sic] has well said:
                        "If we wish to stifle the last spark of that latent unionism at the South,
                        that we confidently anticipate will soon burst forth with irresistible
                        power, and consume the precipitators of rebellion; if we wish to convince
                        the Union men that the Government uttered a great lie, when it declared that
                        the object of the war was the suppression of rebellion, and not the
                        emancipation of the slaves; if we wish to falsify the solemn records of
                        Congress; if we wish to unite the Southern people as one man against the
                        Government, and steel their hearts against the North; if we wish to deceive
                        and betray the noble patriots of Kentucky, Tennessee and Missouri, who,
                        relying upon our good faith have taken the field in defence of the
                        Government, and cause their weapons to fall from paralised arms; if we wish
                        to justify the declarations of the rebel leaders that the Government aims at
                        the liberation of the slaves; if we wish to stand before the world as a
                        Nation that broke its word and falsified its promises; and if we wish to see
                        a divided North, a united South and a protracted and hopeless contest, let
                        us take the advice of the abolition enemies of the Government and the Union,
                        by issuing a decree of universal emancipation.["]</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Praises Lincoln for the stand he has taken against abolition, arguing that
                    he is essentially adopting Democratic doctrines. If Lincoln continues on this
                    path, the Valley Spirit argues, he might save the country from the horrors of a
                    radical Republican party in power. The editorial puts the blame for the war on
                    abolitionists, not on slavery, and argues that there is absolutely no
                    constitutional ground for abolition. If abolition were to become a war aim, the
                    editorial concludes, it would invalidate the Congressional declaration of war
                    and would betray the slave-holding Unionist border states. It would also erase
                    any trace of unionist sentiment in the South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Blowing Hot and Cold</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The semi-weakly [italics] makes a feeble effort to 'mollify its outraged
                    Republican friends' for its attempt to fasten on them the disgrace and
                    disloyalty that belongs to the Abolition party."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Pokes fun at the Dispatch for its attempt to defend abolition while
                    simultaneously claiming that the Dispatch's editor is not an abolitionist.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Southern News</head>
                <origin>Norfolk (VA) Day Book, Nashville Banner</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Several articles published by southern newspapers, one accusing northern
                    papers of fabricating stories about the war in order to manipulate the stock
                    market; another exhorting all Southerners to volunteer unless they desire to
                    live under Northern tyranny.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="j">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Court Proceedings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nill</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Winters</ln>
                        <fn>Wash.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLaughlin</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shiffert</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gurion</ln>
                        <fn>Cyrus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McElwaine</ln>
                        <fn>James S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rankin</ln>
                        <fn>A.N.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Banks</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Levi</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Addison</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sellers</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McFerren</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mentzler</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deems</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Perry</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Renfrew</ln>
                        <fn>Harris</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>J.E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McFerran</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Welsh</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Welsh</ln>
                        <fn>Ambrose</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McFerran</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deems</ln>
                        <fn>Israel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deems</ln>
                        <fn>Eliz</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deems</ln>
                        <fn>Mary C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beatly</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kelso</ln>
                        <fn>Chas.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoffman</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kyner</ln>
                        <fn>Eliz</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoner</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shanabrook</ln>
                        <fn>Soloman</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brand</ln>
                        <fn>A. Jackson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shanabrook</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ditzler</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lindsay</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gzell</ln>
                        <fn>Obed</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Little</ln>
                        <fn>Edmund</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rutrauff</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patten</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crooks</ln>
                        <fn>Washington</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rankin</ln>
                        <fn>A.N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Easton</ln>
                        <fn>Hezekiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wertz</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McNulty</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Culbertson</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garver</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garver</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilbert</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heister</ln>
                        <fn>J.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGrath</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brigham</ln>
                        <fn>John G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Neff</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vanderaw</ln>
                        <fn>Adam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hyder</ln>
                        <fn>James S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Long</ln>
                        <fn>Christian</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strine</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Summary of decisions from the county court term that began on Monday. Judge
                    Nill presiding, Judges Orr and Carson on the bench. Quarter Session:
                    Commonwealth v. Wash. Winters--Assault and battery on oath of Mrs. McGlaughlin;
                    verdict, guilty; sentence, three months in county jail. Commonwealth vs. Dr.
                    Shiffert--False Pretenses, on oath of Cyrus Gurion; verdict, not guilty.
                    Commonwealth vs. James S. McElwaine--Assault and Battery on person of son of
                    A.N. Rankin Esq; defendant is a teacher in Chambersburg public school, accused
                    of chastising son of prosecutor with undue severity; verdict, not guilty.
                    Commonwealth vs. William Banks--Assault and Battery, on oath of Levi Miller;
                    verdict, guilty; sentence deferred. Commonwealth v. John Addison (black)--Surety
                    of the Peace, on oath of Henry Sellers (black); case dismissed. Commonwealth vs.
                    Peter McFerren--Larceny, stealing a watch from Mr. Mentzler; case abandoned by
                    Commonwealth. Commonwealth vs. Isaac Deems--Keeping disorderly house; verdict,
                    guilty; sentence, due to extenuating circumstances, since some of disorderly
                    conduct was out of defendant's control, was light, defendant to pay costs of
                    prosecution and serve thirty days in the county jail. Commonwealth vs. Jacob
                    Perry--Adultery, no evidence submitted by Commonwealth, jury directed to render
                    verdict of not guilty. Commonwealth vs. Harris Renfrew--Fornication and
                    Bastardy, on oath of J.E. Myers, entered into security for his appearance next
                    term. Commonwealth vs. Jacob McFerran--Manslaughter; Defendant is charged with
                    stabbing John Welsh in the heart with a dirk knife during a dispute in Tomstown
                    on November 16; defendant claimed that Welsh, a strong, athletic man had seized
                    him by the throat and that he killed Welsh in self-defense; verdict, not guilty.
                    Commonwealth v. Ambrose Welsh--Assault, on oath of Jacob McFerran; Commonwealth
                    v. Ambrose Welsh--Assault, on oath of Samuel McFerran; both this and previous
                    cases submitted to same jury; verdict, not guilty. Commonwealth vs. Israel
                    Deems, Eliz. Deems, Mary C. Deems--Assault and battery, not a true bill,
                    "prosecutrix" Margaret Myers to pay costs; Commonwealth vs. Margaret
                    Myers--Assault and battery, not a true bill, Eliz. Deems to pay costs.
                    Commonwealth vs. James Beatly--Perjury; not a true bill. Commonwealth vs. Chas.
                    Kelso--Fornication and Bastardy, on oath of Eliz. Kyner; case settled.
                    Commonwealth vs. Benjamin Hoffman--Fornication and bastardy on oath of Sarah
                    Stoner; defendant arrested. Common Pleas: Commonwealth ex relation Solomon
                    Shanabrook vs. A. Jackson Brand--Writ of Habeas Corpus, commanding Shanabrook to
                    produce in court son of plaintiff, who is a minor and enlisted in company of
                    defendant without father's knowledge or consent; verdict, Charles Shanabrook
                    ordered to be returned to Captain Brand's company. John Ditzler vs. John
                    Lindsay--recover of $10; verdict for plaintiff. Obed Gzell vs. Edmund
                    Little--action to recover a mare; verdict for plaintiff; John Rutrauff and James
                    Patten, executors of Washington Crooks vs. A.N. Rankin and Hezekiah
                    Easton--action on promissory note for $1841.35, plaintiffs took a non-suit.
                    Imbrie and Grove vs. George Wertz and wife--order to recover necessaries
                    supplied to wife; verdict, $54.61 for plaintiff. Margaret McNulty, Margaret
                    Culbertson, and Eliza Rodgers vs. Jacob Garver, Samuel Garver and James
                    Ery--Action to recover possession of a tract of land in Greene township; verdict
                    for defendants. James Gilbert vs. Dr. J.M. Heister--Action on debt on award of
                    arbitrators; plaintiff suing to recover damages awarded in arbitrated dispute;
                    jury unable to agree and was dismissed. Sheriff McGrath presented deeds for
                    property sold by him: John G. Brigham bought a house and lot in Fayetteville
                    sold as property of Michael Neff; Adam Vandrew for four acres and improvements,
                    sold as property of James S. Hyder; Christian Long for 88 acres in Lurgan, sold
                    as property of Jacob Strine.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.01.29.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>T.B.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The editors call attention to the property being offered for sale by T.B.
                    Kennedy Esq, which they feel is "worthy of the attention of those seeking to
                    purchase a home."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Shattuck's Band</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shattuck</ln>
                        <fn>J.T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The band attached to the 77th Regiment was mustered out of service on
                    January 23; Mr. J.T. Shattuck, the leader, will take the position of second
                    lieutenant in Capt. Derby's company in the 77th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Franklin County</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The valuation of property and taxables in Franklin County was announced.
                    Property was valued at $11,661,656.00; a tax of $30,255.83 was assessed. The
                    population of the county was 42,242 people with 9,816 taxable items.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>York County Lawyer</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kell</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James Kell, Esq, formerly of Chambersburg, has been admitted to practice in
                    York County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Horrible</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Two Irish "trampers" got into a knife fight on Market Street, with the man
                    stabbing the woman; both were sent to jail as vagrants.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Relief for the Soldiers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The sick soldiers from our county are in need of many articles to make
                    them comfortable, and this noble effort to supply their wants so promptly is
                    deserving of all praise."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nixon</ln>
                        <fn>J.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A collection of hospital supplies is being arranged by local women to send
                    to the 77th Pennsylvania Volunteers in Kentucky; contributions may be left at
                    the drug store of J.S. Nixon.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Burglary</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rankin</ln>
                        <fn>A.N.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Burglars entered the home of A.N. Rankin Esq, probably before the family
                    had retired, waited until they were asleep, then made off with $600 in bank
                    notes, taken from a pocketbook in the coat of Mr. Rankin on a chair at the head
                    of his bed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Deserters Caught</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt> "A brace of soldiers were arrested, on Thursday night, by the Night
                    Police, for disorderly conduct at a negro house in the <emph rend="italic"
                        >faubourg de Wolfstown</emph>, and lodged in jail." </excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A brace of soldiers were arrested, on Thursday night, by the Night Police,
                        for disorderly conduct at a negro house in the <emph rend="italic">faubourg
                            de Wolfstown</emph>, and lodged in jail. They turned up to be a couple
                        of deserters from Capt Brand's company. They were taken back to their old
                        quarters at Camp Curtin, and will not likely grant themselves another <emph
                            rend="italic">furlough</emph> to wander about the out-skirts of "Camp
                        Slifer" for some time to come.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Soldiers arrested at an African-American's home for disorderly conduct
                    turned out to be deserters from Captain Brand's company, and were returned to
                    Camp Curtain.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Bank and the Schools</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Points out that the funds supplied by the state to support Franklin County
                    schools ($3,713.67) is about $200 less than what the Bank of Chambersburg pays
                    in state taxes. The editors suggest people should thank the Bank and not the
                    state for the support of the schools.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>What We Buy and What We Sell</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"It will be seen that our exports exceed our imports to a very creditable
                    amount. We are decidedly of the opinion that a glance at these figures must
                    convince the rest of creation, or 'any other man,' that Chambersburg is not a
                    'one-horse town.'"</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>From an examination of a table in the Report of the Cumberland Valley
                        Railroad, for the past year, we find the following set down as the amount of
                        freight carried to and from this place by that route. The following are the
                        items of importation and exportation with their quantity in pounds:</p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell cellspan="2">
                                <emph rend="italic">Imported</emph>
                            </cell>
                            <cell cellspan="2">
                                <emph rend="italic">Exported</emph>
                            </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Dry Goods,</cell>
                            <cell>1,200,400</cell>
                            <cell>Seeds,</cell>
                            <cell>318,100</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Hides,</cell>
                            <cell>176,000</cell>
                            <cell>Hay,</cell>
                            <cell>59,300</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Marble,</cell>
                            <cell>57,500</cell>
                            <cell>Agr'l Prod't,</cell>
                            <cell>251,700</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Iron,</cell>
                            <cell>406,700</cell>
                            <cell>Iron,</cell>
                            <cell>15,700</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Nails,</cell>
                            <cell>228,100</cell>
                            <cell>Leather,</cell>
                            <cell>205,700</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Oysters,</cell>
                            <cell>199,300</cell>
                            <cell>Paper,</cell>
                            <cell>41,300</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Paper,</cell>
                            <cell>15,400</cell>
                            <cell>Bark,</cell>
                            <cell>11,300</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Rags,</cell>
                            <cell>41,600</cell>
                            <cell>Rags,</cell>
                            <cell>54,600</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Salt,</cell>
                            <cell>79,100</cell>
                            <cell>Castings,</cell>
                            <cell>1,301,600</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Fish,</cell>
                            <cell>45,500</cell>
                            <cell>Grain,</cell>
                            <cell>7,752,000</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Bacon,</cell>
                            <cell>54,500</cell>
                            <cell>Pork,</cell>
                            <cell>25,900</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Pig Metal,</cell>
                            <cell>187,000</cell>
                            <cell>Potatoes,</cell>
                            <cell>97,200</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Tobacco,</cell>
                            <cell>40,800</cell>
                            <cell>Straw Paper,</cell>
                            <cell>366,400</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Cement,</cell>
                            <cell>7,100</cell>
                            <cell>Furniture,</cell>
                            <cell>66,000</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Sand &amp; Stone,</cell>
                            <cell>57,100</cell>
                            <cell>Whiskey,</cell>
                            <cell>459,280</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Whiskey,</cell>
                            <cell>143,630</cell>
                            <cell>Flour,</cell>
                            <cell>25,012,584</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Furniture,</cell>
                            <cell>118,110</cell>
                            <cell>Cattle,</cell>
                            <cell>1,113,300</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Plaster,</cell>
                            <cell>1,282,070</cell>
                            <cell>Hogs,</cell>
                            <cell>689,600</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Lumber,</cell>
                            <cell>3,[illegible]5,080</cell>
                            <cell>Sheep,</cell>
                            <cell>205,900</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Coal,</cell>
                            <cell>15,[illegible]6,100</cell>
                            <cell>Lumber,</cell>
                            <cell>76,100</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Bricks,</cell>
                            <cell>13,600</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Agri'l Prod's</cell>
                            <cell>1,039,700</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Total</cell>
                            <cell>80,99-,080</cell>
                            <cell>Total</cell>
                            <cell>38,181,564</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <p>It will be seen that our exports exceed our imports to a very creditable
                        amount. We are decidedly of the opinion that a glance at these figures must
                        convince the rest of creation, or "any other man," that Chambersburg is not
                        a "one-horse town."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A list of imports and exports into the county derived from the records of
                    the Cumberland Valley Railroad from the previous year.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Money From the Soldiers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stewart</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Soldiers from Col. Stumbaugh's regiment have sent a great deal of money
                    home from Kentucky to friends and relatives in Franklin County this week,
                    upwards of $4200. Col. Stumbaugh's law partner, J. Stewart, will distribute the
                    money. The editors encourage soldiers to send money home regularly rather than
                    waste it in camp.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Military Expenses</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A list of money paid to Franklin County individuals and businesses for
                    services rendered the military. Considering the amount of time the soldiers were
                    quartered in Franklin County, the editors claim, the $15,380 paid is a fairly
                    small sum, and does not indicate any sign of wartime profiteering.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sincks</ln>
                        <fn>F.E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>?</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sincks</ln>
                        <fn>Saloma</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George ? and Saloma Sincks, both of Chambersburg, were married on January
                    29.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dittman</ln>
                        <fn>Elmar Vandraw</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dittman</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dittman</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Elmar Vandraw Dittman, son of George and Sarah J. Dittman, died on January
                    21 at the age of 4 months and 5 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richison</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richison</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richison</ln>
                        <fn>Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Margaret Richison, daughter of Isaac and Jane Richison, died on January 7
                    near Spring Run, age 1 year and 3 months.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kirkpatrick</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Alexander Kirkpatrick, age 22 years, 2 months and 5 days, died on January
                    12 near Dry Run.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamsher</ln>
                        <fn>James B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamsher</ln>
                        <fn>B.Y.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamsher</ln>
                        <fn>Mary A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James B. Hamsher, son of B.Y. and Mary A. Hamsher, died last Sunday, age 4
                    years, 9 months and 7 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Also includes a table showing the aggregate tax assessments in Franklin
                County.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.01.29.06">
            <pageNote>Classified advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.01.29.07">
            <pageNote>Classified advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.01.29.08">
            <pageNote>War news and classified advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
