<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1862/pa.fr.vs.1862.06.04">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andrew Morris</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1862-06-04">
            <year>1862</year>
            <month norm="06">June</month>
            <day norm="04">4</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.06.04.01">
            <div type="l">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Letter from Hon. H. B. Wright</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Hendrick B. Wright</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Wright addresses the constituents in his Congressional district to explain
                    his vote against the abolition of slavery in Washington D.C. Apparently he has
                    received protests in the mail, and he was not able to explain his position on
                    the floor because debate was closed on the bill. He opposes making abolition a
                    war aim, arguing that winning the war should be the first and only goal. He then
                    argues against abolition on constitutional grounds, but goes on to say that even
                    if he were to overlook that objection, the fact that the residents of D.C. were
                    not able to vote on the issue troubled him. He adds that the taxation necessary
                    to reimburse owners for freed slaves would also bankrupt the federal government.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Party</head>
                <origin>Louisville Democrat</origin>
                <commentary>"We commend the following article .... to the sober judgement of those
                    Democrats who permitted themselves, under the influence of this most superlative
                    humbug, to be transferred body and soul into the ranks of the abolition
                    republican party.... Read it and tell us what you think of your no-party party."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Accuses Republicans of using the mantle of Northern unity to tar the
                    Democrats with secessionist sympathies and to solidify Republican control of the
                    executive and legislative branches of the federal government.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Patriotism Without "Ifs" or "Buts"</head>
                <origin>Philadelphia Inquirer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Attacks Governor Andrew of Massachusetts for his foot-dragging on supplying
                    additional troops for the conduct of the war. The author accuses him of being
                    half abolitionists and half states-rights secessionist for his insistence that
                    the war aims be adjusted to fit his desires. Andrew's actions compare
                    unfavorably, says the author, to the response of Gov. Curtain of Pennsylvania,
                    Gov. Yates of Illinois, Gov. Morgan of New York, and particularly Gov. Sprague
                    of Rhode Island.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.06.04.02">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.06.04.03">
            <pageNote>Classified advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.06.04.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Democratic Loyalty</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We are not surprised at all to find that these narrow-minded bigots cannot
                    understand the patriotism of the Democratic party."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that it is the Democratic Party that has stood against the opposing
                    pulls of the abolitionists in the Republican party and the secessionists in the
                    South. Despite Republican accusations that Democrats are disloyal, the Democrats
                    actually have higher aims than what the editors see as the narrow, sectional
                    goals of the Republican Party. They remind readers that it was the very same
                    type of people who now make up the Republican party who opposed the war of 1812
                    and who contested Andrew Jackson's opposition to nullification.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>W. H. T. Pauley</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that the Democrats of Greene County are pushing W. H. T. Pauley, a
                    Democratic newspaper editor, for nomination for one of the two state offices
                    open for election this year. As Greene has never asked for a state candidate
                    before, and as Pauley's Democratic credentials are impeccable, the Valley Spirit
                    endorses his nomination for one of the two spots.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>A Few Thoughts for Honest Republicans</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that, at every step of the process leading up to the war, the
                    Democratic party acted in the most patriotic and loyal manner. First, they
                    attempted to settle the dispute amicably. When Fort Sumter was fired upon,
                    Democrats swore their support to the administration they had opposed, and
                    thousands of Democrats volunteered for the army. Instead of acting treasonably,
                    as the Republicans accuse, the Democrats have done whatever is necessary to
                    suppress the rebellion. It is the Republican abolitionists in Congress who are
                    doing more for the rebellion than the Democrats, conclude the editors.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Sentiments of the Union Men of Kentucky</head>
                <origin>Henderson (Kentucky) Weekly Mail</origin>
                <commentary>"What is the real feeling produced by the constant discussion in
                    Congress of the negro question, may be judged by the following extract from the
                    Henderson (Ky.) Weekly Mail, a vigorous and unconditional Union sheet."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Claims that disloyal sentiment is on the rise in Kentucky due to the
                    abolitionist sentiment displayed in Congress.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Hon. Hendrick B. Wright</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Directs the reader's attention to the speech printed on the first page by
                    Hon. Hendrick B. Wright, a Congressman from Luzerne, who opposed the abolition
                    of slavery in Washington, D.C. The editors endorse Wright's position and wonder
                    whether the Republicans would call him a traitor. Wright had just lost a son in
                    service to the Union, and the editors speculate that even this would not be
                    enough for him to prove himself to the Republicans.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>From Gen. Banks' Command</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A report from a May 31 engagement with the Confederate cavalry.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.06.04.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Sick Soldier</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKesson</ln>
                        <fn>S. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Captain McKesson, of Company A of the 77th Reg't Penn. Volunteers, was
                    forced to leave his command on May 15 due to bad health. He started for home,
                    but was not heard from for several weeks until he turned up at a military
                    hospital in St. Louis. McKesson, a Mason and an Odd Fellow, will hopefully find
                    friends who will help supply his needs. The editors note that he is an
                    "esteemed" member of the community, and that all hope for his safe return.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Boomerang</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors relate a story of a number of sick and wounded soldiers who
                    arrived at the depot from Hagerstown on Monday. One soldier claimed that the way
                    to end the war was to hang all the abolitionists, much to the chagrin of the
                    Republicans in the crowd that surrounded them.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Deceased Soldier</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wallace</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George Wallace, a former resident of Greenvillage, died in a military
                    hospital in Cincinnati. His remains were brought home last Monday and interred
                    in the Presbyterian cemetery. Wallace was a member of General Buell's bodyguard
                    and was serving in Tennessee when he fell sick. He was on his way home when he
                    died in Cincinnati.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Recovering</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Housum</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Col. Housum is reported to be recovering well and hopes to rejoin his
                    regiment shortly. Though the editors saw him at George Wallace's funeral, where
                    he still appeared unwell, Housum assured them that he was recovering quickly. He
                    was the only representative of General Buell at Wallace's funeral.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Col. Campbell</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn>Charles T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A telegraph notice informs the editors that Col. Charles T. Campbell was
                    severely wounded in the arm and the leg in the battle near Richmond last
                    Saturday. He was at the White House, unable to be moved.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Stragglers from the Army</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Last Friday a number of cavalrymen came through town, "creating some little
                    stir." They were apparently from the Ira Harris Cavalry of New York and were
                    pursuing deserters from Banks' army, though several of their own number deserted
                    while in Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>War News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Collection of dispatches of the week's war news, leading with the repulsion
                    of the Confederate attack on McClellan's army on the Chickahominy River near
                    Richmond, and including a report from General Banks on his retreat, as well as
                    optimistic reports regarding the probability of the capture of Richmond.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dickson</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Alt</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crider</ln>
                        <fn>Dorothy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Alt and Dorothy Crider, both of Franklin County, were married on May
                    29.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Britton</ln>
                        <fn>Alice Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Britton</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Britton</ln>
                        <fn>Stetira</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Alice Jane Britton, daughter of William and Stetira Britton, died on May 22
                    in Upper Strasburg at the age of 6 years, 9 months and 24 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.06.04.06">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Effect of the Democratic Address in Richmond</head>
                <origin>Chicago Times</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The recent address of several Democratic members of Congress to the
                    Democratic party as a whole has been distributed in Richmond. It allegedly was
                    well-received by many prominent citizens, who began expressing sentiments for
                    the Constitution and the old union. These expressions greatly worried
                    Confederate leaders.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Five columns of classified advertising</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.06.04.07">
            <pageNote>Classified advertising</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.06.04.08">
            <pageNote>Includes a reprint of the confiscation bill as it passed the House of
                Representatives, and four and a half columns of classified
            advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
