<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1870/va.au.ss.1870.04.12">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>11/14/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date>
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day norm=""/>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1870.04.12.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1870.04.12.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Richmond and the Valley Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In our last, we promised to say some thing in reply to what we have
                        considered the harsh and unkindly comments upon the people of the Valley, in
                        connection with the Valley Rail Road, recently published in the Richmond
                            <emph rend="italic">Whig</emph> and the <emph rend="italic">State
                            Journal</emph>. The articles, which we complain of, have been written in
                        the interest of the scheme of consolidation now before the Legislature. As
                        we understood them they were assaults upon the patriotism, the loyalty "to
                        the old Mother" and the integrity of purpose of our people, in desiring to
                        have the Valley Rail Road extended from Harrisonburg, through Staunton and
                        Lexington, to Salem. Our impression has been, that as God made this Valley,
                        bounded by mountains on each side of it, running from Southwest to the
                        Northeast, with streams of water flowing between these mountains, with
                        fertile fields, and inexhaustible mineral wealth scattered up and down it,
                        the only practicable mode of developing its treasures, is, by constructing a
                        Rail Road through it lengthwise. Before this Valley was settled, the
                            <sic>Buffaloe</sic> track passed through its rich pastures -- then
                        followed the old wagon road, terminating at Knoxville, Tennessee, along
                        which the six horse wagon teams transported the merchandise and produce of
                        the county -- then came the McAdamized and plank roads extending from
                        Shepherdstown to Bristol, and now, in broken links, are found fragments of
                        Rail Roads over the same grand trade line. Our people desire these links to
                        be united, so that instead of the sound of the wagon bells of sixty years
                        ago, we may hear the sound of the engine whistle from one end of this Valley
                        to the other. Our desires flow in the channels which God has made, and we
                        consider it no "treason to the old Mother," as the <emph rend="italic">State
                            Journal</emph> intimates it is, to strive to secure that improvement
                        that will do us most good. Nor, in our opinion, will the construction of the
                        Valley Rail Road be otherwise than a blessing to Virginia and especially the
                        city of Richmond. It is manifest that if the wealth, productive resources
                        and population of the Valley, be, as we expect they will be, greatly
                        increased by the making of this Road, Virginia in all her borders must be
                        blessed by the increase. As our wealth increases so will our capacity to pay
                        our taxes; and so will the burden of taxation fall more lightly on others.
                        -- Increase of prosperity too is diffusive, and the leaven of our blessings
                        will spread over the mountains and extend Eastward, and to no point more
                        surely than to Richmond.</p>
                    <p>Let us remind our Richmond friends, (her old merchants will recollect the
                        fact, that when we had nothing but Turnpikes from Staunton to Winchester and
                        to Scottsville, with a Rail Road from Winchester to Baltimore, Richmond drew
                        trade up the Valley and across the mountain down to Scottsville, from New
                        market, forty-two miles from Staunton and fifty miles from Winchester. That
                        was the dividing point. -- Now, we ask, if Rail Roads be substituted for
                        Turnpikes and free interchange of cars be secured at Staunton, what shall
                        prevent Richmond from drawing to itself, the wheat of this granary of
                        Virginia, and a large portion of its productions? Now that the Valley is
                        tapped up to Harrisonburg, the only chance of Richmond to secure its trade,
                        is, in a free and unobstructed transit, up and down the whole Valley. Our
                        people desire free trade with all points, and repudiate the idea that these
                        communications shall be obstructed for the benefit of any other community.
                        We shall insist on the free transit of produce from Harrisonburg or
                        Lexington to Richmond, as strenuously as we shall demand free transit from
                        Lewisburg or Charleston, to Winchester, Alexandria or Baltimore, if trade
                        seeks the Valley Route for its vent. And so in our connections with the
                        Virginia &amp; Tennessee Road, we shall demand the free interchange of
                        trade and travel from one road to the other, at Salem, and if consolidation
                        be against this, we oppose consolidation, on this ground, if on no other. We
                        look to the day when the plaster, salt and other productions of the
                        Southwest, shall be brought directly to our warehouses; in a word our Rail
                        Road policy is this, simply, that the Rail Roads of Virginia shall be the
                        arteries of trade through which free currents shall flow according to the
                        great laws of supply and demand.</p>
                    <p>We seek no war with Richmond; on the contrary we desire her growth and
                        prosperity and our people prefer, other things being equal, to trade with
                        Richmond. But the day has gone by when the growth of cities can be
                        stimulated by artificial processes of forced development, and the cities
                        which claim for themselves the right to tax others for their benefit, to
                        make large regions tributary to them, against the nature laws of trade and
                        the best interests of others, will make more enemies than friends by the
                        claim.</p>
                    <p>We accept with pleasure the disclaimer of our old friend the <emph
                            rend="italic">Whig</emph> in a recent issue of any unfriendly feeling
                        towards our people. -- What we desire is <emph rend="italic">first</emph>
                        the Valley Rail Road and <emph rend="italic">second</emph>, "let us have
                        peace" in Virginia.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spectator responded to criticisms of the people of Augusta, made in a
                    pair of Richmond newspapers. The Richmond papers spoke out against the Valley
                    Railroad's route through Staunton as a threat to its own interests. The
                    Spectator desired the continuation of Richmond's prosperity, but maintained that
                    the Valley Rail Road remained a sound investment that would profit both Staunton
                    and Richmond.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1870.04.12.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>C. and O. R. R.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reported that a large number of African-Americans passed up the
                    Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad to work on the western end of the line.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pinkerton</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Rev. John Pinkerton of Mossy Creek will preach at the Presbyterian
                    Church tonight, and every night throughout the week.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>N. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Summerson</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>N. K. Trout sold the National Hotel for $9,950. James W. Crawford bought
                    the portion on Main Street for $7,000 and R. Summerson bought the frame building
                    in the rear.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Our City Judge</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>Alex B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Alex B. Cochran, representative in the House of Delegates, was elected
                    judge of the city of Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>N. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Congress passed a bill removing N. K. Trout's political disabilities.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Flour Shipped</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>771 barrels of flour have been shipped from the Staunton Depot of the
                    Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad during the week ending April 7th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>County Townships</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>Bolivar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Merritt</ln>
                        <fn>C. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hogshead</ln>
                        <fn>M. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fulton</ln>
                        <fn>J. Givens</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennerly</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The following commissioners have been appointed to lay off Augusta County
                    into townships: Bolivar Christian, C. G. Merritt, M. W. Hogshead, J. Givens
                    Fulton, and Dr. Samuel Kennerly.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Horse Stealing</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parent</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Chief</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fultz</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Parent, Chief of Police of Staunton, arrested three men going by the
                    names of Wilson, Clarke, and Green who fit the description of men wanted for
                    horse theft in West Virginia. The men sought freedom before Judge Fultz on
                    grounds of habeas corpus, but the owners arrived and identified their horses in
                    time to keep them in jail awaiting trial.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Robert W. Burke, Esq.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"Many Citizens" wrote to suggest Robert W. Burke for a vacancy in the House
                    of Delegates.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Commissioned</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Alexander B. Cochran received his commission as city judge of Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Runcle</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wiseman</ln>
                        <fn>Mary A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wayman</ln>
                        <fn>B. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>David Runcle of Augusta and Miss Mary A. Wiseman of Rockbridge were married
                    on March 3rd by the Rev. B. C. Wayman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilkeson</ln>
                        <fn>David W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>David W. Gilkeson died near Greenville on March 31st of consumption. He was
                    22 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1870.04.12.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
