<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1870/va.au.ss.1870.04.26">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>11/15/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date>
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day norm=""/>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1870.04.26.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1870.04.26.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Register that you may Vote</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reminded readers to register so they will be eligible to vote.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>15th Amendment Celebration</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Described how Richmond's African-American community held a celebration upon
                    passage of the 15th amendment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Income Tax</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Ways and Means Committee of the House of Representatives have agreed to
                        recommend non-concurrence in the extension of the income tax another year.
                        The pressure on Congress to abolish this inquisitorial tax is very great,
                        and it may yield. There never was a worse law, for the reason that it bears
                        unequally upon the people -- the honest and conscientious men alone making
                        correct returns, while those who are less scrupulous, make such reports as
                        suit themselves. The law was never intended to last, and ought to be
                        abolished at once.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spectator reported that a Congressional Committee issued a
                    recommendation against the extension of the income tax. Argued against the
                    income tax because dishonest men will evade paying their share, which will hurt
                    honest taxpayers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>"Relief"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>MR. EDITOR: -- The newspapers throughout the State contain many articles in
                        favor of what is called "relief" to the debtor classes. -- The general idea
                        seems to be that the Legislature should provide by law, that no property
                        should be sold, under execution, unless it will bring something like its
                        value.</p>
                    <p>As a matter of <emph rend="italic">morals</emph> and of <emph rend="italic"
                            >equity between man and man</emph>, this may be all right, and it would
                        be a very desirable thing, if by <emph rend="italic">agreement</emph>
                        between creditors and debtors this rule could be adopted.</p>
                    <p>But as a question of <emph rend="italic">law</emph> it is impracticable. It
                        has been tried and failed. The Constitution of the U.S., which is the
                        supreme law of the land, <emph rend="italic">and over-rides all State laws
                            and constitutions which come in conflict with it</emph>, provides that
                        no State shall "pass any law impairing the obligation of contracts."</p>
                    <p>In 1842, the Legislature of Illinois passed a law, exactly like the one which
                        it is proposed that the Legislature of Virginia should pass, viz.: that no
                        sale should be made of property levied on, under an execution, unless it
                        should bring two-thirds of its valuation according to the opinion of three
                        householders.</p>
                    <p>The validity of this law was tested in the U. S. Circuit Court of Illinois,
                        and upon a certificate of division between the Judges, the case went to the
                        Supreme Court of the U.S., and at the January term of 1844, it was
                        considered and decided.</p>
                    <p>The case was that of McCracken vs. Hayward, and will be found reported in 2nd
                        Howard, 608. The purpose of the decision, as appears from the abstract of
                        the Reporter, is in these words: "A law of the State of Illinois, providing
                        that a sale shall not be made, of property levied on, under an execution,
                        unless it will bring two-thirds of its valuation, according to the opinion
                        of three householders, is UNCONSTITUTIONAL AND VOID."</p>
                    <p>This decision settles the matter of relief, in that form, beyond all
                        controversy.</p>
                    <p>Is it not, therefore, idle, to tantalize people with the hope of relief which
                        cannot be afforded? Any attempt at relief of this kind, will certainly prove
                        a delusion and a snare. If the Legislature were to undertake, in defiance of
                        the Supreme Court, and of the Constitution of the U.S., <emph rend="italic"
                            >which they have sworn to support</emph>, to pass such a law, as seems
                        to be desired by many, it would, promptly, be decided to be
                        "unconstitutional and void," even by our State Courts, because they are
                        bound to respect the Constitution of the U.S.</p>
                    <p>The only hope of relief to debtors is, by an appeal to the sense of justice,
                        and kind feeling of their creditors. They must try to make the best
                        arrangements they can, for a gradual liquidation of their debts. And
                        although it is fashionable with some to cry out about extortion, griping,
                        grinding the faces of the poor, "Shylock creditors," &amp;c., we are
                        persuaded these are exceptional cases. There may be some bad men who may be
                        disposed to use their power as creditors to oppress their debtors; but we
                        are happy to say, that in nine cases out of ten, no such feeling animates
                        creditors as a class. A very large proportion of the suits that have been
                        instituted in our county, were brought with no such purpose. In most cases,
                        the object was to render the debts secure by obtaining judgment liens. This
                        having been accomplished, most creditors will be disposed to make fair
                        arrangements with their debtors.</p>
                    <p>It might not be unprofitable to enquire how far the outcry about relief and
                        repudiation may have stimulated creditors to adopt stringent measures for
                        the collection of their debts. It is said, by leading London journals, that
                        the movements in Congress looking to partial repudiation, have seriously
                        affected the credit of the U.S. and the market value of our national bonds.
                        A like cause will doubtless affect the credit of individuals. Capital is
                        proverbially timid, and credit is a sensitive plant. The bare suggestion of
                        relief measures inspires distrust, and causes all who hold bonds, to sue on
                        them, and seek to collect or secure them. Indiscreet advocates of illegal
                        forms of relief, therefore, by their mistaken action, aggravate the very
                        mischiefs which they desire to avoid. X.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Anonymous contributor "X" wrote to the Spectator, claiming that a law being
                    considered for debt relief was both unconstitutional and unwise. The law would
                    bar creditors from selling debtors' property at less than its full value even
                    though a similar law in Illinois was declared unconstitutional. "X" also
                    believed that acts making it more difficult for creditors to obtain payment
                    discouraged investment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1870.04.26.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoover</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Hoover has been appointed Notary Public of Augusta.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Karicofe</ln>
                        <fn>James M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James M. Karicofe of Mt. Solon received a patent for a corn-planter.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Horse-Thieves</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parrent</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hilbert</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>Ned</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jacob T. Parrent, J. W. Hilbert, and Ned Burke moved three horse-thieves
                    arrested in Staunton from Augusta to West Virginia, where they will stand trial.
                    "Jacob T. Parrent has rendered efficient service in the arrest of horse
                    thieves--having been instrumental in the arrest of five within the last six
                    months."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>County Court</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The new County Court system, provided by the present Constitution of this
                        State, was inaugurated in this county on yesterday -- Judge John N. Hendren
                        presiding.</p>
                    <p>He appointed the following officers to serve till their successors shall be
                        elected in accordance with the provisions of the Constitution:</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Clerk of the County.</emph> -- Wm. A. Burnett; and as his
                        deputy, Jas. W. Baldwin.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Sheriff of the County.</emph> -- Geo. W. McCutchen; and
                        as his deputies, Wm. Hoover, Jno. W. Cline, R. G. Byers, J. H. Craun, W. A.
                        Reed, Wm. H. Bull, R. T. Gamble and Geo. Harlan.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Commonwealth's Attorney.</emph> -- James Bumgardner, Jr.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Commissioners of the Revenue</emph>. -- John Towberman,
                        1st District; and as his deputy, Thos. M. Donoho, J. H. Stover, 2nd
                        District, and as his deputy, John G. Stover.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Commissioners in Chancery.</emph> -- Jos. A. Waddell and
                        Thos. D. Ranson.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hendren</ln>
                        <fn>John N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burnett</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCutchen</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoover</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cline</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Byers</ln>
                        <fn>R. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craun</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>W. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bull</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gamble</ln>
                        <fn>R. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harlan</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Towberman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donoho</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stover</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stover</ln>
                        <fn>John G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ranson</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Listed the appointed officers of the County Court under the new
                    Constitution.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Dramatic Reading</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scharf</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Prof. Scharf will read Sheridan's comedy of the "Rivals" in the Town Hall
                    tonight. Everyone, especially students, should attend.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>James E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>"Many Voters" wrote to suggest James E. Hanger for nomination to the office
                    of County Treasurer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>Robert W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>A. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>"Many Farmers" wrote to suggest Robert W. Burke as a replacement for A. B.
                    Cochran as representative to the legislature.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Knisely</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Showalter</ln>
                        <fn>Amanda C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Forsyth</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jacob Knisely and Miss Amanda C. Showalter, both of Augusta, were married
                    on April 14th by the Rev. W. H. Forsyth.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henkel</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henkel</ln>
                        <fn>S. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henkel</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sarah H. Henkel and Charles Koiner of Augusta were married in New Market at
                    the residence of S. D. Henkel on April 18th by the Rev. S. Henkel.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cain</ln>
                        <fn>Patrick Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Humphrey</ln>
                        <fn>Virginia E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bushong</ln>
                        <fn>A. A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Patrick Henry Cain and Miss Virginia E. Humphrey, both of Augusta, were
                    married on April 14th by the Rev. A. A. J. Bushong.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fulwider</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Catharine Fulwider died at her residence in Dutch Hollow, Augusta
                    County, on April 12th. She was 101 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1870.04.26.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
