<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1870/va.au.ss.1870.11.01">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>11/28/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date>
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="11">November</month>
            <day norm="01"/>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1870.11.01.01" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Constitution of the Augusta Memorial Association for the Confederate Dead,
                    Adopted October 19th, 1870</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>ARTICLE I.</p>
                    <p>The name of this Association shall be "The Augusta Memorial Association for
                        the Confederate Dead."</p>
                    <p>ARTICLE II.</p>
                    <p>The object of this Association shall be the preservation, care and annual
                        decoration of the graves of the Confederate Dead, who are interred in
                        Thornrose Cemetery, and other localities in Augusta County.</p>
                    <p>ARTICLE III.</p>
                    <p>The members of this Association shall consist of all persons, not deserters
                        from the Confederate Army, who shall contribute annually the sum of fifty
                        cents for the purposes of the Association.</p>
                    <p>ARTICLE IV.</p>
                    <p>Honorary members of the Association shall consist of all persons who shall
                        contribute to the sum of five dollars for the purposes of the Association.</p>
                    <p>ARTICLE V.</p>
                    <p>The officers of the Association shall be a President in Staunton, and one
                        Vice President in each Township of the County, a Secretary and a Treasurer;
                        and these officers shall be elected by the Association at each annual
                        meeting, convened for the purpose of decorating the graves of the
                        Confederate dead. Their duties shall be such as are appropriate to their
                        respective offices, and as may be specified by the By-Laws of the
                        Association.</p>
                    <p>ARTICLE VI.</p>
                    <p>There shall be an Executive Committee consisting of five members, inclusive
                        of the President of the Association, who shall be <emph rend="italic">ex
                            officio</emph>, a member and chairman thereof, to be chosen by the
                        Association at each annual meeting thereof, and of whom three shall
                        constitute a quorum for the transaction of business. It shall be the duty of
                        the Executive Committee to transact the current business of the Association;
                        to determine and direct all the operations of the Association in reference
                        to the graves of the Confederate dead, and to make all contracts in regard
                        thereto; and to control all the expenditure of the Association. Upon their
                        draft, all the moneys of the Association shall be paid by the Treasurer, and
                        to them the Treasurer shall report the condition of the Finances of the
                        Association whenever required so to do. Said Committee shall have the power
                        to draft by-laws for their own government and for the government of the
                        officers of the Association, to appoint sub-committees, and to appoint a
                        Secretary for purposes of keeping a record of all their acts and
                        resolutions; and shall meet whenever required to do so by the chairman of
                        the Committee. The Executive Committee shall make a report of their
                        transactions to each annual meeting of the Association.</p>
                    <p>ARTICLE VII</p>
                    <p>The Association shall meet yearly at a place to be designated by the
                        President, on the 9th of June, as the annual "Memorial Day" of the
                        Association, to decorate the graves of the Confederate dead and to transact
                        appropriate business.</p>
                    <p>The President of the Association, assisted by the Executive Committee, shall
                        prescribe the ceremonies of the Memorial Day, provide for the delivery of
                        such addresses as may be proper, and give sufficient previous notice thereof
                        by publication to the newspapers of the County.</p>
                    <p>The President and Vice President shall be, <emph rend="italic">ex
                        officio</emph>, Marshals at the day.</p>
                    <p>ARTICLE VIII.</p>
                    <p>The annual contributions of the members of the Association shall be expended,
                        under the direction of the Executive Committee, in keeping in repair the
                        graves of the Confederate dead in Augusta. The fund arising from the
                        contribution of honorary members may be invested in a permanent fund or
                        otherwise as the Association may determine.</p>
                    <p>ARTICLE IX.</p>
                    <p>The Secretary shall inscribe the names of the members of the Association in a
                        well bound book for preservation, and the roll of members shall be published
                        annually, in the papers of Augusta, under the direction of the President.</p>
                    <p>A true copy,</p>
                    <p>CHAS. D. McCoy,</p>
                    <p>Secretary of the Association.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Printed a copy of the Constitution of the Augusta Memorial Association.
                    Included articles detailing when meetings would be held, how much each member
                    pays in dues, and when to gather for a Memorial Day.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>06</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>For the Spectator</p>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">To the Voters of Augusta County:</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>There are three candidates in the field for the office of Treasurer of
                        Augusta county. Two of them are independent candidates; the other being the
                        nominee of a county convention. Disclaiming any intention of assailing the
                        integrity of either of the other candidates, the sole object of this
                        communication is to remind the voters of the county of the urgent claims
                        that Capt. Samuel Paul, the independent conservative, has for their support.</p>
                    <p>Capt. Paul chose not to submit his claims to the decision of the convention;
                        to do this he had not only the privilege, but an unquestionable right. And
                        why? I claim that no man, who has substantial and <emph rend="italic"
                            >specific</emph> claims, is safe in submitting them to a hasty,
                        boisterous, and fillibustering convention. Do not construe me as calling
                        into question the honest intentions of the county convention; but had it
                        been held in the territories, I would not hesitate to assert that it
                        stultified itself. Why? In the first place the avowed object of the
                        convention was to rule off all the conservative candidates save one who
                        would the more likely be able to defeat the so-called republican candidate.
                        This part of its duty the convention performed, but it committed the
                        singular paradox of nominating for one of the county officers an individual
                        whose war record is identically the same as that of the republican candidate
                        for treasurer. Again, the convention floundered into the wretched error of
                        nominating for treasurer of Augusta county a citizen of the city of
                        Staunton. Why not a citizen of Lynchburg or Richmond? If Staunton be a city
                        it is doubtful whether a citizen thereof is eligible to a county office. The
                        city will have its municipal officers, including treasurer. The treasurer of
                        Staunton will have nothing whatever to do with the funds of the county; nor,
                        on the other hand, will the county treasurer have aught to do with the funds
                        of the city. If Staunton be not a city, but vote, and so on, with the county
                        as heretofore, why then I cannot appreciate the modesty or magnanimity of
                        one of her citizens who would desire the office of county treasurer, when
                        the town already monopolizes the offices of profit and honor in the county.</p>
                    <p>Although Staunton has the State Senator, the three members of the House of
                        Delegates, the Superintendent of Public Schools, and the Clerks of both the
                        Circuit and County Courts, yet she had not less than four candidates for
                        treasurer--being nearly one-half of all the candidates--although she has
                        only about one-seventh of the whole population of the city and county
                        combined. It is truly distasteful to see such an inordinate greed for
                        office.</p>
                    <p>There is springing up in the county a feeling of antipathy towards the town
                        (city?) By way of parenthesis, I ask to be pardoned for using the terms
                        "town" and "city" interchangeably. I do not wish to give color to the
                        allegation of many citizens of the county that Staunton wishes to be a city
                        for certain other purposes. But, to return to this contest between the
                        county and the city: Is it causeless? it is surely needless. It is
                        impossible for the one to prosper without the other prospering also. But
                        whilst the prosperity of the county and the city is almost necessarily
                        mutual, yet this contest is not altogether innocuous. It may be hurtful when
                        concert of action is necessary in some public measure. It has already
                        defeated one measure which was deemed of vital importance to the county. The
                        contest is either not causeless, or the city of Staunton contains all the
                        talent and qualification for office in the limits of the county. It is
                        difficult to imagine that all the talent, integrity and qualification for
                        office is concentrated in the city of Staunton. Yet, after the incubation of
                        a miserable caucus before the election for members of the Legislature in
                        1869, we received the startling intelligence that the caucus had hatched out
                        all four of the candidates from the town of Staunton, and we must vote for
                        them, otherwise a radical or radicals would be elected. This was just a few
                        days before the election, and the people of the county voted for and elected
                        them; they will never do so again. We honestly believe that there is some
                        talent, qualification and patriotism outside of the city.</p>
                    <p>What are the comparative claims of the three candidates for your support? As
                        to Mr. McCutchen, the so-called republican candidate, I choose to draw the
                        mantle of charity over his war record, and pass on to Mr. Cochran, the
                        nominee. He has as much claim as any other honest and qualified man of
                        Richmond or Petersburg; or if Staunton does actually embody all the talent
                        and qualification for offices of honor and profit in the county, why then
                        vote for him. But I unhesitatingly assert that he has no substantial claim
                        whatever upon the people of the county for their support. He has no specific
                        claim, for he was not in the army at all, being exempted from duty all the
                        while.</p>
                    <p>Capt. Paul has substantial and specific claims upon you. That he is honest
                        and capable no one will undertake to deny. These are the pre-requisites for
                        all offices. He needs the profits of the office, a thing not remarkable, for
                        nearly every faithful soldier who served throughout the war was necessarily
                        crippled in finances. His war record is well known; of this I need only give
                        a very succinct review. He volunteered in 1861 and served faithfully in the
                        armies of Gens. Johnson and Jackson until the battle of Port Republic where
                        he lost a leg. As soon as he sufficiently recovered, he was appointed
                        Enrolling officer for Augusta county, in which position he gave entire
                        satisfaction to the close of the war.</p>
                    <p>Voters of Augusta! a faithful and disabled soldier, one of the county's
                        wards, desires and needs an office. I deem it almost a work of
                        supererogation to more than simply remind you of your solemn obligation to
                        support him in preference to all others. This is an obligation from which
                        nothing can absolve you. I boldly assert that no convention, nor the fear
                        that a candidate of the Republican party may be elected, nor anything else
                        can release you from your obligation to support one of Augusta's disabled
                        sons. If the voters of the county have so soon forgotten their obligations
                        to their crippled defenders, it matters but little who is elected to office,
                        provided he be honest and competent. I hope it will be a cheerful duty for
                        every man in the county to go to the polls and cast his vote for Capt.
                        Samuel Paul.</p>
                    <p>MONTANUS</p>
                    <p>October 1870, lt.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"MONTANUS" wrote to the Spectator to complain that a Staunton resident has
                    been nominated candidate for County Treasurer. He suggested county resident
                    Samuel Paul as an alternative because Staunton already dominated so many of the
                    county offices.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>07</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>STANTON, FRYDAY NITE,</p>
                    <p>after thee Fare</p>
                    <p>DEAR WIFE--I arriv here Mundy arter-noon at the "Merriken," kep by Ed.
                        Cushin--u recolik he war a little boy when we imigrated to "ole Flu." I tel
                        u Pol, Stanton is pintedly changed since we last seed it. It is a city now
                        counten the deef and dumb and the lunatix. Lots abildings has gon up and
                        lots of the old citizens two. A grate big hi brik house has bin put up on
                        the korner where Nob Brooks used to hand u out your male. Nob is gone as
                        well as the ole bildin. The Post Offis is now kept up on Augusty street,
                        what we use to call the Mackadmized rode. Time and space wood fale me to tel
                        u 1/2 the strange things that have taken place. I tel u ole gal, when I
                        looked roun for the ole residenters and could'nt fine none; for the ole lan
                        marks and they want thar; when i seed the gas lite's and the grate number of
                        yung gals at the skules, and the bar rooms and the tigers which is even in
                        the winders, I felt orfully solum and tolrable ole--u bet i did--and I cood
                        but xclame in the langwige of the poit,<lb/> "I'll drink a cup of kindness
                        yet<lb/> For ole lang sine."<lb/> So I stept into the fust salune I cum to
                        and drunk it.</p>
                    <p>Tuesdy mornin I pade a quawter to ride doun to the Far grouns in a hak. I war
                        by myself on the hine seet an u ort to hav seed me rar bak. I no u would hav
                        bin proud of my personal appearance. It war the same bak which was used to
                        haul niggers to the poles at the Ralerode eleckshun, but tha did'nt have to
                        pa nuthin. I nu it war the saim by the smell. I did'nt think much of the
                        Far--thats honest. I don't think any body did, unless it war a feller that
                        got the niggers to strike a boarde with a big wooden hammer at 10 cents a
                        lik. The niggers war licked as wel as the board. Kunnel Baldin was ridin
                        aroun the trak on a white hoss considerabel. The Kunnel is grate on a notty
                        case at the bar and rite hard to beat in a perlitical canvas, but I hurd
                        peeple sa he made sum mistake in carryin on these Farrs. Tha sed if thar war
                        more attenshun pade to bizness and less promenence given to amuzements, the
                        Farrs wood not come so nigh unto a fizzle. Tha beleeved that if thar war
                        more good stock and other sorts of agricultural produxs and so forth to look
                        at and less ridin of tournaments and kickin-ups on the green, the practicle
                        farmers of the county wood fele more interest in the consurn. One feller sed
                        that the Judges did'nt no much about what they had to xamine--xcept the
                        licker judges which ar generally appinted from the legle perfesshun. I'm a
                        good judge of licker miself.</p>
                    <p>The Bloon did'nt go up Tuesday, which war a grate disappintment to menny who,
                        findin nuthin else to look at, intended to look at the Bloon. Wednesday she
                        went--but not very far, and sune cudid in smoke.</p>
                    <p>Thursday it raned and the fellers could'nt ride at the tournament. It war a
                        fine thing for the hosses, but a wanderful disappintment to the Queen of
                        Buty and the Mades of Honor and the gallant Nites.</p>
                    <p>I hav heard considerabul tawk on politix since I arriv in the city. Folks
                        generally is doun on Harris. U reckerleck Jno. Harris who was at the law
                        schule when we lived here. Well, he ar the radicle nominee on the
                        conservativ ticket for Kongress. Tha do sa John is a political
                        trikster--always on the winnin side. The Harris family ar grate for
                        luk--sho. Sum sa tha intends to vote fur Aron Shovler. He ar a cullud
                        radical and a man of sum principle. John's perliticle principles hev always
                        counted 7--5 loaves and two fishes.</p>
                    <p>I mus now bring this effectionate correspondence to a close. When I found out
                        they did'nt pay premiums at the Farr, I koncluded not to enter the dried
                        simmons. Remember me to all the children and tell Isaac not to fergit to
                        fede the houn purp.</p>
                    <p>your affexionable Husburn,</p>
                    <p>SIMON SOCKS, of</p>
                    <p>Fluvanner cownty.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter purportedly from Simon Socks, a rural visitor to the Augusta County
                    Fair. He talked about the changes in Staunton in recent years and gave a
                    day-by-day account of the fair. The letter served to poke fun at rural views and
                    speech patterns by printing the letter in dialect.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1870.11.01.02" exists="no">
            <div type="l">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reynolds</ln>
                        <fn>Corbin M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>John T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>"Augusta" urged conservative voters to cast a ballot for Corbin M. Reynolds
                    instead of John T. Harris for representative. Told voters to ignore rumors that
                    only a vote for Harris would prevent a Radical victory.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>To the Conservative Party of the 6th Congressional District</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>John T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John T. Harris wrote to denounce "false and sensational circulars" being
                    distributed by his political enemies on the eve of the election. He asserted
                    that a united conservative party offered the best chance to defeat the radicals.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1870.11.08.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Valley of Virginia Manufacturing Company</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reported on the impending formation of a joint stock company called the
                    "Valley of Virginia Manufacturing Company". The company hoped to establish a
                    capital stock of between $50,000 and $100,000 at $50 per share. The company also
                    had plans to build a factory in Staunton to manufacture agricultural equipment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kreamer</ln>
                        <fn>Konrote</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The House passed a bill providing for re-assessment of Staunton real
                    property values. Mr. Cochran also planned to introduce bills appointing a
                    constable and three justices of the peace for Staunton, along with a bill
                    rescinding the contract between the Board of Public Works and Konrote Kreamer in
                    regard to the Staunton and Parkersburg Railroad.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Catholic Fair, held in Staunton, raised $500.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echols</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Catlett</ln>
                        <fn>N. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>E. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Echols and N. P. Catlett passed resolutions of sympathy and respect on
                    behalf of the National Valley Bank of Staunton upon the death of E. M. Taylor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Plan of Organization for the Formation and Distribution of a Relief Fund for
                    the Sufferers from the Late Flood</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Circulated resolutions calling for the formation of county committees to
                    begin the work of flood relief. Said committees should be appointed at public
                    meetings, and asked ministers to give their support to the endeavors. Also
                    requested all the donations should go to the Governor of Virginia for
                    distribution.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keller</ln>
                        <fn>Jerome</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCutchen</ln>
                        <fn>Audie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Engle</ln>
                        <fn>J. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jerome Keller and Miss Audie McCutchen, both of Augusta, were married at
                    Churchville on October 24th by the Rev. J. J. Engle.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taliaferro</ln>
                        <fn>Edwin F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stover</ln>
                        <fn>Lizzie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Engle</ln>
                        <fn>J. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Edwin F. Taliaferro and Miss Lizzie Stover, both of Augusta, were married
                    at Jenning's Gap on October 27th by the Rev. J. J. Engle.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Acord</ln>
                        <fn>William F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yago</ln>
                        <fn>Annie E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fletcher</ln>
                        <fn>P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William F. Acord and Annie E. Yago, both of Augusta, were married at West
                    View on October 19th by the Rev. P. Fletcher.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>Lelia Hendren</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>D. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dudley</ln>
                        <fn>W. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Lelia Hendren Wilson, wife of D. N. Wilson and daughter of W. M.
                    Dudley, died at Aspen Hill, Augusta County, on September 22nd. She was 25 years
                    old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>Edwin M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Edwin M. Taylor died at his Staunton residence on October 29th. He was 57
                    years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>Robert Lee</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Robert Lee Cochran, son of George W. and Mary Jane Cochran, died near
                    Summerdean on October 12th. He was 7 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brunt</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Mary Ann Brunt died on September 27th. She was 26 years old. "Mrs. B.
                    left a husband, two little girls, and many friends to mourn her loss."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1870.11.01.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
