<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1870/va.au.ss.1870.12.06">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>11/29/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date>
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="12">December</month>
            <day norm="06"/>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1870.12.06.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1870.12.06.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"For the first time in the history of the country," says the Richmond <emph
                            rend="italic">Whig</emph>, "military interference in elections has been
                        legalized, and has become as universal as suffrage itself. It is one of the
                        curious contradictions of the times, that free suffrage should be made
                        subject to military force, and that the ballot and the bullet should be
                        brought into intimate association.</p>
                    <p>Such are the means resorted to by Radicalism to maintain its ascendancy. One
                        thing is to be observed -- that after trying all other means, shifts, and
                        contrivances, they have at length been driven to that last resort, <emph
                            rend="italic">ultima ratio</emph>, force. This brings them to the end of
                        their tether, and, if it fails, down they must go to certain ruin. It failed
                        in North Carolina, it failed here, it failed in New York, and it failed in
                        other places. Should it fail in the great Presidential battle of '72, as
                        seems likely, where will Radicalism be? The answer is plain: it will find
                        itself standing exposed to the very <sic>enginery</sic> of war it prepared
                        for its adversaries, and the only question is, whether that
                        <sic>enginery</sic> will be used against it, or whether those adversaries
                        will have the magnanimity to forbear its use?"</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Heavily criticized Radical measures involving using military force in
                    elections. Editor said the Radicals failed to secure victory every time they
                    used military force and would soon find themselves in ruins if they persisted in
                    using it.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1870.12.06.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Wilson died near Swoope's Depot of natural causes. Some papers
                    mistakenly reported it as a suicide.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Death of Capt. James A. McClung</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClung</ln>
                        <fn>James A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Capt. James A. McClung died in Staunton at the residence of his
                    brother-in-law, Joseph A. Waddell, after a month-long illness. Many friends
                    mourned his death.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Christmas Tree</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Simpson</ln>
                        <fn>A. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harlan</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hall</ln>
                        <fn>N. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The teachers and friends of the Southern M. E. Sunday School will hold a
                    Christmas Tree ceremony for Staunton's children.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Temperance Address</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On Friday night last, in the M. E. Church South, of this place, Mr. Jas. W.
                        Baldwin, on behalf of Staunton Council, No. 47, "Friends of Temperance,"
                        delivered a well-conceived, methodical, and interesting address, abounding
                        with good doctrine and wholesome counsel. In the language of Saint Paul, he
                        spoke "the words of truth and soberness." The address was of a character, in
                        temper, matter, and manner calculated to do much good, and we hope that such
                        will prove to be the case. Next to church membership, with young men
                        especially, membership in one of the temperance organizations is the most
                        important -- it furnishes them with a safe refuge from the dangers of "the
                        all-pervading destroyer," which annually slays its thousands and tens of
                        thousands, and inflicts woes unutterable upon countless families, which
                        otherwise would be blessed with happiness and prosperity. Intemperance,
                        though not the greatest sin, is the greatest evil that afflicts our
                    country.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Highly praised an address given by Jas. W. Baldwin in favor of temperance.
                    Fervently hoped for the success of the movement because alcohol "is the greatest
                    evil that afflicts our country."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Valley Virginian</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yost</ln>
                        <fn>S. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoneburner</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Major S. M. Yost purchased the Valley Virginian from Mr. Stoneburner and
                    Co. He planned to assume editorial duties in a few weeks. "He needs no
                    introduction to the citizens of this community, for a considerable portion of
                    his life has been spent here, and he is known by the Press of the State
                    generally in his character as Editor, as he was, before the war, the Editor for
                    some years of the Staunton Vindicator, and, since the war, for a year or more,
                    one of the editors of the Rockingham Register."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Public Free Schools</head>
                <origin>Va. Herald (Fincastle).</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Free School system, in many places, has proved successful -- in some
                        places it has been the reverse. Whether, in our midst, it will meet with
                        success and the approval of our people remains to be tested by practical
                        experience. We have no other alternative than to put the free schools into
                        operation; to encourage them to the extent of our power, and endeavor to
                        reap all the benefit we can from them. The tax to support them has been
                        assessed, and will have to be paid; and although it is not sufficient to
                        support the number of schools contemplated, the plan of the trustees to
                        raise the amount sufficient, by private subscription, should be encouraged,
                        as it seems to be the most feasible one, and one which will secure all the
                        benefits of the institution, without discriminating in favor of any
                        particular section of the Township.</p>
                    <p>To the greater portion of the people the public free schools will be a
                        blessing, because their tax will not amount to one-fourth the tuition of a
                        single child; and this class, (whose tax will be small, but who have
                        children to educate,) should contribute liberally towards raising the
                        additional sum necessary to carry out the programme of the trustees. --
                            <emph rend="italic">Va. Herald (Fincastle)</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprinted an article from the Virginia Herald expressing tacit support for
                    the new public school system. The editor cannot guarantee the system will work
                    but does appreciate that a majority of the people who could not afford private
                    school will benefit.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Conservative Party</head>
                <origin>Montgomery Messenger</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The organization of the Conservative party of Virginia was thought to be
                        merely <emph rend="italic">local</emph>, and formed for an emergency -- self
                        preservation. It has already assumed a national character and its principles
                        will most certainly present the issues upon which the battle for the
                        Presidency in '72 is to be won. To Virginia belongs the honor of having
                        inaugurated what is now called the "Reform Movement in Politics." A close
                        analysis of the principles and issues which were carried so triumphantly by
                        the <emph rend="italic">people</emph> of Missouri, Tennessee, Kentucky,
                        Alabama, New York, &amp;c., against politicians, the influence of the
                        administration and the force of bayonets, will be found to be the same
                        principles and the same issues upon which Virginia planter herself in 1869;
                        it will be further seen that where these principles were broadly and
                        squarely presented, divested of all collateral issues, the majorities were
                        much larger and the sentiments of the people more emphatic and decisive.</p>
                    <p>The example of Virginia has given 100 <emph rend="italic">honest</emph>
                        representatives in Congress instead of 59. Call them Democrats,
                        Conservatives, Reformers, or what not, they are the representatives of the
                        people and exponents of the principles of the Virginia Conservative party.
                        Sixteen independent Republicans are also elected, whom it is said will
                        co-operate cordially with the 109 in the election of speaker and the
                        formation of the committees. Clearly we will have the power to control the
                        House of Representatives and direct its policy. What then? The formation of
                        a party based on the principles presented by Virginia in her local election
                        in '69, which will sweep away the whole Union as it did Missouri and other
                        States in the last election.</p>
                    <p>To all Conservatives, then, we have to say, stand firm -- be not drawn away
                        by any side issue -- forget dead issues -- ignore party name, and array
                        yourself under the banner and follow the lead of the man that promises the
                        quickest deliverance to honest men, and the speediest retribution to rogues
                        and carpet-baggers. -- <emph rend="italic">Montgomery Messenger.</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Called on all Conservatives to forget old party labels and unite under the
                    Conservative banner to ensure the reestablishment of southern prosperity.
                    Assured conservatives that their movement was sweeping the country, as indicated
                    by recent elections in Missouri, Tennessee, New York, etc.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Troxell</ln>
                        <fn>John G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Price</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wayman</ln>
                        <fn>B. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John G. Troxell and Miss Sarah J. Price, both of Augusta, were married near
                    Newport on November 16th by the Rev. B. C. Wayman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swisher</ln>
                        <fn>James F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Troxell</ln>
                        <fn>Mary J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wayman</ln>
                        <fn>B. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James F. Swisher of Rockbridge and Miss Mary J. Troxell of Augusta were
                    married near Newport on November 17th by the Rev. B. C. Wayman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ellinger</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wayman</ln>
                        <fn>B. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Ellinger and Miss Sarah M. Gordon, both of Augusta, were married
                    near Newport on December 1st by the Rev. B. C. Wayman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Edward</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Sadie Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Handy</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac W. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Edward Crawford and Sadie Elizabeth Crawford, daughter of William Crawford
                    of Augusta, were married on November 30th at the house of the bride's father by
                    the Rev. Isaac W. K. Handy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shumate</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shafer</ln>
                        <fn>Jennie M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shafer</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pratt</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Thomas Shumate of Staunton and Miss Jennie M. Shafer, daughter of the late
                    David Shafer of Rockbridge, were married on November 30th at the residence of
                    the bride's mother by the Rev. Mr. Pratt.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn>Nimrod</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swink</ln>
                        <fn>Nancy J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ewing</ln>
                        <fn>D. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Nimrod Gordon and Miss Nancy J. Swink, both of Augusta, were married on
                    November 10th by the Rev. D. B. Ewing.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lamb</ln>
                        <fn>Clara C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ewing</ln>
                        <fn>D. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John M. Brown and Miss Clara C. Lamb, both of Augusta, were married on
                    December 1st by the Rev. D. B. Ewing.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dunlap</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rohrer</ln>
                        <fn>Eliza D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hott</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel A. Dunlap and Miss Eliza D. Rohrer, both of Augusta, were married
                    near Churchville on December 1st by the Rev. J. W. Hott.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cootes</ln>
                        <fn>Willie Graham</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cootes</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cootes</ln>
                        <fn>M. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Willie Graham Cootes, daughter of B. F. and M. E. Cootes, died in Staunton
                    of croup. He was 2 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waid</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John B. Waid died near Newport on November 27th of consumption. He was 27
                    years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Arehart</ln>
                        <fn>Lieucetta H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Arehart</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lieucetta H. Arehart, daughter of Mr. and Mrs. Andrew Arehart, died on
                    November 25th. He was 3 years old. A poem of mourning accompanied the notice.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1870.12.06.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
