<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1870/va.au.ss.1870.04.05">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>11/15/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date>
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day norm=""/>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1870.04.05.01" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>President pro-tem of the Senate</head>
                <origin>Richmond Whig</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Waddell of Staunton, long-time editor of the Staunton Spectator, was
                    selected President pro-tem of the State Senate.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1870.04.05.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Valley Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On Thursday, the 28th of April, the vote will be taken on the proposition
                        that Augusta county shall subscribe $300,000, to the stock of the Valley
                        Railroad. This subscription, and $200,000 from Roanoke is necessary to be
                        given in order to hold the $1,000,000, just voted by Baltimore, and without
                        Augusta's subscription the whole road fails for an indefinite time; <emph
                            rend="italic">with it</emph>, the work will <emph rend="italic">at
                        once</emph> be put under contract from Harrisonburg to Lexington, and for
                        the $300,000 given by Augusta more than $1,500,000 <emph rend="italic">will
                            be paid out in the county</emph>, for the building of the road and for
                        land damages. Augusta cannot afford to lose this chance for maintaining her
                        reputation for sagacity and public spirit.</p>
                    <p>We shall have something to say next week in reply to what has been said
                        recently in some of the Richmond papers about the people of this Valley, in
                        connection with this great improvement, the success of which will depend
                        upon the action of the people of Augusta. We will now merely remark that
                        whilst our people are true to Va. and to all her best interests, they
                        demand, as their right, the development of the boundless resources of their
                        Valley, and perfect freedom of trade with all portions of the Commonwealth,
                        and especially do they insist that their vital interests shall not be
                        crushed by the power of a consolidation, which, through the preference of
                        fear of Baltimore, seeks to repress their energies and enterprise. Give us a
                        complete line of Road throughout the Valley and our increased wealth and
                        population will give to Virginia strength and prosperity which the chance
                        afforded us of trading with Baltimore can neither impair nor avert.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Commented on an upcoming vote concerning subscription to the stock of the
                    Valley Railroad. The Spectator favored such a subscription because it will speed
                    up the construction of the railroad line through Augusta.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Shenandoah Valley R. R.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reported that the Shenandoah Valley Railroad Company has been
                    organized in earnest. A large amount of stock has been subscribed and the
                    officers ready for action.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Programme of the "True Republicans"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We publish below the protest of such of the "True Republicans," as they call
                        themselves, as oppose the attempts to divide them from the great body of the
                        Conservatives of the State, with whom they acted in the election of the 6th
                        of last July. This protest, with the prefatory remarks as published in the
                        Richmond papers, is as follows:</p>
                    <p>Be kind enough to publish the subjoined paper. Several efforts were made to
                        get a meeting of all the members of the True Republican Executive Committee,
                        but failed, because of the absence of some of them from the State, and the
                        business engagements of others. This protest, however, was shown and read to
                            <emph rend="italic">eleven</emph> of the original sixteen members, all
                        of whom endorsed its provisions and signed it, save Normond Smith, John B.
                        Crenshaw, John M. Higgins and C. S. Bundy.</p>
                    <p>TRUE REPUBLICAN EXECUTIVE COMMITTEE'S PROTEST.</p>
                    <p>The undersigned members of the State Executive True Republican Committee deem
                        it due, alike to the party they represented, and to the great body of
                        Conservatives with whom they co-operated, in the election of the 6th of July
                        last, and to their own consistency and self-respect, to declare their
                        opinion of the political movement which occurred recently in this city.</p>
                    <p>The True Republicans were invited to aid "in combining and perfecting an
                        organization which shall be made as effective and instrumental as possible
                        in support of the administration of General Grant, and the policy of the
                        majority in Congress." The purpose was declared to "kill off his Excellency
                        and the <emph rend="italic">rebel</emph> majority in the Legislature;" and
                            <emph rend="italic">Senator Lewis</emph>, who left his seat in the
                        Senate for the occasion, thought proper to repeat the stale slander of
                        Radicalism upon the people who elected him, "that the safety of every Union
                        man in the State depended upon rescuing the State from the hands of the
                            <emph rend="italic">Rebel Democracy</emph>," that is, from the hands of
                        those upon whose ticket he was elected Lieutenant-Governor last summer, and
                        who, but the other day, made him Senator.</p>
                    <p>To compare these ends Senator Lewis, Porter, Platt, Wells and the like came
                        together, with three members of the True Republican Committee, and have set
                        on foot further measures to make the intended coalition complete and
                        perfect, and to rally a popular vote to its support. What are the elements
                        which are expected to compose this vote? Not the mass of True Republicans
                        and Conservatives who gave Governor Walker and the expurgated constitution
                        18,000 majority! It must comprise the 97,000 colored voters and 4,000 white
                        voters who gave Wells his 101,000. The accessions which are to turn this
                        vote into a majority must be drawn from the Conservative and True Republican
                        ranks which elected Walker, and this result, it is hoped, will be achieved
                        by the seductions of the Federal patronage, which these men profess to
                        command, the expected divisions to arise from competitions for the State
                        offices and by what proselytism may be effected through the supineness and
                        false security they think they see in their opponents.</p>
                    <p>It is apparent that the first fruit of their success would be to band the
                        colored voters together against the whites who oppose it, as <emph
                            rend="italic">Democrats</emph> who opposed their freedom and are
                        inimical to their newly acquired rights, to keep up, and a word, the war of
                        races; and in the next place to disperse the political party which organized
                        the State, and to defeat the policy it maintains.</p>
                    <p>What is the policy of our party?</p>
                    <p>It aims to maintain the control of the affairs of the State, and in that
                        connection to give a firm and hearty support to the State administration
                        which it has placed in power. It would consign to the grave of the past old
                        party names and party dissensions, and shuns the renewal of dead political
                        issues. It would secure to the colored race all the rights properly
                        resulting from their enfranchisement, and infuse into them, as far as
                        practicable, sound and wholesome views of their new situation and of their
                        relations with the whites. It would strive for the rebuilding of the fabrics
                        of the State upon stable foundations, connecting with that object the
                        renovation of its domestic resources, undisturbed in its work by the baneful
                        influence of party spirit. Cut off by the exclusion of the test-oath from a
                        proper representation in the General Government, and thus divested of
                        influences in its action, it will not be embarrassed, at present, with
                        national political names and issues, but will reserve itself for the time
                        when, with a restored representation in Congress and in the Electoral
                        College, the weight of the State may be fairly cast in the scale which will
                        settle what is best for all her interests.</p>
                    <p>Holding the new elements which are seeking to coalesce, as at war with the
                        policy here indicated, and with the successful party which maintains it --</p>
                    <p>Resolved, That to unite with and strengthen the defeated Wells' party, would
                        be, on the part of those who defeated it, an unprincipled desertion of the
                        men and the measures which succeeded in the elections of the 6th of July;
                        and that we denounce all such attempts as totally unworthy of the approval
                        or adoption of the people of this State.</p>
                    <p>Resolved, That the members of the Legislature who support these men and these
                        measures, should, in our judgement, proceed to organize the true Republican
                        and Conservative vote of this State in time for the approaching contest,</p>
                    <p>GEORGE RYE,</p>
                    <p>J. W. LEWELLES,</p>
                    <p>H. J. SMITH,</p>
                    <p>JAMES C. SMITH,</p>
                    <p>P. F. BOYLE,</p>
                    <p>JOHN VILES,</p>
                    <p>B. HASSEL,</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spectator published a letter of protest from the "True Republicans,"
                    who disagreed with their party's decision to reject the leadership of Governor
                    Walker. The True Republicans hoped to gain the support of the voters who elected
                    Walker, and then use that support to win upcoming elections.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1870.04.05.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>R. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>R. P. Kinney of Staunton has received an appointment to the United States'
                    Naval Academy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Centenarian</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fulwider</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper reported that Catharine Fulwider of Dutch Hollow, Augusta County,
                    just turned 101 years old. She has 14 children, 101 grand-children, between 500
                    and 600 great-grand-children, and between 15 and 20 great-great-grand children.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Breast Excised</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henkel</ln>
                        <fn>A. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reese</ln>
                        <fn>B. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henkel</ln>
                        <fn>S. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newman</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. A. M. Henkel, assisted by Dr. B. P. Reese and S. H. Henkel,
                    successfully performed surgery to remove the left breast of Catharine Newman,
                    who was suffering from cancer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Sad Accident</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Alexander</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Quinland</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunt</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A son of Dr. Alexander of Waynesboro accidently shot a boy named Quinland
                    who had come to get the gun for Mr. Hunt. The wound will probably prove fatal.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dunlap</ln>
                        <fn>William B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ewing</ln>
                        <fn>D. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William B. Dunlap and Miss Sarah C. Brown, both of Augusta, were married on
                    March 20th by the Rev. D. B. Ewing.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trainum</ln>
                        <fn>David C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Francis L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ewing</ln>
                        <fn>D. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>David C. Trainum and Miss Frances L. Smith, both of Augusta, were married
                    on March 24th by the Rev. D. B. Ewing.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dunlap</ln>
                        <fn>James L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kerr</ln>
                        <fn>Mary A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ewing</ln>
                        <fn>D. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James L. Dunlap and Miss Mary A. Kerr, both of Augusta, were married on
                    March 27th by the Rev. D. B. Ewing.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>John S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John S. Crawford, who owned a large mercantile establishment in Staunton,
                    died at his home in Bath County on April 2nd of heart disease.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKee</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKee</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Catharine McKee, wife of Samuel McKee, died near Middlebrook, Augusta
                    County, on March 18th after suffering a painful illness for three weeks.
                    Previously connected with the United Brethren Church, for the last three years
                    she was a devoted member of the M. E. Church. She lived an outstanding Christian
                    life and bore her suffering with fortitude. She left behind a husband, two sons,
                    and many friends.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1870.04.05.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
