<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1870/va.au.ss.1870.09.06">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>11/23/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date>
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day norm="06"/>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1870.09.06.01" exists="no">
            <div type="l">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Voters of Staunton</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Council can not be indifferent to the fact that 3-5 of the voters of
                        Staunton are non-property holders, and it is questionable whether they have
                        any distinct and well defined idea of the amount of $150,000, and if their
                        conception of such a number be imperfect, how vague must their idea be of
                        the ability of the property of Staunton to assume a debt of $150,000. It is
                        evident, therefore, that a million dollars would as likely be voted as
                        $150,000, and would as likely be paid.</p>
                    <p>The responsibility of the Council in adopting this Ordinance is a very great
                        one, as it puts in jeopardy the interests, the welfare and happiness of our
                        Town, especially when the tax is going to exist through a long course of
                        years, and the benefits (which are conjectural at best) may be entirely
                        inadequate to relieve the property-holders against the accumulating tide of
                        taxation. Our desire is to avoid the too probable consequence that may
                        result from taxing the people beyond their ability, of seeking redress in
                        the courts or otherwise, in <emph rend="italic">repudiation of bonds of
                            doubtful validity</emph>, for we apprehend if this stock is subscribed,
                        there is great risk to the bond-holders that this ordinance will have no
                        binding force upon the town.</p>
                    <p>After this stock of $150,000 is subscribed, the Valley Railroad Company, to
                        complete the Road, will be compelled to mortgage it to such an extent that,
                        if sold, the Road would be sold subject to the mortgage, and in this way the
                        Town would lose every dollar of its stock, and yet the Company might go on,
                        and be solvent and run the road, or what is more probable, the Baltimore
                        &amp; O. Rail Road Company would become the purchasers, and have the
                        exclusive control and benefits of the Valley Railroad. -- Will not the
                        tax-payers ask themselves, what is the interest which thus prompts these
                        Railroad authorities to interfere with our town, and to dictate to us what
                        policy we should pursue? What relations have existed between these
                        authorities and the people, that should so deeply interest them in the
                        destinies of Staunton? We are afraid they do not seek us for our good, but
                        the loaves and fishes are in the answer.</p>
                    <p>In this crisis of our Town, let us take counsel from our duty and not from
                        our fears that 'Staunton will not be made a point.' Let us jealously watch
                        these proceeding while we have the means of resisting a tax that will be
                        grievously oppressive, and will frighten enterprise and capital from our
                        Town.</p>
                    <p>Will any friend of this subscription undertake to name to the tax-payers one
                        town in Virginia, (not in the North or West, but in Virginia,) where the
                        manufacturing interests of various kinds have been built up, or the
                        population increased by Railroads running through and by said town? The
                        result in this case will be just as it has been in years past, disappointed
                        hopes, and not one Railroad promise realized.</p>
                    <p>The general prosperity of Staunton, as we have said in a former article,
                        depends more upon the rich and populous County of Augusta than upon the
                        Valley Railroad. We want good McAdamized roads from every portion of the
                        County, centering at Staunton. Then she will become the mart of the County,
                        and as the County improves and develops her resources, so will the Town
                        improve and increase her population and wealth. VOTER.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"VOTER" criticized the Staunton Council for its repeated efforts to carry
                    the Valley Railroad subscription. Reminded them that 3/5 of the county voted
                    against the proposal and cited previous false promises of prosperity from the
                    railroads. Insisted Augusta's real potential lay in building McAdamized roads
                    and building up the resources of the county, not mortgaging property away to
                    Railroad men.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1870.09.06.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Nomination for Congress</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>As we stated last week, the choice of Congressmen is restricted to two
                        classes, to wit: Those who can take the iron-clad oath, and those whose
                        disabilities have been removed, and who, consequently, are not required to
                        take it. There are not, in this District at least, a great many of either
                        class who possess the other requisite qualification to make suitable
                        representatives in the National Legislature. We should be represented by the
                        very best that can be selected from the few who possess the requisite
                        qualifications.</p>
                    <p>Without any disparagement to others in other portions of the District, we
                        think we are justified in saying that Augusta county can present in the
                        person of one of her sons, whose disabilities have been removed, the peer,
                        in talents, character, public service, legislative experience, and claims to
                        popular support, of any that can be presented by any county in the District.
                        As the reader has no doubt anticipated, we allude to Hon. A. H. H. Stuart,
                        who was a few years ago elected, by a triumphant majority, to represent this
                        District in Congress, but was refused admittance because he could not and
                        would not take the iron-clad oath. This would not be required of him now, as
                        his political disabilities have been removed by act of Congress. We suppose
                        the delegates to the Harrisonburg Convention from this county, will vote to
                        secure the nomination of Mr. Stuart, if he be willing to accept it. [We
                        write in ignorance of his wishes upon the subject.] He was elected, but was
                        prevented from serving by a cause which did him honour -- it was because his
                        sentiments were in accord with those of the great mass of the citizens of
                        the District -- because he was a true exponent of the people whom he was
                        elected to represent. The fact that he would, in truth, <emph rend="italic"
                            >represent</emph> the people of this District, was the reason why he
                        was, by Radical policy, prevented at that time from acting as their
                        Representative. Besides his indisputable qualifications to make an able and
                        faithful representative, the fact that he was prevented from serving, for
                        the reason we have stated, gives him <emph rend="italic">special</emph>
                        claims to the support of the people -- such as no other in the District can
                        present.</p>
                    <p>It seems to us that it is due to themselves that the voters of this District
                        should re-elect Mr. Stuart. The right which was wrongfully denied them, they
                        now have an opportunity to exercise, and we think it is their duty to do so.
                        The right to be represented in Congress by the person of their choice was
                        then denied the voters of the District. That right, if their choice be the
                        same, cannot be denied them now. If elected, he must be admitted, and that,
                        too, without taking the oath. This would be a victory over the body which
                        violated the rights of the people of the District -- "a consummation
                        devoutly to be wished."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Editor supported the nomination of A.H.H. Stuart for Congress. Praised his
                    achievements and assured other county delegates that Stuart would not suffer
                    from any political disabilities like the test-oath. Also said he lost his seat
                    earlier because he represented the true sentiment of his constituents against
                    Radical wishes, and thus deserved the honor of representing the county.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>A. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Effinger</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A letter signed "Rockingham" and published in the Old Commonwealth of
                    Harrisonburg recommended Judge A. B. Cochran of Staunton for Congress. A letter
                    signed "Old Augusta" and published in the Vindicator suggested William H.
                    Effinger of Harrisonburg for the same post.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Valley Railroad Subscription</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"Hadst thou the same free will and power to stand?<lb/> Thou hadst. Whom hast
                        thou then or what to accuse,<lb/> But Heaven's free love dealt equally to
                        all?"<lb/> "And in the lowest deep, a lower deep<lb/> Still threat'ning to
                        devour me opens wide."<lb/><emph rend="italic">Milton</emph></p>
                    <p>It is a remarkable characteristic of human nature that when it has taken a
                        false step, and plunged into difficulty or disgrace, it seldom shows any
                        immediate signs of reaction, but more generally assumes, like the arch-fiend
                        above quoted, a defiant position, and recklessly plunges from each lowest
                        deep, to a lower deep. When Augusta County had (under unwise and unfaithful
                        leaders who had no regard for the "best interests of the County") declared
                        by her vote, that although she was the largest, the wealthiest and most
                        populous County, and the one most to be benefitted by the Road, yet she was
                        not willing to do her part, not willing to do anything, because, forsooth,
                        the other counties and Towns would from their small means contribute their
                        own share and hers too, "and the Road would be built anyhow." Some of the
                        friends of the County urged that she should have an opportunity to retrieve
                        her credit by means of private subscriptions. They were the more encouraged
                        to this from the fact that so many who had opposed the County subscription
                        on what they were pleased to term "principle" had loudly declared their
                        willingness to make it up by private subscription. The opportunity has been
                        given -- the subscription papers have been freely circulated -- the
                        subscription has been urged, and what is the result. At the meeting of the
                        Stockholders, on August 30th, there was found to be Five Thousand Six
                        Hundred ($5,600) Dollars subscribed, a considerable portion of this from
                        citizens of other counties, and a still larger portion from citizens of
                        Staunton, who have already taxed themselves for a corporate subscription.</p>
                    <p>It is now hoped by the company that they have made arrangements by which the
                        balance of the Stock will be provided for, except about $13,000. This they
                        still hope to raise by private subscription along the line. Will the
                        citizens of Augusta County avail themselves of this last opportunity to show
                        their good will to the Road by taking this small amount, or must it be done
                        by those who have already taxed themselves three times as much, as ever
                        Augusta was asked to do. The subscription books are open and subscriptions
                        can be sent in to the old office in Staunton for the next two weeks. Will
                        you do it? Perhaps you will say, why do you urge this subscription on us
                        when we have so plainly and repeatedly told you we will not subscribe. This
                        is our last appeal. From this time forward we shall say, "Ephraim is joined
                        to his idols, let him alone."</p>
                    <p>Raphine Va. PROGRESS.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"PROGRESS" issued another plea for Augusta residents to privately subscribe
                    to the Valley Railroad and thus save the project. He was extremely disappointed
                    with the failure of the recent failed vote but accepted it and thus turned to
                    the idea of private subscription.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Valley Railroad Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The stockholders of the Valley Railroad, at the call of the Board of
                        Directors, met at the office of the Company in Staunton, on Tuesday, August
                        30th, 1870, at 11 A. M.</p>
                    <p>On motion of Col. B. Christian, Col. J. T. Anderson, of Botetourt, was called
                        to the chair and Maj. Jed Hotchkiss of Staunton, appointed Secretary at the
                        meeting.</p>
                    <p>Col. M. G. Harman submitted his report as President of the Company, showing
                        its present condition &amp;c., and stating that he declined a
                        re-election, and desired the election of Gen. R. E. Lee to the Presidency of
                        the Board.</p>
                    <p>On motion, Col. Harman's Report was received.</p>
                    <p>On motion of Col. Christian, the chair was directed to appoint a committee of
                        three stock-holders, to examine the credentials of proxies and report the
                        shares of stock represented in the meeting. Col. Christian asked to be
                        excused from serving on the Committee. The chair appointed Col. J. B.
                        Baldwin, Col. J. W. Massie, and Maj. J. B. Dorman.</p>
                    <p>Col. Baldwin, chairman of Committee on proxies, &amp;c., reported that
                        there were present, proxies representing 1000 shares of stock, of the city
                        of Staunton; proxies representing 2000 shares of stock of the county of
                        Botetourt; proxies representing 4000 shares of stock of the county of
                        Rockbridge, and some 56 shares of stock represented by stockholders. The
                        report of the Committee was received, and the Committee discharged. On
                        motion of Col. M. G. Harman, Gen. R. E. Lee was unanimously elected
                        President of the Valley Railroad Company.</p>
                    <p>On motion of Col. Christian, the chair appointed a committee of five to
                        prepare and report a code of by-laws for the government of the Directory of
                        the Company. Col. Christian asked that Mr. Tams be named as chairman of the
                        Committee; the chair named Messrs. W. J. Tams, M. H. Effinger, Geo. E.
                        Price, Maj. J. B. Dorman, and Judge T. D. Houston as the Committee.</p>
                    <p>On motion of Col. Christian, the chair appointed Colonels Christian, Allan,
                        Pendleton, Baldwin and Patton, a Committee to wait on Gen. Lee and inform
                        him of his election to the Presidency of the Valley R. R.</p>
                    <p>On motion of Col Baldwin, the chair appointed a Committee, consisting of
                        Colonels J. B. Baldwin, M. G. Harman, B. Christian, J. W. Massie, Wm. Allan
                        and Edmond Pendleton and Judge H. W. Sheffey, to consider and report
                        business for the meeting, especially the organization and number of Board of
                        Directors.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Tams, chairman of the Committee on by-laws, made a report in writing,
                        which, on motion of Gen. Echols, was received and laid upon the table.</p>
                    <p>On motion the meeting adjourned to 2 P.M.</p>
                    <p>The meeting re-assembled at the appointed hour.</p>
                    <p>Col. Baldwin, chairman of the Committee on Directory, &amp;c., reported
                        as follows, viz:</p>
                    <p>The Committee respectfully recommended that the accompanying resolutions be
                        adopted by the stockholders and that eight Directors be chosen, <emph
                            rend="italic">four</emph> from Rockbridge, <emph rend="italic"
                        >two</emph> from Botetourt and <emph rend="italic">two</emph> from Staunton,
                        and in any increase of the numbers of Directors the new members shall be
                        selected with a view to present in due proportion the new stock hereafter to
                        be subscribed by cities, counties or others.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>,1. That a Board of Directors be now
                        selected to consist of eight members, in addition to the President.</p>
                    <p>2. That until otherwise ordered by the stockholders in general meeting, the
                        Board of Directors shall have the plenary power to do in the organization
                        and government of the company, whatever the stockholders themselves might
                        lawfully do in general meeting.</p>
                    <p>3. That the plenary power hereby conferred shall be construed to include the
                        right to increase the number of Directors and to fill all vacancies by
                        selections to be made upon the nomination of President, so as to give fair
                        representation to all interests concerned, and also to prescribe what number
                        shall, for any purpose, constitute a quorom of their body.</p>
                    <p>Judge Houston offered an amendment: "That the number of Directors be
                        increased to 19, so as to give Baltimore and the B. &amp; O. R. R., 16,
                        Roanoke 3, Botetourt 3, Staunton 2, and Rockbridge 5."</p>
                    <p>Judge Houston advocated, and Col. Baldwin, Col. Pendleton, and Maj. Dorman
                        opposed the amendment. Judge Houston called for a scale vote, which being
                        ordered, the amendment was defeated by a large majority and the preamble and
                        resolution as reported were adopted.</p>
                    <p>The election of Directors, on motion, then took place.</p>
                    <p>Col. Massie, of Rockbridge, nominated Col. Wm. Allan, Col. Wm. T. Poague,
                        Jas. E. A. Gibbs and J. T. Patton as Directors on the part of Rockbridge
                        county, and, on motion, they were unanimously elected.</p>
                    <p>Gen. E. Price, of Staunton, nominated Col. M. G. Harman and Capt. W. A. Burke
                        as Directors on the part of the City of Staunton, and, on motion, they were
                        unanimously elected.</p>
                    <p>Col. T. Anderson, of Botetourt, nominated Col. Edmond Pendleton and Judge T.
                        D. Houston as Directors on the part of Botetourt county, and on motion, they
                        were unanimously elected.</p>
                    <p>On motion of Col. Baldwin, the report of the Committee on by-laws was taken
                        from the table and referred to the new Board of Directors.</p>
                    <p>Judge Houston offered a resolution, from the supervisors of Botetourt county,
                        as follows:</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That in locating the Valley Railroad
                        through the county of Botetourt, the Corps of Engineers be instructed by the
                        Director to make a careful examination of the topography of the county with
                        a view of ascertaining the practicability of making Fincastle a point on
                        said route; and if the Corps should find such route practicable, but prefer
                        another on account of advantages in grade and distance, that then it be
                        required to report to the Directory the differences in grade and distance
                        between the two routes.</p>
                    <p>On motion the resolution was adopted.</p>
                    <p>Col. Christian, chairman of the Committee to inform Gen. Lee of his election
                        to the Presidency, reported that they had discharged that duty, and that
                        Gen. Lee accepted the Presidency.</p>
                    <p>On motion of Col. Christian, it was ordered that the report of the Committee
                        be received and spread upon the record.</p>
                    <p>Col. Massie, after some remarks, offered the following preamble and
                        resolution.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Whereas</emph>, the stockholders of the Valley Railroad
                        Company feel deeply grateful to Col. M. G. Harman for the earnest zeal and
                        energy which he has displayed in behalf of the interests of said Company,
                        whilst acting as its President, and whereas, it is due to services so
                        faithful that there should be some suitable acknowledgement of the same --
                        therefore, Resolved: that the thanks of said Company are hereby tendered to
                        Col. Harman, and as a further testimonial of the high appreciation in which
                        his labors in behalf of the Company are held, that --- shares of the Stock
                        of said Company be, and the same are hereby presented to the late President
                        of the Company, Col. M. G. Harman.</p>
                    <p>Col. Massie, in behalf of the county of Rockbridge, moved the adoption of the
                        preamble and resolution, and Judge Houston seconded the motion. They were
                        unanimously adopted. On motion of Judge Houston, the blank was filled with
                        thirty shares, and the resolution &amp;c. ordered to be spread upon the
                        record. Col. Harman returned thanks and pledged his continual efforts and
                        means in behalf of the Road.</p>
                    <p>Maj. Shumate stated to the meeting the partial results of the efforts of the
                        citizens, along the western line surveyed from Harrisonburg to Staunton, to
                        procure conditional subscriptions.</p>
                    <p>Col. Harman moved that the subscriptions referred to by Maj. Shumate, when
                        completed be referred to the Board of Directors. Adopted.</p>
                    <p>On motion of Col. Harman, the salary of the President was fixed at Five
                        Thousand dollars per annum, to commence from this date.</p>
                    <p>On motion of Gen. Echols, the meeting adjourned sine die.</p>
                    <p>JOHN T. ANDERSON,</p>
                    <p>JED HOTCHKISS, Sec'y President.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>J. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hotchkiss</ln>
                        <fn>Jed</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Massie</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dorman</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tams</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Effinger</ln>
                        <fn>M. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Price</ln>
                        <fn>George E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dorman</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houston</ln>
                        <fn>T. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pendleton</ln>
                        <fn>Edmond</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn>H. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echols</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Poague</ln>
                        <fn>William T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gibbs</ln>
                        <fn>James E. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patton</ln>
                        <fn>J. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Price</ln>
                        <fn>George E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>W. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shumate</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Editor reported on business conducted at a meeting of stockholders of the
                    Valley Railroad. Listed the motions given and passed, reports on the progress of
                    gaining subscriptions for the railroad, and the appointment of General Robert E.
                    Lee as President of the company.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1870.09.06.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Free School system went into operation on September 1st, and the
                    officers plan to open by October 1st.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fall</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Daniel Fall, "a well doing and highly respected citizen of this county,"
                    died near Churchville after being stricken with paralysis. He was 50 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Joseph</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Joseph</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper called attention to John and Elizabeth Joseph, "a healthy couple
                    residing near Churchville," who are 83 and 80 respectively and have lived
                    together for 62 years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Staunton Female Seminary</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J. I.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Rev. J. I. Miller planned to open the seminary on September 15th "with
                    a full corps of Professors and Teachers." Said the new buildings would properly
                    accommodate the students.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoneburner</ln>
                        <fn>D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pemberton</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burdett</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>N. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Stoneburner and Co., who had long published the Valley Virginian, has been
                    dissolved. D. Stoneburner and J. B. Pemberton bought out their former partners
                    J. H. Burdett and N. H. Anderson to found Stoneburner and Pemberton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Valley Musical Association</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The fourth annual meeting of the Valley Musical Association will be held at
                    New Providence Church, Rockbridge County. The Association "is doing a great deal
                    in the cultivation of the musical talent possessed by the citizens of the
                    Valley."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Sunday School Pic Nic</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Sunday School of Staunton's Southern Methodist Church held their annual
                    picnic in the grove near the cemetery. Many children attended and played a
                    variety of games. A feast was served followed by a treat of watermelon.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Tournament at Rockbridge Alum</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Cadet</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Cadet A. Harman of Staunton was the winning knight at the tournament at
                    Rockbridge Alum Springs on August 26th. He crowned Miss Emma C. Harman of
                    Charlottesville queen of the tournament.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Shenandoah Valley</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Editor of the Lynchburg <emph rend="italic">Virginian</emph>, who has
                        recently paid a visit to the lower portion of this noble Valley of Virginia,
                        thus speaks of it:</p>
                    <p>"The scenes of rural peace and plenty to be found in many portions of
                        Virginia are truly refreshing and cheering. Especially is this the case in
                        what is known as the great Shenandoah Valley. We have recently passed
                        through a large portion of that favored region, and were never more struck
                        with its beauty or with the abundant gifts which a munificent Providence has
                        showered upon it than them. From Staunton down to its lowest borders it is
                        one prolonged garden spot, blooming like a verdune-clad oasis. All traces of
                        grim war have been swept away by the hand of industry; and the brutal boast
                        of Sheridan that he would so desolate it that a crow would have to carry its
                        rations while flying over it, exists only in the infamy of the past. The
                        barns and dwellings which his torch-bearing marauders leveled to the earth
                        have been re-built; the destroyed fencing has been replaced, and overflowing
                        garners and waving fields of corn and grass proclaim the triumph of nature
                        over the barbarism of man. It is pleasant to behold the evidences of thrift
                        and prosperity which have so soon followed in the track of fire and sword.
                        The fertile fields which there abound, responsive to the toil of man are
                        giving out a generous yield of the fruits of the earth, and shedding abroad
                        a happy influence on the people.</p>
                    <p>* * * * * * *</p>
                    <p>"Nature was indeed in munificent and prodigal mood when she formed and
                        fashioned the great Valley of Virginia."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Copied an article from the Lynchburg Virginian praising the beauty and
                    bountifulness of the Valley. The editor assured readers the Valley had fully
                    recovered from the devastation of the war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stogdale</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ransbottom</ln>
                        <fn>Mary C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J. I.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Benjamin T. Stogdale and Miss Mary C. Ransbottom, both of Augusta, were
                    married near Churchville, Augusta County, on August 31st by the Rev. J. I.
                    Miller.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Collins</ln>
                        <fn>Nannie R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Collins</ln>
                        <fn>Richard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Collins</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Nannie R. Collins, daughter of Richard and Mary Collins, died in Staunton
                    on September 5th. She was 18 years old. Her funeral will be held at St. Francis
                    Church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>Effie Lee</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>W. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>M. V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Effie Lee Anderson, infant daughter of Col. W. D. and Mrs. M. V. Anderson,
                    died on September 2nd of congestion of the lungs. She was 1 month old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1870.09.06.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
