<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1870/va.au.ss.1870.11.29">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>11/28/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date>
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="11">November</month>
            <day norm="29"/>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1870.11.29.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1870.11.29.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad. Annual Meeting of the Stock-Holders</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>A. H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>H. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mason</ln>
                        <fn>C. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hill</ln>
                        <fn>N. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echols</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The stockholders of the Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad, including men from
                    Augusta, met in Richmond. The president delivered an address on the state of the
                    road and its finances.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>For the Spectator.</p>
                    <p>There is no subject so deeply interesting to the people of Staunton, at the
                        present time, as the extraordinary assessment, by the council, of one dollar
                        and ten cents tax on the hundred dollars worth of property, real and
                        personal, and one dollar per head water tax, which amounts with the license
                        tax to over $27,000. And this excessive and impolitic tax is about to be
                        collected from a people hardly able to meet such violent demands upon their
                        scant means, and this revenue system will result in the seizure of the
                        property of many of our confiding and unoffending workingmen.</p>
                    <p>As this tax is forced upon the tax-payers without their consent, they want to
                        know and they have a right to know, why this waste of their substance. But
                        we are told that it is to repair the damages caused by our late flood. --
                        With prudence and economy the bridges can be placed in the same condition
                        they were before the flood, without any extra tax. Let this heavy expense of
                        digging up one street and removing the dirt to another street, and digging
                        up the most substantial gutters and supplying them with inferior ones, be
                        dispensed with until the bridges are in good condition, and collect only
                        revenue enough to meet the present wants of the Town, as former Councils
                        have done, and obviate so heavy a pressure on the means of subsistence of
                        our people. To give an idea of the operation of this excessive tax, we will
                        give a case of a workingman for your calm consideration. He has a little
                        home valued at $2,000; a wife who does all the indoor work for her husband
                        and seven children, and in order to keep out of debt they do without many of
                        the comforts of life. What will be this workingman's tax on his little
                        property:</p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>City tax, at $1.10 -(2,000)</cell>
                            <cell>$22.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>City water tax at $1.00 per head</cell>
                            <cell>9.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>His watch dog</cell>
                            <cell>2.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>His tools and furniture, value $250</cell>
                            <cell>2.75</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>State tax</cell>
                            <cell>11.25</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Total</cell>
                            <cell>$47.00</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <p>Is it not a pity this workingman, who is by no means wealthy, should be
                        compelled to yield to the necessity of giving up his scanty means, as a day
                        laborer, to pay this excessive tax, leaving a bare remnant for the support
                        of his family? We do not think the judgment of the tax payers can be
                        convinced, that this excessive tax is wise, just, or proper, and we
                        earnestly and calmly ask for a modification of this tax, that the harmony of
                        our Town may not be disturbed and the tax payers driven to the alternative
                        of testing the validity of this ordinance. TAX-PAYERS.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Anonymous contributor "TAX-PAYERS" severely criticized the taxes levied by
                    the Council without voter consent. Claimed a lot of honest people would be
                    ruined and urged the Council to ease off the burden of taxes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1870.11.29.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The ladies of the M. E. Church South will hold a fair in the Town Hall
                    during Christmas week.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>Marshall</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Maj. Marshall Hanger left copies of the act in relation to the public roads
                    at the County Clerk's Office.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Free School System</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper asked the citizens of Augusta to make the new free school system
                    "as effective and as little objectionable as possible." Many people opposed the
                    establishment of the system, but now that it was in effect, the editor urged
                    citizens to get the best teachers and administrators.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Fair and Feast</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The ladies of the Baptist Church will hold a fair and feast beginning
                    December 14th to raise money to repair and paint their church building and add
                    an iron fence to the grounds. The steeple was struck by lightning last summer
                    and in dire need of repair.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Sunday School Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zimmerman</ln>
                        <fn>H. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGruder</ln>
                        <fn>T. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunter</ln>
                        <fn>C. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tucker</ln>
                        <fn>E. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waugh</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn>John L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Monroe</ln>
                        <fn>D. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Sunday School Convention met to discuss business, with Vice President
                    H. F. Zimmerman presiding. They resolved to institute a uniform curriculum and
                    called on all schools to subscribe to regular Sunday School periodicals.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Byerly</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ryan</ln>
                        <fn>Annie Lee</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Liggatt</ln>
                        <fn>J. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William H. Byerly of Spring Hill, Augusta County, and Miss Annie Lee Ryan
                    of Shenandoah were married in Rockingham County on November 23rd by the Rev. J.
                    F. Liggatt.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickle</ln>
                        <fn>Yeizer M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parker</ln>
                        <fn>Henrietta M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parker</ln>
                        <fn>Maurice</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Yeizer M. Bickle and Miss Henrietta M. Parker, daughter of Maurice Parker,
                    all of Augusta, were married on November 23rd at the residence of the bride's
                    father near Staunton by the Rev. H. H. Kennedy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Teabo</ln>
                        <fn>Alex H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Worsham</ln>
                        <fn>Sallie V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Williams</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Alex H. Teabo and Miss Sallie V. Worsham, both of Staunton, were married by
                    the Rev. Mr. Williams.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bishop</ln>
                        <fn>James M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Glass</ln>
                        <fn>Teresa E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Forsyth</ln>
                        <fn>H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James M. Bishop and Miss Teresa E. Glass, both of Staunton, were married on
                    November 20th at the residence of the bride's parents by the Rev. H. H. Forsyth.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hardy</ln>
                        <fn>Charles Lynn</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hardy</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hardy</ln>
                        <fn>Mary V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Charles Lynn Hardy, son of John M. and Mary V. Hardy of Staunton, died on
                    November 26th of croup. He was 3 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Wilson died at his residence near Swoope's Depot. He was 50 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stribling</ln>
                        <fn>Harriet M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>Nicholas K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Harriet M. Stribling died in Staunton at the residence of Nicholas K.
                    Trout on November 27th. She was 50 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ide</ln>
                        <fn>William Baldwin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ide</ln>
                        <fn>E. Louis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ide</ln>
                        <fn>Sallie A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Willie Baldwin Ide, infant son of Prof. E. Louis and Sallie A. Ide, died in
                    Staunton on November 26th. "This is the fifth child these afflicted parents have
                    been called upon to give up to the sleep of death in about three years. Of a
                    lovely group of six, one is left. What heart that believes in the efficacy of
                    prayer will not ascend to Him, who comforteth those that are cast down."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1870.11.29.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
