<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1870/va.au.ss.1870.08.16">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>11/21/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date>
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="08">August</month>
            <day norm="16"/>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1870.08.16.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1870.08.16.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>A Word to Anti-Subscription Voters</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>As we stated last week, the defeat of the subscription by this county of
                        $300,000 to the capital stock of the Valley R. R. Company was due chiefly to
                        the fact that the impression was successfully made in the Eastern portion of
                        the county that the Shenandoah Valley R. R. would be built through that part
                        of the county without cost to the citizens along its line. Though this was
                        the <emph rend="italic">chief</emph> cause of the defeat of the subscription
                        to the Valley Road, it was not due <emph rend="italic">wholly</emph> to that
                        cause. Many in the county voted against the subscription because they
                        believed that the town was allowed to vote on the question for the purpose
                        of carrying the subscription though a majority in the county might vote
                        against it -- that it was done on the theory that the affirmative majority
                        in the town would exceed the negative majority in the county, and thus the
                        subscription would be carried. Taking this view of the subject, and wishing
                        to rebuke what they conceived to be a purpose to force the subscription,
                            <emph rend="italic">nolens volens</emph>, upon the county, quite a
                        number, we believe, voted against the subscription, who, otherwise, would
                        not have done so. We believe that the voters of the county, if the question
                        be submitted to them free from "entangling alliances with the town, will
                        vote a subscription of $200,000. What we now desire to see is a movement on
                        the part of the <emph rend="italic">voters of the county</emph> to have the
                        question of subscribing that sum submitted to their vote. We would be
                        especially pleased to see this movement inaugurated by those who voted <emph
                            rend="italic">against</emph> the subscription. It would present a noble
                        spectacle, and furnish opportunity to win honor and enviable distinction
                        which is but seldom vouchsafed. Those who are now reproached for defeating
                        the subscription necessary to secure the other conditional subscriptions
                        amounting to $2,900,000, and thus defeating wholly this great and valuable
                        Railroad project, would then have the credit of securing the amount
                        necessary to make this great improvement, and they would be hailed as public
                        benefactors, and their praises would be on every tongue.</p>
                    <p>The Railroad men -- builders of improvements -- now value you as of little
                        worth; but will not the stone rejected by the builders become the head of
                        the corner? We do not despair yet of obtaining a subscription by the county
                        to this improvement, which would be so prolific of benefits to the county.
                        We appeal to the calm reason, the dispassionate reflection, the careful
                        calculation, the enlightened self-interest of the voters of the county. We
                        have great confidence in the sober second thought of our people, and believe
                        that they will not fail to reverse the decision they recently rendered. It
                        would be manly in them to have the independence to do so. We appeal from an
                        excited and biased, to a calm and unprejudiced judgement.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Explained the reasons why the Valley Railroad subscription went down to
                    defeat. Though disappointed, the editor did not lose hope and believed that a
                    lot of people who voted against the measure will have second thoughts.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Subscribe Stock to the Valley R. R.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The defeat of the subscription to the Valley R. R. is not only unfortunate on
                        account of its jeopardizing that important enterprise, but it places Augusta
                        county in the unenviable position of having, by her opposition, and arrays
                        against her the opinion, prejudices and interests of all the other counties
                        of the Valley. She thus stands in a humiliating position which she has never
                        before occupied. A plan has been adopted to enable Augusta to make up, by
                        private subscription, what she, in her corporate capacity, has failed to do.
                        Many of those who voted against the tax, declared their willingness to make
                        private subscriptions. They now have a chance to show their sincerity. The
                        friends of the Road can at least subscribe what they would have paid in tax
                        if the vote had been in its favor. Let all who feel able subscribe at once.
                        The time is short. What is done must be done quickly. All subscriptions thus
                        made must be in before the 1st of September. If you feel able and willing to
                        subscribe anything, hunt up one of these papers and subscribe at once. There
                        are a large number of them in circulation. Remember this opportunity to
                        retrieve the credit of Augusta County will only add doubly to the prejudice
                        against her, if it be lost.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Called on Augusta voters to reverse the humiliation of the defeat of the
                    Valley Railroad subscription by privately investing in the railroad. Claimed the
                    reputation of the county could rise again if private subscription enabled the
                    railroad to be built.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Tournament and Ball</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn>H. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carrington</ln>
                        <fn>C. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Opie</ln>
                        <fn>John N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allen</ln>
                        <fn>Brown</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whittington</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>John T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>George D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turk</ln>
                        <fn>Rudolph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Randolph</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Berkeley</ln>
                        <fn>Carter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lyman</ln>
                        <fn>R. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>James H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Effinger</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>Marshall</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hogshead</ln>
                        <fn>M. W. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A "Grand Tournament and Fancy Ball" is planned for Stribling Springs on
                    August 18th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Conservative Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John B. Baldwin announced that the Conservatives of Augusta County will
                    meet on August 22nd to select superintendents for the county, townships, and
                    wards to make up the County Committee.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper denounced any attempt to split Virginia along the old
                    Democrat-Whig party lines. Claimed the only political effort that mattered was
                    defeating radicalism. "Unity and energy are now wanted to disenthrall Virginia."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1870.08.16.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fletcher</ln>
                        <fn>P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Rev. P. Fletcher, Principal, will open the second session of the Loch
                    Willow Female School in Churchville on September 14th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kurtz</ln>
                        <fn>John R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John R. Kurtz, "that vigilant police officer," arrested and fined a "XVth
                    amendment" for galloping his horse through the streets.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>White Sulphur Ball</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Masquerade and Fancy Dress Ball held at White Sulphur Springs was a
                    huge success. The proceeds from the $1 admission tickets went to help the
                    sufferers of an accident at Jerry's Run.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Dr. Dellinger will replace M. P. Bledsoe as manager of Staunton's American
                    Hotel.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>"Death of a Railroad Man"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunter</ln>
                        <fn>J. Albert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. Albert Hunter of Staunton died at Salt Sulphur Springs and was buried at
                    the Episcopal Church. "Quiet in manner and prompt in the discharge of duty, the
                    C. and O. R. R. Company has lost a faithful employee, and his brother railroad
                    men a loved companion whose memory they will be slow to forget."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Valley R. R. Stock</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On Thursday night last, the 11th inst., a meeting was held in the Court-House
                        of this place -- Mayor N. K. Trout, chairman, and the editors of the town
                        papers secretaries -- at which resolutions, offered by Wm. H. Tams, Esq.,
                        were adopted, recommending the Town Council to submit to the vote of the
                        qualified voters of the town, the proposition to subscribe the additional
                        sum of $50,000 to the capital stock of the Valley R. R. Company.</p>
                    <p>On the 8th inst., a similar meeting was held in Lexington which adopted a
                        resolution to submit to the voters the question of subscribing the sum of
                        $30,000 to the capital stock of the Valley Railroad Company.</p>
                    <p>There were some voters in the county who voted against the subscription by
                        the county for the reason that they do not think it right for one man to
                        vote a tax upon another against his will. This class of voters have now an
                        opportunity to take individual stock, and we hope that many of them will
                        avail themselves of it. Vindicate your consistency and show your faith by
                        your works in taking individual stock as your means will justify.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>N. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mayor</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tams</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The editor reported on several meetings held to encourage citizens to
                    privately subscribe to the Valley Railroad. Believed a lot of people voted down
                    the original proposal because they did not want to tax anyone against their
                    will.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Masters</ln>
                        <fn>Dewitt C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>Susan Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fletcher</ln>
                        <fn>P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dewitt C. Masters and Miss Susan Catharine Hanger, both of Augusta, were
                    married in Churchville on August 4th by the Rev. P. Fletcher.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Michie</ln>
                        <fn>E. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Michie</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. E. W. Michie, wife of Thomas J. Michie, died on August 15th. She was
                    71 years old. The funeral will be held at the Episcopal Church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1870.08.16.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
