<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1870/va.au.ss.1870.05.31">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>11/17/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date>
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day norm="31"/>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1870.05.31.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1870.05.31.02" exists="no">
            <div type="l">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>To the Tax-Payers of Staunton</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>GENTLEMEN: -- The election of Thursday is over, and we desire no criminations
                        or re-crimination; but while the election is over the politics and
                        principles involved in that election are not over, and may not be in our
                        generation, and as the much deplored social irritation, and unfriendly
                        demonstrations are past, the issues involved are very grave to the
                        tax-payers, and we invite, as it deserves, your earnest consideration. The
                            <emph rend="italic">real</emph> and <emph rend="italic">only</emph>
                        issue in the canvass was a large increase in the debt of the town, and
                        whether those who were in favor of the increased debt or those who were
                        opposed to it should be elected. <emph rend="italic">And the only object of
                            the gentlemen who organized the Court-house meeting was to defeat those
                            who had been, and are still, opposed to an increase of the town
                        debt;</emph> and they have succeeded in electing some that have not one
                        dollar's worth of real property to tax, but whether they will accomplish
                        their purpose, time alone will tell. It won't do, tax-payers, to say, when
                        the tax gatherer comes around, that your hands were tied -- that you voted
                        under pledges.</p>
                    <p>No amount of ridicule can change facts, or turn us aside from what we believe
                        to be the interest of the town, in which we have a deep interest. The facts,
                        in this case, go to show that we are correct in our assertions. What are the
                        facts? The present debt of the town, now due, in round numbers, $27,650;
                        Valley Railroad subscription, $100,000; proposed increase of debt for steam
                        fire engine, &amp;c., $10,000; purchase of plot for C. &amp; O. R.
                        R. work shops $6,000; and additional Valley Railroad subscription $27,000,
                        making a total of $170,650. This is the amount of debt, then, proposed to be
                        saddled on the tax-payers of poor little Staunton.</p>
                    <p>Now, let us see what our taxes will be on the real and personal property of
                        the town, in order to carry this debt. The interest on $170,650, at 6 per
                        cent per annum, is $10,239; present amount necessary to pay the current
                        expenses of the town $10,000; add $5,000 for school purposes, and $6,000 for
                        State taxes, and you have $31,239, to be raised annually by tax on the real
                        and personal property of Staunton. You will remember, too, that the head tax
                        is reduced to fifty cents, and the license tax is prohibited by the
                        constitution of Va., which tax has heretofore paid two-thirds of the entire
                        tax of the town. So the sum of $31,239 must be levied on the real and
                        personal property. The present assessed value of the real estate is
                        $967,128, and put down the personal property at $300,000 -- a very large
                        estimate -- and you have $1,267,128, upon which to be taxed, and in order to
                        raise annually the $31,239. We must pay a tax of 2 1/2 per cent on the
                        dollar. -- To illustrate -- on a house worth $5,000 you now pay $20 tax; you
                        then will pay $125.00.</p>
                    <p>These are facts -- facts that will make the tax payer groan. We ask you not
                        to let a bitter spirit of hatred, and the <emph rend="italic">false and
                            malicious cry of nigger and Radical, which was raised in this canvass to
                            cover up the real issue before the people</emph>, cause you to shut your
                        eyes to what is going on about you in the impoverished condition of our
                        town, and the burdens of debt under which our people groan. Ask the Sheriff
                        how many executions are in his hands now for collection. Do you feel like
                        entering upon this untried sea of debt and taxation? There may be a bright,
                        delusive, promise, which never will be realized, held out to induce you to
                        submit. Stop and consider before you consent to be bound by these biting
                        chains of taxation.</p>
                    <p>In conclusion, we will state that we still adhere to, and no amount of abuse
                        and slang can drive us one inch from the position heretofore taken, and when
                        the people understand our position they will appreciate our motives, and we
                        do not mean to have our hands tied and quietly submit to the gentlemen who
                        organized the Court-house meeting. And whenever they came before the people
                        to carry into effect the objects that prompted that meeting, we will fight
                        them at every step. Tax-payers, we ask you to investigate these facts and
                        figures for yourselves, and see "who is who," and what is at the bottom of
                        this whole affair.</p>
                    <p>INDEPENDENT TICKET.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An anonymous writer deeply criticized the plans of the recently elected
                    candidates to increase the debts of the town. He displayed figures showing the
                    town's current debt and the taxes property-holders must pay to relieve it. Vowed
                    to fight against rising taxes at every turn.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1870.05.31.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On yesterday evening, for the first time in Staunton, the colored people
                        turned out in procession to decorate the graves of the Federal soldiers
                        interred in the cemetery near the Lunatic Asylum. The procession was large,
                        orderly and very well conducted, consisting of men, women and children,
                        bearing wreaths and boquets of flowers, and a large U.S. flag, and any
                        number of small "stars and stripes."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spectator briefly described a memorial service held in honor of Federal
                    soldiers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Election Day</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>ELECTION DAY. -- The election for municipal officers of Staunton resulted in
                        the election of the ticket nominated at the primary election on last
                        Tuesday. The day was a very disagreeable one, as there was a constant
                        falling of rain. The contest between the "Independent" and "Conservative"
                        tickets was spirited and brought out almost the entire registered vote of
                        both wards. Mr. Trout's majority for mayor is 74. The cry of "Radical"
                        swamped the "Independents," and they have applied themselves with fishing
                        tackle, &amp;c., preparatory to a trip up "Salt River." -- Some of them
                        have already secured tickets, guaranteeing them a "free passage."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Conservatives won the municipal election, defeating the Independent
                    ticket.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Presbyterian Fair</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The ladies of the Presbyterian Church hope many citizens will attend their
                    fair. The highlight of the event will consist of a dinner, including ice cream,
                    ices, and strawberries.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Election Results</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>N.K. TROUT, Conservative, for Mayor</cell>
                            <cell>JOHN B. EVANS, Independent, for Mayor</cell>
                            <cell>JAS. F. PATTERSON, Conservative, for Clerk</cell>
                            <cell>S.T. PHILLIPS, Conservative, for Com's Att'y</cell>
                            <cell>J.T. Parrent, Conservative, for Sergeant</cell>
                            <cell>JNO. M. CARROLL, Conservative, for Treasurer</cell>
                            <cell>HEBER KERR, Independent, for Treasurer</cell>
                            <cell>GEO. H. HUDSON, Conservative, for Com'r of Rev</cell>
                            <cell>J.M. HARDY, Conservative, for Councilman</cell>
                            <cell>W.H.H. LYNN, Conservative for Councilman</cell>
                            <cell>W.H. GORMAN, Conservative for Councilman</cell>
                            <cell>WM. L. BALTHIS, Conservative for Councilman</cell>
                            <cell>J.H. WATERS, Conservative for Councilman</cell>
                            <cell>W.L. LUSHBAUGH, Conservative for Councilman</cell>
                            <cell>C.T. Cochran, Conservative for Councilman</cell>
                            <cell>W.J. NELSON, Conservative for Councilman</cell>
                            <cell>W.A. BURKE, Conservative for Councilman</cell>
                            <cell>J.B. SCHERER, Jr., Conservative for Councilman</cell>
                            <cell>R.H. CATLETT, Conservative for Councilman</cell>
                            <cell>W.B. KAYSER, Independent for Councilman</cell>
                            <cell>R.G. BICKLE, Independent for Councilman</cell>
                            <cell>B.T. BAGBY, Independent for Councilman</cell>
                            <cell>H.A. GLEN, Independent for Councilman</cell>
                            <cell>W. BLACKBURN, Independent for Councilman</cell>
                            <cell>D.E. STRASBURG, Independent for Councilman</cell>
                            <cell>JOS. EARMAN, Independent for Councilman</cell>
                            <cell>J.F. BEARD, Independent for Councilman</cell>
                            <cell>A.H. FULTZ, Independent for Councilman</cell>
                            <cell>JAS. A. PIPER, Independent for Councilman</cell>
                            <cell>G.F. ELICK, Independent for Councilman</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>WARD NO. 1</cell>
                            <cell>246</cell>
                            <cell>156</cell>
                            <cell>374</cell>
                            <cell>379</cell>
                            <cell>406</cell>
                            <cell>279</cell>
                            <cell>123</cell>
                            <cell>403</cell>
                            <cell>313</cell>
                            <cell>285</cell>
                            <cell>288</cell>
                            <cell>270</cell>
                            <cell>259</cell>
                            <cell>253</cell>
                            <cell>251</cell>
                            <cell>254</cell>
                            <cell>246</cell>
                            <cell>247</cell>
                            <cell>247</cell>
                            <cell>178</cell>
                            <cell>167</cell>
                            <cell>156</cell>
                            <cell>148</cell>
                            <cell>152</cell>
                            <cell>149</cell>
                            <cell>145</cell>
                            <cell>147</cell>
                            <cell>143</cell>
                            <cell>84</cell>
                            <cell>36</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>WARD NO. 2</cell>
                            <cell>200</cell>
                            <cell>216</cell>
                            <cell>354</cell>
                            <cell>345</cell>
                            <cell>417</cell>
                            <cell>237</cell>
                            <cell>164</cell>
                            <cell>419</cell>
                            <cell>282</cell>
                            <cell>261</cell>
                            <cell>245</cell>
                            <cell>218</cell>
                            <cell>211</cell>
                            <cell>210</cell>
                            <cell>210</cell>
                            <cell>206</cell>
                            <cell>204</cell>
                            <cell>202</cell>
                            <cell>200</cell>
                            <cell>219</cell>
                            <cell>223</cell>
                            <cell>215</cell>
                            <cell>214</cell>
                            <cell>206</cell>
                            <cell>207</cell>
                            <cell>210</cell>
                            <cell>205</cell>
                            <cell>204</cell>
                            <cell>123</cell>
                            <cell>73</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>TOTAL</cell>
                            <cell>446</cell>
                            <cell>372</cell>
                            <cell>728</cell>
                            <cell>724</cell>
                            <cell>823</cell>
                            <cell>516</cell>
                            <cell>287</cell>
                            <cell>822</cell>
                            <cell>595</cell>
                            <cell>546</cell>
                            <cell>533</cell>
                            <cell>488</cell>
                            <cell>470</cell>
                            <cell>463</cell>
                            <cell>461</cell>
                            <cell>460</cell>
                            <cell>450</cell>
                            <cell>449</cell>
                            <cell>447</cell>
                            <cell>397</cell>
                            <cell>390</cell>
                            <cell>371</cell>
                            <cell>362</cell>
                            <cell>358</cell>
                            <cell>356</cell>
                            <cell>355</cell>
                            <cell>352</cell>
                            <cell>347</cell>
                            <cell>207</cell>
                            <cell>109</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>372</cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>287</cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>MAJORITIES</cell>
                            <cell>74</cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>229</cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <p>AUGUSTA COUNTY.</p>
                    <p>The following is a list of the officers elected in the various townships of
                        this county on Thursday last. We have not the space to give tabular
                        statements of all the votes polled, but merely give the names of those
                        elected and to what offices, and the time for which the Justices and
                        Constables were drawn.</p>
                    <p>BEVERLY MANOR.</p>
                    <p>For Supervisor John Paris received 363 votes.</p>
                    <p>" do Sam'l K. Taylor 1 "</p>
                    <p>" Collector Jas. N. McFarland " 213 "</p>
                    <p>" do Jas. W. Houseman " 142 "</p>
                    <p>do Clerk Joseph R. Meriken " 224 "</p>
                    <p>do do Wm. K. Piper " 85 "</p>
                    <p>do do W. H. Wayland " 36 "</p>
                    <p>do Assessor John M. Kinney " 336 "</p>
                    <p>do Com'r of Roads Jas. Henderson 262 "</p>
                    <p>do do do Michael McAleer, 2 "</p>
                    <p>do do do John A. Harman, 31 "</p>
                    <p>do do do Henry Mahaney 56 "</p>
                    <p>do Over. of Poor Michael McAleer, 242 "</p>
                    <p>do do do Wm. Croany 86 "</p>
                    <p>do Justices of the Peace L. R. Waddell, (1 year), A. W. Harman, (2 years),
                        David Henkel, (3 years). For Constables -- J. T. Little, (1 year,) Wm. S.
                        Young, (2 years), John A. Stuart, (3 years).</p>
                    <p>MIDDLE RIVER. -- John D. Craig, supervisor; Wm. L. Mowry, collector; Stuart
                        M. Crawford, clerk; J. Alex. Kerr, assessor; D. R. Henton, com'r of roads;
                        David Myers O. of P.; Chas. S. Roller, 1 year, John W. Gillespie, 2 years,
                        and Casper Koyner, 3 years J. of P.; James C. McClung, 1 year, Arthur T.
                        Grooms, 2 years, and Samuel N. Patterton, 3 years, Constables.</p>
                    <p>NORTH RIVER. -- John G. Fulton, Sr., supervisor; John G. Fulton, Jr., clerk;
                        Peachy W. Wheeler, assessor; Robert G. Byers, collector; Phillip Airheart,
                        commissioner of roads; John C. Rusmiel, overseer of poor; Thomas S.
                        Hogshead, 3 years, Wm. S. Hiser, 2 years, James T. Clarke, 1 year, Justices
                        of the Peace; Nelson Andrew, 1 year, Jonas Lowman, 2 years, and James F.
                        Davis, 3 years, constables.</p>
                    <p>SOUTH RIVER. -- Dr. T. W. Shelton, supervisor; Charles R. Haynes, collector;
                        Hugh N. Bateman, com'r of roads; Charles Brooks, overseer of poor; W. W.
                        Clineqinst, 1 year, David W. Coitier, 2 years, and John Huff, 3 years,
                        Justices of the Peace; Robert M. Hix, 1 year, Chas. R. Haynes, 2 years, and
                        William H. Grooms, 3 years, constables.</p>
                    <p>RIVERHEADS. -- William T. Rush, supervisor; John S. McCorkle, clerk; George
                        P. Lightner, assessor; D. A. Ott, collector; Adam Rusmiel, overseer of poor;
                        John H. Rush, 1 year, Irving W. Gilkeson. 2 years, and A. A. Sproul 3 years,
                        Justices of Peace; David B. Zimmerman, 1 year, Wm. H. Cale, 2 years, John B.
                        Smith, 3 years, constables.</p>
                    <p>PASTURES. -- Henry B. Seig, supervisor; Lewis R. Boswell, assessor; Joseph A.
                        Wilson, collector; John Waldrop, clerk; Baxter Crawford, com'r of roads;
                        James M. Lickliter, overseer of poor; George A. Shuey, 1 year, John S. Guy,
                        2 years, Benjamin O. Furguson, 3 years, Justices of Peace; Geo. Lacky, 1
                        year, Thos. H. Cross, 2 years, James F. Hizer, 3 years, constables.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Printed the results of the election for municipal offices in Augusta.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoover</ln>
                        <fn>James M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Teaford</ln>
                        <fn>Rachel M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James M. Hoover and Miss Rachel M. Teaford, both of Augusta, were married
                    near Staunton on May 26th by the Rev. J. L. Miller.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ayres</ln>
                        <fn>William L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rice</ln>
                        <fn>Martha R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Forsyth</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William L. Ayres of Rockbridge and Mrs. Martha R. Rice of Augusta were
                    married in Staunton at the American Hotel on May 19th by the Rev. W. H. Forsyth.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Churchman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Churchman died at his Augusta residence on May 29th. He was 78 years
                    old. A funeral will be held at the Episcopal Church in Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Lucy V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Lucy V. Myers died in Maryland on May 21st of congestion of the lungs
                    induced by measles. She was 28 years old. She had joined St. John's Reformed
                    Church in Augusta County "on profession of faith, and died in calm and confident
                    hope of blissful immortality."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gorman</ln>
                        <fn>Frances DeSales</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gorman</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gorman</ln>
                        <fn>Julia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Frances DeSales Gorman, son of William H. and Julia Gorman, died in
                    Staunton on May 18th after a protracted illness. "This little boy, who has left
                    behind him so many aching hearts, was the pet of the community."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1870.05.31.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
