<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1870/va.au.ss.1870.08.23">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>11/22/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date>
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="08">August</month>
            <day norm="23"/>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1870.08.23.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1870.08.23.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Tournament and Ball</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phillips</ln>
                        <fn>S. Travers</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Opie</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moorman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parker</ln>
                        <fn>E. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gold</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGuffin</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eskridge</ln>
                        <fn>Bettie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>Alex</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>Lizzie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn>H. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carrington</ln>
                        <fn>C. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lyman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A Grand Tournament and Fancy Ball was held at Stribling Springs on August
                    18th. The knights assembled in front of the hotel for an afternoon of riding.
                    Judge H. W. Sheffey delivered the coronation address to the queen of the ball.
                    The evening ended with a quadruple Virginia Reel at half past two in the
                    morning.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Public Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In pursuance of the call of the County Superintendent published last week, a
                        meeting for the purpose of electing County, Township, and Ward
                        Superintendents was held in the Courthouse on Monday, the 22d inst. On
                        motion Col. Ceo. Baylor was called to the Chair, and Dr. Ceo. S. Walker was
                        elected Secretary.</p>
                    <p>On motion of Col. Jo. B. Baldwin, the following resolutions were adopted
                        unanimously.</p>
                    <p>1. <emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That the Conservatives of Augusta
                        county accept the plan of party organization recommended by the Conservative
                        members of the Virginia Legislature, and recognize the State Central
                        Committee appointed by them as the authorized representatives of the
                        Conservative party of Virginia.</p>
                    <p>2. That in conformity to the plan of organization, and in pursuance of the
                        notice published in the county newspapers this meeting will now proceed to
                        select a Superintendent for the county, one for each Township, and one for
                        each Ward of the town of Staunton to constitute together the county
                        committee.</p>
                    <p>3. That the County Committee shall have the exclusive authority to call
                        County, Township or Ward Conventions, and to prescribe in advance the mode
                        of selecting delegates, and the scale of voting in such Convention.</p>
                    <p>On motion of Jam. J. Marshall Hanger, Col. Jo. B. Baldwin was unanimously
                        re-elected Superintendent of the County.</p>
                    <p>The following Ward and Township Superintendents were then elected.</p>
                    <p>Staunton Ward No. 1. Col. Bolivar Christian.</p>
                    <p>Staunton Ward No. 2, Col. M. G. Harman.</p>
                    <p>Beverly Manor Township, Jacob Baylor, Esc.</p>
                    <p>River heads Township, Am. F. Smith, Esc.</p>
                    <p>South River Township, Ceo. A. Bruce, Esc.</p>
                    <p>Middle River Township, Capt. Chad. S. Grata.</p>
                    <p>North River Township, J. G. Fulton, Esc.</p>
                    <p>Pastures Township, Jam. Am. M. Tate.</p>
                    <p>On motion of Am. A. Burke, the meeting resolved to recommend that a District
                        Convention be held in Harrisonburg on Wednesday, the 5th day of October, for
                        the purpose of nominating a candidate for Congress.</p>
                    <p>On motion, the meeting adjourned.</p>
                    <p>Ceo. BAYLOR, President.</p>
                    <p>Ceo. S. WALKER, Secretary.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>George S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>J. Marshall</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Jam.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>Bolivar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>William F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bruce</ln>
                        <fn>George A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grata</ln>
                        <fn>Charles S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fulton</ln>
                        <fn>J. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tate</ln>
                        <fn>William M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Jam.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>George S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Local Conservatives held a meeting to elect county, town, and ward
                    superintendents. Passed a series of resolutions to that effect and printed the
                    names of the men chosen as superintendents.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Old Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>From a communication bearing the above caption, published in the Rochester
                        (N. Y.) <emph rend="italic">Union and Advertiser</emph>, we make the
                        following extract:</p>
                    <p>"A gentleman by the name of Winthrow, from Waynesboro' -- a native Virginian,
                        a merchant, and a man of intelligence and strength -- a good social,
                        princely man, who was "cleaned out" by the war, has made large efforts and
                        written much in our New York papers, and even in our own city papers, to
                        induce "Yankee enterprise and capitol" to strike in Virginia, and with some
                        success. But another gentleman, Mr. N. H. Hotchkiss, a native of this State,
                        but long time a resident of Virginia, was in our city a few days since
                        beating up recruits for the South and using such arguments as are almost
                        irresistible. This Mr. Hotchkiss is now at Baltimore, Md., and has been
                        persuaded to take the agency of the Richmond &amp; York River and
                        Chesapeake &amp; Ohio railroads, and any one to hear Mr. Hotchkiss tell
                        the story of what they want in that country and they can do for men that
                            <emph rend="italic">mean business</emph> will see that a great promising
                        field is open for the true citizens of these United States in the Old
                        Dominion.</p>
                    <p>But what I was particularly desirous to say in this communication, was about
                        the Virginia Springs, and the interest Mr. Hotchkiss has in sending
                        passengers to them; for of all the places of resort for pleasure and by
                        invalids, these old Virginia Springs claim precedence. On going to Baltimore
                        one should go to No. 90 Light st., where he can take choice of routes -- by
                        rail with splendid cars, or by water to Richmond in magnificent
                    steamers."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Withrow</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hotchkiss</ln>
                        <fn>N. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Printed an article from a New York paper that reported on the efforts of a
                    few southerners who tried to encourage investment in southern railroads.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1870.08.23.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>Lizzie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Lizzie Kinney's school for children will re-open on September 14th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Risk</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. H. Risk, census enumerator, estimated the population of Staunton at
                    5,120.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ruhl</ln>
                        <fn>B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Madam B. Ruhl recently moved to Staunton and will take charge of the
                    Wesleyan Female Institute's music department.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Ladies Festival</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The ladies of Augusta are holding a festival on August 24th. They will
                    serve refreshments and a "sumptuous dinner." The proceeds will cover the costs
                    of renovating the "old church" and its grounds.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Judge Alexander B. Cochran</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The gentleman whose name heads this article is one of the young men of
                        Virginia who is just entering upon a career of public usefulness and
                        distinction. He gave early indications of great promise, and won laurels at
                        the University of Virginia. After his academic course was finished he
                        retired to his home and engaged in the study and then the practice of the
                        law; from the pursuit of which he was called by his countymen to represent
                        them in the House of Delegates of Virginia. -- Few young men, untrumpeted,
                        have so soon commanded the attention of the House and won its confidence,
                        and fewer, under the circumstances which have surrounded the present
                        Assembly, have continued to hold this attention and confidence. Judge
                        Cochran at the close of the late session possessed, probably in a greater
                        degree than any other member, the ear of the House, and though he rarely
                        trespassed upon its time, he never addressed it without effect. His
                        position, as chairman of the committee of finance, imposed upon him much
                        labor and called for a great mental exertion. He proved fully equal to all
                        the demands upon him.</p>
                    <p>As a clear, forcible and logical debater he had no superior in the House. He
                        was one of the few who thought for himself, and rare indeed was it that he
                        did not lead the House to <emph rend="italic">his</emph> conclusion. When
                        the General Assembly was called on to elect city Judges he was selected as
                        eminently fit to wear the ermine, as well for his irreproachable moral
                        character as for his native intellect and legal attainments. For many weeks
                        he kept the question of acceptance under advisement, and finally concluded
                        that he could better serve his constituents in the House of Delegates than
                        on the Bench, and he allowed the period for qualification to pass by
                        default.</p>
                    <p>We can but congratulate the State, and especially the people of Augusta, upon
                        this determination of Judge Cochran, for if there ever was a time when
                        Virginia needed in her legislative halls men of enlarged views, with
                        learning sufficient to enforce them and character to give them weight, now
                        is that time, and Judge Cochran is precisely one of that sort.</p>
                    <p>We feel satisfied that there is a brighter future yet in reserve for this
                        gentleman, and we doubt not that his constituents will be quite ready to
                        secure his abilities and retain his services until the State shall demand
                        him for a yet more enlarged arena.</p>
                    <p>Judge Cochran has it in his power to win the highest honors, and for him we
                        have not the fear that the glitter of present place will withdraw him from
                        the earnest pursuit of those studies necessary to make the finished
                        statesman. He has youth, strength, health and intellect, polished by a
                        generous education, needing only the spur of ambition to meet the fullest
                        hopes of his friends.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor highly praised the work of Judge Alexander B. Chochran. Outlined
                    his career thus far and predicted even greater future opportunities for him to
                    serve the interests of the county.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Proceedings of the County Court--In Vacation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>John S. Guy and Benj. O. Ferguson qualified as Justices of the Peace in
                        Pastures Township.</p>
                    <p>Stuart M. Crawford qualified as Clerk in Middle River Township.</p>
                    <p>John Waldrop qualified as Clerk in Pastures township.</p>
                    <p>Thomas H. Cross qualified as Constable in Pastures township.</p>
                    <p>Jas. Henderson qualified as Com'r of Roads in Beverly Manor Township.</p>
                    <p>The following appointments have been made by Judge Hendren to fill the
                        vacancies of officers who failed to qualify in the time prescribed by law.</p>
                    <p>Saml. A. East, Supervisor, North River Township, <emph rend="italic"
                        >vice</emph> J. Givans Fultop.</p>
                    <p>Jo. W. Crist, Justice of Peace, North River Township, <emph rend="italic"
                            >vice</emph> Jas. T. Clarke.</p>
                    <p>Am. H. Wooddell, Constable, North River Township, <emph rend="italic"
                        >vice</emph> Nelson Andrew.</p>
                    <p>Jo. T. Litten, Overseer of Poor, North River Township, <emph rend="italic"
                            >vice</emph> Jo. C. Rusmisel.</p>
                    <p>Am. Crawford, Supervisor, Middle River Township, <emph rend="italic"
                        >vice</emph> J. D. Craig.</p>
                    <p>David Myers, Overseer of Poor, Middle River Township, re-appointed.</p>
                    <p>Lucien M. Donaho, appointed by the State Auditor, Commissioner of Revenue,
                        1st District, <emph rend="italic">vice</emph> Jo. Towberman, resigned,
                        qualified and entered upon the duties of his office. -- <emph rend="italic"
                            >Vindicator.</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guy</ln>
                        <fn>John S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ferguson</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Stuart M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waldrop</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cross</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henderson</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hendren</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>East</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fulton</ln>
                        <fn>J. Givens</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crist</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn>James T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woddell</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Andrew</ln>
                        <fn>Nelson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Litten</ln>
                        <fn>John T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rusmisel</ln>
                        <fn>John C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craig</ln>
                        <fn>J. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donaho</ln>
                        <fn>Lucien M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Towberman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reported on business at the county court, mainly named people appointed to
                    different county offices.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Meeting of Conservative County Committee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Conservative County Committee met on August 22nd. The committee
                    resolved to hold a convention to nominate county officers on September 26th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lacy</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lacy</ln>
                        <fn>Allen R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Elizabeth Lacy, widow of the late Allen R. Lacy, died at her residence
                    near Warm Springs on July 21st. She was 77 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Humate</ln>
                        <fn>William J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Humate</ln>
                        <fn>James P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William J. Humate died near Warm Springs at the residence of his father,
                    James P. Humate, on July 31st. He was 23 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bite</ln>
                        <fn>Catherine E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bite</ln>
                        <fn>J. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Catherine E. Bite, wife of J. F. Bite and daughter of Peter and M. M.
                    Lucas, died in Newport on August 11th. She was 50 years old. "She was, from her
                    youth, a member of the Christian church, and adorned her profession by a
                    consistent walk and conversation till the time of her death." She left behind a
                    husband and four children. Many community members attended her funeral, which
                    symbolized her widespread popularity.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hensley</ln>
                        <fn>Conrad L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hensley</ln>
                        <fn>Robert D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Conrad L. Hensley, son of Robert D. Hensley of Bethlehem, Augusta County,
                    died on July 13th. He drowned while fishing in Blackwell's Mill Dam on South
                    River. An account of the tragedy and the parents' sorrow accompanies the notice.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1870.08.23.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
