<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1870/va.au.ss.1870.09.20">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>11/23/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date>
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day norm="20"/>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1870.09.20.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1870.09.20.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Extracts from the Minutes of the Executive Committee of the Augusta Memorial
                    Association for the Confederate Dead, Sept. 10th, 1870</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The following resolution was unanimously adopted as the first action of the
                        Committee:</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That the thanks of the relatives and
                        friends of the Confederate dead, who lie in Thornrose Cemetery, are due to
                        Mrs. Robert Cowan individually, and as President of the Augusta Ladies'
                        Memorial Association, for her untiring zeal and unselfish devotion in the
                        cause of protecting, caring for, and consecrating the graves of the fallen
                        Soldiers of the South; and this Committee trusts that her health and life
                        may long be preserved, and thus her efforts in this holy cause be long
                        continued."</p>
                    <p>A Constitution prepared by order of the meeting in June last, was adopted as
                        follows:</p>
                    <p>ARTICLE I.</p>
                    <p>The name of this Association shall be, The Augusta Memorial Association for
                        the Confederate Dead.</p>
                    <p>ARTICLE II.</p>
                    <p>The object of this Association shall be the preservation, care and annual
                        decoration of the graves of Confederate dead, who are interred in Thornrose
                        Cemetery, and other localities in Augusta County.</p>
                    <p>ARTICLE III.</p>
                    <p>The members of this Association shall consist of all persons, not deserters
                        from the Confederate army, who shall contribute annually the sum of fifty
                        cents for the purposes of the Association.</p>
                    <p>ARTICLE IV.</p>
                    <p>Honorary members of the Association shall consist of all persons who shall
                        contribute the sum of five dollars for the purpose of the Association.</p>
                    <p>ARTICLE V.</p>
                    <p>The officers of the Association shall be a President in Staunton, and one
                        Vice President in each Township of the County, Secretary and Treasurer, who
                        shall be elected by the Association at each annual meeting, convened for the
                        purpose of decorating the graves of the Confederate dead; their duties shall
                        be such as are appropriate to their respective offices, and as may be
                        specified by the By-Laws of the Association.</p>
                    <p>ARTICLE VI.</p>
                    <p>There shall be an Executive Committee of its Association, consisting of five
                        members, inclusive of the Presidents of the Association,, who shall be <emph
                            rend="italic">ex officio</emph> a member thereof, to be chosen by the
                        Association at each annual meeting thereof, and of whom three shall be a
                        quorum for the transaction of business. It shall be the duty of the
                        Executive Committee to transact the current business of the Association, to
                        determine and direct all the operations of the Association in reference to
                        the graves of the Confederate dead, to make all contracts in regard thereto,
                        to control all the expenditures of the Association, and upon whose draft all
                        the moneys of the Association shall be paid by the Treasurer, and to whom
                        the Treasurer of the Association shall report the condition of the Finances
                        of the Association whenever required to do so by said Committee. Said
                        Committee shall have power to draft by-laws for their government, to appoint
                        Sub-committees, and shall appoint a Secretary, and keep a record of all
                        their acts and resolutions, and shall meet whenever required so to do by the
                        President of the COmmittees. The Executive Committees shall make a report of
                        their transactions to each annual meeting of the Association.</p>
                    <p>ARTICLE VII.</p>
                    <p>The Association shall meet yearly at a place to be designated by the
                        President on the 9th of June, as the annual "Memorial Day" of the
                        Association, to decorate the graves of the Confederate dead and to transact
                        appropriate business.</p>
                    <p>The President of the Association assisted by the Executive Committee shall
                        prescribe the ceremonies of the Memorial Day, provide for the delivery of
                        such addresses as may be proper, and give sufficient previous notice thereof
                        by publications in the newspapers of the County.</p>
                    <p>The President and Vice Presidents shall be ex-officio Marshalls of the Day.</p>
                    <p>ARTICLE VIII.</p>
                    <p>The annual contribution shall be expended under the directions of the
                        Executive Committee, in keeping in repair the graves of the Confederate dead
                        in Augusta. The fund arising from the contributions of honorary members, may
                        be invested in a permanent fund or otherwise as the Association may
                        determine.</p>
                    <p>ARTICLE IX.</p>
                    <p>The Secretary shall inscribe the names of the members of the Association in a
                        well bound book for preservation, and the roll of members shall be published
                        annually in the papers of Augusta, under the direction of the President.</p>
                    <p>Upon motion it was <emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That each Vice
                        President now in office (together with the Committees to be hereafter
                        published) shall proceed without delay to enroll members of the Association,
                        and that a meeting of all the members be held at the County Fair on the
                        second day in Gatherem Hall to perfect the organization of the Association
                        in all respects; also</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That a member of the Executive Committee
                        be assigned to each Township, to select therefrom Sub-committees of two
                        gentlemen and three ladies at each precinct to collect contributions and to
                        obtain members for the Association.</p>
                    <p>Under this resolution the following appointments were made, viz:</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Staunton and Beverly Manor,</emph> -- Capt. J. H. Waters</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Riverheads.</emph> -- Capt. James Bumgardner</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Middle River.</emph> -- Capt. J. N. Opie</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">North River and Pastures.</emph> -- S. Travers Phillips.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">South River.</emph> -- Col. B. Christian.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That the Secretary request the papers of
                        Staunton to publish from the minutes extracts for general circulation in the
                        County.</p>
                    <p>The name of the Sub-committees will be published next week.</p>
                    <p>BOLIVAR CHRISTIAN,</p>
                    <p>Chm'n Ex. Com.</p>
                    <p>S. TRAVERS PHILLIPS, Secretary.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cowan</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waters</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Opie</ln>
                        <fn>J. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phillips</ln>
                        <fn>S. Travers</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Editor reported on the actions of the Committee of the Augusta Memorial
                    Association. Printed in detail the constitution they adopted and the provisions
                    taken to care for the graves of the Confederate dead.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Hon. A. H. H. Stuart</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>A. H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Article attesting to widespread support for A. H. H. Stuart as candidate
                    for the Congressional District that included Augusta.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1870.09.20.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Precinct Meetings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John B. Baldwin, County Superintendent, called on all voters from precincts
                    who failed to hold primary meetings to come together on September 24th to
                    appoint delegates to the county convention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Staunton Delegates to County Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>At eight o'clock on Saturday night last, Wards No. 1 and 2 of Staunton, held
                        meetings, respectively, at the Court-house and at the Town Hall to elect
                        three delegates each to the County Convention.</p>
                    <p>Ward No. 1 elected Wm. G. Sterrett, Bolivar Christian and Richard H. Fisher,
                        and declined to instruct them with reference to securing the nomination of
                        any particular individual, and also declined to recommend particular
                        individuals to them to be elected delegates to the Congressional Convention
                        -- leaving the delegates chosen free and untrammeled to act in accordance
                        with the dictates of their own sound judgment and discretion.</p>
                    <p>Ward No. 2 elected H. M. Bell, M. G. Harman and J. M. Hardy delegates to the
                        County Convention, and also recommended them to vote in that Convention for
                        the following delegates and alternates to the Congressional Convention:</p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Delegates,</cell>
                            <cell>Alternates,</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>John B. Baldwin,</cell>
                            <cell>P. H. Trout,</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Wm. A. Burke,</cell>
                            <cell>W. H. Lynn,</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>M. H. Effinger,</cell>
                            <cell>S. H. Hilb,</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>S. Travers Phillips,</cell>
                            <cell>A. S. Lara,</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>M. G. Harman,</cell>
                            <cell>R. G. Bickle,</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sterrett</ln>
                        <fn>William G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>Bolivar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>Richard H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>H. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hardy</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Effinger</ln>
                        <fn>M. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phillips</ln>
                        <fn>S. Travers</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>P. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lynn</ln>
                        <fn>W. H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hilb</ln>
                        <fn>S. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lara</ln>
                        <fn>A. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickle</ln>
                        <fn>R. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reported on the meetings held in Staunton for choosing delegates to the
                    County Convention and the people chosen from both wards. Each delegate did not
                    receive any binding instructions and so could act on their own in selecting
                    candidates.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Railroad Subscription by Staunton</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Some time since Staunton voted almost unanimously in favor of the
                        subscription of $100,000 to the capital stock of the Valley Railroad
                        Company. On Saturday last, she voted an additional subscription of $50,000
                        -- thus making her subscription of stock to that Company the considerable
                        sum of $150,000. The vote of Saturday last resulted as follows:</p>
                    <p>For subscription.....................................286.</p>
                    <p>Against subscription.................................90.</p>
                    <p>Total vote.............................................376</p>
                    <p>Affirmative majority, 196. With 90 negative votes, only 135 affirmative votes
                        were required to carry the requisite three-fifths majority, but as 286
                        affirmative votes were cast, there were 151 more affirmative votes than were
                        necessary, and it would have required 101 more negative votes to have
                        defeated the subscription. If 191 negative votes had been cast, it would
                        have required 287 affirmative votes to have obtained the requisite
                        three-fifths majority, whereas only 286 were cast.</p>
                    <p>There was no excitement, as none doubted that the subscription would be
                        carried, and the vote was consequently small. Less than half of the voters
                        in the city voted at this election.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Commented on the approval by voters of $150,000 in stock to the Valley
                    Railroad, carried by a near unanimous vote.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Delegates to the County Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Finley</ln>
                        <fn>S. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grattan</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillespie</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roller</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>A. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Merickan</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Croft</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roberts</ln>
                        <fn>St. F. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mitchell</ln>
                        <fn>J. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>A. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Abney</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guthrie</ln>
                        <fn>H. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>David S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burkholder</ln>
                        <fn>P. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Caldwell</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tate</ln>
                        <fn>William M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Baxter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sibert</ln>
                        <fn>Lorenzo</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Delegates to the County Convention were selected at recent meetings. New
                    Hope: S. B. Finley, Charles Grattan, Dr. Gillespie. Mt. Sidney: William
                    Crawford, Thomas Burke, Charles Roller. Bolivar: A. W. Harman, Joseph Merickan,
                    S. Croft. Hebron: Jacob Baylor, St. F. C. Roberts, J. T. Mitchell. Barterbrook:
                    A. G. Christian, William A. Abney, H. G. Guthrie. Fishersville: David S. Bell,
                    P. T. Burkholder, William Caldwell. Buffalo Gap: William M. Tate, Baxter
                    Crawford, Lorenzo Sibert.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We have at least three candidates for Congress in this District, and it is
                        necessary to an intelligent choice between them, that the relation each of
                        them proposes to sustain to the only two parties at this time dividing the
                        people, should be unequivocally stated. It is my clear conviction that no
                        man ought to receive the support of the anti-Republican voters of this
                        district, unless he distinctly announces himself uncompromisingly opposed to
                        "Republicanism" in all its phases and degrees. -- And as the only mode in
                        which successful opposition to that corrupt and unscrupulous party, which
                        has for years controlled the Federal Government to the ruin of the country,
                        is possible, is by a hearty and earnest co-operation with the National
                        Democratic party, it would be suicidal to send a Representative to Congress
                        upon any other basis.</p>
                    <p>I hope therefore we will have an early and unmistakable declaration from all
                        the candidates upon this vital matter.</p>
                    <p>AN OLD WHIG.</p>
                    <p>September 15th, 1870.</p>
                    <p>We feel warranted in saying that Mr. Stuart is uncompromisingly opposed to
                        the whole policy of centralization, usurpation, corruption and oppression,
                        practised by the Radical party in regard to the Southern States, and that he
                        will cordially co-operate with any party, and employ any and every honorable
                        means to defeat radicalism in all its forms and phases. He has no sympathy
                        with modern republicanism as represented either by Underwood &amp; Co.,
                        or by Rives and McKenzie.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"AN OLD WHIG" suggested that no candidate for Congress should receive the
                    endorsement of Conservative voters unless he fully repudiated all Republican
                    policies. In reply, a follow-up letter supported A.H.H. Stuart and assured
                    voters that he opposed all aspects of the Republican party.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scrogham</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Humbert</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garber</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Daniel T. Scrogham and Miss Elizabeth F. Humbert, both of Augusta, were
                    married on September 8th by the Rev. Martin Garber.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keneday</ln>
                        <fn>Henry S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rhinehart</ln>
                        <fn>Lucy C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rhinehart</ln>
                        <fn>Oliver</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolfe</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Henry S. Keneday and Lucy C. Rhinehart, daughter of Oliver Rhinehart, all
                    of New Hope, were married on September 14th by the Rev. John H. Wolfe.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yarbrough</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Yarbrough died in New Hope on September 4th. He was 81 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Edmondson</ln>
                        <fn>Lucy A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Edmondson</ln>
                        <fn>E. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Lucy A. Edmondson died near Staunton at the residence of her brother,
                    E. L. Edmondson, on August 24th. She was 35 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1870.09.20.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
