<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1865/pa.fr.fr.1865.08.30">
    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>09/15</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1865-08-30">
            <year>1865</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day>30</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1865.08.30.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Richmond</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Frater</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Repository's correspondent describes the state of Virginia's capital
                    and its hinterland, much of which, he avers, lays in ruin. The blaze that
                    destroyed large sections of the city, causing $30,000,000 worth of damage was
                    ignited by the Confederates as they retreated.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1865.08.30.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Seed Wheat</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Responding to queries from farmers as to which seed they should plant, the
                    editors recommend the use of the Lancaster variety. In light of the destruction
                    caused by the weevil last harvest, this decision has taken on an increased
                    importance.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Vandal McCausland</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The grand jury of Franklin county returned a true bill on the 16th inst.,
                        against Jos. A. M'Causland--late general in the rebel army, and the officer
                        in command when Chambersburg was sacked and burned--for arson and high-way
                        robbery; and Gov. Curtin promptly issued his requisition upon Gov. Boreman,
                        of West Virginia, for the rendition of McCausland to the civil authorities
                        of this county. Gov. Boreman responded to the demand of Gov. Curtin and
                        rendered every possible facility to aid in the arrest of the fugitive; but a
                        careful recognizance of his old residence and neighborhood developed the
                        fact that he had fled to Canada some two months ago. Ever after his
                        atrocities in Chambersburg, his command ceased to be soldiers--were useless
                        save as free-booters, and some of the gravest disasters suffered by Early in
                        the Valley were with some justice attributed by Early and the rebel press to
                        the thieving cowards of M'Causland's command. Before the war closed the
                        chief vandal and his men were as cordially despised by the rebels as they
                        were by the North, and when Lee surrendered, M'Causland found himself
                        without a resting place. He was paroled under the stipulations of Lee's
                        capitulation, and went to his old home near Point Pleasant, West Virginia,
                        but no voice of welcome greeted him, and nought but execration or studied
                        contempt confronted him wherever he directed his steps. Conscious of his
                        guilt against every principle of humanity, and constantly haunted with the
                        fear that he should be brought to meet the avenging arm of justice in
                        Chambersburg, he finally fled by way of Cincinnatti, Cleveland, and St.
                        Louis to Canada, where he has taken his abode as the only "sequestered spot"
                        that can shield him from the terrible retribution his crimes have invited.</p>
                    <p>We have hitherto, for obvious reasons, refrained from giving publicity to a
                        fragment of M'Causland's history that we received from confidential but
                        entirely reliable sources some six weeks ago; but as the Federal cavalry
                        have been in search of him at his own home, he cannot now be ignorant of the
                        purpose of the government to bring him to justice, and we can with propriety
                        state that there is an order of the War Department commanding his arrest by
                        the military authorities. When Lee was retreating from Richmond, McCausland
                        was with him, commanding a brigade of cavalry and aiding to cover the rear
                        of the army. At Farmville several wounded Union prisoners were brought into
                        the rebel lines where McCausland commanded, and among them was one of
                        Lieutenant General Grant's staff officers. McCausland greeted him with a
                        volley of profanity, and crowned his wanton insults to a captured foe by
                        deliberately murdering him with his own sword. No provocation whatever was
                        offered by the wounded officer, who was then a prisoner of war; but
                        M'Causland, true to his fiendish instincts, murdered him before his own
                        command. Information of this atrocity was communicated to us by an ex-rebel
                        officer who had been here in one of the rebel raids in which the humanities
                        of war were duly observed, and he gave the names of several rebel officers
                        who witnessed the brutal murder and authorized their names and residence to
                        be communicated to the government. This information was of course furnished
                        to the authorities, and an order was promptly issued for M'Causland's
                        arrest. The cavalry of West Virginia proceeded at once to Point Pleasant,
                        but the vandal had already fled. Since then an order has been issued to the
                        commander of every military department in the Union for his arrest, and Gov.
                        Boreman of his own State is ready at any time to arrest him for rendition to
                        the civil authorities of this county. Such is the fate of the traitor,
                        vandal and murderer M'Causland. Hated and shunned by loyalists and traitors
                        in his own land, and pursuing vengeance shadowing his pathway at every step,
                        he is a wanderer and outcast--a stranger to home, to country and to
                        friendship, as he crouched beneath the reluctant hospitality of a government
                        that now hates his cause since it won only discomfiture. Truly--<lb/> "The
                        mills of the Gods grind slowly<lb/> But they grind exceeding fine!"</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is reported that Gen. McCausland, the officer in command when
                    Chambersburg was sacked and burned to the ground, has fled to Canada, thus
                    placing in doubt the likelihood that he will face justice for his "crimes"
                    during the war. In spite of the information, report the editors, the Federal
                    Cavalry continues to search for him, due in large measure to an incident that
                    occurred near the closing of the war in which he executed one of Gen. Grant's
                    staff officers who had been taken prisoner. "Hated and shunned by loyalists and
                    traitors in his own land," they say, he has become "a wanderer and outcast" with
                    no one to turn to.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Proclaiming his selection as "eminently merited," the article lauds the
                    nomination of William B. Mann for the fourth term of the District Attorneyship
                    of Philadelphia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Morton McMichael, the editor of the North American, has been nominated as
                    the Union (Republican) candidate for Mayor of Philadelphia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A brief piece reminding readers that, by virtue of President Lincoln's
                    proclamation of March 3, 1863, all persons who avoided the draft are "prohibited
                    from exercising the elective franchise" in the upcoming election.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Philadelphia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Repository's correspondent relates that the Nominating Convention for
                    the Union Party provoked a stir in the "second city" last week. Much of the
                    strife, he contends, was caused by the delegates failure to place former
                    soldiers on the party's ticket, as several counties around the state, including
                    Franklin, had done. As a result, a faction within the party has threatened to
                    bolt the organization and work against its nominees for Mayor and City
                    Commissioner.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Washington</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is reported that the residents of the nation's capital are incensed by
                    the actions of their Mayor who defrauded the city's black residents of $20,000,
                    which was to be used to fund their schools. According to the correspondent, the
                    Mayor's "sharp trick" will likely have the unexpected result of serving as a
                    rationale for Congress to grant blacks the right to vote in the District.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Political Intelligence</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The majority of the newly-elected Kentucky Legislature is opposed to
                    emancipation and will refuse to ratify the amendment abolishing the institution,
                    which, the article notes, illustrates the Democratic party throughout the nation
                    intends on resisting the "consummation of this legislation."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1865.08.30.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>LIST of white and colored soldiers from the Borough of Mercersburg, who died
                        by disease, killed in battle, and starved in Southern prisons.</p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>1. George Edmiston,;</cell>
                            <cell>16. L. Myers,<emph rend="italic">d</emph></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>2. George Duncan,||</cell>
                            <cell>17. Jno. Eckman, <emph rend="italic">d</emph></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>3. Samuel Hornbaker,<emph rend="italic">a</emph></cell>
                            <cell>18. L. Potter,<emph rend="italic">c</emph></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>4. John Mowrey,<emph rend="italic">S</emph></cell>
                            <cell>19. D. Carson, <emph rend="italic">d</emph></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>5. Greenbury M'Conley,;</cell>
                            <cell>20. Samuel Reitzel,<emph rend="italic">d</emph></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>6. James Amsley,;</cell>
                            <cell>21. Jno Chambers (col.)#</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>7. Nelson Conner,;</cell>
                            <cell>22. Henry Imes (col.)#</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>8. Jno S. Dick,||</cell>
                            <cell>23. Wm. Jones (col.)#</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>9. Samuel Winters,<emph rend="italic">S</emph></cell>
                            <cell>24. Thos. Stoner (col.)<emph rend="italic">b</emph></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>10. P. A. Rice,+</cell>
                            <cell>25. Chas. Jackson (col.)<emph rend="italic">b</emph></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>11. Henry Creager,#</cell>
                            <cell>26. Jas. Smith,<emph rend="italic">c</emph></cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>12. Wash. Brinkley,*</cell>
                            <cell>27. Stant, Johnston (col.)#</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>13. George Bowman,#</cell>
                            <cell>28. Rob. Lions (col.)#</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>14. J. J. Good,<emph rend="italic">a</emph></cell>
                            <cell>29. Wm. Christy (col.)#</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>15. Wat. Skinner,#</cell>
                            <cell>30. E. D. Mowen,*</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell cellspan="2">EXPLANATION</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>*Killed at Fredericksburg.</cell>
                            <cell>#Killed in Battle (unknown)</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>+Died in Libby.</cell>
                            <cell><emph rend="italic">a</emph>Died in Hospital.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>;Killed at Gettysburg.</cell>
                            <cell><emph rend="italic">b</emph>Killed at Bat. Wagoner.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>||Killed at 2d Bull Run.</cell>
                            <cell><emph rend="italic">c</emph>Died in Prison.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell><emph rend="italic">S</emph>Starved at Andersonville.</cell>
                            <cell><emph rend="italic">d</emph>Died in Service</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Edmiston</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duncan</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hornbaker</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mowrey</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McConley</ln>
                        <fn>Greenbury</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Amsley</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Conner</ln>
                        <fn>Nelson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dick</ln>
                        <fn>John S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Winters</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rice</ln>
                        <fn>P. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Creager</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brinkley</ln>
                        <fn>Washington</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowmans</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Goods</ln>
                        <fn>J. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eckman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Potter</ln>
                        <fn>L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carson</ln>
                        <fn>D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reitzel</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chambers</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imes</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoner</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jackson</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Jason</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnston</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lions</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christy</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mowen</ln>
                        <fn>E. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A list of the white and "colored" soldiers from the borough of Mercersburg
                    who died in battle, as a result of disease, or in Southern prisons.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Death of a Soldier</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deitrich</ln>
                        <fn>Emanuel C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Emanuel C. Deitrich, formerly a resident of Chambersburg, died last week in
                    Harrisburg from chronic diarrhea. Detrich was a member of the 213th Penna. Reg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Political</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wunderlich</ln>
                        <fn>D. K.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duncan</ln>
                        <fn>C. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stenger</ln>
                        <fn>William S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLellan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doyle</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyd</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes that at the Democratic County Convention held the day before, the
                    following nominations were made: Senator, C. M. Duncan; Assembly, William
                    McLellan; Treasurer, Joseph M. Doyle; Sheriff, Samuel Boyd, District Attorney,
                    William M. Stenger.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Item</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Culbertson</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. Samuel D. Culbertson, "once the leading Physician of the county, and
                    one of our eldest and most respected citizens," passed away on August 25th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grimison</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gardner</ln>
                        <fn>Annie M. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turner</ln>
                        <fn>Curtis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On August 23rd, Thomas Grimison and Annie M. R. Gardner were married by
                    Rev. Curtis F. Turner.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strouse</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lauferty</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stine</ln>
                        <fn>Rachel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On August 23rd, Lewis Lauferty, of Three Rivers, Michigan, and Rachel Stine
                    were married by Rev. R. Strouse.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Leininger</ln>
                        <fn>Reuben</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mitchell</ln>
                        <fn>Emma</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>P. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On August 24th, Reuben Leininger and Emma A. Mitchell were married by Rev.
                    P. S. Davis.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roberts</ln>
                        <fn>Elisha</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roland</ln>
                        <fn>Nancy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Akers</ln>
                        <fn>J. Benson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On August 21st, Elisha Roberts, of Hancock, Md., and Nancy Roland were
                    married by Rev. J. Benson Akers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cunningham</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>Ann E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn>J. H. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On August 23rd, David Cunningham and Ann E. Taylor were married by Rev. J.
                    H. S. Clarke.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waldron</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Helferrich</ln>
                        <fn>Barbara</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gerdemann</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On August 13th, William Waldron, of Virginia, and Barbara Helferrich were
                    married by Rev. J. Gerdemann.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolff</ln>
                        <fn>Florence</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolff</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolff</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On August 15th, Florence, daughter of John and Elizabeth Wolff, died at
                    Welsh Run. She was 13 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1865.08.30.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
