<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1865/pa.fr.fr.1865.01.11">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sally Henninger, 1st pass; Susanna Michele Lee, 2nd pass, 1/1/99</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1865-01-11">
            <year>1865</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day>11</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1865.01.11.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Governor's Message</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Repository reprints Governor Curtin's message to the state legislature,
                    in which he discusses the good finances of the state; recruiting for the Union
                    army; revision of the act providing the vote to soldiers; abuse and fraud of the
                    bounty system; and the damage by rebels in Bedford, Fulton, Cumberland, York,
                    Adams, and Franklin counties in 1863.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>The page includes merchant advertisements, real estate sales, and legal
                notices.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1865.01.11.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Bedford Legislative Contest</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Discusses B. F. Meyers, the editor of the Bedford Gazette, who participated
                    in the recent Bedford legislative contest. The author argues that Meyers
                    fraudulently attempted to take office with false certifications of election
                    returns. The Gazette accuses the Repository of personally attacking Meyers. The
                    editor responds that he only criticized Meyers's illegal actions.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Gen. Hancock's New Corps</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Thousands of brave Pennsylvanians, misled into organizations outside of
                    the State, have families in our midst who are denied the benefits of our laws
                    because their husbands or fathers were mustered into foreign regiments and
                    credited to foreign districts."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Supports the call for volunteers for the new corps raised by Gen. Hancock.
                    The author raises the fear that the state will not provide monetary support for
                    widows, dependent children, and orphans since Hancock's corps will not be a
                    Pennsylvania regiment. Gov. Curtin refers the matter to the legislature because
                    state law must be modified to extend benefits to Pennsylvanians mustered into
                    Gen. Hancock's corps.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Collection Of Bounties</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Defends the practice of offering an additional $200 bounty to encourage
                    volunteers and avoid a draft. The author favors increased taxation to pay for
                    this higher bounty.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gotwalt</ln>
                        <fn>Luther A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Justifies the coverage of a criminal trial in Adams County (by the
                    Harrisburg correspondent in column 5) with its "latitudinous" nature. The
                    legislature will consider a change of venue plea for the trial. Gowalt, the
                    defendant, is the brother of Rev. Luther Gotwalt, formerly of Greencastle,
                    Franklin County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Richmond Examiner</origin>
                <commentary>"The Richmond Examiner, the official organ of Jeff. Davis, recently
                    published a lengthy editorial reviewing the position of affairs in rebeldom. It
                    states the exhausted conditions of the traitors with a degree of frankness
                    unusual in rebel journals, and concludes by proposing to form an alliance with
                    France and England to secure their independence by abolishing Slavery. The
                    article is attributed by the Richmond Sentinel to Jeff. Davis himself. The
                    following is the concluding paragraph of it:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Richmond Examiner favors an alliance with France or England to secure
                    the independence of the Confederacy on the condition of abolishing slavery. The
                    Examiner believes that France or England would "favorably" receive the
                    proposition.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Harrisburg. The Organization--The Speaker--The Clerks--The Contest from the
                    Bedford District in the House--Ross and Armstrong Placed on the Roll--Probable
                    Legislation Relative to Frauds of Return Judges--The Other Contested Seats--The
                    Committees--Adjournment.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>"Horace"</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the Senate decided on William J. Turrell of Pennsylvania as
                    Speaker and Hamersly of Philadelphia as Clerk and that the House decided on
                    Arthur G. Olmstead of Potter as Speaker. "Horace" also reports the contested
                    election returns from several districts.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>An Interesting Case--Rev. W. V. Gotwalt of Gettysburg, Asks a Change of
                    Venue--Intense Political Feeling in a Criminal Case in Adams county--Probable
                    Transfer of the Trial to Franklin or Cumberland County--Singular Details of the
                    Case.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>"Horace"</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>"Horace" details a criminal case originating in Adams County. A "highly
                    respected young lady" of Gettysburg named Walters accused Rev. Washington V.
                    Gotwalt of fornication and bastardy. As a Republican with Democratic accusers in
                    a county dominated by Democrats, Gotwalt requests the legislature to order a
                    change of venue. "Horace" agrees that Gotwalt can not receive a fair trial in
                    Adams County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>From The Southern Coast. The North Atlantic Squadron--The Attack on Fort
                    Fisher--Explosion of the Powder Ship--Withdrawal of the Fleet.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>"O. B."</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes the attack on Fort Fisher by the North Atlantic Squadron. "O. B."
                    believes the fleet inflicted considerable damage on the fort.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Washington. Congress Re-assembled--Spirited Debates--Secretary Stanton Gone
                    South--Applicants for Position in Gen. Hancock's Corps--Dismissal of Jimmy,
                    Door-keeper at the White House--Reception at the White House--Great
                    Rush--Senator McDougal Knocked Down--The Oil Fever.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>"S. C."</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Details the return of the members of Congress to Washington. "S. C."
                    believes that the spirited debates surrounding a proposed Constitutional
                    amendment abolishing slavery signal the unlikelihood of its passage.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Personal</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Comments on notable individuals: Rev. A. G. Marlatt, Col. James, C. Biddle,
                    and Gen. Grant.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1865.01.11.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Gossip With Our Friends</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes the celebration of the new year. The author witnessed the
                    performance of the actor Booth in "Hamlet," a drunken Irishman picking fights,
                    and dinner at Astor House.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Casualties In The 17th Cavalry</head>
                <origin>The Waynesboro Record</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Royer</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Royer</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kurtz</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rodgers</ln>
                        <fn>Arnold</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Straley</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tracey</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Unger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoner</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Record relates the casualties for the 17th Cavalry described in a
                    letter from Capt. Kurtz to his family in Waynesboro. David Royer and son, Daniel
                    Royer, of the Waynesboro vicinity, were shot and killed. Arnold Rodgers was
                    wounded. The Confederates took Privates Benjamin Straley, Tracey, Unger, and
                    Stoner as prisoners.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Religious</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Conrad</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces the sermon of Rev. Dr. Conrad in the Lutheran Church for soldiers
                    stationed in the vicinity.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Appointments</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foreman</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stewart</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richards</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wertz</ln>
                        <fn>H. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports the appointments made by the County Commissioners: George Foreman
                    as Clerk, John Stewart as Attorney, Dr. J. C. Richards as Prison Physician, and
                    H. E. Wertz as Mercantile Appraiser.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dick</ln>
                        <fn>S. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dick</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mourns the loss of Lieut. S. J. Dick, of the 18th U. S. Infantry. S. J.
                    Dick, son of Joseph Dick, formerly of Mercersburg, was found murdered in the
                    public square of Nashville, Tennessee, on December 29.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>A Good Shot</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keefer</ln>
                        <fn>Hezekiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Congratulates the skill of Hezekiah Keefer of Hamilton Township in killing
                    four wild turkeys at one shot at a distance of sixty yards.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Mr. S. S. Garver</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garver</ln>
                        <fn>S. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garver</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that S. S. Garver, son of Joseph Garver, formerly of Franklin
                    County, died in Kansas City. He served some time in the army and was a merchant
                    at the time of his death.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Promoted</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces the promotion of H. G. Bonebrake, of Waynesboro, as Second
                    Lieutenant of Co. G, 17th Pa. Cavalry.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Summary Of War News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Briefly reports on guerillas along the Potomac, expeditions on the
                    Rappahannock River, Gen. Dana's destruction of part of the Mobile and Ohio
                    Railroad, the siege of Wilmington, and Gen. Sherman's progress in Georgia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Finance And Trade</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes the excellent financial condition of the Cumberland Valley
                    Railroad Company.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dyson</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Laird</ln>
                        <fn>R. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sergt. Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cross</ln>
                        <fn>Lottie C..</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On January 8, by Rev. Dyson, Sergt. Maj. R. A. Laird, of 22nd Pa. Cavalry,
                    formerly of Juniata county, to Lottie Cross, of Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lesher</ln>
                        <fn>H. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shank</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Funk</ln>
                        <fn>Susie A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Funk</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On January 5, at the home of the bride's mother, by Rev. Lesher, John Shank
                    married Susie Funk, both of the Waynesboro vicinity.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ausherman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On December 16, near Barkettsville, Frederick County, Md., John Ausherman,
                    died at the age of 73 years and 4 months.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lackens</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lackens</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lackens</ln>
                        <fn>Eleanor</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On January 1, at Welsh Run, Margaret, daughter of William and Eleanor
                    Lackens, died at the age of 12 years, 1 month and 3 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On January 2, near St. Thomas, John Miller, died in his 55th year.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kaufman</ln>
                        <fn>Fanny</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kaufman</ln>
                        <fn>George D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kaufman</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On December 25, in Chambersburg, Fanny, youngest daughter of George and
                    Mary Kaufman, died at 8 months and 21 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Charlotte E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>John S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Julia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On January 5, in Fayetteville, of Scarlet Fever, Charlotte, only child of
                    John and Julia Brown, died at the age of 2 years, 4 months and 21 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>The page includes new advertisements, financial notices, personal property
                sales, and military proposals.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1865.01.11.04">
            <pageNote>The page includes advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
