<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1865/pa.fr.fr.1865.06.21">
	<header>
		<title>Franklin Repository</title>
		<tagger>
			<taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
			<tagDate>07/24/99</tagDate>
			<tagNote/>
		</tagger>
		<address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
		<date n="1865-06-21">
			<year>1865</year>
			<month norm="06">June</month>
			<day>21</day>
			<weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
		</date>
		<frequency>weekly</frequency>
		<extent/>
		<editionNote/>
	</header>
	<paperBody>
		<page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1865.06.21.01">
			<div type="a">
				<column>7</column>
				<head>Negro Suffrage In The South</head>
				<origin>Frankfort Commonwealth</origin>
				<commentary>"To the objection that negro suffrage implies negro social equality, the
					Frankfort Commonwealth promptly responds:"</commentary>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>NEGRO SUFFRAGE IN THE SOUTH--To the objection that negro suffrage implies
						negro social equality, the Frankfort <emph rend="italic">Commonwealth</emph>
						promptly responds:</p>
					<p>Negroes have voted in the South and yet were in no sense advanced to an
						equality with the whites. In every southern State, except South Carolina,
						the right of suffrage was originally exercised by all "freemen." The
						original Constitutions of Delaware, Maryland, North Carolina, Virginia and
						Georgia, make no mention of color, or distinction between white and black,
						in their privileges as to who may vote. Till within comparatively few years,
						negroes voted in Tennessee, in Maryland they voted until 1833, and in North
						Carolina as late as 1835. Now, did this advance them at all in the scale of
						equality? Were the schools in those States thrown open to them? Did they
						visit in gentlemen's parlors? Was amalgamation any more common in those days
						than it is now? We hope not. Was there, in any sense, the "equality" of
						which the opposition is now so offensively talking, and with which they are
						as pertinaciously insulting the common sense and decency of the people? Not
						a bit of it.</p>
					<p>In Pennsylvania colored people voted until 1838. Yet in that State a negro
						has not the same privileges that he has here in Kentucky. In Connecticut the
						negro voted till 1817, and yet he had not attained an equality sufficient to
						preserve for himself the privilege. In New York the negro, if he has the
						requisite property qualification, may vote now, but he has scarcely advanced
						one step in the scale of equality. Not even near enough to have the property
						restriction removed in his case, when it was removed in 1836, as far as it
						applied to the white voter.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>The article repudiates the notion that conferring blacks with suffrage
					rights will result in their social advancement by pointing out the fact that
					blacks, in the late 18th and early 19th centuries, had the right to vote in a
					number of states, both northern and southern, yet clearly their status had not
					markedly improved as a result.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="e">
				<column>7</column>
				<head/>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Noting the apparent hypocrisy, the brief piece points out that the same
					"journals who pleaded the strongest for the hanging of old John Brown five years
					ago, are now the most anxious that Jeff Davis and conferees should escape."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1865.06.21.02">
			<div type="e">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>The Problem of Reunion</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary>"The work of conquering the rebels in arms was easy in comparison with
					the task of restoring them to a brotherly and harmonious sympathy with us, whom
					they have met with such deadly malice and whom they have so long been taught to
					regard with malevolence."</commentary>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>The subjugation of the rebels, in the only sense in which it was ever
						purposed by the government to subdue them, has at length been accomplished.
						It proved to be the most stupendous military achievement in the annals of
						history. The determination of the loyal people of the country to preserve
						the integrity of the Union, and their unexampled valor effected this result.
						Now that our armies have performed their mission, comes the hardest problem
						for the solution of our statesmen. It is not enough that the territorial
						integrity of the nation should have been preserved and the honor of our flag
						sustained. It is not our desire that the smitten disloyal States shall be
						held in an inferior political position, to be governed as provinces by
						coercion. The feelings of our hearts, as well as the spirit of freedom
						require that there should be no inequality in the citizens of the Republic,
						excepting, of course, such degradation as justice demands in punishment of
						crime. The people of the South must be blended in a community of interests,
						privileges and sentiments with those of the North. The effects of this
						bitter war are to be obliterated as soon as possible. The work of conquering
						the rebels in arms was easy in comparison with the task of restoring them to
						a brotherly and harmonious sympathy with us, whom they have met with such
						deadly malice, and whom they have so long been taught to regard with
						malevolence. The mortification of unexpected defeat in the trial of arms;
						the humiliation of having their territory overrun upon every acre: their
						forts, their ships, their arms, captured; their wealth destroyed; their
						unrighteous privileges rudely abrogated; their sons slain; all prevent a
						ready and graceful acceptance of the offers of free and hearty fellowship we
						shall extend to them. The highest qualities of statesmanship are needed to
						manage this great theme--the utmost wisdom and prudence upon the part of our
						rulers and people. No unnecessary harshness, no injudicious leniency will
						serve. We believe the administration will manage this difficult task wisely
						and well. But they need the support of the people now as much at least as
						they needed their support in waging war. It is painful to see, however, that
						this encouragement is not given with the unanimity that it should be. The
						rebel sympathisers among us, who co-operated with the traitors during the
						fierce struggle just ended, and controlled the opposition at the last
						election, seem to feel that their party existence depends upon their making
						odions, and thwarting the administration, and are busy in impeding and
						deranging the efforts of the government. They seek to make the people, North
						and South, believe that the Unionists are cruel and unjust; that they have
						the simple desire of elevating the negro and procuring him power. And as
						they apologized for the traitors while in arms, they are striving to keep
						alive the resentments of those traitors and prevent their cordial re-union
						with the kindred they so foolishly abandoned and so revengefully fought. The
						treason of these Northern recreants is no less than that of the overthrown
						traitors who built up the short lived Confederacy. But we believe, yea, we
						know, that the evil they are devising will have no power to do much
						permanent mischief.</p>
					<p>The hand of the Almighty disposer of events has hitherto guided us. The voice
						of mankind has welcomed our triumph with rejoicings. The mission of this
						Nation is assured, its unity fully and forever confirmed. The right of the
						people to rule, and the right of all people to elevation and prosperity are
						maintained. It is a sad spectacle to see our citizens, men whom in their
						social and friendly relations we respect and love, arraying themselves
						against the common sentiments of mankind, and setting their faces against
						the everlasting truth. They know not what they do. They stand apart from the
						masters of their fellow-men, their feeble voices of discord lost in the
						swelling volume which sings hosannas to the triumph of their race. It is the
						men who denied the right of the soldier to vote, who proclaimed the war an
						unrighteous failure, who opposed the ratification of the constitutional
						amendment, who are striving to interrupt the harmonious settlement of the
						perplexities upon us, and seek to keep up the hostility of the people of the
						South to their blood relations of the loyal States. The most scandalous
						vilification of the President and his cabinet are circulated greedily to
						weaken these functionaries in public confidence. The accusations of hasty
						and testy generals are seized with avidity, and no hero can make himself
						half so acceptable as when he is using his influence to prejudice the
						administration. Verily his defeat of the enemy is nearly compensated in the
						estimation of those men by a raid upon the Secretary of War. It is evident
						that these factious opponents of the government do not realize the positions
						they occupy. The jealousy with which we watch the faintest encroachment upon
						popular rights may for a time save them from the scorn so soon to overwhelm
						them. But the day will come when the people of this restored and happy
						Republic will regard as the most dangerous and meanest of its enemies the
						men who lived in the midst of their loyal countrymen, and labored to cripple
						its energies, when struggling for its life--the men who, when that struggle
						ended in sustaining the supremacy of law and order, sought to foster
						discontent, sullenness, bitterness, and unarmed disloyalty among the people
						led back by force to their allegiance.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>With the war over, the difficult task of sectional reconciliation must
					begin, say the editors. Complicating matters, they claim, are the efforts of the
					Democrats, who, after lending their tacit support to the rebels during the late
					conflict, are "striving to keep alive the resentments of these traitors and
					prevent their cordial reunion with kindred they foolishly abandoned and
					revengefully fought."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>2</column>
				<head/>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>ENLISTED men of volunteers mustered out of service under recent orders from
						the War Department are to be considered as so mustered out on account of
						Government no longer requiring their services, and are entitled to the
						balance of whatever bounty they may at the time be legally receiving. From
						this bounty balance are to be excepted those discharged who were enlisted
						under the Act of July 4, 1864, and the call of the President of July 18,
						1864, and such as are clearly shown to be discharged for confirmed
						disability or as pensioners. Veterans who go out of service under General
						Orders, No. 77, Current Series, do not go out, because their services are no
						longer required, as they are expressly excepted for operation, under orders
						for the reduction of the army, only as prisoners of war. Non-commissioned
						officers of infantry and cavalry volunteers, mustered out of service by
						reason of being supernumeraries, in consolidation, consequent upon recent
						orders for the reductions of the army, are to be considered as mustered out
						on account of their services being no longer required by the Government, and
						are entitled to the balance of the bounty remaining unpaid.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>A notice specifying which soldiers are eligible for government bounties.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>2</column>
				<head/>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Among the recent petitions for special pardons received by the President
					were those of Robert E. Lee, late commander of the Rebel forces, and Alexander
					H. Stephens, late Vice-President of the Confederacy.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Washington</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer>S. C.</trailer>
				<names/>
				<summary>The Repository's Washington correspondent informs readers that the
					"excitement that arose from the conspiracy trial has all died out." Instead, the
					chief topics of conversation in the capital are black suffrage and
					reconstruction. According to reports, the President has met with representatives
					from both sections of the country, who have sought to sway the Chief Executive
					to their way of thinking regarding the appropriate policy for re-admitting the
					former rebel states. It is unclear whether the interviews have had an impact.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>7</column>
				<head>Horrible Affair In Illinois</head>
				<origin>Quincy (Ill.) Herald</origin>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>An account of the lynching of a wounded guerilla captain in Quincy who was
					seized from his jail cell and dragged through the streets before finally being
					hanged in a remote area on the outskirts of town.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1865.06.21.03">
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Local Items</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>A copy of the resolution passed at the anniversary of the Franklin County
					Bible Society, held on May 7th, requesting local churches to collect donations
					"to aid the Society to carry on its work of supplying the destitute."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Local Items--The Wheat Crop</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Relates that the milk-weevil has infested wheat crops in the vicinity of
					Chambersburg and threatens to destroy all of the Mediterranean variety. White
					wheat, however, has avoided the destruction because its grains were too hard
					when insects arrived.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Local Items--Sale Of Oil Lands</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Four hundred acres of the Irvin Farm were sold to a New York Oil Company
					for $70,000 and a ten-percent interest in any future oil production on the land.
					Recently, however, the six-hundred acre property was offered for $12,000.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Local Items--Honorably Discharged</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Lane</ln>
						<fn>William C.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Dr. William C. Lane, Surgeon of the Board of Enrollment of the District,
					was honorably discharged last Thursday.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>2</column>
				<head>Local Items--Gone To Europe</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Schaff</ln>
						<fn>P.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Rev. Dr. P. Schaff, of the Mercersburg Theological Seminary, left for
					Europe from New York on June 10th.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>2</column>
				<head>Local Items</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Rev. Thomas X. Orr, of Allegheny, and formerly a member of the Chambersburg
					Bar, preached in the Presbyterian Church last Sunday.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>2</column>
				<head>Local Items</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Carnahan</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Rev. Carnahan, formerly Pastor of the Associate Reformed Church, was
					installed Pastor of the Presbyterian Church of Gettysburg on the June 13th.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>2</column>
				<head>Local Items</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Notes that the court house roof will be completed early in the fall. The
					cost is expected to be equal to the cost of the original structure.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Hall</ln>
						<fn>A. J.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Wiston</ln>
						<fn>Susan E.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Wilson</ln>
						<fn>E. B.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On June 18th, A. J. Hall and Susan E. Wiston were married by Rev. E. B.
					Wilson.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Bechtol</ln>
						<fn>Abraham</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On June 14th, Abraham Bechtol died after a protracted illness.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Simmers</ln>
						<fn>John K.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On April 1st, John K. Simmers, of Co. D. 210th Pa. Vols., died during the
					Battle of Five Forks, Va.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1865.06.21.04">
			<pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
		</page>
	</paperBody>
</hwp>
