<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1865/pa.fr.fr.1865.01.18">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sally Henninger, 1st pass; Susanna Michele Lee, 2nd pass, 1/1/99</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1865-01-18">
            <year>1865</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day>11</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1865.01.18.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>A British Officer's Visit to the Army of the Potomac</head>
                <origin>London Star, December 24</origin>
                <commentary>"The London Star, of Dec. 24th, has an interesting letter from a British
                    field officer who was recently on a visit to Grant's army. He thus describes
                    Gen. Grant:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprints a letter from the London Star describing a British field officer's
                    visit to Grant's army.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Ordeal of Battle</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prints a story of Rachel Clay and her suitor Harry Cleveland. Clay rejected
                    Cleveland for his lack of firmness and purpose. She only decided to marry
                    Cleveland after his decision to enlist and his display of worth on the battle
                    field.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>A Little Lesson for Well Disposed Wives</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Encourages wives to keep their husbands' interests with their charm and
                    domesticity.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Contraband</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"A contraband undertaking to find a situation for her daughter in
                    Cincinnati, insisted upon said daughter being instructed. Upon being requested
                    to indicate what kind of accomplishments she was desirous of having her hopeful
                    daughter possess, she said--'De gal must be larned de piano and painting,
                    anyhow, and mebbe arter awhile, readin and writin'.'"</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Mocks blacks for pretentious and impractical aspirations.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Nothing can be more senseless than the conduct of a young woman, who seeks
                    to be admired in general society for her politeness and engaging manner, or
                    skill in music, when, at the same time, she makes no effort to render her home,
                    whether a palace or cottage, the very centre of her being, the nucleus around
                    which her affections should revolve."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Cautions wives against making themselves more agreeable in society than at
                    home.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Contraband</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Contraband Tom, who has come into Sheridan's lines, says the rebels are
                    having a 'right smart talk' about arming the colored men, and the negroes are
                    talking about it themselves, but the blacks are about equally divided on the
                    matter. Says Tom:--''Bout half de colored men tink dey would run directly over
                    to de Yankees wid de arms in their hands, and toder half tink dey would jiss
                    stand an' fire a few volleys to de rear fust, fore dey run--dat's all de
                    difference.'"</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Mocks blacks while recounting their loyalty to the Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The way the negro guards talk to the southern chivalry which Gen. Butler
                    has put to work in the trenches: 'Hurry up dar--hurry up, Lieutenant. Go on
                    dar--go on wid dat are shubble, Major--Take up dat are pick, Cappun, and get to
                    work libely, or I'll blow you out ob de ranks.'"</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes the interactions between "negro guards" and the "southern
                    chivalry."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>The page includes advertisements, military proposals, personal property sales,
                a poem entitled "God Bless You, Soldier!," and anecdotes.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1865.01.18.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The War</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on the failure of the Wilmington siege, the removal of Gen. Butler,
                    Sherman's movement towards Charleston, and the progress of the constitutional
                    amendment abolishing slavery.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Revision Of The Cabinet</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Discusses Lincoln's revision of his cabinet for his second term. The author
                    believes that Lincoln will be able to choose qualified members who will work
                    well together for his second term, instead of using the appointments to balance
                    the conflicting political pressures.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Proposed Amendment To The Constitution</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Its grave has been dug by its own friends and if we but decently inter it,
                    the people of the South ere long will be slowest to wish its resurrection. Let
                    the great criminal die."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Predicts the approval of the Constitutional amendment to abolish slavery.
                    The amendment passed in the Senate and needs a three-fourths majority in the
                    House. The author believes that the war demonstrates the impossibility of slave
                    and free states peacefully co-existing.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports Blair's mission to the South to discuss a peaceful resolution to
                    the war. The author believes the mission will be a failure since the rebels are
                    "desperate men, engaged in a desperate undertaking, and will abandon it only
                    when compelled."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Continues its coverage of Meyers fraudulent attempts to gain a seat in the
                    legislature.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports the "almost unanimous" vote of the constitutional convention of
                    Missouri against slavery.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Removal Of Gen. Butler</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Concludes that Lincoln removed Gen. Butler after an unfavorable evaluation
                    of his conduct as commander of the land forces in the recent attack on
                    Wilmington. The author praises Butler for his "eminent abilities" and service to
                    his country.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The State Library</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Details the expansion of the state library's holdings. The library spent
                    eleven hundred dollars in 1864 on the purchase of books to increase its holdings
                    to 40,000 volumes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Maj. R. J. Dodge</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports the repeal of the quotas calculated for Pennsylvania. New quotas
                    will be announced.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the Senate voted to terminate the Canada Reciprocity Treaty.
                    The proposal awaits Lincoln's approval.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Washington. Peace Rumors--F. P. Blair, Sr., in Richmond--The Amendment
                    Abolishing Slavery--The Removal of Gen. Butler--Provost Marshal Gen.
                    Fry--Resolution giving all Clerical Vacancies to Disabled soldiers--Petitions
                    for Increase of Pay.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>"S. C."</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>"S. C." reports rumors of Blair's peace mission and deems the likelihood of
                    passage of the abolition amendment "very poor." He also criticizes the
                    "absurdity" of Provost Marshal Gen. Fry's decisions. Fry ruled against allowing
                    credit to districts for volunteers enlisting before the draft date. He also
                    decided to grant exemptions of only one year for those who find substitutes to
                    enlist for three years. "S. C." finds the "obnoxious" decisions unsurprising
                    since Fry is known as "no friend of the conscription law."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1865.01.18.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Lieut. S. J. Dick</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dick</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dick</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reprints a letter written by a fellow officer to the sister of Lieut. Dick.
                    The letter describes Dick's death.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Directors Elected</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLellan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Linn</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Culbertson</ln>
                        <fn>Edmund</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>James C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Immel</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chambers</ln>
                        <fn>William L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolf</ln>
                        <fn>Barnard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lists Samuel M. Linn, Edmund Culbertson, James C. Eyster, George W. Immel,
                    William L. Chambers, and Barnard Wolf as the directors elected to the National
                    Bank of Chambersburg on January 10. The Board re-elected William McLellan as
                    president.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Relief Of Our Citizens</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports A. H. Coffroth's resolution recommending inquiries into a bill for
                    the relief of the people of Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Gen. Butler's Farewell Address</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"I have refused to order the useless sacrifices of the lives of such
                    soldiers, and I am relieved of my command. The wasted blood of my men does not
                    stain my garments."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprints Butler's speech to his troops, in which he implies that Lincoln
                    removed him because he was not willing to unnecessarily sacrifice his men.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>N. Y. Tribune</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"It seems that some of the poor sufferers worn to skeletons and suffering
                    from the natural weakness of mind which follows such torment, have undertaken to
                    swear allegiance to the rebel Government, in the hopes of getting food enough to
                    sustain life."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The New York Tribune describes "galvinized Yankees," prisoners coerced by
                    starvation into swearing allegiance to the Confederacy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Fort Fisher Fallen! 2,500 Prisoners Taken! 72 Guns Captured! 1 General and 1
                    Colonel Prisoners! Union Loss Severe!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports the victory by Gen. Ames's Division and the Second Brigade of the
                    First Division of the 29th Army Corps in taking Fort Fisher.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Important From Georgia</head>
                <origin>The Republican</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprints an article from the Republican newspaper, which describes
                    Georgians' desire to rejoin the Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Our Prisoners</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Disputes charges that "nothing has been done by our Government to carry out
                    the arrangements for taking care of prisoners, agreed upon by Generals Grant and
                    Lee." The author reports that the Union prisoners in Richmond received the first
                    installment of a shipment of 2,500 blankets soon after Christmas.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Finance And Trade</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports a general depression of stocks because of the scarcity of currency
                    and "the failure of the government to meet its engagements."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bishop</ln>
                        <fn>Jason M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shearer</ln>
                        <fn>Elias D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richardson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On January 15, in Upper Strasburg, by Rev. Bishop, Elias Shearer, of Co. D,
                    Pa. Cavalry, to Miss Richardson, both of Franklin County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kester</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deal</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dyson</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dyson</ln>
                        <fn>Ada</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On January 11, at the home of the bride's brother-in-law, J. Deal, by Rev.
                    Dyson, Rev. Kester married Ada Dyson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brandt</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sheriff</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dickson</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snow</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On January 10, at the home of Sheriff Brandt, by Rev. Dickson, William
                    Harris, of Orrinville, Maine, married Mary Snow, of Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Krebs</ln>
                        <fn>E. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolf</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Berger</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On January 12, by Rev. Krebs, John Wolf married Susan Berger, both of the
                    Waynesboro vicinity.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Krebs</ln>
                        <fn>E. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoeflich</ln>
                        <fn>S. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mentzer</ln>
                        <fn>Maria</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On January 9, by Rev. Krebs, S. Hoeflich married Maria Mentzer, both of
                    Waynesboro.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dixon</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bitner</ln>
                        <fn>Harry A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Matthews</ln>
                        <fn>Sallie J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On January 8, in Leesburg, Cumberland County, by Rev. Dixon, Harry Bitner,
                    of Southampton Township, married Sallie Matthews, of Cumberland County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McHenry</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gift</ln>
                        <fn>John G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moll</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On January 5, by Rev. McHenry, John Gift, of Guilford Township, married
                    Mary Moll, of Green Township.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McHenry</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClintock</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Meredith</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On January 10, by Rev. McHenry, at the home of Dr. McClintock, of Loudon,
                    William Martin married Sarah Meredith, of Loudon.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheldon</ln>
                        <fn>James Hacket</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On December 22, near Waynesboro, J. Sheldon died at the age of 22 years and
                    4 months.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Washabaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Washabaugh</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On January 5, near Greencastle, Mary, widow of David Washabaugh, Esq., died
                    at the age of 66 years and 1 month.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickley</ln>
                        <fn>Anna</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickley</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On January 7, Anna, infant daughter of George Bickley, of Chambersburg,
                    died at 1 year and 6 months.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nicklas</ln>
                        <fn>Drucilla</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nicklas</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On January 10, Drucilla, infant daughter of Peter Nicklas, of Chambersburg,
                    died at 1 years and 11 months.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Ann Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On December 23, in Chambersburg, Ann, daughter of George and Catharine
                    Smith, died at 9 weeks old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gerbig</ln>
                        <fn>Francis Ludwig</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gerbig</ln>
                        <fn>John C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gerbig</ln>
                        <fn>Maria</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On December 24, Francis, son of John and Maria Gerbig, died at 1 year, 5
                    months and 14 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hostetter</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Black</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hostetter</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hostetter</ln>
                        <fn>Georgiana</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On January 10, in Greencastle, Mary, daughter of Jacob and Georgiana
                    Hostetter, died at 14 months and 12 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>The page includes advertisements, real estate sales, and legal
            notices.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1865.01.18.04">
            <pageNote>The page includes advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
