<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1865/pa.fr.fr.1865.02.22">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sally Henninger, 1st pass; Susanna Michele Lee, 2nd pass, 1/3/99</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1865-02-22">
            <year>1865</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day>22</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1865.02.22.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Don't Forget Your Girls</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges parents to educate their daughters, so that they can educate their
                    sons. The article recounts the tale of a traveler who states that Indians
                    perpetuate their uncivilized character by educating only their men.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Remarks of A. K. McClure</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>A. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reprints A. K. McClure's speech to the Pa. House, in which he provides a
                    history of slavery and the extent of its criminality, efforts in Pennsylvania to
                    preserve slavery, and an argument with Purdy over treasonous statements.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>McClure's speech continues on page 2. The page includes advertisements, a
                story entitled "The Tables Turned," and anecdotes.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1865.02.22.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Extinction Of Slavery</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Slavery is now dying, not by the hands of those who long since favored a
                    prohibitory constitutional amendment, not by the hands of abolitionists so
                    called, not by virtue entirely of the executive proclamation, but by war, cruel
                    war, provoked and made by its friend."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In political affairs the end is not always apparent from the beginning. Both
                        nations and statements are sometimes compelled to accept the logic of events
                        as their instructor. The aspirations of the first are often quickened by
                        unexpected realization, whilst the latter are content to shape that whose
                        being they could neither forestall nor create.</p>
                    <p>How long African slavery would have existed upon this continent, had it not
                        been for the occurrence of the stupendous civil war now drawing to a close,
                        none can say. It might have lingered many centuries, an impediment to our
                        civilization, a blot upon our escutcheon, a cause of disintegration, and an
                        element of death. It might, too, in the ways of an inscrutable Being, have
                        been taken through the process of eradication by some noiseless, gentle
                        means, so that as scarce no man could tell whence it came, none should know
                        whither it went. But as the great Same controls both the zephyr and the
                        hurricane, so doth He rule in the armies of heaven and among the children of
                        men. None can take Him to task for His agencies.</p>
                    <p>Notwithstanding the present incumbent of the Presidency had years ago
                        declared that the States of this government could not remain permanently
                        half free and half slave; notwithstanding his premier had declared that
                        between the two systems--free and slave labor--there must ever be an
                        irrepressible conflict; at the very commencement of hostilities it was
                        authoritatively announced by both the executive and legislative branches of
                        the government that the object of the war was solely to compel obedience to
                        the national authority under the constitution and laws.</p>
                    <p>Thus whilst the insurgent leaders avowed the object of rebellion to be the
                        establishment of an unrestricted system of enforced labor, the power they
                        were about to engage as unhesitatingly disclaimed past encroachment and
                        future interference with the unclean thing.</p>
                    <p>It may be interesting now for a moment to leave the giants interlocked--to
                        let the strife progress--whilst we consider for a moment the probability of
                        the eradication of slavery by other means than through the war.</p>
                    <p>Its extinction may at any time have been effected by one of three means--war,
                        either on the part of the enslaved or by those favorable to abolition; a
                        constitutional amendment providing for its prohibition or voluntary
                        emancipation.</p>
                    <p>As regards voluntary emancipation, alas! the cupidity of human nature
                        rendered it almost impossible. The evil had its origin in a love of gain.
                        The same insatiate desire caused it to thrive. Tears and blood were no
                        obstacle to its inhuman barters. Its advantages were reciprocal. Coffers
                        were filled at the North, where the crack of the lash and the sigh from the
                        block were unheard; coffers were filled at the South, where both were
                        equally unheard. There could be no hope for voluntary emancipation when the
                        demands of avarice never ceased to be met and the national heart was growing
                        harder.</p>
                    <p>For the same reasons a constitutional amendment was equally out of the
                        question. Arrayed against the progress was every sordid and selfish
                        interest, every besotted and brutalized instinct, every debasing and
                        unchristian sentiment. Men in their own estimation proclaimed the African as
                        not of human kind, but allied to his own native gorilla. Even such as
                        admitted his humanity insisted that he was accursed of God. The argument
                        then was not confined to a street car, but they insisted upon perpetually
                        and systematically debasing him upon earth and finally excluding him from
                        Heaven. The aid of the highest judicial officer in the government was
                        invoked, and it was announced from the Bench that he had no rights a white
                        man was bound to respect. What wonder then that both voluntary and
                        constitutional emancipation were out of the question.</p>
                    <p>But slavery had been doomed. Permitted originally for some wise purpose, it
                        was not intended that it should have a perpetual lease, nor never be called
                        to settle an account. The enslaved it is true were helpless. Long years of
                        oppression and neglect had fitted them more for servitude than for freedom.
                        Bestial masters and their allies had often paraded this as a reason why
                        their bondage should be continued. Death they said was the best antidote for
                        death--the virus that produced the disease should be used in its cure.</p>
                    <p>It was just here, when all hope seemed to have died out, when the heart of
                        the lover of justice to all failed within him, that a ray of light appeared,
                        a speck in the heavens no bigger than a man's hand. Mr. Lincoln was elected.
                        He was about to be inaugurated. The revolution of slaveholders was begun. At
                        first to human perception it seemed of trifling importance, easy to be
                        quelled. The retiring President let it severely alone. It waxed strong. The
                        new President soon found himself in the midst of a tremendous convulsion.</p>
                    <p>It is not necessary to detail events. None fail to remember how the present
                        Chief Magistrate has from the beginning sought to win the South back by
                        appeals to duty and patriotism--how every ulterior measure of war has been
                        anteriorly proclaimed and opportunity afforded to return to a cast-off
                        allegiance.</p>
                    <p>Slavery is now dying, not by the hands of those who long since favored a
                        prohibitory constitutional amendment, not by the hands of abolitionists so
                        called, nor by virtue entirely of the executive proclamation, but by war,
                        cruel war, provoked and made by its friend. Had not a syllable of the
                        emancipation proclamation been uttered the result had been all the same; for
                        the present conflict will scarcely close before our armies shall have
                        overrun all parts of the South and given practical freedom to the slaves.</p>
                    <p>Our own measure resorted to for the purpose of weakening the enemy is about
                        to be adopted by him with the view of adding strength to his armies. It is
                        proposed now in the South to put the slaves into service and manumit [sic]
                        them for anticipated heroic efforts. It is not a matter of surprise that
                        such a proposition meets much opposition there. Few thinking men can have
                        faith in the idea that the negroes will fight for their oppressors under the
                        promise of freedom when these very oppressors have failed in a contest, the
                        object of which was by a separation from the old government to insure the
                        permanency and enlarge the area of slavery. The idea is preposterous. It is
                        as if a Pacific adventurer returning with his hoarded dust when shipwrecked
                        and utterly without hope, should first cast his treasure into the yawning
                        sea and leap into its jaws for a perpetual sleep.</p>
                    <p>Whilst slavery dies by the war as an element of strength in the rebellion, if
                        we seek a more remote and moral reason for its extinction we find it in the
                        prevading [sic] sentiment of patriotism and pride of nationality of the
                        loyal North. So long as the institution did not strike directly at the
                        vitals of the government it had its friends, but when it sought to disrupt
                        the Union and overturn the constitution, ambition, party spirit, prejudice,
                        cupidity, hatred of the negro--all obeyed the behests of a true patriotism
                        and came to the rescue. The large majority of the people notwithstanding the
                        seditious appeals of enemies of the government and rebel sympathizers, are
                        desirous to conduct the war in such a way as will deal the hardest blows
                        upon the enemy and most quickly and thoroughly re-establish the national
                        authority. The result of the late election shows that the government has met
                        the expectations of the many, whilst for its double work it has called down
                        upon itself the benedictions of mankind.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Recounts the history of several movements to end or curb slavery. The
                    author emphasizes the obstacles to abolition and emancipation before the war,
                    including the "helpless" of enslaved blacks caused by "Long years of oppression
                    and neglect [which] had fitted them more for servitude than freedom." The war
                    finally effected the death of slavery.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Progress Of The War</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"If Sherman cannot be defeated in detail, how is he to be beaten when his
                    immense army is concentrated?"</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>There are manifest signs of dissolution in the dominions of treason. The
                        Raleigh <emph rend="italic">Progress</emph> confesses, in an elaborate
                        article that the capital of that State is at the mercy of Sherman; that the
                        last rebel legislature is now in session there, and that Charleston,
                        Columbia, Wilmington and ultimately Richmond must be surrendered to the
                        Union armies. Part of the prediction has already been fulfilled. Sherman
                        entered Columbia, the capital of South Carolina, unopposed, and the Richmond
                        papers confess that the occupation of Columbia necessitates the surrender of
                        Charleston. The <emph rend="italic">Progress</emph> adds that when Sherman
                        does come the people of Raleigh and North Carolina will accept him as
                        conqueror, and imitate Savannah by making the best terms possible with him.
                        It also frankly admits that the rebel government cannot maintain the war,
                        and that justice and humanity demand its early termination on the basis of
                        re-union.</p>
                    <p>In the mean time Sherman is pursuing his victorious march practically
                        unopposed. Had it been in the power of the rebels to defend Columbia and
                        Charleston, it would have been done. If Sherman cannot be defeated in
                        detail, how is he to be beaten when his immense army is concentrated? When
                        he moved upon Columbia, he had two other columns operating in different
                        directions, while Beauregard had the interior lines and could have
                        concentrated against any one of Sherman's wings; but he failed to do so
                        solely because he was too feeble to meet any considerable force in battle.
                        We do not apprehend that there can be any better point at which Beauregard
                        can give battle than the positions already surrendered. Every day's march
                        Sherman makes brings him nearer to heavy co-operating columns. The 23d corps
                        is in North Carolina, and must now be acting in direct support of Sherman,
                        and soon the grand armies of Grant must be in supporting distance of each
                        other to compass the reduction of the rebel capital.</p>
                    <p>Outside of the general aspect of military affairs, there are the strongest
                        evidence of the dissolving strength of treason. The speech of Secretary
                        Benjamin made recently in Richmond, admits that Richmond must be surrendered
                        unless the slaves are put in to the field, and he admits that unless they
                        are induced to go voluntarily by offers of freedom, they will fight <emph
                            rend="italic">against</emph> the rebels. He admits that the white
                        population of the South now subject to the despotism of Davis, is unequal to
                        the contest, and puts the issue squarely to the people that unless the
                        slaves come to the rescue of traitors, the rebellion is crushed. It is most
                        remarkable, too, that Vice President Stevens, although several times
                        announced, has never spoken since his return from the conference at Fortress
                        Monroe. He was understood as desiring peace before he came there; but it was
                        freely stated that he would now take the stump and advocate the maintenance
                        of the war at every sacrifice. But he is still reticent as ever, and seems
                        to have retired again to allow the madness of treason to expend itself in
                        the most wicked and hopeless war of history.</p>
                    <p>On every hand the cause of the government seems to promise decisive and early
                        success; and we hope that the day is near at hand, when the last army of
                        crime--that of Gen. Lee, will be compelled to seek uncertain refuge in the
                        Cotton States, and the authority of the government be resumed in Virginia
                        and North Carolina, as in Tennessee, Kentucky, Missouri, Arkansas and
                        Louisiana.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates the signs of the Confederacy's dissolution reported in the Raleigh
                    Progress.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Major Dodge</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The result is that volunteering has been almost wholly arrested, so men do
                    not appreciate the system of Major Dodge, whereby they are made the victims of
                    every atrocity his ingenuity can devise."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Major Dodge, the Assistant Provost Marshal of this State, and commandant at
                        Harrisburg, has been gravely censured by the legislature, and also by the
                        heads of Departments connected with the military service at the capital, for
                        wanton cruelty and shameless disregard of the wants of soldiers sent to Camp
                        Curtin to be organized into companies. A committee of the legislature was
                        appointed, upon the complaint of sundry soldier, to investigate the
                        condition of affairs of Camp Curtin, and they reported that the recruits,
                        just from their homes and not inured to the rigors of the camp, were left
                        there without adequate shelter or protection from the excessive cold, when
                        Maj. Dodge had not only ample authority but ample recources [sic] to supply
                        every want of the men. The same committee, or a part of it, also confer[r]ed
                        with Maj. Dodge on the subject, and found him entirely indifferent alike to
                        the wants of the soldiers and the efforts of the State authorities to remedy
                        his cruel negligence. The result was a joint resolution demanding his
                        removal, which passed the House by an overwhelming majority, and was passed
                        to third reading in the Senate by the decisive vote of 17 to 10, and even
                        those who voted in the negative took especial pains to state that they did
                        not mean to justify the conduct of Maj. Dodge.</p>
                    <p>The government is now in want of men, and particularly in need of volunteers,
                        who can be placed in the field with much more facility than can be attained
                        by the enforcement of the conscription. Harrisburg is the rendezvous for
                        such volunteers, and Maj. Dodge is the commander there. One company from
                        Lewistown--the first to respond to the call for fifty companies--tried Maj.
                        Dodge for a day or two, and then disbanded and returned home. The next lot
                        of volunteers that reached Camp Curtin enjoyed the luxury of standing out in
                        the snow day and night during the excessively cold weather of two weeks ago,
                        and had their feet and ears frozen because Maj. Dodge prefer[r]ed to have
                        them so exposed. The result is that volunteering has been almost wholly
                        arrested, as men do not appreciate the system of Major Dodge, whereby they
                        are made the victims of every atrocity his ingenuity can devise. How long
                        this state of things is to continue, the authorities at Washington must
                        determine. Gov. Curtin has repeatedly demanded the removal of Maj. Dodge
                        without indicating his successor or caring who he might be so that he should
                        come prepared to discharge his duty, and the legislature, certainly in no
                        factious spirit, has seconded the request of the Executive in the most
                        positive manner. Will the authorities at Washington disregard these demands?
                        If so they must prefer that Pennsylvania shall not promptly furnish
                        volunteers to strengthen our armies. No matter who Maj. Dodge is, or who
                        wants him here, or don't want him at the front. If he can't be used
                        advantageously elsewhere, let him report to a pile of brick or his arm-chair
                        at home if need be; but we submit that his insolent disregard of the wants
                        of our volunteers shall not be perpetrated at Harrisburg to chill the ardor
                        of our young men who are prepared to swell the ranks of our armies.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports the censure of Major Dodge, the Assistant Provost Marshal of
                    Pennsylvania, by Gov. Curtin for his mistreatment of enlisted men. Curtin
                    demands that Lincoln remove Dodge from office.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>A. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Describes two bounty bills relating to Franklin County: a bill authorizing
                    the collection of an additional $200 bounty paid by taxation and a bill
                    authorizing the townships of Green and Guilford to pay $300 to drafted men.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Harrisburg. Franklin County Bounty Bills. Bounties to Drafted New To Green and
                    Guilford--Removal of Major Dodge Demanded</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>"Horace"</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>"Horace" reports on the Franklin County bounty bills and the joint
                    resolution demanding the removal of Major Dodge.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Washington. March of Gen. Sherman--Congress--Important Bills yet to be
                    passed--Deaths of Senator Hicks--Murder in a Hotel--Re-Arrest of Baltimore and
                    Washington Merchants, &amp;c., &amp;c.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lists the important bills waiting for consideration, including the internal
                    revenue bill, bankrupt bill, and army and navy appropriations bills.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1865.02.22.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Memorial</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Earley</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Provides a biography of Robert Earley, formerly of Franklin, who served as
                    chief clerk of the Registrar's office and served the Union as a soldier.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Deserter Record</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The genuine, bonafide deserters, . . . should each apply for a copy to
                    preserve and hand down to their children (if the latter ever consent to own
                    them) as a memento of ancestral treason and poltroonery."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces the intention to publish a list of deserters and non-appearing
                    drafted men for 1863 and 1864.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>On Furlough</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foster</ln>
                        <fn>John D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that John D. Foster, a former member of the Repository staff and
                    member of Co. C, 19th Regiment Veteran Reserve Corps, is coming home for a
                    visit. He originally enlisted with the 140th New York.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Washington</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Conrad</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces a lecture by Conrad given at the Methodist church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Accident To Col. Spear</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spear</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports the injury to Col. Spear, of the 11th Cavalry. His horse fell on
                    him, causing internal injuries.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Acknowledgement</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"Lieut. Kingsbury on behalf of his company, makes the following
                    acknowledgement of mittens received from the Ladies' Aid Society of this place."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>"J. T. Kingsbury, 1st Lieutenant Comd'g"</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prints Kingsbury's letter thanking the Ladies' Aid Society for their
                    donations.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Resigned</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pyfer</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut. Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces the resignation of Lieut. Col. Pyfer, of the 77th Regiment,
                    because of bad health.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>To The Town Council</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Calls the town council's attention to the wall at Spahr's corner which "is
                    likely to fall at any moment."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Masonic Donations</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stover</ln>
                        <fn>J. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes the contribution of $200 by the St Louis Lodge, California, to the
                    sufferers of the George Washington Lodge of Chambersburg. J. E. Stover, formerly
                    of Chambersburg serves as the secretary of the St. Louis Lodge.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Sad Accident</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hargleroad</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports the injury of a young son of J. Hargleroad (who lives a few miles
                    north of Chambersburg) by a cog-wheel in the mill. He is expected to die.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Postmaster Appointed</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Goshorn</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doyle</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces the appointment of John Goshorn to replace Doyle as Postmaster at
                    Doylesburg, Franklin County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Summary Of War News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on the numerous deserters from rebel Gen. Early's army, Gen.
                    Grant's fortification of his army, and Lieut. Cushing's capture of numerous
                    towns and groups of soldiers on the Little River in South Carolina.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Personal</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Provides news on various notable people including Gen. Winder and H. S.
                    Foote.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Good News!! Sherman's Triumphant March! Columbia, S. C., Captured!! Charleston
                    Evacuated! The Old Flag Floats Over Sumpter!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes the situation in South Carolina, including the capture of
                    Columbia and evacuation of Charleston.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Capture of Gens. Kelly and Crook</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Discusses the capture of Gens. Kelly and Crook by rebel forces in
                    Cumberland, Maryland.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnhart</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woodward</ln>
                        <fn>George R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Switzer</ln>
                        <fn>Emily</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Switzer</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Switzer</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On February 15, by Rev. Barnhart, at the home of the bride's parents, in
                    Hamilton Township, George Woodward, of Wilmington, Delaware, married Emily
                    Switzer, of Franklin County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McHenry</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keckler</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hepfer</ln>
                        <fn>Matilday</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hepfer</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hepfer</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On February 15, at the home of the bride's parents, in the Jackson Hall
                    vicinity, by Rev. McHenry, Rev. Keckler, of Waynesboro, married Matilda Hepfer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bohn</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On February 6, in Charlestown, Virginia, Bohn, died at 22 years, 1 month
                    and 10 days. He was accidentally shot by a fellow soldier and was buried in the
                    Mentzer Grave Yard near Fayetteville.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baum</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On February 17, in Hamilton Township, Elizabeth Baum died in her 43rd year.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>The page includes advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1865.02.22.04">
            <pageNote>The page includes advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
