<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1865/pa.fr.fr.1865.05.31">
	<header>
		<title>Franklin Repository</title>
		<tagger>
			<taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
			<tagDate>07/19/99</tagDate>
			<tagNote/>
		</tagger>
		<address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
		<date n="1865-05-31">
			<year>1865</year>
			<month norm="05">May</month>
			<day>31</day>
			<weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
		</date>
		<frequency>weekly</frequency>
		<extent>04</extent>
		<editionNote/>
	</header>
	<paperBody>
		<page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1865.07.31.01">
			<div type="a">
				<column>6</column>
				<head>Andy Johnson Says The Debt Must Be Paid</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>The article supports President Johnson's contention that the nation's debt
					should be paid off as soon as possible.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1865.07.31.02">
			<div type="e">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Our Returning Soldiers</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>Since the national cause has triumphed and peace is restored, we have no
						longer any use for a large military force. All that the public service
						requires now is a force sufficiently large to garrison a few disaffected
						districts where treason and rebellion are chronic. Beyond this there can be
						no necessity for any formidable military power. Public sentiment in this
						country has always been averse to a large standing army in times of peace,
						and we think with good reason, inasmuch as it is a constant and exhausting
						drain upon the resources of the country with no compensating advantage,
						since our citizen soldiery are always enthusiastic in answering the call of
						the government and as effective as any when properly organized. As soon as
						our triumph was known to be complete, orders were issued providing for the
						immediate reduction of the military force. Thousands of soldiers who have
						been absent from their regiments in hospitals and elsewhere have already
						been mustered out, and the work of mustering out entire organizations will
						be commenced in a few days. The several divisions of the army will lose
						their distinctive organizations and remnants of each will be consolidated
						into one body known henceforth as the ARMY OF THE UNION.</p>
					<p>The armies of the Potomac, the James, the Ohio, the Tennessee and others, all
						of which have won for themselves imperishable renown, will pass into
						everlasting history, and the brave men who compose them, abandoning the
						weapons of war, will return to the peaceful pursuits of life. These
						different divisions were but parts of one grand army, the end of whose
						existence was the suppression of rebellion and the rescue of the Republic.
						The end having been gloriously attained, it is fit and proper that it should
						pass out of existence. The world has seen armies that could rival it in mere
						numbers, but in nothing else. The mighty hosts that centuries ago shook the
						earth with their tread were too often under the bondage of gross
						superstition, and those of more modern times have too often been the tools
						of power and the unwilling followers of ambitious men.</p>
					<p>There is nothing of this kind to detract from the fame of this grand army of
						ours. It was an army of free and intelligent men, with a cause to vindicate
						which of itself was sufficient to inspire all engaged in it with true
						courage and fortitude. Its soldiers fought not for empire, nor were they
						actuated by any but the noblest motives. They fought to defend and maintain
						a Republic which was the object of their pride and affection, and were
						animated by a lofty patriotism and sustained by a noble faith.</p>
					<p>The debt the nation owes them can never be repaid. To their heroic valor and
						patient endurance it owes its existence, and it stands to-day a monument of
						their devotion to liberty, dearer to us all because of the sacrifices by
						which it has been preserved. With its history they are inseparably linked as
						are their fathers who struggled to establish it. History will accord them
						equal honor, and the heroes of Gettysburg, of Petersburg, of Chattanooga and
						the hundred other battlefields of this war, will always be recognized as
						worthy descendants of the illustrious men who made immortal the names of
						Bunker Hill and Yorktown.</p>
					<p>All honor to these brave men! And now that those who have survived the fierce
						struggle are about to return to their homes, let the people who applauded
						them when they joined their fortunes with their imperiled country, and who
						have reaped incalculable benefits from their toils and sacrifices, manifest
						their gratitude by extending to them a cordial welcome. Let us show to them
						that we are willing to accord to them all that they have earned.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Though the war has ended and the ranks of the army will soon be thinned,
					the legacy of the soldiers' valor will never be forgotten, insist the editors.
					They will forever "be recognized as worthy descendants of the illustrious men
					who made immortal the names of Bunker Hill and Yorktown."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="e">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Treason</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt>"The law must be clothed with majesty and terror, and its vengeance must
					not be thwarted."</excerpt>
				<transcript>
					<p>The great drama of rebellion has closed and the government is now starting on
						a new era. If that era is to be concluded as the last was, by rebellion, it
						will be because we failed to profit by our experience and refused to make
						the proper use of the victory we gained.</p>
					<p>The recent triumph of the national arms ought not only to give to the
						Republic a new lease of existence, but with it an immunity from treason
						evermore. This much it will certainly do if we are but faithful to the laws
						and true to ourselves. But, if on the other hand, in taking counsel from our
						impatient desires for a return of the era of general amity and good feeling
						that existed before the war, we overlook the great crime that has drenched
						the land in fraternal blood, we need not be surprised if the bloody scenes
						of the past four years be re-enacted at some future period. It will not do
						to say that the failure of a rebellion so powerful as the last one was will
						deter men in future from attempting to subvert the Government, and that we
						can rest in perfect security in the newly acquired strength of that
						Government. This may be true today, and yet the events of another year may
						falsify it all. Heretofore we have relied entirely upon the good and
						friendly disposition of men's minds and hearts towards the Federal Union for
						its stability, and it needed a great rebellion to teach us that an
						additional safeguard was necessary. Let us learn still further from our
						bloody experience, or our security is but fancied. The law must be clothed
						with majesty and terror, and its vengeance must not be thwarted. We have a
						constitution which makes treason a crime and which affixes the penalty for
						its commission. Unless we enforce what is here decreed we rob the law of its
						virtue and the crime of its ignominy. If we wish to prevent a repetition of
						the offence we must unalterably determine it now, that they who trade in
						treason must expect to pay the penalty of their traffic. The course of the
						Government has determined to pursue in regard to Davis and other leading
						Southern conspirators is the one we think most likely to subserve the
						interests of this country in this particular. It is known that at least
						several of them are to be arraigned and tried for treason. The indictments
						have already been drawn against Davis and Breckinridge, and a true bill
						found by the grand jury of Washington. The next thing in order will be the
						trial. Apart from any consideration of the guilt or innocence of the
						prisoners, it will be of the greatest importance. We trust that it will be
						conducted with deliberation, and that a due regard will be paid to every
						legal formality, so that its adjudications of the many important questions
						involved may afterwards be recognized as the true and proper construction of
						the constitution and the laws. We ask only that the efficacy of the law be
						fully and fairly tested. Let it be determined now what treason is, and by
						whom and under what circumstances it can be committed. If Jefferson Davis
						and his associates have not been guilty of treason let them be acquitted of
						the charge, and let us so amend the laws that hereafter the offence will
						have its proper penalty. If their guilt is relieved by any constitutional or
						legal rights they have acquired during the war, let them have the full
						benefit of all such rights and let us do what we can to provide against such
						escape in the future. But if on the other hand they shall be adjudged guilty
						of treason and the law demand its victims, let it have them. If we interfere
						to thwart its vengeance we will be treasuring up danger for the future. In
						the language of Thomas Jefferson, "let us hear no more of confidence in man,
						but bind him down from future mischief by the strong chains of the
						constitution and the laws." The law must be made a terror to evil doers.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Having emerged victorious from the conflict with the South, the government
					should strive to ensure that such treason will never again threaten the nation's
					foundations, assert the editors. To prevent such a reoccurrence, the editors
					insist that the leaders of the rebellion should be punished appropriately.
					Should justice not be meted out to the perpetrators of "the great crime" that
					"drenched the land in fraternal blood," they maintain, it would not be
					surprising if the "bloody scenes of the past four years" were "re-enacted at
					some future period."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>2</column>
				<head/>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>It is reported that the Attorney-General has determined that the Amnesty
					Proclamation was "a means only to secure" the "suppression of the Rebellion."
					Consequently, the Amnesty is now void since the war has ended and, thus, the
					President no longer has the "power to pardon except for what is past." Moreover,
					the "decrees of confiscation" pertaining to land in the South "must stand."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>2</column>
				<head>Legal Tender Notes</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>The article relates that the State Supreme Court ruled on the case of
					William Shellenberger vs. Mary W. Brinton, which concerns the constitutionality
					of the United States' legal tender notes. Judges Strong, Reed, and Agnew
					affirmed the constitutionality of the bills while Judges Woodward and Thompson
					dissented from the majority opinion.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1865.05.31.03">
			<div type="e">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Local Items--Gossip With Our Friends</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>Gossip With Our Friends--I have once more been amid the ashes of old
						Chambersburg, and have soiled my fingers in rooting among the debris,
						obtaining as precious relics sundry broken tea cups and plates, fused
						goblets, and con-fused masses of bottles, nails, door knobs, locks, keys and
						lamp stands--trifles in themselves, but how priceless to the homeless, but
						thank God, not friendless. Let any one search through the mass of cinders
						and bricks, all that is left of his once happy home, and see if he can pick
						up any little thing, however defaced, if only recognizable, with which there
						may not be some association, whether it be the baby's doll, or the marble
						topped table upon which one or more children may have lain for the last time
						before being placed in the coffin that hid them forever from their parents'
						eyes. It is sad beyond description; and as anxious as we may be to have the
							<emph rend="italic">houses</emph> rebuilt, yet we know the <emph
							rend="italic">homes</emph> are gone, and we feel it to be almost
						sacrilege to have the shapeless mound of ruin removed--like the removal of a
						tablet from the grave of one dear to us. Thus the stir and bustle incident
						to rebuilding has something repulsive in it; for alack and alas, in a few
						short years the young will have forgotten the bitter story, and the old will
						die, their deaths hastened by the terrible calamity; and the whole history
						will occupy one paragraph, "In the year 1865, July 30, Chambersburg was
						fired and destroyed by a body of Rebels, under command of General
						McCausland." Your gossip has taken notes by the way, and thinks the rising
						generation is not inclined to trouble itself even now about the condition of
						the town; for happy faces and merry laughs and gay dresses meet him at every
						step. Perhaps it is well; but it grates upon the thoughts of one who <emph
							rend="italic">looks back</emph>. Well, well, let it go, the sooner the
						old fogies are laid aside, the sooner will the town be itself again. <emph
							rend="italic">Itself?</emph> Ah, never, never--"a town again"--that is
						better. Will the old trees grow again, the old rose bushes and honeysuckles
						put forth, the rare old ivy be green, the cedars that grew before the town
						was in existence, will <emph rend="italic">these</emph> same ever make us
						happy to give us shelter or make us swell with pride again. Let the young
						enjoy themselves, we old folks will meet unostentatiously, and will remind
						each other of our losses, not of our houses and lands and books and
						clothing, but of our <emph rend="italic">associations</emph>, that are gone
						forever. And as we repeat our Jeremiads, we cannot even point to a tree
						"planted by a forefather's hands."</p>
					<p>But I suppose the wishes of the old folks will not be regarded, and changes
						will be made; and if changes must come, I do hope that better, instead of
						worse houses will be erected. Already have some buildings of the <emph
							rend="italic">accidental</emph> order of architecture gone up--only to
						tumble down, in the first high wind. Taste costs nothing--indeed it often
						saves money. A good two story house is cheaper than a poor one of three; it
						is desirable that doors should shut, and windows slide; a house with a leaky
						roof is dear at any price; a serpentine wall is undesirable, either for
						beauty or safety; green timber indicates a similar mental condition in the
						builder; convenience is always economy, in the long run; and above all, it
						is not fair or honorable to rear a tumble down shanty along side of your
						neighbor's handsome mansion; for by doing so you injure his property as much
						as he has enhanced the value of yours. Temporary houses <emph rend="italic"
							>have been</emph> allowable under the circumstances; but they should all
						come down when the necessity is past.</p>
					<p>We should all feel truly grateful to the Trustees of the Academy for
						protecting the grounds with so substantial a fence; for the beautiful yard
						ran a risk of returning to the commons it had been [illegible]. Doubtless
						the academy will be rebuilt, when the proper time comes.</p>
					<p>The occupation of Richmond, the surrender of Lee and Johnston, and the
						capture of Jefferson Davis, have given new zest to the old town, and the
						sound of hammer and saw lasts the livelong day. If only Uncle Sam would give
						us a little help; we could soon show the world how much of recuperation
						there is in Americans.</p>
					<p>Yes, the war is over. Now who doubts that the roar of Niagara is the rustling
						of the American Eagle's wings; that the lakes are his washpots; that the
						Rocky Mountains were made for his resting place; that thunders are but the
						sound of the flapping of his wings, that the lightning is the flashing of
						his eyes. The London Times will please copy. Already we hear Europe shriek
						with Trabb's boy, "Hold me, I'm so frightened!"</p>
					<p>John Thomas Fitz Gerald (some say his name is <emph rend="italic"
						>Gerald</emph>, and that his wife, who is rather high minded, gave him
						"Fitz") visited me last evening, looking very low spirited, and handed me
						the following for publication "in our esteemed journal:"</p>
					<p>A LADY'S LOGIC--BY A LADY<lb/> You can't, I can; you aren't, I am;<lb/> You
						won't, I will;--I'll <emph rend="italic">not</emph> be still;<lb/> You
						may'nt, I may; I'll strike dismay<lb/> Where e'er you go, with sounds of
						woe;<lb/> Your "yes," my "no;" your "head," my "toe;"<lb/> I'll scratch, and
						bite, and scream, and fight<lb/> And spit, and howl with language foul.<lb/>
						Until you cry, "I faint, I die,<lb/> Unless I fly--" Thus argue I.<lb/>
						"John Thomas, beware!"</p>
					<p>I have not heard from my southern correspondent this week, though I hear she
						landed safely as Fortress Monroe.</p>
					<p>New York, May 29, 1865</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Gossip laments the passing of "old Chambersburg," which was destroyed
					during McCausland's raid, and cautions local residents to avoid shoddy
					construction practices when rebuilding the town.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Local Items--In Memoriam</head>
				<origin>Shippensburg News</origin>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Bayne</ln>
						<fn>William U.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>A short piece memorializing William U. Bayne, who died in the Andersonville
					POW camp during the war. Prior to enlisting in the army, Bayne was employed at
					the Shippensburg News.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>2</column>
				<head>Local Item--Serious Accident</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Clark</ln>
						<fn>Joseph</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Rev. Joseph Clark broke his arm in an accident that occurred while he was
					hauling logs with his wagon. Although the pain is severe, he is expected fully
					recover.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>3</column>
				<head>Latest News</head>
				<origin>Chicago Tribune</origin>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Reports that an ordinance depot exploded in Mobile on May 26th, levelling
					eight square blocks of buildings and burying five hundred people.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>3</column>
				<head>Latest News</head>
				<origin>Washington</origin>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Arrangements for the surrender of General Kirby's forces in the
					Trans-Mississippi have concluded.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Fahnestock</ln>
						<fn>Benjamin A.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Sellers</ln>
						<fn>Frances R.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Hassler</ln>
						<fn>Jacob</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On May 13th, Benjamin A. Fahnestock and Frances R. Sellers were married by
					Rev. Jacob Hassler.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>McAtee</ln>
						<fn>John J.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Craig</ln>
						<fn>Louisa M.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Craig</ln>
						<fn>Jesse</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Creigh</ln>
						<fn>Thomas</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On May 25th, Rev. John J. McAtee, of Lunenburg, Nova Scotia, and Louisa M.,
					daughter of Jesse Craig, of Welsh Run, were married by Rev. Thomas Creigh.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Snyder</ln>
						<fn>Robert</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Robinson</ln>
						<fn>Martha</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Eshelman</ln>
						<fn>John</fn>
						<sf>Esq.</sf>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On May 23rd, Robert Snyder and Martha Robinson were married by John
					Eshelman, Esq.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Murray</ln>
						<fn>Sarah</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On March 31st, Sarah Murray, formerly of Franklin county, died in Urbana,
					Ohio. Murray was 38 years old.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Nicklas</ln>
						<fn>William H.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On May 16th, William H. Nicklas, a member of Co. D. 207th, Penna. Vols.,
					died of typhoid fever at the 3rd Division, 9th Army Corps Field Hospital.
					Nicklas was 21 years old.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1865.05.31.04">
			<pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
		</page>
	</paperBody>
</hwp>
