<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vr1863/pa.fr.vr.1863.02.27">
    <header>
        <title>Waynesboro Village Record</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>10/31</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Waynesboro</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1863-02-27">
            <year>1863</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day>27</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vr.1863.02.27.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>It Surpasses Uncle Tom's Cabinet</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In one of Gen. Butler's late speeches at the East, he said:</p>
                    <p>He had on reading Mrs. Stowe's book--"Uncle Tom's Cabin,"--believed it to be
                        an overdrawn, highly-wrought picture of Southern life, but he had seen with
                        his own eyes, and heard with his own ears many things which go beyond her
                        book as much as her book does beyond an ordinary school-girl's novel. He
                        related an instance of shocking demoralization of society at New Orleans.
                        There came into his office a woman, 27 years of age, perfectly white, who
                        asked him in proper language if he would put her in one of her father's
                        houses. Her history was this: Her father had educated her in the city of New
                        York, until she was between 17 and 18 years of age, and taken her to one of
                        the metropolitan hotels, where he kept her as his mistress. Not relishing
                        the connection, and desiring to get away from him, she went to New
                        Orleans--he followed her, but she refused to live with him, at which he
                        whipped her in the public street, and made her marry a slave. She afterwards
                        resumed the unnatural relation, and went to Cincinnati, but was brought back
                        by her husband, or father, with a child, belonging to somebody. Her father
                        fled from the city at the time of its occupation by the United States
                        forces, leaving her in a state of destitution. She wanted to live in one of
                        her father's houses, but her story was not credible, and he determined to
                        investigate it. To his surprise it was found to be well known, and testimony
                        of its truth was obtained from A, B and C without difficulty.</p>
                    <p>Notwithstanding this fact, widely known as it was, this man could be elected
                        in Louisiana, in the city of New Orleans, a Judge of one of the Courts. On
                        one occasion, one of his aids brought before him a young woman almost white,
                        who had been brutally whipped and turned out of the house of her father. For
                        this outrage the man had been made to pay a fine of $1,000 and give the
                        woman a deed for emancipation. [Applause.] These were the kind of charges
                        which had been brought against him. [Cheers; and cries of [unclear].] Yes,
                        no right minded man could be sent to New Orleans without returning an
                        unconditional Anti Slavery man, even though the roofs of the houses were not
                        taken off and the full extent of the corruption exposed. All the lower class
                        of the people of New Orleans were loyal. During the first fourteen days
                        after the Union forces entered the city, 14,600 took the oath of allegiance
                        and, when he went on board the steamer, on his return to the North, at least
                        one thousand laboring men came down upon the levee, and uttered no words
                        except those of good will to him as the representative of the Government.
                        General Butler continued by saying that the war could only be successfully
                        prosecuted by the destruction of slavery, which was made the cornerstone of
                        the Confederacy.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An extract from a speech delivered by Gen. Butler in which the commander
                    recounts several anecdotes that reveal the depth of depravity occasioned by the
                    institution slavery.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Nashville Union</origin>
                <commentary>"The Nashville Union thus forcible and truly discourses on the sham
                    unanimity of the South infavor of the slaveholders' rebellion:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Nashville Union thus forcible and truly discourses on the sham unanimity
                        of the South in favor of the slaveholders rebellion:</p>
                    <p>"The <emph rend="italic">Louisville Union</emph> says that the Southern
                        people <emph rend="italic">were</emph> not disunionists. We never said the
                        contrary, and we go still further, and affirm our belief that the <emph
                            rend="italic">Southern people are</emph> not to-day disunionists. If the
                        conscription law, enforced by Morgan, Forrest, Wade, and hundreds of other
                        guerilla chiefs with armed bands of desperadoes, had not recruited the rebel
                        armies; if a military tyranny, more terrible than Austrian despotism, did
                        not stamp out the first symptoms of resistance; if it were not high treason
                        to hinder the circulation of confederate notes; if the power of a wealthy
                        and a most unanimous consolidated slaveholding minority were broken, a large
                        majority of the citizens of the south would to-day be for the Union. The
                        fear of the dungeon, the halter, and the sword, have silenced the voice of
                        southern loyalty."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article contends that, despite their opposition to the war, common
                    whites in the South are forced to support the Confederacy. "If the power of a
                    wealthy and almost unanimous consolidated slaveholding minority were broken," it
                    argues, "a large majority of the citizens of the south would to-day be for the
                    Union." It is only out of the "fear of the dungeon, the halter, and the sword"
                    that "the voice of southern loyalty" has been silenced.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vr.1863.02.27.">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Promoted</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brownson</ln>
                        <fn>R. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>It is reported that Capt. R. S. Brownson, of Co. C, 126th Regiment P. V.,
                    was made the Major of the regiment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Promoted</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>John E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John E. Walker, member of Co. A, 77th Regiment, P. V., has been promoted to
                    captain.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Editor Arrived</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Kennedy has returned home to Chambersburg after being honorably
                    discharged from the army as a result of illness. It is expected that Kennedy
                    will resume his work with the Spirit and Times. Kennedy served as a member of
                    the 126th Regiment P. V.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Brought Home</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>George F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harlan</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The remains of George F. Davis were returned to his home in Franklin county
                    where they will be interred in the cemetery of the German Reformed Church. Davis
                    died last September in Suffolk, Va., while fighting in Col. Harlan's cavalry,
                    and was initially buried there.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Good Act</head>
                <origin>Pilot</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Easton</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Easton</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McPherson</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. M. Easton, son of Capt. Easton, who was killed in the Battle of Gains
                    Hill, was appointed to a position in the Naval Academy by Hon. E. McPherson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Our Citizens in Richmond</head>
                <origin>Mercersburg Journal</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rice</ln>
                        <fn>Perry A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>As indicated by a letter from Perry A. Rice, word has arrived that the
                    Union soldiers from Franklin county, who were being held in Libby prison in
                    Richmond, have been transferred to Castle Lightning. There is little chance that
                    the men will be exchanged; in fact, rumor has it that the prisoners will be
                    transferred further south "in order to keep them with greater safety and at less
                    expense."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Look Out for Them</head>
                <origin>Examiner Herald</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The piece cautions readers to be on the alert for high quality counterfeit
                    five-dollar bills from the Bank of America, of New York City.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Harrisburg Counterfeits</head>
                <origin>Spirit and Times</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Counterfeit five-dollar bills from Harrisburg have recently appeared in
                    Philadelphia. Two men have been arrested in connection with the crime. The bills
                    "are tolerably well executed and calculated to deceive."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Officers Dismissed</head>
                <origin>Republican</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Black</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>Jeremiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Horsbaker</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>It is reported that Capt. G. W. Black, of the 107th Regiment, Lieut.
                    Jeremiah Cook, of Chambersburg, and Lieut. Samuel Horsbaker, of Mercersburg,
                    both of the 126th Regiment, have been dismissed from the service for being AWOL.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Emancipation Bill</head>
                <origin>New York Tribune</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"If it was right to buy Louisiana in order to secure the West to the Union,
                    it is clearly so to purchase the slaves of Missouri in order thereby to protect
                    the National existence against an instant and deadly peril."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">The Emancipation Bill</emph>. The Senate on Thursday week
                        passed the bill to aid Missouri to emancipate her slaves by 28 Yeas to 18
                        Nays. This is purely a measure of national defence against a great and
                        imminent peril. Slavery in Missouri has already put the Nation to an expense
                        of at least One Hundred Millions within the last two years and is certain to
                        cost much more unless eradicated. If it was right to buy Louisiana in order
                        to secure the West to the Union, it is clearly so to purchase the slaves of
                        Missouri in order thereby to protect the National existence against an
                        instant and deadly peril. In no possible contingency must Missouri be lost,
                        and her loyalty in this crisis may save the Union. If this bill be passed,
                        she is with us evermore.--<emph rend="italic">New York Tribune</emph>.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article relates that the Senate approved a bill, by a vote of 28 to 18,
                    to aid Missouri in a program to emancipate the slaves within its borders.
                    According to the piece, in addition to putting the country in "imminent peril,"
                    the continued existence of slavery in Missouri cost the government "at least One
                    Hundred Millions" over the course of the last two years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Revivals of Religion</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is reported that several revivals are now in progress throughout
                    Pennsylvania. The revivals are being conducted chiefly by Lutheran and Methodist
                    churches, and are having tremendous success at converting the masses.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Depreciation of Slave Property in Maryland</head>
                <origin>Baltimore</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In an appraisal of the estate belonging to Charles Carroll, one of the
                    largest slave holders in Maryland, his 130 slaves were valued at an average of
                    $5 each. The surprisingly low figure, remarks the article, "is considered a
                    striking illustration of the depreciation of slave property by the rebellion,
                    and will have a powerful influence" in Maryland.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Altar</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Leckrone</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Funk</ln>
                        <fn>Barbara C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rebaugh</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Feb. 5th, Lewis Leckrone and Barbara C. Funk were married by Rev. John
                    Rebaugh.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Altar</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kittinger</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Holsinger</ln>
                        <fn>Christean B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Good</ln>
                        <fn>D. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Holsinger</ln>
                        <fn>Dan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Feb. 24th, Benjamin F. Kittinger, of Adams county, and Christean B.
                    Holsinger, daughter of Rev. Dan Holsinger, were married by Rev. D. F. Good.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Tomb</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>Charlotte</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Feb. 15th, Charlotte, youngest daughter of John and Sarah Johnson, died
                    near Waynesboro. She was 18 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vr.1863.02.27.03">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vr.1863.02.27.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
