<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vr1863/pa.fr.vr.1863.02.13">
    <header>
        <title>Waynesboro Village Record</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>10/30</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Waynesboro</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1863-02-13">
            <year>1863</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day>13</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vr.1863.02.13.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Truths About Rebel Leaders</head>
                <origin>Chester County Democrat</origin>
                <commentary>"The editor of the Chester County Democrat, himself an old Democrat,
                    thus writes from Washington:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Though a Democrat, the author of the piece rails against treasonous
                    Southerners and refutes the notion that they have "great integrity" and a
                    "chivalric sense of honor."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Loyalty of Kentucky</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A copy of the resolution offered in the Kentucky Legislature on Jan. 26th.
                    The decree declares the state's "unwavering" "devotion and attachment" to the
                    federal government.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Singular Incident</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Our correspondent T., writing from the Ninth Army Corps, apposite
                        Fredericksburg narrates the following, which occurred on Christmas day,
                        while the writer was out on picket with his company:</p>
                    <p>After partaking of a Christmas dinner of salt junk and hard tack, our
                        attention was attracted by a rebel picket who hailed us from the opposite
                        side of the river:</p>
                    <p>"I say, Yank, if a fellow goes over there will you let him come back again?,"</p>
                    <p>Receiving an affirmative answer, he proceeded to test the truth of it by
                        paddling himself across the river. He was decidedly the cleanest specimen of
                        a rebel I had seen. In answer to a question, he said he belonged to the
                        Georgia Legion. One of the boys remarked, "I met quite a number of your boys
                        at South Mountain." "Yes, I suppose so--if you were there," said the rebel,
                        while his face grew very sad. "We left very many of our boys there. My
                        brother, poor Will, was killed there. It was a hot place for a while, and we
                        had to leave it in a hurry." "That's so, Georgia, your fellows fought well
                        there, and had all the advantage, but the old Keystone boys were pressing
                        you hard. By the way I have a likeness here (taking it out of his pocket)
                        that I picked up on the battle field the next morning and I have carried it
                        ever since." He handed it to the rebel, who, on looking at it, pressed it to
                        his lips, exclaiming "my mother! my mother!" He exhibited considerable
                        emotion at the recovery of the picture, but on regaining his composure, he
                        said, that his brother had it in his possession, and must have lost it in
                        the fight.</p>
                    <p>He then asked the name of the one to whom he was indebted for the lost
                        likeness of his mother, remarking "There may be better times soon, and we
                        may know each other better." He had taken from his pocket a small pocket
                        bible in which to write the address, when Alex---, who had taken no part in
                        the conversation, fairly yelled, "I know that book! I lost it at Bull Run!"
                        Thar's whar I got it, Mr. Yank," said the rebel--and he handed it to Alex.
                        "I am much obliged to you, Georgia Legion, for I wouldn't part with it for
                        all the Southern Confederacy." I was a little curious to know something
                        further of the book, so I asked Alex to let me see it. He passed it to me. I
                        opened it, and on the fly leaf saw written in a neat lady's hand: "My
                        Christmas Gift to Alex---, Dec 25th, 1860. Ella." "Well, Alex," said I, "it
                        is not often one has the same gift presented to him a second time." "True,
                        Captain; and if I could but see the giver of that to-day, there's but one
                        other gift that I would want."--"What's that, Alex?" "This rebellion played
                        out, and my discharge in my pocket."</p>
                    <p>The boys had all been busily talking to our rebel friend, who, seeing a
                        horseman approaching in the direction of his post, bid us a hasty good-bye,
                        and made as quick a trip as possible across the Rappahannock. Night came on,
                        and those not on duty lay down on the frozen ground, to dream of other
                        Christmas nights, when we knew not war.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A sentimental account of a conversation that occurred between a Union
                    soldier and Confederate soldier during a brief interlude from the fighting at
                    the Battle of Fredericksburg. Over the course of the interaction, the soldiers
                    discovered that they shared a strange bond, one that extends beyond the fact
                    that they have fought in the same battles.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vr.1863.02.13.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Small Pox</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that the outbreak of small pox in Waynesboro appears to be
                    subsiding.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Lieutenant Colonel</head>
                <origin>Lancaster Examiner</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The piece relates that Capt. Pyfer, of Lancaster, has been appointed
                    Lieutenant Col. of the Pennsylvania 77th Regiment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Mr. Stephen's Bill</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is reported that Mr. Stephen's bill to raise 150,000 black soldiers
                    passed the House on Monday by a count of 83 to 55. At Mr. Casey's urging, the
                    bill contained an amendment exempting Maryland, Kentucky, Tennessee, Delaware,
                    Missouri, and Western Virginia from the provisions of the bill. It also forbade
                    black officers from commanding white soldiers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Deserved Promotion</head>
                <origin>Dispatch</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sergt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The article proudly notes that Sergt. Thomas Myers, of Co. K, 107th
                    Regiment Pa. Vol., has been promoted to First Lieutenant and commissioned by
                    Gov. Curtin. Myers participated in "several severe engagements" prior to the
                    Battle of Fredericksburg, where he was severely wounded. Myers is recovering
                    quickly and is expected to return to duty soon.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Fourteen Battles</head>
                <origin>Dispatch</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An addendum to the notice of Sergt. Patrick Curran's death. Curran had an
                    illustrious career as a soldier, participating in at least fourteen battles,
                    before falling at Fredericksburg. Lauding Curran's actions on the battlefield,
                    the piece asserts that the Union would have long since vanquished the South if
                    all Union troops had the "same heroic, unselfish patriotism" that Curran and his
                    outfit, the Irish Brigade, possessed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Defense of Rev. I. J. Stine</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Defense of Rev. I. J. Stine</emph>.--Our readers
                        doubtless remember an article published in our paper, some time since,
                        announcing the arrest and imprisonment of the Rev. I. J. STINE, on the
                        charge of betraying Captain PALMER, of the Anderson Troop, into Rebel
                        captivity, while acting as a scout for him. We are pleased to learn,
                        however, it is incorrect, and that since the return of Captain P. from
                        rebeldom, he has written to Mr. Stine a letter in which he not only
                        establishes his innocence of the charges preferred against him, but also
                        compliments him for important and useful services rendered our Army during
                        the week of the Rebel so-journ in Maryland. Below we publish a letter from
                        Mr. Stine, and also the one written by Captain Palmer to him:--</p>
                    <p>Shippensburg, Pa, Feb. 5.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Editor, Village Record</emph>:--The following letter
                        which I have received from Capt. Palmer since his return from "Dixie," will
                        explain itself.</p>
                    <p>The story of my betrayal of him is known, as also the facts of my arrest and
                        imprisonment on that charge with two others annexed.</p>
                    <p>You will oblige by publishing this very important testimony to my fidelity to
                        Capt. P. I am preparing a defense in full, which I will send you next week.</p>
                    <p>If I have suffered wrongfully, the satisfaction of having been useful in the
                        service of my country, even for one brief but <emph rend="italic"
                        >auspicious</emph> week, has been something to me. The wreck of rebel rule
                        in Maryland and the rout of the invader has marked an epoch in my life, as
                        in the history of the "great Rebellion." I am satisfied. "All's well that
                        ends well," I have also had a personal interview with Capt. P., very
                        pleasant and satisfactory indeed.</p>
                    <p>Very Respectfully,</p>
                    <p>I. J. Stine.</p>
                    <p>Germantown, Jan. 28th, 1863.</p>
                    <p>Rev. I. J. Stine, Shippensburg, Pa.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Dear Sir</emph>:--I take the earliest opportunity, after
                        my return from Rebeldom, to write to you.</p>
                    <p>Nothing, during my confinement in Confederate prisons, caused me more regret
                        than the report that you had been arrested and imprisoned on charge of
                        having betrayed me into Rebel captivity; and take much pleasure in saying
                        that there never existed the slightest foundation in fact, for the charge
                        referred to. The services you rendered our Army, at the time of the invasion
                        of Pennsylvania, were of the most important and useful character, and in my
                        opinion, there is not a more loyal man in the State than yourself.</p>
                    <p>Allow me to add, that for the disinterestedness you manifested during your
                        imprisonment, and since your release on parole, in not mentioning any of the
                        particulars connected with my capture, preferring rather to suffer awhile
                        longer under the imputation of being guilty, in the hope of my return, than
                        to imperil my safety by attracting further attention to my case--you have my
                        profound gratitude.</p>
                    <p>I have written to the Secretary of War, requesting him to discharge you from
                        parole.</p>
                    <p>You are at liberty to use this in any way you see fit for the vindication of
                        your character.</p>
                    <p>Yours Truly,<lb/> WM. J. Palmer,<lb/> Captain Commanding<lb/> Anderson
                    Troop.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Correspondence from Capt. William J. Palmer exonerating Rev. I. J. Stine
                    from the rumors that he betrayed Palmer into "Rebel captivity."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Altar</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Horn</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Benedict</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Benedict</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Oiler</ln>
                        <fn>J. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Jan. 30th, John Horn and Elizabeth Benedict, daughter of Samuel
                    Benedict, were married by Rev. J. F. Oiler.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Altar</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dahoof</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gonder</ln>
                        <fn>Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Oiler</ln>
                        <fn>J. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Feb. 5th, Jacob Dahoof, Frederick county, Md., and Ann Gonder were
                    married by Rev. J. F. Oiler.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Tomb</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hellane</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Jan. 28th, Catharine Hellane, 58, died in Quincy township.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Tomb</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allen</ln>
                        <fn>Rachael V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allen</ln>
                        <fn>Henry C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allen</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Feb. 10th, Rachael V., daughter of Henry C. and Mary Allen, died in
                    Waynesboro. She was 8 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vr.1863.02.13.03">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vr.1863.02.13.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
