<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vr1863/pa.fr.vr.1863.05.22">
    <header>
        <title>Waynesboro Village Record</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Waynesboro</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1863-05-22">
            <year>1863</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day>22</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vr.1863.05.22.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Women</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>From the earliest ages to the present time women have been alternately
                        worshiped as "angels" and reviled as "cats" and "serpents"--according as
                        they have behaved to their adorers and detractors. Women puzzled King
                        Solomon and perplexed St. Paul. Messages to his female converts testify to
                        the difficulty some of them caused him. In our day, however, our schoolboy
                        seems to think he can solve all the difficulties of the woman
                        question--their natural tendencies, possibilities and prospects in this
                        life. Woman, instead of being, as heretofore, the rock on which wise men
                        have split, are now become little more than the blocks which fools try to
                        cut with their razors, while waiting for their beards to grow. What women
                        have been, we know pretty well--average human beings, on the whole doing
                        their duties as well as they know how, nurturing the qualities of their
                        husbands, their sons or their brothers. They have made themselves effectual
                        elements in the ordering of human affairs. There is no instance where a man
                        has become a great leader, either as general, statesman or religious
                        reformer, who had not some woman living at the root of his inner life,
                        fostering his ideas and his aims--with whom he has taken counsel--out of
                        whose thoughts he has derived nutriment for his own thoughts--who has helped
                        him, and believed in him, and advised him; and stuck to him, when the whole
                        world seemed against him. Women do not often achieve greatness for
                        themselves, but they are at the bottom of all that is good and the most of
                        what is bad, in the world.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Though they have been both vilified and valorized throughout history,
                    women, notes the article, are "average human beings," who have "made themselves
                    effectual elements in the ordering of human affairs." No man, it concludes, has
                    ever succeeded without the support of a good woman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vr.1863.05.22.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Public Dinner</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An announcement that a dinner will be held on June 3rd in honor of the
                    return of the "nine month soldiers."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Union League Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Besore</ln>
                        <fn>Josiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoner</ln>
                        <fn>S. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sanders</ln>
                        <fn>Levi</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Potter</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coon</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hennicle</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Leckrone</ln>
                        <fn>Simon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bonebreak</ln>
                        <fn>D. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoner</ln>
                        <fn>Henry X.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heller</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Monn</ln>
                        <fn>A. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>At the meeting of the Union League last Monday, a committee was selected to
                    make arrangements for the public dinner to be given for the returning "nine
                    month soldiers" from Co. E. 126th Regiment P. V.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Indignant</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The arrest of Vallandigham has sparked considerable unrest among
                    copperheads, says the article, even in Waynesboro. Some of his supporters
                    proposed having a rally in town to voice their displeasure with the arrest, but
                    opted not to because it was deemed "inexpedient at this time."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Traitor Vallandigham</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is reported that Vallandigham has been convicted of treason by the Court
                    Martial and sentenced to "close confinement" in Fort Warren for the duration of
                    war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Enrollment for the Draft</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Provost Marshals have been given the order to proceed with the draft. It is
                    believed that it will take between fifty and sixty days to complete the task.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Army Correspondence</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The latest installment from W. T. B. describes life in Washington, N. C., a
                    town near the confluence of the Tar and Swift rivers. Shortly after his company
                    took the town, an order came from Headquarters mandating that all citizens who
                    had not taken the oath of allegiance were to be "conveyed" beyond the lines the
                    following day. In reaction, he writes, most members of the "proud and richer
                    classes" packed their belongings and left town, their future uncertain. The
                    letter also castigates copperheads, including the editor of the Valley Spirit,
                    for their traitorous behavior.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Richmond papers announce the death of the famous Rebel General Jackson,
                        popularly known as Stonewall Jackson. He died on Sunday from wounds received
                        in the late engagements on the south side of the Rappahannock. General
                        Jackson had his left arm shattered near the shoulder, and also received a
                        ball through his right arm. Curiously enough the Richmond Despatch alleges
                        and finds consolation in the fact that he was not wounded by our men, but
                        received his death injuries from his own men in the confusion of the fight.
                        The death of Gen. Jackson is undoubtedly a very severe loss to the Rebels.
                        For some species of work, which required dash, energy and reckless bravery,
                        he was unquestionably their most able General. For the good of our cause we
                        may rejoice that he is out of the way, but even whilst thus rejoicing, a
                        brave enemy will not withhold an expression of admiration of his soldierly
                        abilities and personal virtues. He has hit our army many severe blows and
                        only needed a better cause to have been one of the world's heroes.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is reported that Gen. Jackson died last Sunday after suffering wounds
                    from friendly fire. For the good of the cause, the editors rejoice that Jackson
                    "is out of the way," yet they acknowledge an "admiration of his soldierly
                    abilities and personal virtue."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Tomb</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jacobs</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On May 16th, Elizabeth Jacobs, "a lady of amiable disposition" and
                    "irreproachable character," died in Waynesboro. She was 32 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vr.1863.05.22.03">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vr.1863.05.22.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
