<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vr1863/pa.fr.vr.1863.05.29">
    <header>
        <title>Waynesboro Village Record</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Waynesboro</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1863-05-29">
            <year>1863</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day>29</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vr.1863.05.29.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Original Copperhead</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Utilizing an extract from an address given by Benedict Arnold to validate
                    its claim, the piece casts copperheads as the heirs to his legacy of shame.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>The page includes a variety of sentimental articles concerning social
                relations and religion.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vr.1863.05.29.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Hog Law</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors praise the decision made by Waynesboro's High Constable to
                    enforce the hog law. Already, they declare, several arrests have been made.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Dinner for the Soldiers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jacobs</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Informs readers that the dinner for the returning members of the Co. E.
                    126th Regiment P. V. will be held at the Grove on George Jacobs's farm.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Returned Soldiers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Askwith</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dorsey</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kester</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Discharged members of Co. E. 126th arrived back in town on Saturday evening
                    causing quite a stir. Led by Capt. William Askwith, a delegation from Waynesboro
                    met the soldiers near Greencastle and escorted them the rest of the way.
                    Addresses were given by Rev. Dr. Dorsey and Rev. Kester to mark the occasion.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Loyal Union Leagues</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editorial seeks to increase the ranks of the Union League's membership
                    by dispelling the rumors that the organization is a "Barn Association" or a
                    "secret, oath-bound order."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The $300 Exemption Annulled</head>
                <origin>New York Tribune</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">The $300 Exemption Annulled.</emph>--The Washington
                        correspondent of the New York <emph rend="italic">Tribune</emph> states that
                        the Secretary of War has decided that a proper interpretation of the
                        conscription act makes it the province of War Department and not of the
                        individual drafted to decide whether $300 shall excuse a man or not; from
                        serving under a draft; and that the Secretary will not be likely to excuse
                        any man but for the most valid reasons. This is right. We never approved of
                        this $800 exemption clause in the Conscription act, because we believe that
                        in its operation it would favor the rich and discriminate against the
                    poor.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is reported that the Secretary of War has determined that the
                    conscription act grants the War Department, and not the individual drafted, the
                    right "to decide whether $300 shall excuse a man" from his military obligations.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Case of Vallandigham</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Since last week's report that Vallandigham had been sentenced to
                    confinement for the duration of the war, news has arrived that, on the order of
                    President, the "Copperhead traitor" was instead sent to the enemy lines.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Another Horse Stolen</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Once again, says the article, John Funk had his horse stolen from the
                    stable yard of Kurtz's Hotel. It is widely accepted that the thieves are men who
                    live in-town or nearby.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Issue</head>
                <origin>Shippensburg News</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">The Issue</emph>.--Whilst the direct and primary issue is
                        between Freedom and Slavery, there are other questions of equal importance
                        depending upon the result. No intelligent man can have failed to observe
                        that the present war must either result in the complete and final overthrow
                        of the slave power, or in its substantial triumph. In the former case the
                        feasibility of free institutions will be firmly established, in the latter
                        the last ray of hope will be gone forever. The success of our experiment as
                        a free people depends upon the power of our government to maintain its
                        supremacy over all the States of the American Union. So soon as we are
                        compelled to humiliate ourselves, by yielding to a refractory power, a
                        precedent will be established, which will open the way to speedy and final
                        destruction of American Liberty.</p>
                    <p>The real issue, therefore, is not so much between freedom and African
                        slavery, as between an aristocratic and free form of government. Slavery so
                        far as it is involved in the great issue is only collateral and auxiliary to
                        the accomplishment of the main object of the slaveholders of the South,
                        namely the establishment of a government based upon the power of the few
                        over the many which means not only the oppression of the black man, but of
                        all poor men, of whatever race or color. Therefore the triumph of the slave
                        power in the present issue, must result in the dismemberment of the American
                        Union; it will inevitably lead to the establishment of a monarchy upon these
                        Western shores. In an issue so momentous it behooves every good citizen and
                        christian man to divest himself of all party prejudice and to stand up
                        firmly for the government of our fathers.</p>
                    <p>Never was there an issue in which there were more important interests at
                        stake, yet strange to say there are men to be found in every community who
                        cannot see beyond party interests, who are blind to every principle of
                        patriotism and who are doing everything in their power against the
                        Administration in its efforts to maintain the integrity of the nation. Let
                        these persons remember that whatever they may do by way of embarrassing the
                        government, is doing so much to encourage the enemy, and prolong the war.
                        Had it not been for the encouragement afforded by Northern sympathizers to
                        the enemy, they would be already crushed and the supremacy of the government
                        established. Every effort therefore in opposition to the government, is a
                        blow at American Liberty. And every one of these sympathizes is a wretch
                        unworthy of the protection of a good government, and a murderer of our brave
                        soldiers, who are meeting the enemy in deadly conflict.--<emph rend="italic"
                            >Shippensburg News</emph>.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Though slavery is clearly the primary issue in the conflict between the
                    states, says the editorial, at a certain level, the strife is based upon a more
                    fundamental divide. In essence, the war is a struggle "between an aristocratic
                    and free form of government." Should the North fail to defeat its foe, the piece
                    promises, this outcome "will inevitably lead to the establishment of a monarchy"
                    in the South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>A Call</head>
                <origin>Pilot</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Presbyterians in Greencastle and Waynesboro unanimously decided in favor of
                    hiring Rev. J. W. Whitman, of Pittsburg, to lead their churches.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vr.1863.05.29.03">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vr.1863.05.29.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
