<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vr1863/pa.fr.vr.1863.05.15">
    <header>
        <title>Waynesboro Village Record</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Waynesboro</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1863-05-15">
            <year>1863</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day>15</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vr.1863.05.15.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Gag Rule</head>
                <origin>Exchange</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"All things have an end, and thank God this gagging administration will have
                        an end too," said a soreheaded Vallandighamer in our hearing a few days ago.
                        "A man is not permitted to speak his sentiments; if he does attempt it, he
                        is at once silenced by some Lincolnite," continued he. This is certainly a
                        very grave matter. A freeman in the land of liberty, not permitted to speak
                        his sentiments! This is horrible! but the question arises, what are the
                        sentiments which he is not permitted to utter? If his sentiments are those
                        of loyalty to the Constitution and laws, no man will molest him for his bold
                        and fearless utterance of them wherever the stars and stripes float in
                        triumph above him. No where but in the land of treason is he in danger for
                        the avowal of such opinions. If, however, his sentiments be those of
                        hostility to the government in her efforts to crush out this base
                        rebellion--if they prove that he sympathizes with treason, and that his
                        efforts are directed to the securing of a peace which would prove
                        disgraceful to the nation and dangerous to our liberties, then the
                        Government will 'gag' him and every loyal man will stand firmly by her in
                        her efforts to do so. If men will disgrace themselves and posterity by
                        becoming the apologists of traitors and tyrants, and by basely deserting the
                        flag of their country, they cannot expect that their perfidy will be
                        permitted to pass unrebuked, or that a loyal people will tolerate the
                        utterance of such sentiments. We have a government which is struggling for
                        its life against an unscrupulous and unprincipled foe, and that Government
                        must be sustained let the cost in men and money be what it may, and all who
                        are its enemies either openly or covertly, must be taught a lesson which
                        they can never forget and which will serve as a warning to others who may
                        hereafter seek to overthrow the Republic.</p>
                    <p>A gagging administration, indeed! Shall it tolerate treason without giving
                        evidence of a desire to arrest it? Shall every disloyal tongue be permitted
                        to spit out its venom against it with impunity? Henceforth when we hear men
                        crying "gag," we shall set them down as traitors to their country--wretches
                        who would willingly aid the rebel crew of the south to destroy the glorious
                        work of our patriotic sires--who would exult over our downfall as a nation,
                        and who would willingly become the pliant tools of that despotism which
                        Southern traitors are now attempting to thrust upon us.</p>
                    <p>Gag a man because he denounces the Government for defending the Constitution
                        against the attacks of traitors, thieves and scoundrels! A mild offence,
                        indeed, for such punishment! It would be a favorite doctrine of such
                        worthies, for the administration to sit down with folded hands, and calmly
                        permit them to cripple our brave army in its efforts to uphold the
                        Constitution and laws, and to save the Government from destruction. Allow
                        them to utter their base sympathies in behalf of treason, and many a mother
                        will mourn for the loss of her brave son; many a wife will weep for a
                        husband that she will never see again, and many a child will be fatherless
                        and destitute, compelled to encounter the buffetings of a friendless world.
                        Allow those men to clamor against the cause of right, and justice and
                        liberty, and anarchy will take the place of order, and we will have no law
                        but the law of the bandit, and no security but our strong arm.--<emph
                            rend="italic">Exchange</emph>.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editorial contests the notion that the government's efforts to stamp
                    out the spread of anti-war rhetoric is censorship, and questions whether
                    "traitors" deserve the same protection as loyal citizens.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Altoona Register</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The piece relates the story of a woman from Altoona who concealed her sex
                    and joined the army. The woman fought in three battles before being discovered,
                    which occurred after she sustained an injury to her arm. The wound was her
                    second.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vr.1863.05.15.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Meeting of the Union Loyal Leagues</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>At the last meeting of the Loyal League on Tuesday, arrangements were made
                    to give a public reception to the soldiers of Co. E 126th Regiment P. V. upon
                    their return home.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Still At Large</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Despite the existence of a "hog law," the High Constable of the Borough has
                    failed to enforce the measure, says the article. The cause of his inaction stems
                    from an erroneous belief that the law is unconstitutional. As a solution, the
                    article calls for a "little 'coercion,'" if necessary, to carry out the law.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Legal Notices</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors have received word that the legislation mandating the
                    publication of all legal matters in each counties' two largest journals has no
                    teeth. That is, there is no penalty for failing to comply with the act.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Death of Sergeant Peters</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peters</ln>
                        <fn>John H</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sergeant</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On April 30th, Sergeant John H. Peters, a member of Co. E, 126th Regiment
                    P. V., died at Lincoln Hospital, Washington, D. C. Peters suffered a fatal
                    injury during the First Battle of Fredericksburg, where he was commended and
                    promoted for his part in the engagement. The soldier's death is particularly
                    difficult for the editors at the Village Record because Peters worked as their
                    apprentice prior to joining the army.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>County Superintendent</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McElwain</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Last Monday, the School Directors' Convention elected Andrew McElwain, of
                    Chambersburg, County Superintendent for a term of three years. McElwain will
                    leave his current job as the Principal of the Public High School of Chambersburg
                    to take the post.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The President's Proclamation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In preparation for the enforcement of the Conscription Bill, Lincoln has
                    issued a proclamation declaring that foreigners, who intend on becoming
                    citizens, are not exempted from the draft if they remain in the U. S. within
                    sixty-five days of the passage of the bill.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Another Military Arrest</head>
                <origin>Mercersburg Journal</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is reported David Lawson, an associate of the infamous Solomon Helser,
                    was arrested by the Provost Guard on Monday after his name appeared on some
                    documents taken from Helser.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Board of Enrollment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seiss</ln>
                        <fn>R. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McIlhenny</ln>
                        <fn>John T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The members of the Board of Enrollment for the 16th Military District of
                    Pennsylvania, which includes Franklin county, have received their commissions.
                    The appointments are as follows: Capt. George Eyster, of Chambersburg, Provost
                    Marshall for the District; Dr. R. S. Seiss, of Littlestown, Surgeon of the Board
                    of Enrollment; and John T. McIlhenny, of Gettysburg, Commissioner of the Board
                    of Enrollment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Casualties in the 126th Regiment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Casualties in the 126th Regiment</emph>.--We give the
                        following list of killed, wounded and missing of this regiment, as published
                        in the last <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph>:</p>
                    <p>Killed.</p>
                    <p>Nicholas C. Trout--Comp. C.<lb/> Simon W. Rupley--Comp. K.<lb/> Corp. George
                        F. Missavy--Comp. K.</p>
                    <p>Wounded.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Company B</emph>.--M. W. Kissecker, hand; Jas. Noy, arm;
                        Asa Glenn, side; G. Burns, hand; James O. Cleary, hip; S. N. Salkeld, thigh;
                        John Oliver, leg.</p>
                    <p>Company C.--George Cole, head; James McConnell, leg; Sergt. D. L. Coyle,
                        shoulder; W. Starleper, thigh; B. Bruce, thigh; J. T. Ripple, knee; William
                        S. McDowell, head; Sergt. Thos. D. Metcalf, head; Corp. J. Oliver Parker,
                        hand; J. L. Jimmerman, arm; W. G. McCartney, leg.</p>
                    <p>Company D.--Capt. J. C. Hullinger; Lewis Monath, arm; Adam Nicklas, leg;
                        Upton H. Moore, breast; Walker Shearer; John B. Hart; Corp. Andrew Holby; J.
                        L. Schultz, foot and shoulder; John A. J. Snyder.</p>
                    <p>Company F.--Lieutenant Samuel Bonsall; William Soule, nose.</p>
                    <p>Company G.--Sergt. S. O. B. McCurdy, arm; James McCartney, hand; Corp. R.
                        Walters, leg.</p>
                    <p>Company H.--John Stouffer, wrist; John Wilson, side; N. M. Bowers, leg;
                        Calvin M. Skinner, knee; Wm. A. Gaston, thigh; Martin Stubbs, arm; Andrew A.
                        Pomeroy, arm; Joseph Shaeffer, shoulder; Samuel Lee, shoulder; John Smith,
                        head; Jas. Williams, arm; John H. Everett.</p>
                    <p>Company I.--Sergt. N. H. Gibler; J. A. Still; Cornelius Brantly, shoulder; M.
                        Wilson; James Gray.</p>
                    <p>Company K.--Lieut. J. G. Rowe, head; Corp. S. K. Snively, ankle; J. C.
                        Bemesderfer, head; William Rupert, hip; John Robinson, knee; J. A. Unger,
                        breast; Samuel Palmer.</p>
                    <p>Missing</p>
                    <p>Jonathan Bowman, Company B.<lb/> Lieut. Clay McCauley, Company D.<lb/> Lieut.
                        J. W. Fletcher, Company H.<lb/> Wm. H. Snively, Company K.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>Nicholas C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rupley</ln>
                        <fn>Simon W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Missary</ln>
                        <fn>George F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Corp.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kissecker</ln>
                        <fn>M. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Noy</ln>
                        <fn>Jason</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Glenn</ln>
                        <fn>Asa</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burns</ln>
                        <fn>G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cleary</ln>
                        <fn>James O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Salkeld</ln>
                        <fn>S. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Oliver</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cole</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McConnell</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coyle</ln>
                        <fn>D. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Starleper</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bruce</ln>
                        <fn>B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ripple</ln>
                        <fn>J. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDowell</ln>
                        <fn>William S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Metcalf</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parker</ln>
                        <fn>J. Oliver</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jimmerman</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCartney</ln>
                        <fn>W. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hullinger</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Monath</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nicklas</ln>
                        <fn>Adam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moore</ln>
                        <fn>Upton H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shearer</ln>
                        <fn>Walker</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hart</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Holby</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shultz</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>John A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bonsall</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Soule</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCurdy</ln>
                        <fn>S. G. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Serg.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCartney</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walters</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Corp.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stouffer</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowers</ln>
                        <fn>N. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>Calvin M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gaston</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stubbs</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pomeroy</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shaeffer</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lee</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Williams</ln>
                        <fn>Jason</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Everett</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gibler</ln>
                        <fn>N. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Serg.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Still</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brantly</ln>
                        <fn>Cornelius</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gray</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rowe</ln>
                        <fn>J. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snively</ln>
                        <fn>S. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Corp.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bemesderfer</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rupert</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robinson</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Unger</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palmer</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowman</ln>
                        <fn>Jonathan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCauley</ln>
                        <fn>Clay</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fletcher</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snively</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A list of the wounded, missing, or killed members of the 126th Pennsylvania
                    Regiment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Tomb</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peters</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On April 30th, John H. Peters, of Co. E. 126th Reg. P. V., died at Lincoln
                    Hospital in Washington, D. C. Peters was 22 years of age.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Tomb</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilbert</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilbert</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On May 10th, Sarah Gilbert, wife of Capt. David Gilbert, died in Boonsboro.
                    She was 61 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Tomb</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On May 7th, Henry Myers, 74, died at Welsh Run.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vr.1863.05.15.03">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vr.1863.05.15.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
