<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vr1863/pa.fr.vr.1863.03.20">
    <header>
        <title>Waynesboro Village Record</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>11/07</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Waynesboro</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1863-03-20">
            <year>1863</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day>20</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vr.1863.03.20.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Speech Of Hon. H. B. Wright</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"The following speech was delivered by Hon. Hendrick B. Wright, at the
                    organization of the Union League Association, in Philadelphia, on the 11th
                    inst:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A transcript of Wright's address. Though a Democrat, Wright chastised the
                    faction within his party that sympathizes with the Confederacy, labeling its
                    members "enemies" of the country.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>New Use of Bloodhounds</head>
                <origin>Philadelphia Ledger</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article asserts that a new use has been found for bloodhounds in the
                    South. Though traditionally used to capture runaway slaves, since the outbreak
                    of the conflict, the dogs have been used to track down whites "hiding in the
                    woods to escape the fierce conscription act which is now seizing about every man
                    under sixty years of age able to carry a gun."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vr.1863.03.20.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Graduated</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snively</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The article proudly notes that Isaac N. Snively recently graduated from
                    Jefferson Medical College in Philadelphia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A report that the "colored men" of Pittsburg are actively engaged in
                    raising a regiment for the war. Thus far, they have enjoyed "encouraging
                    success."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>A Union League</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Noting that Union Leagues have sprung up across the North "with surprising
                    rapidity," the article calls for the organization of a chapter in Waynesboro.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Progress of Union Leagues</head>
                <origin>Chicago Tribune</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The piece informs readers that 500 chapters of the Union League have been
                    established in Illinois.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is reported that Union men in Texas are mounting considerable opposition
                    to the Confederacy. In the event of a Union victory, the rebels in the state
                    have formulated a contingency plan; they will "retire to Mexico, and establish a
                    republic under a French protectorate."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The President has issued a Proclamation requiring all men who have been
                    enlisted or drafted into Union forces to return to their respective commands by
                    April 1, 1863 "under pain of being arrested as deserters and punished as such."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Work of Copperheads</head>
                <origin>Detroit Free Press</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Men roamed the streets besplattered with blood of innocent victims,
                    bawling like fiends, and demanding more blood."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A dreadful riot happened in Detroit last week, in consequence of a gross
                        outrage committed by a brutal negroe. For some months, however, copperheads
                        of that place have been endeavoring to incite for political effect, a mob
                        against the negroes, and were unsuccessful until the perpetration of the
                        offence stated. In place of permitting the law to take its course, which
                        would have adequately punished the offender, war was declared against all
                        the negroes of Detroit. Leaders distributed whiskey among their followers,
                        and the work of murder and arson, was commenced and prosecuted until the mob
                        desisted in consequence of sheer exhaustion. To exhibit the fiendish
                        character of this massacre of innocent persons by a drunken, frenzied mob,
                        it is related that a house containing several negroes was set on fire, and
                        according to an account in the Detroit <emph rend="italic">Free
                        Press</emph>, one colored woman made her appearance at the door with a child
                        in her arms and appealed to the mob for mercy. The monstrous fact must be
                        told that her tearful appeals were met with a shower of bricks, stones and
                        clubs, driving herself and the babe in her arms back into the burning
                        building.</p>
                    <p>Men roamed the streets, besplattered with the blood of innocent victims,
                        bawling like fiends, and demanding more blood. It became necessary to call
                        the military from a distance to restore order. Surely such conduct as this
                        is only equalled by the recent Indian massacres in Minnesota, and will
                        always rest as a foul stain on the good name of Detroit. Yet this is the
                        kind of work traitors desire to see inaugurated in the North for which they
                        are working; to counteract which loyal men everywhere must labor
                        unceasingly.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on a "race riot" that occurred in Detroit. During the melee, bands
                    of drunk white men roamed the streets of the city in search of blacks, including
                    women and children, whom they beat, in many instances, to death. The orgy of
                    violence continued until troops were called in to restore order.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Altar</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bellane</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Krebs</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On March 12th, Daniel Thompson and Elizabeth Bellane were married by Rev.
                    W. Krebs.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Tomb</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Speck</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Speck</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Feb. 14th, Mary Speck, "consort" of Frederick Speck, died near
                    Waynesboro. She was 80 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Tomb</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jacobs</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Last Sunday, Henry Jacobs died near Waynesboro. He was 66 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Tomb</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brenner</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On March 9th, Joseph Brenner, 78, died.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Tomb</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On March 4th, Susan Miller, 69, died in Waynesboro.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vr.1863.03.20.03">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vr.1863.03.20.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
