<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1867/va.au.ss.1867.01.29">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>John Riedl</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/11/00</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1867-01-29">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day>29</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1867.01.29.01">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1867.01.29.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Manufacturing Interests</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Undoubtedly the State of Virginia presents, says the <emph rend="italic"
                            >Alexandria Gazette</emph>, a most attractive field for the investment
                        of capital in manufacturing enterprises. Probably, there is not in the
                        world, a country offering the facilities for the manufacture of implements,
                        materials, and goods of all descriptions, woolen, cotton, iron, &amp;c.,
                        &amp;c., &amp;c., that can be found in Virginia-and it so happens
                        that, just at this time, owing to peculiar circumstances, these facilities
                        can be most profitably used, in the hands of those who have the means to
                        embark in the enterprises of which we have spoken. The great want with <emph
                            rend="italic">us </emph>, for such undertakings, is the need of
                        CAPITAL.-Our people have not, generally, the money to expend in building and
                        starting large factories and workshops. But still the inviting prospect of
                        prosperity and wealth, in a short time, by the establishment of
                        manufactories in Virginia, is held open to the people of all nations, and
                        sooner or later their attention will be attracted. Now, in England, Germany
                        and France, there is abundant capital, and labor to spare. Why cannot some
                        of that capital and labor be transferred to Virginia, and be here turned to
                        an account, far surpassing what is generally accumulated by engaging in
                        manufacturing business in European countries? On the other side of the
                        Atlantic the manufactures have our tariffs to contend against. Here they
                        could have the tariff to their own advantage, and thus receive benefits from
                        the laws which were designed to exclude them from our shores. They and all
                        others, who would come to Virginia, to embark in the business, would find
                        the raw material at their doors, the water power thundering in their ears,
                        the coal beneath the soil on which they tread. They would enjoy a fine
                        climate, and healthy country, and productive land. They would be welcomed
                        and hospitably received.-The Legislature, even, we have no doubt, would be
                        liberal in its action, for the encouragement of the growth of manufactures
                        in our State, looking o the benefits that would accrue to all the interests
                        of the Commonwealth. This important subject was favorably noticed by some of
                        the best and most influential of our farmers at their late convention in
                        Richmond. Indeed, the establishment of home manufactories is every way
                        desirable to them, and they feel that it is their interest to promote their
                        success in every possible form. The loom and the forge are the natural
                        allies of the plough, when the work is all done at home, and the profits to
                        enure to the prosperity of our own State, and not to be sent abroad to fill
                        the coffers of others, already "overflowing with money." We trust that this
                        matter will be taken up with zeal, and that the capabilities and advantages
                        of Virginia will be made known to capitalists and manufacturers in Europe,
                        as well as in portions of this country where capital is seeking a profitable
                        investment.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lauds the industrial potential of Virginia, arguing that the "capabilities
                    and advantages" of the state should be "made known to capitalists and
                    manufacturers in Europe, as well as in portions of this country where capital is
                    seeking a profitable investment."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Foreigners North and South</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The census of 1860 shows that the foreign population of the United States now
                        amounts to more than four millions, having nearly doubled in the ten years
                        from 1850 to 1860. The countries from which this emigration has principally
                        come, are Ireland, which has sent 1,611,304 of the foreign residents;
                        Germany, 1,301,136; England 431,692; British America, 249,970; France
                        109,870; Scotland 108,516; whilst the remainder is made up from almost every
                        country on the face of the earth, including China, which sends 33,565 to
                        California; 3,582,999 of the whole number of foreign born are inhabitants of
                        the Free States, and only 553,176 of the Slave States. It is easy, says the
                        Baltimore <emph rend="italic">Transcript</emph>, to account for this
                        difference. Slavery repelled immigration. Free labor could not exist
                        prosperously in contact with slave labor. Slavery required large
                        plantations, and in a land of small farms could not be maintained. But now
                        that slavery is abolished, there is no reason why the main current of
                        immigration should continue in the West. There is, in fact, every reason to
                        the contrary. There is no labor required in the South for clearing and
                        settling, which, in the West, must cost from fifty to a hundred dollars an
                        acre, even if the land be got for nothing. Cleared lands, with all the
                        improvements can be bought in the South for less than half per acre that it
                        will cost the emigrant to clear and settle lands in the West, even if the
                        lands cost nothing. The South has besides the advantages of greater nearness
                        to market, a more genial and healthful climate, an older civilization;
                        churches, houses, roads and mills already constructed. These facts, but for
                        the scandalous misrepresentations of the enemies of the South, and the
                        turmoil and convulsions which are apprehended there from the destructive
                        influence of political fanaticism, would inevitably secure the South its
                        full share of foreign immigration.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the "foreign population" of the country is now four million,
                    having nearly doubled in the decade from 1850 to 1860. The article also contends
                    that the South cannot procure "its full share of foreign immigration" because of
                    "the destructive influence of political fanaticism."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1867.01.29.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News--Mr. Stuart's Lecture</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Rev. S. D. Stuart, of this place, who was recently on a visit to England,
                        delivered a lecture before the Staunton Lyceum on last Friday night. A
                        number of ladies and gentlemen, not members of the Society were present, and
                        all were highly gratified and most pleasantly entertained for more than an
                        hour. Mr. Stuart commenced his lecture with his embarkation from the port of
                        New York, and after a varied voyage-having encountered the cloud, sunshine
                        and the gale-landed safely at Liverpool. And there, being on the soil of old
                        England, he visited many points of interest, and being a minister of the
                        gospel; he heard many of the most distinguished and noted divines, some of
                        whom delighted him, and others fell below what he anticipated. He heard the
                        noted Spurgeon preach to his congregation of 5000 souls, and while there was
                        nothing peculiarly striking or attractive in the personal appearance of this
                        eminent divine, yet he held his audience and seemed to sway them at
                    will.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>S. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. S. D. Stuart delivered a lecture at the Staunton Lyceum last Friday
                    night, detailing his recent trip to England. The large crowd was reportedly
                    "highly gratified and most pleasantly entertained."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News--Staunton Musical Association</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The war has not quite knocked us into flinders, though it has somewhat
                        prostrated us. We have a flourishing Lyceum, a Philomathesian Society, and a
                        talented corps of Thespians. In addition to these intellectual associations,
                        we have now a regularly organized Musical Society, composed of the best
                        professional and amateur talent of our community. On Tuesday night last,;
                        the 22nd inst., a meeting of ladies and gentlemen, lovers of the "divine
                        art," took place and the "Staunton Musical Association" was organized by the
                        election of the following officers:</p>
                    <p>Prof. J. H. Hewitt, President.</p>
                    <p>Mr. R. M. Guy, Secretary.</p>
                    <p>" D. W. Drake, Treasurer.</p>
                    <p>" C. H. Hunter, Librarian.</p>
                    <p>Dr. J. L. Brown, Director.</p>
                    <p>Prof. Joel Ettinger, Organist.</p>
                    <p>Their meetings are to take place weekly, on Tuesday evenings.</p>
                    <p>A large number of ladies were present at the meeting, and contributed greatly
                        to the furtherance of the object in view. On assuming the chair, Prof.
                        Hewitt made some very appropriate remarks-urging the members to promptness
                        and unity. A number of fine choruses were then sung with an effect that
                        would have done credit to an experienced choir, every part being complete.</p>
                    <p>We hail the formation of this Association with feelings of pleasure, as we
                        are confident that it will be the fountain of much social enjoyment to our
                        citizens, and furnish us with a class of music which will please our senses,
                        while it improves our taste.</p>
                    <p>We have been requested to state that honorary membership will be conferred,
                        the trifling subscription being $3 per annum. Such members will have the
                        privilege of attending concerts and rehearsals.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hewitt</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guy</ln>
                        <fn>R. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Drake</ln>
                        <fn>D. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunter</ln>
                        <fn>C. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ettinger</ln>
                        <fn>Joel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Staunton Musical Association was organized last week with the election
                    of officers and scheduling of meetings.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Busey</ln>
                        <fn>E. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cease</ln>
                        <fn>Erasmus P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swink</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Erasmus Cease and Sarah Swink were married on January 22 by Rev. E. F.
                    Busey.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stevenson</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>G. Harvey</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>M. Virginia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>M. Virginia Brown, of Sangersville, and G. Harvey Brown, of Rockingham,
                    were married at the home of the bride's mother on December 24 by Rev. G. W.
                    Stevenson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>W. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fifer</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickle</ln>
                        <fn>Caroline S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Caroline Bickle and Benjamin Fifer were married in Staunton on January 24
                    by Rev. W. E. Baker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Leonard</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yount</ln>
                        <fn>Nannie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Nannie Yount and Jacob Leonard were married at the home of the bride's
                    father on January 22 by Rev. C. Beard.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lindamood</ln>
                        <fn>Carrie Lee Catherine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lindamood</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lindamood</ln>
                        <fn>Hannah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Carrie Lee Catherine, the only child of Hugh and Hannah Lindamood, died on
                    December 29. She was 6 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hansbarger</ln>
                        <fn>G. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thornton</ln>
                        <fn>John S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Morris</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lowry</ln>
                        <fn>G. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. John S. Thornton died at the home of G. C. Harnsbarger, near Mount
                    Sidney, on January 19. She was 22.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1867.01.29.04">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
