<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1867/va.au.ss.1867.10.08">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>John Riedl</taggerName>
            <tagDate>11/29/00</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1867-10-08">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="10">October</month>
            <day>08</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1867.10.08.01">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1867.10.08.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>County Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that a public meeting will be held at the Staunton Court House
                    next Saturday "to nominate conservative candidates to represent Augusta County
                    in the Constitutional Convention."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Our Town and its Business</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It must be a source of pleasure to our citizens to witness the activity and
                        animation which pervades all departments of business in our community. At no
                        former period has there been so much energy, industry and thrift among our
                        people. New buildings are going up in all quarters, and stores and workshops
                        are multiplying and the demand for houses still continues. The present crop
                        of grain, with one stock of old corn on hand, will bring near one million of
                        dollars into our county. Our streets are daily thronged with wagons, loaded
                        with flour, corn and rye, and our enterprising merchants give liberal prices
                        for all kinds of produce.-The apple crop of the present season will also be
                        a source of large revenue, and the time is at hand when our farmers will be
                        forwarding quantities of hogs, sheep and cattle to market. The vast
                        production of the Valley must soon fill the pockets of the farmers, and
                        relieve the pecuniary pressure which has heretofore weighed on our people.</p>
                    <p>All that we need is the assurance of future peace and quiet, in political
                        matters. When this is afforded by the results of the elections in the
                        Northern States, which are now at hand, we shall witness an era of
                        prosperity heretofore unparalleled.</p>
                    <p>Our farmers have shown wonderful elasticity under the difficulties which have
                        heretofore surrounded them. They have promptly accommodated themselves to
                        the new order of things. They are rapidly substituting machinery for negro
                        labour. They have bought hundreds of reapers, mowers, wheat drills, sulky
                        ploughs, and other implements of the best descriptions. They have bought,
                        liberally, guano, bone dust, and other fertilizers, and many are using lime
                        and ashes as manures. An unusually large crop of wheat have been sown, and
                        it has been put in, in good time, and with great care and labour. The recent
                        rains will give the wheat crop a good start, and without some unexpected
                        disaster, we may hope for a bountiful crop next year.</p>
                    <p>But we are sorry to learn that a large part of the trade of the Valley is
                        being diverted from Richmond, to other cities. We learn from the officers of
                        our banks that they find their balances rapidly accumulating in Baltimore,
                        instead of Richmond, and drafts on New York are now freely offered. This
                        indicates that our products are finding a market in those cities. Formerly
                        almost every thing was sold in Richmond. Our Richmond friends must look to
                        this. New York dealers are coming among us and securing all the fine flour
                        of the Valley. Thousands of barrels are brought here, and shipped either
                        directly through Richmond, to New York, or by the Alexandria and Lynchburg
                        R. R. to Baltimore. Our Richmond merchants must rouse themselves to new
                        efforts, or they will find a large part of their trade diverted from
                        them.-The Valley flour is of superior quality, and the New York and
                        Baltimore merchants have discovered the fact, and are striving to monopolize
                        it. In Richmond there has been an "old fogy" idea that none but the Richmond
                        "City Mills" can make good flour. Our mills, though not as extensive as
                        those of Richmond, make quite as good, if not better flour, than that made
                        in Richmond, because they have better material to operate on. The Valley
                        wheat is superior to the lowland wheat, and it is housed in spacious barns,
                        instead of being stacked or ricked.-Hence the wheat is in better condition
                        and makes better flour. Sagacious men from New York have discovered this
                        fact, and have formed connections here to out-bid Richmond for our flour,
                        and secure the control of our trade.-When Valley four goes to Richmond it is
                        put on the level with ordinary Eastern flour and brings no higher prices.
                        New York men, availing themselves of this blunder of our Richmond friends,
                        are rapidly securing all the flour of the Valley and sapping the foundations
                        of Richmond trade. Northern agents are here too secure the fruit crop of the
                        Valley for the New York market.</p>
                    <p>We repeat, our Richmond friends must bestir themselves, and counteract this
                        diversion of trade, which should legitimately belong to them. Why is it that
                        corn is worth $1.35 in Baltimore and only $1.27 in Richmond?-and why is it
                        that farmers can do better by selling to New York agents in Staunton, than
                        by forwarding Richmond? These matters must be looked into and remedied, or
                        Richmond will be left in the lurch.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Praises the "activity and animation which pervades all departments of
                    business in our community," but laments the fact that "a large part of the trade
                    of the Valley is being diverted from Richmond to other cities."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Negro Conventions</head>
                <origin>Lynchburg Republican</origin>
                <commentary>"The Lynchburg Republican very plainly and pointedly exhibits the folly
                    of reconstruction on the plan of the late Rump Congress, in the following
                    article on that subject:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"The only argument we have ever seen advanced in favor of voting for negro
                        Conventions in the Southern States is this: that if our people do not vote
                        for such Conventions they will not get back into the Union, and Congress
                        will proceed at once to impose greater burdens upon us than we now endure.
                        The design of this argument is to appeal to the fears, ambitions and
                        selfishness of the masses, and compel them to vote to negroize their section
                        of the Union.-These specious pretences may deceive for a time "little wanton
                        boys that swim on bladders in a sea of glory," but they are far beyond the
                        depth and unworthy the sense and sanction of wise and patriotic men. To
                        adopt a State Constitution imposing universal negro suffrage upon our people
                        will be a "frost, a killing frost," that will nip the root of our social and
                        political systems, and make us fall as Lucifer fell, never to hope again!</p>
                    <p>1. What are the facts in the case? The first fact is that we are not out of
                        the Union at all! For four years the people of the South fought to get out,
                        and to maintain the right of secession, while the people of the North
                        asserted precisely the contrary, and successfully maintained it. They
                        declared that the Southern States were not out of the Union, and could not
                        fight out or get out. We are, therefore, certainly in the Union, and every
                        citizen is clearly entitled to all the rights of citizenship under the
                        constitution, until he is convicted of treason, rebellion or other crime
                        under the laws of the land. But a revolutionary and tyrannical Congress,
                        influenced by base partizan purposes have resolved to ignore all these
                        clearly defined principles and rights, and not only to legislate us out of
                        the Union, but to impose upon us the most grinding exactions and
                        usurpations! Will it not, therefore, be the extreme of folly and timidity
                        for our people to do more than submit to this despotic rule? Can we, without
                        dishonor and ruin, vote to impose upon ourselves negro suffrage and negro
                        equality, and transform our State governments into the most grinding
                        despotisms at the bidding of a corrupt and lawless Congress?</p>
                    <p>2. The second fact to be considered in refutation of this view of
                        reconstruction is this:--Can Congress impose upon the people of the South
                        anything more odious and oppressive than it has already inflicted "outside
                        the constitution?" We assert that it can do no such thing. Congress has
                        already converted ten States into Territories and placed them under absolute
                        military despotism. Neither our lives, liberty or property and any longer
                        free from violation or abuse, but completely at the mercy of our military
                        commanders. A large portion of our best citizens are disfranchised, and all
                        the white population of these States are made subject to the domination of a
                        different race and color. It is absurd to suppose that Congress can impose
                        upon us a more odious or detestable system of despotism than this. Military
                        rule and Congressional rule are infinitely preferable to negro rule.
                        Congress had better confiscate our property than for our former slaves to do
                        it under State supremacy. In fact, property will be worthless when the
                        negroes take possession of our State and local governments, and the
                        protection of the military is withdrawn from us.</p>
                    <p>It is manifest, therefore, from this reasoning that for the people of the
                        South to seek to get back into the Union under negro governments, is far
                        greater folly than for them to remain where they are under the protection of
                        white military officers.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that voters should not be persuaded to vote for a Convention because
                    of the specter of Congress imposing "greater burdens" on the South if they fail
                    to call conventions. The author contends that Congress could not "impose upon us
                    a more odious or detestable system of despotism" than subjecting whites "to the
                    domination of a different race and color" and concludes that it would be better
                    for Congress to "confiscate our property than for our former slaves to do it
                    under State supremacy."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that "the Radicals of Southampton have nominated John Brown, a
                    genuine negro, for the Convention."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1867.10.08.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News--Staunton Lyceum</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p> On the 30th inst., the following question was discussed:--<emph
                            rend="italic">Ought capital punishment be abolished?</emph> Powell
                        Harrison, Esq., and Col. Bolivar Christian in the affirmative, and Rev. G.
                        B. Taylor and Col. Baldwin in the negative, which was decided by a vote of
                        10 against 6 in the negative.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harrison</ln>
                        <fn>Powell</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>Bolivar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>G.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Staunton Lyceum met on September 30 to discuss the question--"ought
                    capital punishment be abolished?" After debate the question was decided in the
                    affirmative by a vote of 10 to 6.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Many Voters</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gray</ln>
                        <fn>Charles Douglas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>"Many Voters" nominate Charles Douglas Gray as a candidate to the
                    Convention, praising his "sympathy with the conservative portion of the people
                    of the State."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Conservative</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mason</ln>
                        <fn>C. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>"Conservative" nominates C. R. Mason as a delegate to the Convention for
                    the three counties of Augusta, Albemarle, and Louisa.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Many Voters</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harrison</ln>
                        <fn>Powell</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hendren</ln>
                        <fn>J. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>"Many Voters" nominate J. A. Waddell, Powell Harrison, and J. N. Hendren as
                    delegates to the Convention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Numerous Conservatives</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>Jos. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mauzy</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>Alex. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>"Numerous Conservatives" nominate Joseph Waddell, R. Mauzy, and Alex.
                    Cochran as delegates to the Convention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We nominate, as a suitable gentleman to represent you in the approaching
                        Convention. Mr. CHARLES DOUGLAS GRAY, the Register in Bankruptcy for this
                        district.</p>
                    <p>In presenting his name we have no eulogy to pronounce, but venture to
                        suggest, that if superior attainments, spotless purity of character, and
                        thorough sympathy with the conservative portion of the people in the State,
                        be qualifications for the position, he, in a rare degree, possesses them.</p>
                    <p>If Mr. G will announce himself a Candidate for the position he will receive
                        the cordial support of MANY VOTERS.</p>
                    <p>Town papers are requested to copy.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Many Voters</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mauzy</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>Jos. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hendren</ln>
                        <fn>J. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>"Many Voters" nominate R. Mauzy, Jos. Waddell, and J. N. Hendren as
                    delegates to the Convention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Many Conservatives</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mauzy</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>"Many Conservatives" nominate R. Mauzy, the editor of the Spectator, as a
                    delegate to the Convention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Colored Congressmen</head>
                <origin>Mobile Advertiser and Register</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Advises blacks to vote for "their own color" instead of supporting
                    "imported scalawags or pale-faced renegades," arguing that "we can trust a
                    Southern black man when we cannot trust a white traitor or a Yankee speculator."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cox</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary McClure and Alexander Cox were married on September 19 by Rev. C.
                    Beard.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Root</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hizer</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Margaret Hizer and William Root were married on September 22 by Rev. C.
                    Beard.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kiracofe</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yago</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>Virginia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Virginia Johnson and John Yago were married on October 3 by Rev. J. W.
                    Kiracofe.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brower</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strole</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brower</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sarah Brower and Isaac Strole were married near Hermitage on October 5 by
                    Rev. John Brower.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Link</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Link</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Link died at her home near Mt. Pisga Church on October 1. She was a
                    "consistent member of the Evangelical Lutheran Church." The obituary reports
                    that "her death was triumphant and happy."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1867.10.08.04">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
