<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1867/va.au.ss.1867.11.05">
	<header>
		<title>Staunton Spectator</title>
		<tagger>
			<taggerName>John Riedl</taggerName>
			<tagDate>01/08/01</tagDate>
			<tagNote/>
		</tagger>
		<address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
		<date n="1867-11-05">
			<year>1867</year>
			<month norm="11">November</month>
			<day>05</day>
			<weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
		</date>
		<frequency>weekly</frequency>
		<extent>04</extent>
		<editionNote/>
	</header>
	<paperBody>
		<page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1867.11.05.01">
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1867.11.05.02">
			<div type="e">
				<column>01</column>
				<head>The Press Should Act in Concert</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>We observe that the Charlottesville <emph rend="italic">Chronicle </emph> and
						Fredericksburg <emph rend="italic">Herald </emph> approve of the [UNCLEAR]
						we suggested last week of defeating the Radical plan of reconstruction, in
						its application to Va. by abstaining from voting, whereas the <emph
							rend="italic">Dispatch </emph> and <emph rend="italic">Enquirer </emph>
						disapprove and support the policy of trying to effect the same end by voting
						against the ratification of the Constitution. </p>
					<p>Up to this time, no other Conservative papers that we have seen have
						expressed an opinion upon the subject at all. We know that it is not only
						desirable, but absolutely essential that all the Conservative presses in the
						State striving to accomplish the same object, should act in concert-they
						should all adopt the same policy, and there should be "a long pull, and a
						pull all together."</p>
					<p>Whilst we are convinced that the weight of the argument preponderates in
						favor of the plan of not voting, yet if a majority of the press advocate the
						plan of voting, we think that those in favor of the former plan should not
						only cease to insist upon it, but should co operate with the majority in
						their plan, and should labor zealously to induce all to vote-though they
						believe than it is not as safe as the one they prefer-for a want of
						unanimity on the part of the Conservative press would ensure the success of
						the Radicals and the ratification of the Constitution.</p>
					<p>On the contrary, if the majority of the conservative press in the State
						prefer the plan of not voting, those which prefer the opposite should cease
						to advocate it, and should co-operate with those which favor non-action.</p>
					<p>It is all important that all the Conservative presses should act in perfect
						harmony in advocacy of identically the same policy. If the policy of trying
						to vote down the Constitution be agreed upon, then all should labor to
						ensure the largest vote possible, after securing the largest number of
						registered voters; but if the policy of not voting be adopted, all should
						endeavor to get as many white men and to register as possible, and then to
						prevent as many as possible from voting at all. Upon one question there can
						be no division of opinion and that is, that it is all important that every
						white man who has not registered, and who possesses the requisite
						qualifications, should be sure to do so as soon as the opportunity be
						presented.</p>
					<p>An effectual system of organization having this object in view, should be at
						once adopted. There can be no excuse for the white man will fail to
						register, and who possesses the requisite qualifications to do so. He is an
						enemy to the liberties of his country, and should be so considered. He is a
						Radical at heart.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Argues that the "Conservative" press of the state should agree on a single
					plan to defeat the proposed Constitution and then "act in perfect harmony in
					advocacy" of that policy. Currently the press is divided between trying to
					defeat the Constitution by a simple vote and, as the Spectator has advocated, by
					registering large numbers of white men who will then abstain from voting.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="e">
				<column>01</column>
				<head>Impetus to Immigration</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>Heretofore, schemes for the promotion of immigration into the Southern States
						have been abortive because the great majority of the Southern people had not
						very strong motive for exchanging the laborers they had for others. The
						negroes have unwisely supplied such a motive by suffering themselves to be
						the [UNCLEAR] tools of the Radicals who ruthlessly trample upon the dearest
						rights of the Southern people who are the employers of the negroes. The
						negroes have unwittingly given an impetus to immigration which it would not,
						otherwise, have received. That they would be supplanted by white laborers,
						in the course of time, we have never doubted since the day they were
						emancipated, but, if they had not united themselves in solid phalanx in
						opposition to the whites, a long time would have elapsed before this would
						have occurred, and the process would have been so gradual as not to have
						produced much distress, but unless they speedily awake to a due sense of
						their own interests, and cease to allow themselves to be pitted, by their
						Radical advisers and leaders and tyrannical masters against the Southern
						people-the only friends they have-they will suffer "woes unnumbered"-they
						will be supplanted by foreign and Northern laborers, and "the places which
						once knew them will know them no more"-they will disappear as the morning
						mist and the early dew.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Argues that, unless blacks "speedily awake to their own interests" and
					abandon their support of Radicals, "they will suffer 'woes unnumbered'" and will
					"disappear as the morning mist and the early dew," replaced by white laborers
					from the North.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="e">
				<column>02</column>
				<head>Resistance to Negro Domination</head>
				<origin>Richmond Enquirer and Examiner</origin>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>Like some rich and noble treasure ship, freighted with the renown or
						centuries of Caucasian domination, the merited wealth of historic glory and
						countless ingots of proud traditions, Virginia has been captured by black
						and mongrel buccaneers as desperate as ever cruised beneath the red flag of
						the "Spanish Main." While the pirates are gloating over the prize which they
						have won by fraud and the disfranchisement of our ablest men, <emph
							rend="italic">we tell them in the name of the white men, not only of
							Virginia, but of the North, that the negro shall not rule in this fair
							State designed by God to be the dominion of the highest type of the
							white race</emph>. </p>
					<p>We unfurl the standard of resistance to the wretched creatures who are soon
						to meet to complete the work of Africanizing Virginia, and tell them that
						there are no chains which they can forge in the shape of a mongrel organic
						law which can bind the giant limbs of the Old Dominion.</p>
					<p>Firm in the conviction that God will protect the fight we now take the issue
						before the aroused and indignant North, and ask the triumphant Conservative
						masses, "Shall the land of Washington, Jefferson, Henry, Madison, Marshall,
						Monroe be made a negro Inferno more horrible than that visited by Dante and
						Virgil? Shall a negro dispense the mockery of justice where Marshall
						illumined the name of American jurisprudence? Shall some brutal black occupy
						the gubernatorial chair once adorned by Henry and Jefferson? And shall the
						backs like the frogs of Egypt, swarm in the most sacred places of the mother
						of States and of statesmen?</p>
					<p>We call upon the people of this much traduced Commonwealth by conventions,
						primary meetings, resolutions, thorough organization speeches and public
						addresses, to prepare to treat the work of the proposed Convention as a
						nullity and a mockery. Death is preferable to negro supremacy, and
						revolution will be the inevitable result of an attempt upon the part of a
						Mongrel Convention to make a Hayti of Virginia. We desire the people of the
						State to treat the proposed Convention from the very outset as a monstrous
						and wicked farce. We desire them to ceaselessly proclaim to the North their
						loyalty to the laws and Constitution of the Union, but their determination
						to oppose to the death the elevation of the negro over the white man. Let
						this issue be speedily and most distinctly made. Unless the ancient spirit
						of the men, whose ancestors have ruled Virginia for more than two centuries
						is dead-unless the splendid valor which flamed forth in the van of battle
						from Boston to Yorktown during the Revolution of 1776. has become a mere
						phosphorescent light emitted by the bones of a decaying ancestry-unless all
						those heroes who made the name of Virginia the admiration of Christendom
						during the civil war, have turned to dust, and our very women have lost
						their noble enthusiasm.-this outrage shall not and cannot be perpetuated.
						The negro and his wretched parasites shall not rule this State.</p>
					<p>The race which has made it famous and renowned, and which has filled the
						Senate and the army with great statesmen and warriors, shall not creep
						through life the helots of their late slaves, and hide their sorrows and
						dishonor in the grave. No Convention can be permitted thus to violate the
						relation of the two races in Virginia. and no organic law, framed by a
						mongrel minority, can impose the galling yoke of negro supremacy upon the
						white race of this State.</p>
					<p>In the spirit of these declarations, the country will recognize the public
						sentiment in Virginia, and the North will sustain as in the sharp, well
						defined issue of "<emph rend="italic">Virginia must be ruled by white
						men.</emph>" "<emph rend="italic">In hoc signo viaces.</emph>" The war cry
						which toppled over Radicalism in Pennsylvania parlayed the same party in
						Ohio and which will soon deliver New York from the bondage of fanaticism,
						must strike a chord of sympathy when hurled by Virginians in the teeth of
						the Mongrel Convention which will soon attempt to Africanize this noble
						State. </p>
					<p>Undismayed by the result of the late election, confident of the undeveloped
						strength of the Conservative party, assured of Northern sympathy, and
						outraged by the character of the delegates elected to the so-called
						Convention, we declare thus early our determined hostility to it. We ask
						from the press and people of Virginia a united, determined, enthusiastic
						resistance and defiance of this last attempt which will ever be made to
						Africanize the Old Dominion.</p>
					<p>In view of the brutal lust for power manifested by the negro at the late
						elections, and of his objects and designs, the severest penalties which
						Congress could inflict, and the most protracted military rule under the
						harshest military despot, would be preferable to the control of public
						affairs by the negro and the renegades who have degraded themselves below
						the black.-<emph rend="italic">Enquirer and Examiner</emph>. </p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Declares that "the negro shall not rule in this fair State designed by God
					to be the dominion of the highest type of the white race" and urges readers to
					treat the Convention "as a nullity and a mockery." The author also argues that
					"death is preferable to negro supremacy." "Revolution," he contends, "will be
					the inevitable result of an attempt upon the part of a Mongrel Convention to
					make a Hayti of Virginia."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="e">
				<column>02</column>
				<head/>
				<origin>Alexandria Gazette</origin>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Argues that whites should discriminate between the "masses of Radical
					colored people" and "the comparatively few who deplore, oppose, and regret it,
					but who are powerless, at present, to prevent it."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="e">
				<column>02</column>
				<head/>
				<origin>Fredericksburg Herald</origin>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>Ah, ye recreant white, who disgraced the white blood in your veins on
						Tuesday, have you really decided that as for you black government is the
						beau ideal. If you have then blacken your faces, don't go about with a
						counterfeit white face, and black all lurking under the skin Go and deal,
						barter and trade, marry and be married, give your sons to the wenches and
						your daughters to the negroes embrace, and let miscegenation be complete.
						How dare you go into the bosom of your white families after having practiced
						outwardly as you did on Tuesday. If you were sincere, then your families
						should forever divorce themselves from your embrace. If you played the part
						of a hypocrite, repent! Repent!-<emph rend="italic">Fredericksburg
						Herald</emph>.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Disparages the "recreant whites who disgraced the white blood in your
					veins" by voting for a Convention, telling them to "blacken your faces" and give
					their "daughters to the negroes embrace."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1867.11.05.03">
			<div type="a">
				<column>01</column>
				<head>Local News</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Burke</ln>
						<fn>W. A.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Local resident W. A. Burke was awarded five premiums at the Lexington Fair
					for the best plows and for his hay fork.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>01</column>
				<head>Local News</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Taylor</ln>
						<fn>Edwin M.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Edwin Taylor has returned from his European tour in better health, and may
					write about some of his experiences for the Spectator.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>03</column>
				<head>Marriages</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Baker</ln>
						<fn>Wm. E.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Wiseman</ln>
						<fn>Lewis</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Harruff</ln>
						<fn>Catherine M.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Lewis Wiseman and Catherine Harruff were married in Staunton on October 31
					by Rev. Wm. E. Baker.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>03</column>
				<head>Marriages</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Stringer</ln>
						<fn>W. R.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Funk</ln>
						<fn>George</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Grove</ln>
						<fn>Barbara</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>George Funk, of Indiana, and Barbara Grove, of Augusta, were married near
					Waynesboro on October 24 by Rev. W. R. Stringer.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>03</column>
				<head>Marriages</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Stringer</ln>
						<fn>W. R.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Furry</ln>
						<fn>W. H.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Brown</ln>
						<fn>Sue F.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Sue Brown and W. H. Furry were married in Waynesboro on October 30 by Rev.
					W. R. Stringer.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>03</column>
				<head>Marriages</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Stringer</ln>
						<fn>W. R.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Balsley</ln>
						<fn>Cyrus F.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Balsley</ln>
						<fn>Carie N.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Cyrus Balsley and Carie Balsley were married at Sherando on October 31 by
					Rev. W. R. Stringer.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>03</column>
				<head>Marriages</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Preston</ln>
						<fn>Thos. L.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Argenbright</ln>
						<fn>David F.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Payne</ln>
						<fn>Nannie A.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>David Argenbright and Nannie Payne were married on October 10 by Rev.
					Thomas Preston.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>03</column>
				<head>Marriages</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Preston</ln>
						<fn>Thos. L.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Beard</ln>
						<fn>James E.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Beard</ln>
						<fn>Elizabeth</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Elizabeth Beard and James Beard were married on October 10 by Rev. Thomas
					Preston.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>03</column>
				<head>Marriages</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Kiracofe</ln>
						<fn>J. W.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Baily</ln>
						<fn>David M.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Dull</ln>
						<fn>Margaret C. P.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>David Baily and Margaret Dull were married at the home of the bride's
					father near Arbor Hill on October 31 by Rev. J. W. Kiracofe.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>03</column>
				<head>Marriages</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Taylor</ln>
						<fn>George B.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Dever</ln>
						<fn>J. N.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Kincaid</ln>
						<fn>Julia E.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>J. N. Dever and Julia Kincaid were married at Deerfield on October 17 by
					Rev. George Taylor.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>03</column>
				<head>Marriages</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Taylor</ln>
						<fn>George B.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Matheny</ln>
						<fn>Wm. M.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Stanton</ln>
						<fn>Cornelia</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Cornelia Stanton and William Matheny were married on October 24 by Rev.
					George Taylor.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>03</column>
				<head>Deaths</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Harris</ln>
						<fn>G. H.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Harris</ln>
						<fn>R. A.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Harris</ln>
						<fn>Alice Jane</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Harris</ln>
						<fn>Wm. Thomas</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>G. H. and R. A. Harris lost two children to dysentery. William Thomas
					Harris, age 6, died on October 10 and Alice Jane Harris, age 4, died on October
					26.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>03</column>
				<head>Deaths</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Kunkle</ln>
						<fn>Jacob</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Kunkle</ln>
						<fn>Mary J.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Kunkle</ln>
						<fn>Richard Dudley</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Richard Dudley, the eldest son of Mary and Jacob Kunkle, died of diptheria
					on October 15. He was almost 12 years old. Richard was "an exception of a boy"
					and was "beloved by all who knew him."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1867.11.05.04">
			<div type="a">
				<column>02</column>
				<head>Negro Intolerance</head>
				<origin>Lynchburg Virginian</origin>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Reports that a black man who "had the manliness to vote 'the white man's
					ticket'" was attacked by a group of black men and argues that "all the savagery
					of their nature was aroused" by their "Radical tutors."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>02</column>
				<head>Conservative Reward</head>
				<origin>Richmond Enquirer</origin>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>The only black man who voted Conservative in King William county is being
					awarded a piece of land through a subscription by the white community. The
					author encourages rewarding those who display "their good sense and
					conservatism" and urges "every employer of negroes to turn adrift all who voted
					the Radical ticket."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
	</paperBody>
</hwp>
