<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1867/va.au.ss.1867.02.05">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>John Riedl</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/11/00</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1867-02-05">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day>05</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1867.02.05.01">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1867.02.05.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Louisville Courier</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Louisville (Ky.) <emph rend="italic">Courier </emph> says that whatever
                        may be said of the Jacobins, lack of boldness is not among their sins. They
                        have resolved to control this Government for another presidential term, and
                        they have but little hesitation as to the means by which this object is to
                        be accomplished. They find the President in their way, and they propose to
                        impeach him. The Supreme Court thwarts some of their villainy, and
                        immediately they take steps to render that great tribunal incapable of
                        further harm. They find that if they should succeed in turning the President
                        tout of office, they will be compelled, unless the law is changed, to have
                        another election forthwith, and they are not sure but the popular
                        indignation which would be aroused by the expulsion of the President from
                        his office, would work a sufficient change in the public mind to defeat
                        their candidate, which would of course upset all their plans. To obviate
                        this difficulty they have already prepared a bill in Congress to suit the
                        possible emergency. It provides that in case there being no President or
                        Vice-President an election shall be held <emph rend="italic">when ordered by
                            Congress</emph>. In the meantime, the Speaker of the Senate, if thee is
                        one, and the Speaker of the House, if there is not, shall hold the office.
                        Thus they expect to keep the power in the hands of their party, in utter
                        contempt of the popular will.-When will the American people return to their
                        senses, and throttle this fell spirit of Jacobinism, which is leveling all
                        the bulwarks of constitutional liberty before it?</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that "lack of boldness" is not among the sins of the Radicals who
                    have moved against both the President and the Supreme Court and asks "when will
                    the American people return to their senses"?</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Richmond Times</origin>
                <commentary>"The Richmond Times speaking of the attempt of Congress to impeach
                    President Johnson, says:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"In the criminal courts of this country, whenever the blackest felon is
                        arraigned at the bar of justice to answer for his crimes, each juror before
                        he is permitted to sit in the case, is asked by the Judge 'whether he has
                        formed or expressed any opinions as to the guilt or innocence of the
                        accused?' If he has, he is disqualified as a juror. By this rule which
                        protects felons, is Charles Sumner qualified to sit in trial and judgment
                        upon the President? If the laws do not accord the right of peremptory
                        challenge to Andrew Johnson; if there is no one to ask Senators 'whether
                        they have formed or expressed an opinion as to the guilt or innocence of the
                        accused,' where are Charles Sumner's shame and conscience if he shall desire
                        to sit in the trial of the man whom he but yesterday vilified and denounced,
                        when he knew at the time that if Andrew Johnson should be impeached, he
                        would be a member of the court? Such a shameless want of delicacy, we
                        believe, would send a hurricane of hissing scorn at the man whom Brooks'
                        righteous rattan once banished from the Senate for a twelve-month."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that Senators who have "vilified and denounced" the President, such
                    as Charles Sumner, should not be able to sit in judgment during a Senate
                    impeachment trial.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1867.02.05.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Hon. A. H. H. Stuart left Staunton for Richmond on last Friday morning, as a
                        Commissioner to adjust and settle the difficulties existing between the
                        States of Virginia and West Virginia, and will be absent a week or ten
                    days.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>A. H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A. H. H. Stuart has departed for Richmond "as a Commissioner to adjust and
                    settle the difficulties existing between the States of Virginia and West
                    Virginia" and is expected to return in a week to ten days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Billy Wilson, a freedman was committed to jail on Monday, charged with the
                        burning of a barn on Saturday night last, belonging to Wm. A. Mann, on
                        Christian's Creek. He says he was hired by another negro man to do the
                    deed.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>Billy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mann</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Billy Wilson was committed to jail for burning the barn of William A. Mann.
                    Wilson claims "another negro man" hired him.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Two negro men, Wm. and Henry Bird, (brothers) were committed to jail on
                        Sunday charged with the burning of a house, on the last Friday night,
                        belonging to John Hogshead, near Parnassus, in Augusta county.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bird</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bird</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hogshead</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William and Henry Bird were committed to jail on Monday, charged with
                    burning the home of John Hogshead.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We were startled by the cry of fire on Tuesday evening last, about 7 o'clock,
                        and on going out discovered that the small house on the lot of Mr. Wm. A.
                        Burke, on the Western border of the town was wrapped in flames. The fire was
                        occasioned by the bursting of a kerosene lamp, and throwing water on the
                        burning oil. The house was occupied by a freedman named Tom Burke and his
                        family. Be careful how you handle your lamps as some of the oil now sold is
                        very explosive.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>Tom</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A fire engulfed a house on William Burke's lot last Tuesday. A kerosene
                    lamp is suspected to be the cause.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News--Staunton Building Association</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A meeting was held in the Fireman's Hall on last Wednesday night, for the
                        purpose of organizing a Building Association. Most of the persons present,
                        not being acquainted with the workings of an organization of this kind, and
                        desiring time to understand its operations more thoroughly, the permanent
                        organization of the Association was postponed until next Wednesday
                        (to-morrow) night. A committee of five was appointed to draft a constitution
                        and by-laws for the government of the Association, which will be submitted
                        to the meeting on to-morrow night for its adoption or rejection. Books are
                        now open for subscription to stock, and persons wishing to become members of
                        the Association can do so by calling on Mr. H. Ker, and subscribing to
                        stock. None but stockholders are allowed to vote on the adoption of a
                        constitution and by-laws. It is a mutual benefit company in which every one
                        should feel an interest.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ker</ln>
                        <fn>Herber</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A preliminary meeting of the Staunton Building Association was held last
                    Wednesday. A committee was appointed to draft a constitution and by-laws.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News--"Philomathesians"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Philomathesians met in the Temperance Hall on last Saturday night and
                        discussed the question-"Which is the most desirable form of
                        government-Monarchial or Republican." The debate was opened by D. E.
                        Strasburg, in the affirmative, and E. Effinger, in the negative, after which
                        an animated and spirited discussion took place, in which the following young
                        gentlemen participated. Messrs. O'Ferrall, Harrison, Taylor and Points, on
                        the negative, and Messrs. Richardson, Oultman, Moore, Turner and Kinney, on
                        the affirmative side of the question. The question being put to the vote of
                        the society, it was decided in the negative.</p>
                    <p>The question for discussion on next Saturday night is-"Was the execution of
                        Charles First justifiable." Mr. M. W. Chewning will open the debate in the
                        affirmative and Mr. Ed. Kinney in the negative.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strasburg</ln>
                        <fn>D. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Effinger</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>O'Ferrall</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harrison</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Points</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richardson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Oultman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moore</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turner</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>Ed.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chewning</ln>
                        <fn>M. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Philomathesian Society met last Saturday to debate the question "'Which
                    is the most desirable form of government--Monarchial or Republican'"?</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>To the Members of the Lewisburg Thespian Society</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>To the Members of the Lewisburg Thespian Society. <lb/></p>
                    <p>GENTLEMEN:--Our manager received the copy of the "Lewisburg Times" sent him
                        by you a few days since, and returns his thanks for it. In reply to the
                        challenge therein, we beg to say, that being simply novices in the art of
                        acting, we feel that our incompetency will not permit us to accept the trial
                        for the championship which you propose, and must therefore, respectfully
                        decline. We have never, for a moment, entertained the idea that ours is THE
                        Thespian Society, and could not think, for several reasons, of attempting to
                        rob you of the laurels, which you say none but yourselves have a right to,
                        so we are satisfied to let you wear them all. Were we patronized and favored
                        by our citizens as the Yankee Show and Yankee Wyman were, could easily
                        entertain and accept such propositions as the one you have made us. As it
                        is, we are now in a fair way to offer the people here some <emph
                            rend="italic">inducements </emph> to attend our entertainments, having
                        recently secured the services of some good players, and having now in
                        rehearsal some excellent pieces which cannot fail, we think, to gain us
                        large audiences. We have discovered that we must do <emph rend="italic">more
                        </emph> than the Circus and Wyman in order to get our townspeople to sustain
                        us, and when we succeed in doing this, and we are making every effort to do
                        so, we may accept your challenge, for <emph rend="italic">then </emph> we
                        can find judges enough here which will obviate the necessity of our going to
                        Lewisburg, as we would be obligated to do, were we to accept your challenge
                        now. We were organized for the benefit of patriotic and charitable objects,
                        but we have not paid the debt incurred in building our stage yet, much less
                        given any of the aforementioned commendable objects the proceeds of one or
                        more of our entertainments as we had hoped to do. </p>
                    <p>We have several flourishing female schools here which our sisters and
                        sweethearts attend, but the teachers object to their coming to our
                        entertainments, because they say they are not perfectly moral and insist
                        upon the girls going to hear dry (to them) political and financial debates
                        at the Lyceum instead.</p>
                    <p>We have been wondering whether or not these same teachers think that we,
                        proud as we are of our esteem for the ladies and of our <emph rend="italic"
                            >respect for ourselves</emph>, would bring anything before them in the
                        way of a play which would be the <emph rend="italic">least </emph> immoral,
                        when we so carefully avoid the selection of obscene plays. </p>
                    <p>We cannot speak for the Harrisonburg Thespians, gentlemen, who, we believe,
                        like everything down there will do occasionally, are "on a bust," though we
                        expect you will hear from them in due time. For the present, at any rate, we
                        beg to decline your challenge, and to be Yours respectfully,</p>
                    <p>STAUNTON THESPIANS.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Staunton Thespians</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>The "Staunton Thespians" decline a challenge made by the Lewisburg Thespian
                    Society.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1867.02.05.04">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
