<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1867/va.au.ss.1867.02.19">
	<header>
		<title>Staunton Spectator</title>
		<tagger>
			<taggerName>John Riedl</taggerName>
			<tagDate>07/21/00</tagDate>
			<tagNote/>
		</tagger>
		<address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
		<date n="1867-02-19">
			<year>1867</year>
			<month norm="02">February</month>
			<day>19</day>
			<weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
		</date>
		<frequency>weekly</frequency>
		<extent>04</extent>
		<editionNote/>
	</header>
	<paperBody>
		<page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1867.02.19.01">
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1867.02.19.02">
			<div type="e">
				<column>01</column>
				<head>The Blackest Record</head>
				<origin>National Intelligencer; New York Times</origin>
				<commentary>In speaking of the character of the bill reported by Stevens from the
					Committee on Reconstruction and which passed the House of Representatives, on
					Wednesday, the 13th inst., the National Intelligencer of the next day thus
					forcibly describes it:</commentary>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>"The blackest record ever made by an assembly of the representatives of a
						free people stained yesterday the proceedings of the House of
						Representatives. Never, in the most tyrannous hour of the Long Parliament
						misrule; never, amid the utmost subservience to the royal mandate of an
						English King; never, in the most bloodthirsty epoch of a French convention,
						did the representatives of the people stamp themselves with greater <orig
							reg="ignominy">ignomy</orig>. The bill which passed by a vote of 109 to
						55, had some third of the people of this country over to military
						government. For the rule of law, it substitutes the will of an officer. For
						the tribunal of a judge, it furnishes a drumhead court-martial or a military
						commission. For the process of a court and the peaceful visit of a sheriff,
						it proffers the order of a petty satrap and the presence of a squad of
						bayonets It ignores the Chief Magistrate of the United States. It invests a
						General with absolute power over one-third of his countrymen. It erects
						subordinate dictators, armed with unbridled power, from the Potomac to the
						Rio Grande. Throughout this broad domain, comprising the fairest and most
						fertile section of the Republic, no man is to have a secure title to his
						property; no man's house is free from search; no man's chattel's exempt from
						seizure; no mans' liberty unexposed to assault; no man's life safe from
						peril. An army officer, a soldier, exalted above the law, may ruthlessly
						invade a citizen's home an drag him from the bosom of his family. Such a
						bill makes him a mockery of free institutions. It despites all the great
						safeguards of popular liberty. It tramples on the freedom of the press. It
						annihilates the right of free assemblage. It silences the lips of free
						speech. It infringes the right of the people to bear arms. It wipes out the
						guaranty of a grand jury presentment. It abolishes the exemption of freedom
						from seizure and from search. It abrogates the right of trial by a jury of
						one's peers in the vicinage of the commission of the alleged offence. It
						tramples upon the prerogative of the President, it makes war upon the
						Constitution, it rebels against the authority of the Supreme Court. It
						invades the sacred constitutional rights of the citizen. It is treason
						enveloped in the forms of law. It is rebellion wearing the garb of
						legitimate power. It is usurpation assuming the sanctity of constitutional
						enactment. </p>
					<p>As bad as the Stevens' bill is, which is so well described by the <emph
							rend="italic">Intelligencer </emph>, yet Elliott's bill for the
						government of Louisiana, which passed the House by a vote of 113 to 48, Is
						much worse. Even the New York <emph rend="italic">Times </emph>, a
						Republican paper, thus speaks of its character and effects: </p>
					<p>"It is proscriptive after the manner of Tennessee, and will <emph
							rend="italic">give rise to the heart burning, the angry controversies,
							the bitter, bloody strife which prevail in Tennessee to this
						hour</emph>. It confers the franchise upon the negroes, universally, while
						it disfranchises nearly the entire white population. Practically, therefore,
						the reorganization of Louisa will be entrusted to its freedmen, they, and
						they alone, will have the election of legislators, and through the
						Convention the framing of the new Constitution; the resident whites being at
						their mercy in all things political. <emph rend="italic">No gift of prophecy
							is needed to foretell the consequences of this policy. It is irritating
							and dangerous to the last degree,</emph>, and its effect upon the
						property and business interests of the State will be most disastrous. </p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Even in the Long Parliament or "the most bloodthirsty epoch of a French
					convention," the article argues, never have "the representatives of the people"
					acted "with greater <orig reg="ignominy">ignomy</orig>" than in the passage of
					the Reconstruction bill. Includes a critique of the bill for the government of
					Louisiana from the New York Times.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>02</column>
				<head>Military Governments for the South</head>
				<origin>Lynchburg Virginian; Lancaster Intelligencer</origin>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>The bill offered by the joint committee on reconstruction (?) of which Thad.
						Stevens was chairman, establishing military governments in the Southern
						States, passed the House of Representatives on Wednesday last, by a vote of
						109 ayes to 55 nays-within one of being a two thirds vote. In the language
						of the Lynchburg <emph rend="italic">Virginian </emph>, "it makes General
						Grant a military dictator in these States, repudiates the late decision of
						the Supreme Court, suspends the writ of <emph rend="italic">habeas
						corpus</emph>, and effectually deposes the President of the United States so
						far as the government of the Southern States is concerned. As will be seen,
						it contains no provision whatever for the restoration of these States to
						their rightful place in the Union; and does not intimate that this is a
						provisional arrangement, looking to the final rehabilitation of the States
						concerned. For all that the bill intimates to the contrary, it is a plan for
						the subjection, <emph rend="italic">forever </emph>, of the Southern States
						to an absolute and irresponsible military government. How this system is to
						be incorporated with our form of republican government, it is difficult to
						apprehend. Its introduction and continuance here cannot but end in the final
						overthrow of the constitutional government of the United States. All candid
						men must admit that it is a fearful stride in the direction of absolutism ,
						and its inevitable tendency is to a military dictatorship for the whole
						country." </p>
					<p>The following is the most remarkable an iniquitous bill:</p>
					<p>"Whereas, the pretended State governments of the late so-called Confederate
						States of Virginia, North Carolina, South Carolina, Georgia, Mississippi,
						Alabama, Louisiana, Florida, Texas and Arkansas were set up without the
						authority of Congress, and without the sanction of the people; and whereas
						the said pretended governments afford no adequate protection for life or
						property, but countenance and encourage lawlessness and crime; and whereas
						it is necessary that peace and good order should be enforced in the said
						so-called States until loyal and republican State governments can be legal
						established; therefore,</p>
					<p>"Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United
						States of America in Congress assembled. That the so-called States shall be
						divided into military districts and made subject to the military authority
						of the United States, as hereinafter prescribed; and for that purpose,
						Virginia shall constituted the 1st district, North Carolina and South
						Carolina, the 2d district; Georgia, Alabama and Florida, the 3d district;
						Mississippi and Arkansas, the 4th district; and Louisiana and Texas, the 5th
						district.</p>
					<p>"SECTION 2. And be it further enacted, That it shall be the duty of the
						General of the army to assign to the command of each of the said districts
						an officer of the regular army, not below the rank of Brigadier Genera; and
						to detail a sufficient military force to enable such officer to perform his
						duties and enforce his authority within the district to which he is
						assigned.</p>
					<p>"SECTION 3. And be it further enacted, That it shall be the duty of each
						officer assigned as aforesaid to protect all persons in their rights of
						person and property, to suppress insurrection, disorder and violence, and to
						punish, or cause to be punished, all disturbers of the public peace and
						criminals; and to this end he may allow civil tribunals to take jurisdiction
						of and to try offenders, or when in his judgment it may be necessary for the
						trial of offenders, he shall have power to organize military commissions or
						tribunals for that purpose, anything in the constitutions and laws of the so
						called States to the contrary notwithstanding; and all legislative or
						judicial proceedings or processes to prevent or contest the proceedings of
						said military tribunals, and all interference by said pretended State
						governments with the exercise of military authority under this act shall be
						void and of no effect.</p>
					<p>"SECTION 4. <emph rend="italic">And be it further enacted</emph>, That courts
						and judicial officers of the United States shall not issue writs of <emph
							rend="italic">habeas corpus</emph> in behalf of persons in military
						custody unless some commissioned officer on duty in the district wherein the
						person is detained shall endorse upon said petition a statement certifying
						upon honor that he has knowledge or information as to the cause and
						circumstances of the alleged detention, and that he believes that same to be
						wrongful; and further, that he believes that the endorsed petition is
						preferred in good faith and in furtherance of justice , and not to hinder or
						delay the punishment of crime. All persons put under military arrest by
						virtue of this act shall be tried without unnecessary delay, and no cruel or
						unusual punishment shall be inflicted. </p>
					<p>"SECTION 5. <emph rend="italic">And be it further enacted</emph>, That no
						sentence of any military commission or tribunal hereby authorized affecting
						the life, or liberty of any person shall be executed until it is approved by
						the superior officer in command of the district, and the laws and
						regulations for the government of the army shall not be affected by this
						act, except in so far as they conflict with its provisions. </p>
					<p>In commenting upon the outrageous character of this bill, the Lancaster (Pa.)
							<emph rend="italic">Intelligencer </emph> says that it was "devised by
						the Reconstruction Committee for the purpose of completing and perpetuating
						a dissolution of the Union. No man possessed of ordinary judgment can read
						it without being shocked. It proposes to destroy at one sweep every vestige
						of civil government in one-half of the country, and to set up under the
						exclusive control of the Radicals in Congress, a military despotism, pure
						and simple. Ten States are to be at once blotted from existence. They are to
						be reduced, not to the condition of other territories but to the sad state
						of hostile provinces. Military satraps are to be appointed over them. The
						people are to have no choice in the selection of their rulers. These
						arbitrary governors, these minions of a military despotism are not expected
						to rule in accordance with any known or recognized laws. With their dictates
						no civil court can interfere. There are to be no laws throughout the South,
						except the rules of the camp and the will of a military chieftain. In order
						that there may be no mistake about the arbitrary features of this new form
						of government, the bill expressly provides that there shall be no
						interference by any civil authority with the military control. No court can
						grant the privilege of a hearing on a writ of <emph rend="italic">habeas
							corpus</emph> without the consent of some military satrap. Every citizen
						is made liable to arrest, to summary trial, to conviction and execution, by
						an irresponsible and unconstitutional military tribunal, from which there is
						to be no appeal. By this infamous bill war is declared anew, and the whole
						of the Southern States are made a camp. Under its provisions all courts are
						made subordinate to drum head courts martial, and men may be seized, tried
						and hung in a manner sufficiently summary to satisfy the most bloodthirsty
						fanatic." </p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Characterizes the Reconstruction Bill as "a plan for the subjection,
					forever, of the Southern States to an absolute and irresponsible military
					government." Includes a copy of the "remarkable and iniquitous bill."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>01</column>
				<head>An Outrage</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Reports that last week near Fayetteville, North Carolina "a negro attempted
					to commit an outrage on the person of Miss Massey," the daughter of a
					Confederate officer. A suspect was arrested "and while being conducted to the
					jail by the Sheriff was surrounded by a mob and shot dead." The article also
					claims that "no one knows by whom the fatal shot was fired."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1867.02.19.03">
			<div type="a">
				<column>01</column>
				<head>Local News</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>The Fair held by the ladies of the Lutheran Church last week is reported to
					have been a success, grossing about $200.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>01</column>
				<head>Local News--Building Association</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>The building Association of this place has been organized with the most
						promising prospects that it will be eminently a success. On Monday night the
						11th inst., the Association was organized by the election of the following
						efficient officers:--J. B. Evans, President; Jno. K. Woods, Treasurer;
						Herber Ker, Secretary; Messrs J. H. Waters, H. H. Peck, A. M. Bruce, E. M.
						Cushing, B. T. Bagby, and w. J. Nelson, Directors and Messrs P. B. Hoge, N.
						P. Catlett and Saml. A. Hoshour, Trustees.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Evans</ln>
						<fn>J. B.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Woods</ln>
						<fn>Jno. K.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Ker</ln>
						<fn>Heber</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Waters</ln>
						<fn>J. H.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Peck</ln>
						<fn>H. H.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Bruce</ln>
						<fn>A. M.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Cushing</ln>
						<fn>E. M.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Bagby</ln>
						<fn>B. T.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Nelson</ln>
						<fn>W. J.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Hoge</ln>
						<fn>P. B.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Catlett</ln>
						<fn>N. P.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Hoshour</ln>
						<fn>Saml. A.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>The local Building Association was organized with the election of officers
					on Monday night.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>02</column>
				<head>Local News--Concert at the Presbyterian Church</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>The sacred concert at the Presbyterian Church on Friday night last, was well
						attended, not withstanding the inclemency of the weather. It was given, we
						understand, ostensibly for the purpose of displaying one of Henry Esben's
						organs, just put up for the use of the choir of the church, and raising
						money sufficient to defray the heavy expenses incurred for its
						transportation from New York to Staunton. The power of the instrument was
						amply displayed by Mr. G. H. Whitten, under whose superintendence it was
						erected. It is of a medium size, and rather soft in its tone than otherwise;
						containing fourteen stops, viz: Open Diapson, Stopped Diapson, (treble and
						bass,) Principal, Duciana, Gemhorn, Gambra, Twelfth, Fifteenth, Flute, and
						Bourdon. Besides these there are a coupling Pedal, two composition Pedals,
						one swell and a bellows alarm. There are two octaves of pedal keys. After
						Mr. Whitten, had displayed the compass of the instrument, Prof. Ettinger,
						the organist of the church, took his seat, and the miscellaneous concert of
						sacred music commenced. Mr. Whitten, we understand, will remain with us for
						some time, being engaged to repair the organs of the Lunatic Asylum, the
						Deaf and Dumb and Blind Institution and the Episcopal church.</p>
					<p>The concert was well sustained by the choir and their friends of Richmond and
						the Staunton Musical Association. Criticism falls to the ground when
						amateurs are the objects-we shall, therefore, pass by the faults, which were
						few.-The chorusses, though sung with much spirit, were weak, yet, we have
						heard the same compositions sung with far less ability in cities where they
						can obtain singers by the hundreds. The fine bass of Dr. Brown and the
						effective soprano of his daughter were conspicuous throughout the
						evening-the latter particularly excelled in the beautiful quartette of "Lay
						not up treasures," her warblings running tastefully through the harmony of
						the alto, tenor and bass. The quartette and chorus of "House of our God" was
						also admirably performed. The concert, on the whole, was a great success,
						and we of the mountain city have cause to be proud of the musical talent
						that is gradually developing itself among us. There is a general wish
						expressed that it may be repeated, as the inclemency of the weather
						prevented many from attending who would otherwise have been glad to hear
						such sweet music.</p>
					<p>P. S.-Since the above was written, we are pleased to learn that, in
						accordance with the general wish of the community, the choir have consented
						to repeat the concert on Thursday night next.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Whitten</ln>
						<fn>G. H.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Ettinger</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Prof.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Brown</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Dr.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>An account of last Friday's concert at the Presbyterian Church, reported to
					be a "great success."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>02</column>
				<head>Local News</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Watts</ln>
						<fn>John B.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>John B. Watts was commissioned as Vice-President of the local district of
					the Friends of Temperance on December 19.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>05</column>
				<head>Marriages</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Argenbright</ln>
						<fn>Madison L.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Wilson</ln>
						<fn>Mary E.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Madison L. Argenbright, formerly of Augusta, and Mary E. Wilson were
					married on January 27 in Missouri.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>05</column>
				<head>Marriages</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Stringer</ln>
						<fn>W. R.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Harris</ln>
						<fn>Wm. H.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Whitesel</ln>
						<fn>Mary E.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Mary Whitesel and William Harris were married near Barterbrook on February
					14 by Rev. W. R. Stringer.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>05</column>
				<head>Deaths</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer>B.</trailer>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Davis</ln>
						<fn>Evaline</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Davis</ln>
						<fn>James F.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Evaline Davis died on February 8 after intense sufferings. She was 38 years
					old.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1867.02.19.04">
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
	</paperBody>
</hwp>
