<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1867/va.au.ss.1867.05.21">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>John Riedl</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/30/00</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1867-05-21">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day>21</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1867.05.21.01">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1867.05.21.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Register! Register!</head>
                <origin>Richmond Times</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges white readers to register and vote, explaining that "by every white
                    man in Virginia who is entitled to vote taking care to register, the cause of
                    law and order and the supremacy of the white race will be made secure."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Riots in the South</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The teachings of the Radicals who have been addressing the negroes in various
                        parts of the South are beginning to bear their fruits, and the spirit of
                        lawlessness prevails wherever they have appeared. In Mobile, Ala., on
                        Tuesday last; whilst the Radical Judge Kelly was speaking, three men were
                        killed-one white and two negroes. A number were wounded, among them one
                        policeman. A large majority of the shots were fired by negroes, but few of
                        the whites present were armed. On Monday, the day before the riot at Mobile,
                        a serious riot also occurred at Brownsville, Tennessee. Three negroes and
                        two white men were shot, but none fatally.</p>
                    <p>If the Radical incendiaries be permitted to continue their inflammatory
                        appeals to the negroes, we may expect to hear of serious riots in all parts
                        of the South. These speakers are leading the negroes to their doom.</p>
                    <p>The Richmond <emph rend="italic">Times </emph> says that the "professional
                        agitators have been left almost without pretext for agitation, and the
                        unscrupulous leaders of the extreme Radicals have been filled with dismay at
                        the indications of the decadence of their power. As these malignant enemies
                        of peace and order must perish with the base passions which have given them
                        strength, it is perfectly evident that they have determined to goad the
                        people of the South to deeds of folly or violence by turning loose their
                        most vituperative and incendiary orators in our midst.-<emph rend="italic"
                            >Their object is to excite our people to tumults and riots, and thus
                            justify harsher legislation than any which has yet characterized
                            Congress</emph>. This is the evident object of Kelly's mission, and it
                        is most deeply to be regretted that he has been to some extent successful in
                        Mobile. </p>
                    <p>These riots do us incalculable damage, and his African Church speech, Mr.
                        Greeley admitted that the great Radical triumph of 1866 was mainly due to
                        the New Orleans and Memphis riots.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that riots have recently occurred in Mobile, Alabama, and
                    Brownsville, Tennessee, and attributes them to "Radical incendiaries" whose
                    "object is to excite our people to tumults and riots, and thus justify harsher
                    legislation than any which has yet characterized Congress."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1867.05.21.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News--Surgical Operation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Payne</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>C. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fauntleroy</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McChesney</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Atkinson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Frank Payne recently had a three pound "Titro Fatty Tumor" removed by a
                    team of four doctors.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News--Staunton Lyceum</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On Monday night, the 13th inst., the following question was discussed in the
                        Staunton Lyceum: "<emph rend="italic">When universal suffrage is granted to
                            males should it be extended, also, to females?</emph>" </p>
                    <p>The following members participated in discussion:</p>
                    <p>In the affirmative, Powell Harrison, Esq., Col. Bolivar Christian, Prof. J.
                        H. Hewitt and Dr. C. R. Harris; in the negative, J. M. Hanger, Esq., Prof.
                        Pike Powers and Y. H. Peyton, Esq.</p>
                    <p>The vote upon the merits of the question stood: In the affirmative, six; in
                        the negative, thirteen.</p>
                    <p>On Monday night next, the 28th inst., the following question will be
                        discussed: "<emph rend="italic">Is there any reality in spiritual
                            manifestations, or in witch-craft?</emph>" </p>
                    <p>Rev. John L. Clarke will open the debate in the affirmative, and Prof. J. H.
                        Hewitt in the negative.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harrison</ln>
                        <fn>Powell</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>Bolivar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hewitt</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>C. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Powers</ln>
                        <fn>Pike</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn>Y. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn>John L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Staunton Lyceum discussed the question, "'When universal suffrage is
                    granted to males should it be extended, also, to females?'" After debate the
                    question was decided in the negative by a vote of thirteen to six.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News--Staunton Sunday School Union</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Sunday School Union of this place held a most interesting session in the
                        Methodist Church on Sunday afternoon last, at 3 ½ o'clock. A large number of
                        the Episcopal brethren, who were here in attendance on the Council, were
                        present an delivered interesting addresses on the subject of Sunday Schools.
                        The Rev. Geo. B. Taylor presided and introduced the speakers. The order of
                        exercises were as follows:</p>
                    <p>1. Opening Hymn-<emph rend="italic">Lovely Land</emph>, sung by all the
                        Schools. </p>
                    <p>2. Prayer by Rev. Mr. Curtis,</p>
                    <p>3. <emph rend="italic">hymn-Hosanna</emph>, sung by all the schools. </p>
                    <p>4. Address, by Rev. C. J. Gibson, of Hanover county.</p>
                    <p>5. Hymn-<emph rend="italic">Rose of Sharon</emph> Schools. </p>
                    <p>6. Address, by Rev. Mr. Dashiel, of Richmond.</p>
                    <p>7. Hymn-<emph rend="italic">O won't you be a Christian while you're
                        young</emph>? </p>
                    <p>8. Address, by Rev. Dr. Andrews, of Shepherdstown.</p>
                    <p>9. Hymn-<emph rend="italic">Sunday School Battle Song</emph>-Schools. </p>
                    <p>10. Benediction, by Rev. Jas. McKabe, of Md.</p>
                    <p>Rev. Mr. Gibson's address was on the great importance of bringing children
                        unto Christ through the means of Sabbath Schools. His remarks were addressed
                        principally to the Officers, Teachers and Parents of children, and were both
                        interesting and instructive.</p>
                    <p>Rev. T. G. Dashiel's address was directed exclusively to the children and was
                        amusing and entertaining to both young and old.</p>
                    <p>Rev. Dr. Andrew's address was condemnatory of the light and trifling Sunday
                        School literature of the present day, and recommendatory of a more general
                        use of the Sacred Scriptures alone in our Sabbath Schools.</p>
                    <p>The next meeting of the Society will be held in June next, at which time
                        there will be an election of officers for the ensuing year. It is hoped that
                        all the schools will interest themselves in this organization and unite in
                        the effort to advance the cause of Sunday schools. Due notice of the time
                        and place of the next meeting will be given.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>Geo. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Curtis</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gibson</ln>
                        <fn>C. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dashiel</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Andrews</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKabe</ln>
                        <fn>Jas.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Staunton Sunday School Union met last Sunday at the Methodist Church,
                    with hymns and addresses on "the great importance of bringing children unto
                    Christ through the means of Sabbath School."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Local News--Police Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Banks</ln>
                        <fn>Peyton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carey</ln>
                        <fn>Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kayser</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moore</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bruce</ln>
                        <fn>A. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Justice</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hurley</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Richard Taylor</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>N. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mayor</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Powell</ln>
                        <fn>Jordan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A brief summary of four police items of the last week.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stringer</ln>
                        <fn>W. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hill</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kelly</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary Kelly and John Hill were married in Waynesboro on May 16 by Rev. W. R.
                    Stringer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>R. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>A. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>E. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>E. A. Hanger and Lieut. A. B. Young, of Lewis county, were married at the
                    home of the bride's father on May 13 by Rev. R. C. Walker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Long</ln>
                        <fn>Jas. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stevenson</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McFarland</ln>
                        <fn>Eli N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Long</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Maggie Long and Eli N. McFarland, of Independence, Missouri, were married
                    at the home of the bride's father, near Burke's Mill, on April 24 by Rev. G. W.
                    Stevenson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mahan</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>P. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Benson</ln>
                        <fn>Olivia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Benson</ln>
                        <fn>N. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Olivia Benson, of Montgomery, Alabama, and P. H. Trout, of Staunton, were
                    married at St. Paul's Church in Baltimore on May 15 by Rev. Dr. M. Mahan.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>W. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Francisco</ln>
                        <fn>C. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ryan</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Francisco</ln>
                        <fn>Mattie E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mattie Francisco and Lt. Joseph Ryan were married at the home of the
                    bride's father on May 14 by Rev. W. E. Baker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>W. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Francisco</ln>
                        <fn>C. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Francisco</ln>
                        <fn>Sallie C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Robert Cochran and Sallie C. Francisco were married at the home of the
                    bride's father on May 14 by Rev. W. E. Baker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1867.05.21.04">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
