<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1867/va.au.ss.1867.09.03">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>John Riedl</taggerName>
            <tagDate>10/30/00</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1867-09-03">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day>03</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>1867</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1867.09.03.01">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1867.09.03.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Who Favor Radical Re-construction</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Every Radical in the North and South desires to secure the permanent
                        domination of the Radical party, and every one of them desires the
                        reconstruction of the Southern States on the basis of the
                        Sherman-Shellabarger bill. Is it at all probable that <emph rend="italic"
                            >all </emph> the Radicals are deceived as to the effect reconstruction
                        upon that basis would have upon their party? If not, those who urge the
                        people of the South to reconstruct upon that basis are aiding the Radicals
                        to secure the permanent domination of their party. It matters not what their
                        professions may be, they are either deceived themselves, or else they are
                        the willing allies of the Radical party. Some may be honest-and we have no
                        doubt that many are-but the majority of those in the South who favor
                        reconstruction upon the terms prescribed by the Radicals with the view and
                        for the purpose of preserving their party ascendancy are, in truth, Radicals
                        at heart, or are willing to surrender principle and abandon right through
                        motives which never control the purely honest and patriotic. They have some
                        selfish, some mercenary interest to promote by so doing. In many cases, it
                        is by no means difficult to see the object they expect to accomplish-their
                        motives are palpable; their purposes, apparent. It does not require the
                        vision of the Lynx to discover beneath the sheep's clothing the form of the
                        ferocious Radical wolf.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that anyone who supports the Radicals' acts "to secure the permanent
                    domination of the Radical party" must be deceiving themselves about the
                    consequences of their actions.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>How To Avoid Revolution and a War of Races</head>
                <origin>Richmond Enquirer and Examiner</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The people of the Southern States are at last making the discovery that
                        revolution and a war of races will be the inevitable consequences of the
                        plan of reconstruction proposed by Congress. That plan virtually and
                        practically places the Caucasian of the South at the mercy of the African,
                        and gives to the half civilized pauper the right to legislate for the
                        confiscation of property. It is the only instance which history furnishes of
                        a deliberate attempt upon the part of the white men of one section of a
                        country, to make their brethren in color and origin, the political [UNCLEAR]
                        of an inferior race. This crime, from its singularity and enormity, stands
                        out without precedent or parallel. It is a violation of nature and humanity
                        so monstrous and horrible that none can doubt its ultimate failure. <lb/></p>
                    <p>As none more earnestly than ourselves deprecate revolutions and wars of
                        races, we cannot too earnestly oppose a plan of reconstruction which will
                        bring with it, we feel assured, the horrors of the most hideous strife. And
                        as the <emph rend="italic">animus </emph> of the enfranchised blacks becomes
                        more and more clear to the Southern people, we find those who once advocated
                        the Congressional plan of reconstruction, rapidly changing front and
                        arraying themselves in opposition to it.-Wherever registration has revealed
                        to the negro his strength, he has at once proposed to exert it as an
                        unthinking and rapacious savage. All hopes of convincing him that his
                        interests are identified with those of the whites, have been dissipated by
                        the conventions which they have held and the resolutions which they have
                        adopted in the Southern States.-<emph rend="italic">Enquirer and
                        Examiner</emph>. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that the Congressional Reconstruction plan "places the Caucasian of
                    the South at the mercy of the African, and gives to the half civilized pauper
                    the right to legislate for the confiscation of property." Whites are abandoning
                    their tepid support for the reconstruction plan, the article declares, as "the
                    animus of the enfranchised blacks becomes more and more clear to the Southern
                    people"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Another Street Car Difficulty</head>
                <origin>Richmond Whig</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A negro from the North, named Jim Brown, boarded the ladies' street car,
                        yesterday afternoon, against the protest of the conductor, about the time it
                        reached Eighteenth street, on its up trip. When it arrived in front of the
                        station house, on the corner of Seventeenth and Main streets, the aid of the
                        police was sought, and Sergeant Kendrick proceeded to oust the intruder.
                        Brown, who is a rough customer, made fight, and Mr. Charles H. Page was
                        called to assist in arresting him. This, Mr. P. did promptly, and in obeying
                        orders was well pummelled by Brown. He held on, however, manfully, and
                        showed that he had the nerve. In the meanwhile, Sergeant Kendrick, who had
                        gotten him into trouble, contented himself with shaking his baton over
                        Brown's head instead of giving him a striking demonstration of the fact that
                        he was in custody of the officers of the law.-<emph rend="italic">Rich.
                            Whig.</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on a conflict between "a negro from the North, Jim Brown," and the
                    Richmond police broke out after Brown resisted attempts to remove him from the
                    "ladies' street car."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1867.09.03.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News--Augusta County Fair</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the directors of the County Fair have selected a site for the
                    fair grounds near the ruins of the old woolen factory and encourages readers to
                    provide funds to pay for and improve the grounds.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News--A Radical Emissary</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It will be remembered that, on the day that Robinson's Circus exhibited here,
                        a man dubbed <emph rend="italic">Gen</emph>. D. B White addressed the
                        negroes in front of the Court House. The following will show what manner of
                        man he is: </p>
                    <p>"Mr. D. B. White was Major was Major of the Eighty-first New York volunteers,
                        resigned his commission in the fall of 1864, when his regiment was serving
                        in the field in front of Richmond. Immediately after his resignation was
                        accepted, he applied to General B. F. Butler, commanding army of the James,
                        for the position of sutler of the regiment in which he had resigned his
                        commission.</p>
                    <p>General Butler issued a general order thereupon, to the effect that Major D.
                        B. White having resigned his commission while in front of the enemy, was not
                        fit to hold the position of boot-black in his department, and that Mr. White
                        would immediately leave the department."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that on the day that Robinson's Circus performed in Staunton, "a
                    man dubbed Gen. D. B. White addressed the negroes in front of the Court House."
                    The article offers a scathing critique of White's military record.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Negro Candidates for Congress</head>
                <origin>Fredericksburg Herald</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>There is little doubt that in the events of Southern reconstruction a
                        majority of the Members of Congress from the South will be negroes! It is
                        too early to speculate as to the policy of Virginia, but we have heard over
                        and again, the observation: "I would rather be represented by a negro than
                        by a white man who can take the oath."</p>
                    <p>We observe that in Georgia, the negroes themselves are ambitious of the post.
                        In two Districts colored men have announced themselves, and enforced their
                        claims in published addresses. They claim that the right to vote gives them
                        the right to hold office, and as they are in the majority the whites shall
                        not be elected by their votes. The candidates are Conservatives, and are in
                        favor of universal amnesty. The impression prevails that a large number of
                        whites will vote for those negro candidates in preference to white ones who
                        can take the test oath.-<emph rend="italic">Fredericksburg Herald</emph>.
                    </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Contends that "there is little doubt" that "a majority of the Members of
                    Congress from the South will be negroes" since many whites "would rather be
                    represented by a negro than a white man who can take the oath."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Colored Congressmen</head>
                <origin>Mobile Advertiser</origin>
                <commentary>"The Mobile Advertiser expresses the views and preferences of many
                    Southern men in the following:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"It is altogether a mistake to suppose that we indulge in a bad joke when we
                        advise the negroes in the present condition of things to prefer their own
                        color as Senators and Representatives in Congress to imported scalawags or
                        pale faced renegades. We prefer them an hundred to one, and we do not see
                        why the negroes should not do it. We prefer them, because in the first
                        place, we can trust a Southern black man when we cannot trust a white
                        traitor or a Yankee speculator in negro votes. If
                        'reconstruction'-so-called-is to be carried out on the plan of the last
                        supplement, the choice is between the two classes we have named, and it is
                        no 'Hobson's choice,' either. Give us the Southern negro, every time, before
                        either a domestic or an imported Radical."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that Southern blacks should vote for men of their own color,
                    declaring "give us the Southern negro, every time, before either a domestic or
                    an imported Radical."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn>Jno. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walton</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walton</ln>
                        <fn>Catherine H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Catherine Walton and William Walton were married at the American Hotel in
                    Staunton on August 30 by Rev. Jno. L. Clarke.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Grove died at the residence of his mother, in Staunton, on August
                    26. He was 27.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1867.09.03.04">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
