<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1867/va.au.ss.1867.08.06">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>John Riedl</taggerName>
            <tagDate>10/19/00</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1867-08-06">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="08">August</month>
            <day>06</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>1867</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1867.08.06.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Radical Resolutions</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The following are the preamble and resolutions which were adopted at the
                        meeting in the Court House on the 29th ult., which sent delegates to the
                        Radical Convention in Richmond which met on Thursday last:</p>
                    <p>This meeting deeply impressed with the importance of a speedy restoration to
                        the people of their political rights, and to have once more elected over
                        them a Government of their own choice; securing to all the blessings of
                        peace and prosperity; and heartily approving of the Convention proposed to
                        be held in the city of Richmond on the 1st of Aug., to take into
                        consideration the important subject of reconstructing the State Government,
                        and restoring the Union. Therefore be it Resolved:</p>
                    <p>1st. That it is the imperative duty of every good citizen, of all parties and
                        without distinction of color, promptly and in good faith, to give their aid
                        to the work of reconstruction, in accordance with the requirements of the
                        Military Bills.</p>
                    <p>2nd. That the only security for our Republican Institutions is a speedy
                        re-union of all the States, under the constitution of the United States.</p>
                    <p>3d. That the Constitution of the United States is the Supreme law of the
                        Land, and to the extent of the powers delegated by it, every citizen owes
                        allegiance first to that government: and it is only in reference to the
                        reserved powers that his allegiance is due to the State Government.</p>
                    <p>4th. That David Fultz Esq, the Rev. Geo A. Shuey, and Maj. John Yates, white,
                        Benj. Downey and Aaron Shoveler, colored, be appointed delegates to
                        represent this Meeting in the Convention to be held in Richmond on the 1st
                        of August next.</p>
                    <p>5th. That the Newspapers of Staunton, and Richmond Whig be requested to
                        publish the proceedings of this meeting.</p>
                    <p>JOHN YATES, President.</p>
                    <p>GEO. W. MCCUTCHEN, Secretary.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>John Yates, Geo. W. McCutchen</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fultz</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shuey</ln>
                        <fn>Geo. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yates</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Downey</ln>
                        <fn>Benj.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shoveler</ln>
                        <fn>Aaron</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yates</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCutchen</ln>
                        <fn>Geo. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Contains the resolutions produced at the Radical meeting at the Staunton
                    Court House on July 29, including the selection of delegates to attend the
                    Radical Convention in Richmond.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1867.08.06.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Radical Convention in Richmond</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>FIRST DAY. <lb/></p>
                    <p>On Thursday last, the day appointed for the meeting of the Radical Convention
                        in Richmond, the chief cooks of the Radical party of this State, composed of
                        "black spirits and white," put their pot to boil which contained the mess of
                        pottage for which they had sold their birthright, and as its contents
                        seethed and bubbled those who surrounded it may have sung in chorus, as did
                        the witches in the dark cave on the blasted heath,</p>
                    <p>Who did "about the cauldron sing,</p>
                    <p>Like elves and fairies in a ring,</p>
                    <p>Enchanting all that pit in." <lb/></p>
                    <p>The witches' cauldron contained, among other savory ingredients, <lb/></p>
                    <p>"Eye of newt, and toe of a frog</p>
                    <p>Wool of bat, and tongue of dog,</p>
                    <p>Adder's fork and blind-worm's sting,</p>
                    <p>Lizzard's leg, and owlet's wing," <lb/></p>
                    <p>The hell-broth of the witches' cauldron was not comparable to that of the
                        Radicals', and the <lb/></p>
                    <p>"Black spirits and white</p>
                    <p>Red spirits and grey," <lb/></p>
                    <p>who sang in glee around it, and would have been abashed and ashamed and would
                        have vanished in disgust could they have been thrown into association with
                        the "black spirits and white" who composed the Radical convention in
                        Richmond.</p>
                    <p>The scene is represented by those who witnessed it as being indescribable.
                        "Hunnicutt and his set" had their own way-the patriotic co-operationists
                        were not recognised in the proceedings-they were not deemed worthy of any
                        consideration-they were as chaff before the black storm-as mere drift-wood
                        in the dark rushing torrent. "Hunnicutt and his set" first filled the
                        African church to suffocation, then adjourned for more air and room to the
                        Capitol Square, where they organized temporarily, then appointed a committee
                        who recommended in their report the election of the same officers who acted
                        in the Hunnicutt convention of the 17th of April last, and the adoption of
                        the same platform of principles-making this Convention re-affirm what was
                        done in that. This report was adopted by the meeting, after which the
                        Convention adjourned till the next day at 10 o'clock. Having dispatched all
                        the business they wished, "Hunnicutt and his set" would have adjourned <emph
                            rend="italic">sine die</emph>, had they not wished to remain in session
                        that they might watch the action of Botts and the patriotic
                        co-operationists. The <emph rend="italic">Dispatch </emph> has a full and
                        graphic report of the proceedings, but being too long to publish, we give
                        the brief and tame report of the <emph rend="italic">Whig </emph> as
                        follows: </p>
                    <p>"The African Church was designated as the place and twelve o'clock as the
                        time for holding the Republican Convention for the State of Virginia on
                        Thursday the 1st inst. Many thoughtful friends and members of the party
                        believed that it would meet as other conventions of a political character
                        had done in former years-that outsiders, black and white, would stand back
                        and let the delegates be seated, but such was not the case. Before the hour
                        of the meeting, the African Church, which, in winter seats comfortably two
                        thousand persons, was jammed to an extent that recalled all of the reputed
                        horrors of the black hole of Calcutta.-Delegates of the highest standing and
                        the most undoubted loyalty stood in front of the steaming building in mute
                        amazement at the exhibition. A bake-oven would have been preferable to the
                        squeezing quarters into which they would have had to crowd had they sought
                        admittance and business in such an assembly and under such circumstances
                        was, to say the least of it, an impossibility. In the meanwhile,
                        propositions without effect were offered to diminish the crowd, and speeches
                        made which no doubt led them to forget that they were perspiring like glass
                        blowers or hearty pugilists preparing to become light weights. But neither
                        persuasion nor harangues availed to bring about an evacuation of the
                        building, until they were authoritatively informed that the convention would
                        meet forthwith on the Square. Then a stampede indescribable commenced, and
                        within a period too short to calculate with accuracy, they were on the east
                        side of the Capitol, when Mr. Tucker mounted the steps and proceeded to
                        nominate Mr. Hauxhurst, of Alexandria, for temporary chairman, and Mr.
                        Charles Whittlesy, of the Alexandria <emph rend="italic">State
                        Journal</emph>, was appointed secretary. </p>
                    <p>Mr. Tucker next moved to appoint a committee of five upon permanent
                        organization, which a stentorian voice in the crowd, which some one told us
                        was Beckley, a most respectable colored man Alexandria, cried out give us a
                        fair chance-one from every county. Somebody else amid the hubbub which
                        prevailed proposed one from each Congressional district, while another, more
                        grasping wanted one from each precinct. Mr. Tucker, who represented the
                        Chairman, as soon as he could re moderate approximation to order, put the
                        question amid cries, 'We are not ready for the question," when it was
                        decided by him that the proposition to appoint one from each county was
                        agreed to by the meeting, which, at this point resembled a bedlam more than
                        anything else of which we can now think. Then came calls for delegates from
                        the various counties to meet at designated places. Some under trees on the
                        Square, some at hotels, and others at points too numerous to mention. At
                        this juncture, we discovered that the white delegates were nearly all
                        absent, and that the colored representatives of counties and colored people
                        of Richmond were having it all their own way.-A recess of half an hour was
                        voted, to give the delegations time to select their representatives on the
                        committee, but, as usual, it was elongated considerably, and it was quite 4
                        o'clock before the committee reported, when it recommended the election of
                        all the officers of the Republican Convention of the 17th of April last. The
                        retirement of the delegations did not, , however, retard the exuberance of
                        oratory which had been manifest from the beginning of the meeting. The
                        speeches were varied in style and argument-some of the speakers being
                        applauded while others less fortunate or attractive were hooted down.</p>
                    <p>One of the speakers, the colored preacher Givens replied to his predecessor
                        who had reflected harshly upon Mr. Botts, and said that he regretted it as
                        much on account of his hearers as Mr. Botts. He then proceeded to state that
                        Mr. B. would be required to shape a bee line. The times have strangely
                        changed where a colored adventurer from New York deems it his duty first to
                        defend John Minor Botts from assault and then to prescribe the course of his
                        political action in the future.</p>
                    <p>The convention wound up its proceedings on "the square" by adopting the
                        platform and re-electing the officers of the convention of the 17th April
                        last. After which it adjourned until ten o'clock Friday morning.</p>
                    <p>At night, meetings of white and black were held in the Hall of the House of
                        Delegates and at Republican Hall. The negroes still seemed to be the ruling
                        spirits, though the sentiment in both bodies seeming to be that of regret
                        that the Botts' party had been shown the cold shoulder so effectually during
                        the proceedings of the day, gave promise that the two parties might be made
                        to coalesce the next day. In the Hall of the House of Delegates two of the
                        negro speakers said that they "hoped that they might yet sit in that
                        Legislative Hall as representatives of the people."</p>
                    <p>The following is an extract of the report of the speech of Gen. Pierce in the
                        meeting at Pepublican Hall:</p>
                    <p>"If Mr. Botts would go for progress and the best interests of Virginia, he
                        would strike hands with him; but if he stood in the way of the great car of
                        progress it would grind him to powder. [Great cheers.] The General charged,
                        gesticulated, and cavorted with great energy. In the course of his remarks,
                        referring to General Longstreet, whose bravery he eulogized, he said he
                        would not refuse him admission; but that he would not vote for him. "There
                        was a devilish sight of difference between voting for General Longstreet and
                        General Longstreet voting with us." [Great cheering.] He wanted General L.
                        to sit on the anxious bench until his robes were washed white. [Cheers.]"</p>
                    <p>Thus the Northern people think in reference to the negroes-they think there
                        is a "devilish sight of difference" between the negroes voting <emph
                            rend="italic">with them</emph> and their voting <emph rend="italic">for
                        </emph> the negroes.-They are willing for the negroes to vote if they vote
                        with them, but are unwilling to vote for the negroes for any office. This
                        the negroes will, in time, find out. <lb/></p>
                    <p>SECOND DAY.</p>
                    <p>It will be remembered that "Hunnicutt and his set," as they were a short time
                        since contemptuously termed by the Richmond <emph rend="italic">Whig
                        </emph>, on the first day had everything their own way, and re-adopted the
                        platform of the Hunnicutt Convention of the 17th of April, and adjourned to
                        10 o'clock the next day-Friday-instead of adjourning <emph rend="italic"
                            >sine die</emph>, because they wished to watch the Botts' party and the
                        co-operationists, and to give them an opportunity to join the "Simon pures"
                        if they could furnish satisfactory evidence that they were sufficiently
                        loyal to be accepted into the true fold of Radicals. </p>
                    <p>As soon as the appointed hour had arrived and the meeting called to
                        order-which was like calling spirits from the vasty deep-Dr. Bayne of
                        Norfolk, colored, offered the following resolution:</p>
                    <p>"Resolved, That as the business of the Convention are completed as per call,
                        that it adjourn <emph rend="italic">sine die</emph>." </p>
                    <p>Thereupon there were many cries of different kinds, and "confusion was worse
                        confounded." Finally Hunnicutt succeeded in gaining the attention of the
                        assembled mass, and said that he was for receiving all who would sincerely
                        repent of their political sins, and would stop cursing "old Hunnicutt and
                        the Republican party," and concluded by hoping that the motion to adjourn
                        would be withdrawn. Thereupon the confusion was worse confounded than before
                        and after an indescribable scene the motion to adjourn <emph rend="italic"
                            >sine die</emph> was passed, the party triumphing expressing by loud
                        cries great exultation.-Thus ended the great Radical Convention, which Botts
                        and the co-operationists confidently expected to control, but which they
                        found they could do nothing with. </p>
                    <p>The negroes triumphed over Botts, the co-operationists, and, in the end, even
                        over Hunnicutt himself.</p>
                    <p>The whites who sought affiliation with the negroes were rebuffed, contemned,
                        despised.-If they have any feeling of self-respect left, they must feel
                        humiliated to a degree bordering upon agony-and that feeling must be
                        intensified by the reflection that their treatment was deserved and that
                        none feel for them a particle of sympathy. The bottom rail was certainly on
                        top in that Convention.</p>
                    <p>In the Convention, Botts and the co-operationists were not recognized, and
                        Botts was not allowed an opportunity even to speak. When the Convention had
                        adjourned, those who had controlled it-"Hunnicutt and his set"-graciously
                        agreed to allow Botts to speak to the assembled crowd. He spoke, tried to
                        impress the negroes that he had been their special friend for thirty years,
                        denounced the Democrats, said they must be watched, that they had, like
                        cats, nine lives; then read a written address embracing his platform which
                        had been adopted in a caucus of his party the day before the Convention met,
                        and which it was then agreed should be submitted for adoption to the
                        Convention, but which they never got the shadow of a chance to do. The
                        object now was, as they failed utterly in <emph rend="italic">Convention
                        </emph>, to get an endorsement of that address from the <emph rend="italic"
                            >mass meeting</emph> then present, and accordingly Geo. Rye, of
                        Woodstock, moved the adoption of Botts platform, but it was met with such a
                        storm of opposition that Rye soon withdrew his motion, and thus the platform
                        fell, and with it Botts and the co-operationists. They met with no more
                        success in mass meeting than in Convention-the bottom rail was still
                        painfully felt to be on top. </p>
                    <p>Speeches were then made by Gov. Pierpont, Chandler of Norfolk, Lewis Scott
                        (colored) of Danville, Rev. Jno. Givens (colored) of Brooklyn, N. Y.,
                        Whittlesy, Pierce, and others-Resolutions endorsing the conduct of General
                        Sheridan were offered by Butts of Norfolk and adopted by the meeting.</p>
                    <p>The author of these resolutions was charged with being a horse-thief. The
                            <emph rend="italic">Dispatch </emph> says that "the concluding words of
                        the Governor's address were lost in the confusion attendant upon a personal
                        difficulty between Mr. Buttz, of Norfolk, and Mr. J. F. Lewis. The latter
                        charged Mr. Buttz with being a horse-thief, or alleged that he had stolen a
                        horse. For some moments a fight was considered imminent; but Lewis finally
                        made a public apology, with the explanation that he had only <emph
                            rend="italic">heard </emph> that Mr. Buttz had stolen the horse." </p>
                    <p>So far as the co-operationists are concerned, the world has never exhibited
                        such a disgraceful and ignominious failure-so far as the negroes are
                        concerned, it has no record of a more decided victory or more insulting
                        exultation over the prostrate fallen.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Includes a summary of events during the two days of the Radical Convention
                    in Richmond, where the cooperationist movement was defeated. The editor argues
                    that "so far as the negroes are concerned," the world "has no record of a more
                    decided victory or more insulting exultation over the prostrate fallen."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Negro Suffrage and Representatives</head>
                <origin>Lynchburg Republican</origin>
                <commentary>"The Lynchburg Republican thus speculates upon the effect of negro
                    suffrage and negro representatives:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"When the ten Southern States are swept, as they certainly will be, by negro
                        majorities in nearly every Congressional district, they will knock at the
                        doors of Congress with 'loyal' <emph rend="italic">black </emph>
                        representatives in many cases. Can Congress exclude them on any pretext? Are
                        they not 'loyal' beyond all doubt? If they are not eligible, how long will
                        it be before they demand that privilege also, and enforce it at the hands of
                        the negro party? Indeed, while we know that the negroes have not been made
                        eligible so far by any legislative enactment, who dare say that if one be
                        elected, he will not be permitted to take his seat? The Radical party has
                        committed some of the grossest inconsistencies that ever marked the career
                        of any political organization, and has shown an entire disregard for its
                        good faith and honor. But it <emph rend="italic">dare </emph> not resist the
                        claims of the negroes to be admitted to any office to which they may not be
                        raised. We saw that only a few days since the Radicals of South Carolina
                        demanded that a negro should run for Vice President on the next Republican
                        Presidential ticket. And while this great concession may not be granted so
                        soon, it is clear that no feint of opposition can be made to the admission
                        of negro Congressmen, elected from the reconstructed States. </p>
                    <p>"And just so soon as these gentlemen from Africa advance to the seats once
                        occupied by Webster and Randolph, and Calhoun and clay, and the long file of
                        scholars and statesmen whose voices have rung through those frescoed halls,
                        the glory will have departed from the party which brought them there, to the
                        shame and confusion of the American people. The ambition of political
                        distinction, the greed of office, the love of party power, may have betrayed
                        the great Northern masses into many excesses in favor of this race. Indeed,
                        it were but justice to say that many susceptible natures were deeply moved
                        by the supposed horrors of African slavery, and have run into those extremes
                        of sympathy and partiality which we naturally indulge towards the victims of
                        fancied wrongs. But the prejudices of race and color are the deepest and
                        most ineradicable of those that divide mankind. When men grow angry, there
                        is no insulting epithet that sooner leaps to their lips than the reminder of
                        belonging to an inferior or dishonored race. And just so soon as the
                        citizens of America, whose fathers discovered it, conquered it, peopled and
                        civilized it, and made its name great and honored in every corner of the
                        earth-just as soon as these white citizens, proud and self-complacent as
                        they are, see a race just relived from bondage made equal to them, and set
                        to legislate over them, there will come a quick cry of disdain and
                        indignation, and the authors of their degradation will soon be brought to a
                        summary account.</p>
                    <p>"This will be but the beginning of the end. When the reaction comes, and the
                        Radical party is hurled from power, there is no foretelling the extent to
                        which the people will go in the other direction. The negroes will certainly
                        be rendered incapable of holding office, and may possibly be deprived of the
                        right of suffrage.-We have no idea that any effort will ever be made, in the
                        face of the world's opposition, to resolve them into a state of bondage. But
                        we feel well assured that on the mere question of losing the civil and
                        political privileges to which they have been elevated by recent legislation,
                        the negroes will strongly resist and fight, and will thus precipitate that
                        great war of races to which we have looked forward, with fearful
                        forebodings, ever since the termination of the recent struggle.</p>
                    <p>"What will be the issue of such a collision, no one can doubt for a moment.
                        While we deprecate earnestly its dreadful scenes, we believe that the white
                        race would come out of them, not only triumphant but almost unhurt, while
                        the inferior race would be swept away like the dead leaves of November. The
                        work would be sharp and decisive. The genius of the Caucastan blood would
                        assert itself with a terrible emphasis, and no subject race would ever
                        thereafter attempt to cope with that dominant and ever victorious people.</p>
                    <p>"These seem to be the experiences upon which we are about to enter. They are
                        full of tragedy and suffering and danger, and are well calculated to make us
                        apprehensive. We have the consolation of believing that we are in no wise
                        responsible for the present crisis, nor any impending evils with which the
                        country may be visited. Our duty in the premises is to be collected and well
                        prepared for any ordeal and emergency, so that when the storm breaks it will
                        find us under shelter, and provided against the sorest perils and
                        visitations."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that because "the prejudices of race and color are the deepest and
                    most ineradicable of those that divide mankind," when "white citizens . . . see
                    a race just relieved from bondage made equal to them, and set to legislate over
                    them, there will come a quick cry of disdain and indignation." In the ensuing
                    backlash, the article argues, "the negroes will certainly be rendered incapable
                    of holding office, and may possibly be deprived of the right of suffrage,"
                    events which will likely be followed by a "great war of races."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1867.08.06.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hogshead</ln>
                        <fn>Meredith</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that Meredith Hogshead fell from a second story window of his home
                    near Middlebrook, breaking his leg and suffering internal injuries.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News--Burglaries</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Having missed from time to time money from his money-drawer, John B. Evans.,
                        Esq., suspected that some one must be in the habit of entering his store at
                        night and concluded to watch, and sure enough, whilst his brother David and
                        Y. M. Bickle were in the store on Friday night last awaiting the entrance of
                        the rogue, he opened the door with a key and walked in, but as he was
                        greeted with the blow of a stick, which failed to knock him down, he did not
                        stand upon the order of his going but went at once, and succeeded in making
                        his escape.</p>
                    <p>On the next night-Saturday-some one broke open the window shutters and
                        entered the store of John Engleman, on New Street, and stole some candy,
                        &amp;c. If this conduct is to be kept up Staunton will soon become as
                        bed as Harrisonburg for burglary and robbery.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Evans</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickle</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickle</ln>
                        <fn>Y. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Engleman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that the stores of John Engleman and John Evans were the sites of
                    attempted burglaries and suggests that if such conduct continues, "Staunton will
                    soon become as bad as Harrisonburg for burglary and robbery."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News--Sunday School Picnic</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Sunday School of the Episcopal Methodist Church-South of this place, held
                        a picnic in Taylor's grove, near town, on last Friday. The school was formed
                        at the church, between 8 and 9 o'clock under the command of their
                        Superintendent Mr. A. M. Simpson, and marched to the woods, where they spent
                        the day very pleasantly swinging, eating and singing, and in many other
                        modes of amusement. Rev. Mr. Phares, of Norfolk, delivered a very
                        interesting and amusing address.</p>
                    <p>We regret to state however, that the enjoyments of the day was somewhat
                        marred by an accident which occurred to two of the children-Willie Hughes
                        and Mamie Steinbeck. Late in the evening when the school was making
                        preparation to return to town, these two children were thrown from a swing,
                        and were very severely hurt, but, it is hoped, not dangerously injured.
                        Willie Hughes was badly stunned but has almost entirely recovered. Mamie
                        Steinbeck sprained her foot, and ankle very severely, and is still confined
                        to her bed.</p>
                    <p>With this exception the day was one of wild enjoyment and true pleasure.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Simpson</ln>
                        <fn>A. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hughes</ln>
                        <fn>Willie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Steinbeck</ln>
                        <fn>Mamie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Episcopal Methodist Church held a Sunday School picnic last Friday,
                    which went off "very pleasantly" except for injuries sustained by two children
                    who fell from the swings.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stringer</ln>
                        <fn>William R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lambert</ln>
                        <fn>Thompson H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Austin</ln>
                        <fn>Martha C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Martha Austin and Thompson Lambert were married on July 29 by Rev. William
                    Stringer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pinkerton</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanna</ln>
                        <fn>John N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carson</ln>
                        <fn>Angeline</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Angeline Carson and John N. Hanna were married on August 1 by Rev. John
                    Pinkerton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baskins</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baskins</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baskins</ln>
                        <fn>Amanda</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Henry, the son of Samuel and Amanda Baskins, died on July 29. He was six
                    years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1867.08.06.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Tribute to a Son of Augusta</head>
                <origin>Lewisburg Times</origin>
                <commentary>"The Lewisburg Times pays the following tribute to a gallant son of this
                    good old county which can boast of so many heroic sons:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"Mr. Peters is a native of Augusta Co. , Va., but volunteered in a company,
                        under the command of Capt. R. F. Dennis, which left this place in the early
                        part of May, 1861, for Staunton Va., from which place it was ordered to
                        Harper's Ferry and placed in the 27th Va. Reg., under command of Col. W. W.
                        Gordon of our town. The 27th Va. Reg. was a part of the Brigade then
                        commanded by Colonel Thos. J. Jackson, subsequently known as the famous
                        "Stonewall" Brigade. Mr. Peters was with his Regiment in all of the hard
                        fought battles and skirmishes during Jackson's first Valley campaign. He
                        helped to win his name as "Stonewall" at the first Manassas. He was with his
                        old chieftain when his guns were heard, speaking in thunder tones, in
                        McClellan's rear at Richmond. He was with him in his last struggle for
                        freedom, and was one among many who strove to avenge his death. From the
                        death of Jackson he, as before, was always at his post, and, when that
                        terrible day arrived, the surrender of the Confederate forces, he was there.
                        When Co. E. 27th Va. Reg. was called upon to stack their arms, this noble
                        soldier, with one companion, stepped forward as the representatives of a
                        company, which, during the first of the war, numbered over one hundred men.
                        When called upon to surrender the old gun, which had been his companion on
                        so many hard fought fields, his noble heart revolted at the idea, and rather
                        than give it into the hands of one of the enemies of his country, he broke
                        it into a thousand pieces before their eyes, but this is not all, this noble
                        soldier never asked for a furlough during the war. he was never absent from
                        his company at any time and was never wounded.</p>
                    <p>Old Augusta gave some noble sons to our dear "lost cause," but she has none
                        that she should feel more honor in claiming than Mr. Henry Peters.</p>
                    <p>In doing what he has done, he was led by no ambition-he did not strike
                        because he wished his name to appear as one of Virginia's bravest sons-he
                        had no rank in the army-he wore no bars or stars, but his noble heart
                        throbbed for the state that gave him birth, and he hesitated not to strive
                        for her liberty."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peters</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Praises the valor and nobility of Henry Peters, who served in the Stonewall
                    Brigade, arguing that "his noble heart throbbed for the State that gave him
                    birth, and he hesitated not to strike for her liberty."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
