<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1867/va.au.ss.1867.01.22">
	<header>
		<title>Staunton Spectator</title>
		<tagger>
			<taggerName>John Riedl</taggerName>
			<tagDate>07/11/00</tagDate>
			<tagNote/>
		</tagger>
		<address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
		<date n="1867-01-22">
			<year>1867</year>
			<month norm="01">January</month>
			<day>22</day>
			<weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
		</date>
		<frequency>weekly</frequency>
		<extent>04</extent>
		<editionNote/>
	</header>
	<paperBody>
		<page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1867.01.22.01">
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1867.01.22.02">
			<div type="a">
				<column>01</column>
				<head>The Power of Pardon</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>In the platform of asserted principles, published some time since by Hon.
						John M. Botts with an air of undoubting confidence, he maintained that the
						pardons granted by President Johnson were null and void, so he had no right
						to pardon in advance of trial and conviction.-The Supreme Court of the
						United States have recently decided the contrary. That august Judicial
						tribunal have decided that the power of the President "extends to every
						offence known to the law, and maybe exercised at any time after its
						commission, either before legal proceedings are taken, or during their
						pendency, or after conviction and judgment."</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>The Supreme Court recently upheld President Johnson's right to grant a
					pardon before legal proceedings have begun.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="e">
				<column>01</column>
				<head>The Negro Population</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>It seems from the reports of the Commissioners of the Revenue that there has
						been an astonishing diminution in the negro population, including free and
						slave, within the present limits of Virginia, was 531,000. Comparing this
						with the amount of the same population of this State since the year 1860. In
						reference to these reports of the Commissioners of the Revenue, the Richmond
							<emph rend="italic">Dispatch</emph> says that, "in 1860, the whole negro
						population in February, we discover that there has been a loss in the
						members of blacks in Virginia of upwards of 190,000! If their diminution has
						continued in the same ratio since the 1st of February as from 1860 to that
						time, the number of negroes now in Virginia cannot be much over 300,000.
						This is a terrible result of emancipation to these people." </p>
					<p>It would seem that the ultimate fate of the African race in this country is
						foreshadowed by that of the Indian. The bell which announce the emancipation
						of the negroes tolled the knell of their hopes of peace, plenty and
						contentment in future</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Claims that the black population of Virginia has declined by over 190,000
					since 1860 and suggests that, from this "terrible result of emancipation," it
					seems "that the ultimate fate of the African race in this country is
					foreshadowed by that of the Indian."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="e">
				<column>01</column>
				<head>What the Negroes Want</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>We have repeatedly said that those who make loudest professions of friendship
						for the negroes are, practically, their worst enemies. We cannot impress it
						too often upon the minds of this class that the best friends, and, in fact,
						the only true friends they have, are the people of the Southern States.</p>
					<p>When the negroes ask for bread, the Radicals give them a stone, and when they
						ask for fish, they give them a serpent. The negroes want employment, bread,
						clothing, fuel and shelter.-They don't desire the right of suffrage; but few
						would exercise it if granted.</p>
					<p>In the language of the Richmond <emph rend="italic">Whig</emph>, "it is due
						to the negroes of the South to say that if left to themselves they would not
						concern with politics. They are thinking more about bread and meat than
						voting. The resolutions and addresses which we so often see in the
						newspapers demanding suffrage and equality, and which purport to emanate
						from them, are not theirs. They are the productions of the white agitators
						and incendiaries who go about drumming them up to attend the meetings they
						call and when they succeed in getting a handful together they read the
						resolutions and addresses they have prepared, and give them to the world as
						the productions of the negroes. The negroes know and care no more about what
						they contain than they do about the problem in Euclid. </p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Argues that "those who make the loudest professions of friendship for the
					negroes are, practically, their worst enemies." The article claims that blacks
					"don't desire the right of suffrage" and asserts that "few would exercise it if
					granted." The demand for black suffrage, it avows, is the work of "white
					agitators and incendiaries."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>02</column>
				<head>Dangerous Counterfeit</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Reports that a new counterfeit five dollar National Bank note is now in
					circulation and warns readers to examine such notes carefully.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1867.01.22.03">
			<div type="a">
				<column>01</column>
				<head>Local News</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>Mr. P. H. Trout requests us to correct an account which appeared in this
						paper some weeks ago giving a detailed statement of a supposed attempt to
						rob him. He states that he is now convinced that the man who was here the
						night before he left, and was thought to have followed him to Philadelphia
						was not M. W. Price (formerly of Harper's Ferry) nor did he see him (the
						said M. W. Price) arrested after they met in Philadelphia.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Trout</ln>
						<fn>P. H.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>P. H. Trout corrects an account of an attempted robbery on his person that
					appeared in the Spectator a few weeks ago.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>01</column>
				<head>Local News--"Aunt Milly"--136 Years Old</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>We have published on several occasions, notices of "Aunt Millie," a colored
						woman, formerly the property of Capt. Jas. M. Harris, of Nelson county. She
						died on the 7th inst., in the <emph rend="italic">one hundred and thirty-six
							year of her age</emph>. She was born in 1731, and was, consequently 45
						years of age at the declaration of Independence, and 52 when the
						independence of the colonies was recognised by the mother country. She was
						56 years older than the Constitution of the United States which was adopted
						in 1787. </p>
					<p>Caroline James, a colored woman, aged one hundred and thirty years, died in
						Richmond a few days since. She was only once married and was the mother of
						thirty-five children.</p>
					<p>Silvia Leach, another colored woman, died near Ford's Depot, in Dinwiddie,
						recently, aged one hundred and ten years.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln/>
						<fn>Milly</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Aunt</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Harris</ln>
						<fn>Jas. M.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Capt.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Former slave "Aunt Milly" died on January 7 and was reported to be 136
					years old at her death.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>01</column>
				<head>Local News--"Philomathesian Society"</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>A debating club, entitled the "Philomathesian Society," composed of the young
						men of this place, was organized on last Saturday night, by the election of
						the following officers: Herber Ker, President; S. N. Giles, Vice President;
						C. C. Wheat, Treasurer, and Carrie Taylor, Secretary. We are pleased to see
						our young men organized into a society of this character, as it is
						calculated to develop and burnish the oratorical jewel of the mind, which
						is, when polished, the most enviable talent with which man can be gifted.
						Who knows by that our "city of the hills" may produce a second Patrick Henry
						or a Webster.?</p>
					<p>They will meet every Saturday night, in the Temperance hall. The subject for
						discussion on the next Saturday night is, "Which is the greater incentive to
						exertion, the fear of punishment or the hope of reward?"</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Ker</ln>
						<fn>Herber</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Giles</ln>
						<fn>S. N.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Wheat</ln>
						<fn>C. C.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Taylor</ln>
						<fn>Carrie</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>The young men of the county have organized a new debating club, entitled
					the Philomathesian Society.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>01</column>
				<head>Local News--Staunton Lyceum</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>The question discussed in the Staunton Lyceum on last Friday night was the
						following:</p>
					<p>"Is the mind of woman naturally equal to that of man."</p>
					<p>Powell Harrison, Esq. had been appointed to open the debate in the
						affirmative and J. M. Hanger, Esq., in the negative.</p>
					<p>As Mr. Harrison was not present, the debate was opened by J. M. Hanger, Esq.,
						in the negative, in a speech which was facetious, humorous and witty.</p>
					<p>The affirmative was advocated by Messrs. Y. Howe Peyton, Prof. Pike Powers,
						Dr. C. R. Harris and Col. Jas. M. Skinner, and the negative by Messrs. J. M.
						Hanger, Prof. J. H. Hewitt, and Jas. Bumgardner, Jr.</p>
					<p>Upon being submitted to the vote, it was decided in the affirmative by 14 to
						8.</p>
					<p>On next Friday night, Rev. S. D. Stuart will deliver a lecture before the
						Lyceum. His subject will be his recent visit to England. We hope he will be
						honored with a large audience.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Harrison</ln>
						<fn>Powell</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Hanger</ln>
						<fn>J. M.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Peyton</ln>
						<fn>Y. Howe</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Powers</ln>
						<fn>Pike</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Prof.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Harris</ln>
						<fn>C. R.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Dr.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Skinner</ln>
						<fn>Jas. M.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Col.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Hewitt</ln>
						<fn>J. H.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Prof.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Bumgardner</ln>
						<fn>Jas.</fn>
						<sf>Jr.</sf>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Stuart</ln>
						<fn>S. D.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Last Friday the discussion at the Staunton Lyceum addressed the question
					"is the mind of woman naturally equal to that of man?" When put to a vote, the
					question was decided in the affirmative by a vote of 14 to 8.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="l">
				<column>02</column>
				<head/>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>It is with feelings of sorrow, I communicate the death of LILBURN R. STOUT,
						eldest son of James M. Stout Esq., of New Hope.</p>
					<p>The circumstances connected with this sad event were peculiarly painful and
						distressing. On Friday morning last, he left his father's house for the
						farm, on Middle River, where he resided; and, on his way, was thrown from
						his horse, not far from the residence of Mr. Albert Armentrout. He was found
						shortly after the accident, by his relative. Dr. Gillespie, (who had but a
						short time before parted with him,) in a state of insensibility, and who
						promptly administered to his relief. He was taken to Mr. Armentrout, where
						he received the kindest attention of his hospitable family. He lingered
						until Tuesday night when death released him from his sufferings. His remains
						were taken to Augusta Church on Thursday morning, where they were interred,
						and a sermon, appropriate to the occasion as preached by the Rev. Mr.
						Bowman.</p>
					<p>Thus, almost in a moment, have a kind and affectionate father and mother,
						sisters and brothers been called upon to weep and to mourn the loss of one
						thus suddenly and unexpectedly cut down, and a gloom been cast over the
						community where the deceased was so generally known.</p>
					<p>Mr. Stout possessed many amiable traits of character-kind, and generous and
						noble-hearted. I believe he had not an enemy. It was during his service in
						the Confederate army, that he and a younger brother were taken prisoners and
						sent to Elmira, New York, where they remained for nearly a year. By taking
						the oath of allegiance to the Northern Government, he could, at any time,
						have obtained his release; but true to his principles, he choose rather to
						suffer and endure all the hardships and privations of a prison than prove a
						traitor to his country.</p>
					<p>But he is gone! and how impressively are we all reminded, and with what deep
						and solemn emphasis does this sad and mysterious dispensation speak to his
						surviving companions and associates, "in the midst of life we are in death."
						W. A. J.</p>
					<p>January 12, 1867.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer>W. A. J.</trailer>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Stout</ln>
						<fn>Lilburn R.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Stout</ln>
						<fn>James M.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Armentrout</ln>
						<fn>Albert</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Gillespie</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Dr.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Bowman</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>"W. A. J." details the life and death of Lilburn R. Stout, who died after
					being thrown from his horse last Friday.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>03</column>
				<head>The Test Oath Decision</head>
				<origin>National Intelligencer</origin>
				<commentary>"The Supreme Court of the United States has rendered a decision
					declaring the test oath unconstitutional, and rescinding the rule of the Court
					requiring Attorneys to take the oath:--The National Intelligencer says:"</commentary>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>The Supreme Court of the United States has rendered a decision declaring the
						test oath unconstitutional, and rescinding the rule of the Court requiring
						Attorneys to take the oath:--The <emph rend="italic">National
						Intelligencer</emph> says: </p>
					<p>"By the solemn award of the Supreme Court test oaths are pronounced contrary
						to the Constitution, and inconsistent not only with its spirit, but its
						letter."</p>
					<p>The opinion was first delivered, by Justice Fields, in the case of Rev. John
						A. Coummins of Missouri, a Roman Catholic Priest, indicted for preaching and
						teaching without taking the oath prescribed by the constitution of that
						State, being plaintive in error. The court decides the test oath in this
						case unconstitutional, being in the nature of punishment without trial and
						in its character <emph rend="italic">ex post facto</emph>, and as a bill of
						attainder. The judgment of the court below is reversed. </p>
					<p>In the <emph rend="italic">ex parte</emph> cases of Garland &amp; Marr,
						attorneys, who having participated in the "rebellion," ask to be admitted to
						practice, the majority opinion of the court is that the test oath law is in
						the nature of an <emph rend="italic">ex post facto</emph> law; that
						attorneys are not officers of the United States, they are officers of the
						court, and hold their offices during good behavior. The court is not the
						register of the edicts of any other power. The applicants obtained a pardon
						from the President, which relieves from the consequences of offence, and
						makes the citizen in the eye of the law what he was before it was committed.
						Congress cannot limit, the prerogative of mercy cannot be fettered by
						legislative restriction, and therefore the rule which requires attorneys to
						take the test oath must be rescinded, and the order is made accordingly. </p>
					<p>The dissenting opinion was read by Associate Justice Miller, for himself,
						Chief Justice Chase, and Associates Swayne and Davis.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>A report on the reasoning in the recent Supreme Court ruling that declared
					the test oath unconstitutional.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>04</column>
				<head>Marriages</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Cease</ln>
						<fn>Erasmus P.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Swink</ln>
						<fn>Sarah A.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Busey</ln>
						<fn>E. F.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Erasmus Cease and Sarah Swink were married on January 15 by Rev. E. F.
					Busey.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>04</column>
				<head>Deaths</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Risk</ln>
						<fn>Amanda</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Risk</ln>
						<fn>John W.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Amanda Risk, infant daughter of John W. Risk, died on January 4 at Crawford
					Springs. She was 4 months old.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>04</column>
				<head>Deaths</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Stafford</ln>
						<fn>John F.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Lieut.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Lieut. John Stafford, of the 5th Va. Infantry, died on January 13 at his
					home in Staunton. He was 49.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>04</column>
				<head>Deaths</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Bell</ln>
						<fn>Walter Hazlewood</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Bell</ln>
						<fn>J. C.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Dr.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Bell</ln>
						<fn>M. M.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Walter Hazlewood Bell died on December 31. He was 6 months old.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1867.01.22.04">
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
	</paperBody>
</hwp>
