<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1861/pa.fr.vs.1861.01.23">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Brian Erb</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1861-01-23">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day>23</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.01.23.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Inaugural Address of Gov. Andrew G. Curtin</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A transcript of the Governor's address. The address takes a pro-Union tone
                    and denies the right of secession.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Rebellions</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Enumerates past rebellious attempts to resist the Federal Government.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Governor's address columns 2-6. Bottom illegible.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.01.23.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Sermon</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Text of a sermon delivered by Rev. Dr. Francis Venton in Trinity Church,
                    New York. Sermon denies scriptural basis to the opposition to slavery. Sermon
                    occupies columns 1-5.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Letter from Vice President Breckinridge.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In a letter to Gov. MaGuffin of Kentucky, Vice-President Breckinridge
                    advocates compromise to save the Union. He doesn't, however, hold out much hope
                    for such a solution.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Bottom illegible</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.01.23.03">
            <pageNote>Continuation of Breckinridge's letter and advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.01.23.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Our Union Record</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spirit outlines its faithfulness to the cause of restoring the Union.
                    The Spirit maintains that the Union can best be preserved on a ground of
                    compromise and that Constitutional rights of the South should be recognized. The
                    Spirit prints extracts from its own editorials to prove its dedication to the
                    Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Seward's Speech</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Criticizes Seward's speech for being too anti-Southern and not recognizing
                    the legitimate grievances of the South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Necessity of Compromise</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Asserts that the Union must choose coercion or compromise and that any
                    attempt to steer a middle course will fail.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Times Hard Up</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spirit accuses the Times of printing falsehoods just to get a notice
                    from the Spirit. In this case, the Times accused the Spirit of approving treason
                    in South Carolina.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Poverty of the South</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spirit criticizes another attempt by the Times to downplay the economic
                    value of the Cotton States to the Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Bottom illegible</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.01.23.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Douglas Simmering Down</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>States that Douglas has backed away from his alleged hard line against the
                    South since losing to Lincoln. The Spirit thinks his new conciliatory attitude
                    toward the South is an improvement.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Our Disunion Congress</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Accuses the Republicans in Congress of being the cause of disunion and
                    questions their dedication to the Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Railroad Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The importance of having a connection by Railroad with the Great West
                    cannot well be over-estimated, and it is with sincere satisfaction that we
                    notice this effort now being made towards the accomplishment of this highly
                    desirable object."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--A Meeting of the Citizens of Franklin County will be held in the Court
                        House, in this place, on Friday evening, 29th inst., to consider the project
                        of constructing a Railroad from Chambersburg to connect with the Pittsburg
                        and Connellsville road. Mr. J. B. McIlroy, Civil Engineer, will be present
                        and address the meeting.</p>
                    <p>The importance of having a connection by Railroad with the Great West cannot
                        well be over-estimated, and it is with sincere satisfaction that we notice
                        this effort now being made towards the accomplishment of this highly
                        desirable object. We do not deem it necessary to repeat all the arguments we
                        have from time to time advanced in favor of this road--we have already
                        presented them in every shape to enlist inquiry and secure co-operation.
                        There is too much indifference manufactured by our citizens in this great
                        enterprise. We are the parties that will be most benefitted and we should
                        show, if we do not subscribe a dollar, that we properly estimate the great
                        and permanent benefits which must result from the completion of this road.
                        It is not too late to repair our past negligence. This meeting may give a
                        fresh start to the project that may result in much good. The farmers along
                        the line have taken hold of the matter with much earnestness, and they now
                        appeal to the citizens of the towns for active co-operation.</p>
                    <p>Fortunate will it be for Chambersburg when that day arrives that this great
                        avenue to wealth will be opened up for its benefit. There is not an
                        individual in the community to whom it will not bring immense personal
                        advantages.</p>
                    <p>We are not asked at this time to subscribe a dollar. Let us attend the
                        meeting, one and all, and learn all we can about the prospects of
                        constructing the road. Let us by our presence at the meeting show that we
                        feel some interest in the progress and prosperity of our town, and that our
                        hearts are in the work and it will afford some encouragement to others to
                        lend us a helping hand.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mallray</ln>
                        <fn>J.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A meeting in Franklin County will take place to consider the building of a
                    railroad to connect Chambersburg to the Pittsburgh line.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/jan61.html#1.23b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>U.B. Conference</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The following are appointments made by the Penn'a Annual Conference of the
                    United Brethren in Christ held in this place, January 17th, 1861:"</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--The following are appointments made by the Penn'a Annual Conference of the
                        United Brethren in Christ held in this place, January 17th, 1861:</p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Chambersburg District</cell>
                            <cell>Jas M Bishop, P E</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>" Station</cell>
                            <cell>Z A Colestock</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Orrstown Station</cell>
                            <cell>John Dickson</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Rocky Spring "</cell>
                            <cell>J W Bard</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Big Spring "</cell>
                            <cell>W O Owen</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Greencastle Circuit</cell>
                            <cell>A Tripner, J F Wilt</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Path Valley "</cell>
                            <cell>H Y Hummelbaugh</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Shippensburg "</cell>
                            <cell>F Gilbert</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Mercersburg "</cell>
                            <cell>Samuel Young</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Bethany Mission</cell>
                            <cell>Wm Humberger</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>York District</cell>
                            <cell>Wm B Raber, P E</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>York Station</cell>
                            <cell>S Enterline</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Baltimore Ger. "</cell>
                            <cell>J A Sand</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Baltimore Eng. "</cell>
                            <cell>J Philip Bishop</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Shopps "</cell>
                            <cell>J C Smith, W Leacock</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>York Circuit</cell>
                            <cell>H Brown</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>York Spring "</cell>
                            <cell>N Altman</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Littlestown "</cell>
                            <cell>D Eberly</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Manchester "</cell>
                            <cell>J A Clem</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Carlisle "</cell>
                            <cell>S L Minnick, J G Shoaff</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Perry "</cell>
                            <cell>J S Wents, H A Sleighter</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Liverpool "</cell>
                            <cell>J B Jones</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Paradise "</cell>
                            <cell>P Corl</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Bendersville</cell>
                            <cell>Js Weidler</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <p>The membership of this conference numbers about 6, 000; Preachers traveling
                        and local, about 60; Number of Meeting Houses, 61; Number of Sabbath
                        Schools, 50; Number of Scholars, 3, 000; Amount of Missionary funds raised
                        during the year about $2500; $1160 of which were secured on Saturday
                        evening, during Conference.</p>
                    <p>This Conference embraces within its bounds some four or five counties.</p>
                    <p>The following Resolution was adopted by Conference:</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That the thanks of this body be tendered
                        to the people of Chambersburg for their kindness and hospitality during our
                        stay among them, and to the Cumberland Valley and Franklin Railroads for
                        free return tickets; also to the gentlemanly Cashier of the Bank of
                        Chambersburg for exchanging money and giving drafts for missionary purposes
                        free of the usual charges.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bishop</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Colestock</ln>
                        <fn>L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tripner</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilt</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports the meeting of the Conference of the United Brethren in Christ in
                    Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/jan61.html#1.23a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The National Troubles</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports several news items from around the country dealing with the
                    secession crisis, including military preparations and the status of the
                    secession ordinance debates in the Southern States.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Peace Propositions from Pennsylvania</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Nathaniel Burt, a Pennsylvania Republican, advocates taking immediate steps
                    to conciliate the border states and pledge the constitutional rights and freedom
                    from interference from each state.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Philips</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cassel</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on January 17.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McHenry</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Solenberger</ln>
                        <fn>Solomon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingert</ln>
                        <fn>Lizzie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on January 15.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn>J. Smith</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harry</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McElroy</ln>
                        <fn>Anna</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McElroy</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Harry married Anna McElroy on January 16.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snider</ln>
                        <fn>Martha</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snider</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snider</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Martha Snider died on January 18th, aged 7 years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClintock</ln>
                        <fn>Elisa</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClintock</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Elisa McClintock died of consumption on January 18 in Baltimore.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newton</ln>
                        <fn>Anna</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Anna Newton died on January 17, aged 71 years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Alleman</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Henry Alleman died on January 13.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Logan</ln>
                        <fn>Isabel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Isabel Logan died on January 8th, aged 75 years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patton</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rebecca Patton died on January 10 of apoplexy, aged 80 years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.01.23.06">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.01.23.07">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.01.23.08">
            <div type="l">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Letter from Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Oglethorpe</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter from Virginia favors compromise based on the recognition of Southern
                    rights.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
