<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1861/pa.fr.vs.1861.07.31">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Brian Erb</taggerName>
            <tagDate>04/09/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 5/13/97</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1861-07-31">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day>31</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>semi-weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.07.31.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Graphic Description</head>
                <origin>New York World</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Account of the Federal retreat from Manassas.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Confederate Account of the Battle of Manassas</head>
                <origin>Baltimore Sun</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A Southern view of the battle.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Gen. Scott and the Cabinet</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Gen. Scott had advocated a less aggressive policy to defeat
                    the Confederacy. He argued that the North should rely on the blockade to weaken
                    the South and should attempt to control the Mississippi and the Gulf before
                    moving on Richmond. However, his advice was not heeded by the Cabinet.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Returned Volunteers</head>
                <origin>Harrisburg District</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Complains of the Government's delinquency in the paying of Pennsylvania
                    volunteers. The terms of a number of volunteer regiments expired, and the
                    members of these regiments waited in Harrisburg to be paid. When no pay was
                    forthcoming, the men hung a paymaster in effigy and almost started an armed
                    riot.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>More reports from Manassas</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.07.31.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Home Again</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"On Sunday afternoon last our town was thrown into quite an excitement by
                    the unexpected announcement that the Franklin County companies, belonging to the
                    2nd Regiment, were at the Depot."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On Sunday afternoon last our town was thrown into quite an excitement by the
                        unexpected announcement that the Franklin County companies, belonging to the
                        2nd Regiment, were at the Depot. As soon as the news of their arrival spread
                        our streets were crowded by a dense mass of people all eagerly rushing to
                        the Depot to welcome them home. The companies were marched from the Depot,
                        followed by a vast concourse of people, to the Public Square, where they
                        were dismissed. The men have all, without an exception that we noticed,
                        improved in personal appearance, and the full number that left here come
                        back in excellent condition. They have performed a good share of arduous
                        service during their three months enlistment, but, with a few slight
                        exceptions, all have enjoyed remarkably good health, and return to their
                        homes in fine spirits. Quite a number of the men say that they are ready to
                        re-enlist for three years, and many would have entered the service at once,
                        at Harrisburg, had it not been for the outrageous treatment they there
                        received. We are satisfied, from the feeling among our people that a full
                        regiment could be raised in this county, in less than a month, if the men
                        could be assured that the bad treatment our soldiers have been subjected to
                        would not be repeated. As it now stands, few, if any, would be willing to
                        risk another enlistment for so long a term.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports the return of 3 month enlistees to Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/july61.html#7.31a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Another Awful Panic</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Well, some good may come out of this, after all. The country has got rid
                    of Greeley's valuable services and we shouldn't wonder that the next battle
                    would be a victory."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Greeley has admitted that "an awful panic has seized upon
                    him," and he has promised that he won't open his mouth about the war again.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Sunday Battles</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Asserts that battles fought on Sunday always result in the defeat of the
                    attacking Army.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The London Times on the War</head>
                <origin>London Times</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spirit quotes the London Times in a criticism of the strategic
                    competence of the Northern officers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Dangers of the Hour</head>
                <origin>New York Observer</origin>
                <commentary>"It would be well for all sects and parties to take the same view of the
                    dangers that now beset our country before their liberties are 'clean gone
                    forever.'"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The New York Observer criticizes the disregard for civil liberties shown by
                    many politicians and journalists. The paper castigates those who would allow the
                    Constitution to be "trampled upon in order to carry on and carry out this war."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>How to Know Them</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Asserts that those who most loudly denounce the South and praise the war
                    are the least likely to join the Army.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Democrats Sustaining the Union</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Alleges that most soldiers are Democrats and sights in-camp votes to
                    support this claim.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>J. Allison Eyster</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"While in Winchester he was not, we believe, molested, but shortly after
                    leaving that place, to return home, he fell into the hands of some rebel scouts
                    and was arrested by them and taken back and lodged in the Winchester jail."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It is with no ordinary feelings of regret that we announce to our readers
                        that our esteemed fellow townsman, Mr. J. ALLISON EYSTER, is a prisoner in
                        the hands of the dastardly rebels of Virginia. Mr. Eyster visited
                        Charleston, a short time ago, for the purpose of looking after some business
                        matters, and while there accompanied a friend, a Virginian, to Winchester.
                        While in Winchester he was not, we believe, molested, but shortly after
                        leaving that place, to return home, he fell into the hands of some rebel
                        scouts and was arrested by them and taken back and lodged in the Winchester
                        jail. Several acquaintances of Mr. EYSTER, at Winchester, made efforts to
                        have him released and had hopes of being successful, but before they could
                        accomplish it he, with several other prisoners, was removed to Richmond
                        where he is now detained in the hands of Jeff Davis' minions. We look upon
                        the arrest of Mr. EYSTER as a most wanton outrage. He was not in arms
                        against them, or in any way connected with the army, and is too honorable
                        man to act in the capacity of a spy. There was no charge brought against
                        him--nothing to warrant his arrest, or to justify or palliate, in any way
                        such an outrage on an unoffending citizen of Pennsylvania. Mr. EYSTER has
                        many friends in Virginia and we have no doubt, as soon as his ease is
                        brought to the attention of the proper authorities, that he will at once be
                        released and sent home.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>J. Allison</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that Eyster is a prisoner of the rebels in Virginia, having been
                    captured while on business in Winchester.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/july61.html#7.31b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>More Arrests by the Rebels</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brotherton</ln>
                        <fn>W.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kurtz</ln>
                        <fn>L.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCumsey</ln>
                        <fn>Joshua</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that other Franklin County citizens not connected with the Army
                    have been imprisoned in Virginia. The Spirit asks that these men be freed and
                    threatens to retaliate by seizing prominent Virginians if the Franklin men are
                    not released.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Killed by Lightning</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ashway</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grossman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that John Asway's colt was killed by lightning and Mr. Grossman's
                    barn was also hit and burned.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Thanks</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Thanks those who have begun subscribing to the Spirit.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Laid Over</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"...we have not picked the quarrel and feel little disposed to continue
                    it."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spirit takes issue with the constant attacks from the Times, which has
                    become the "Lincolnites' ally."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Sesesh Help</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Buchanan County, Virginia has been renamed Stephens County by
                    the Secession convention because of Buchanan's support of the Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>President's Message</head>
                <origin>Columbia Democrat</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Criticizes Lincoln's message, in which he said that it remains for the
                    people "to demonstrate to the world that those who can fairly carry an election
                    can also suppress a rebellion." The paper believes that this is a deliberate
                    insult to Northern Democrats. The article alleges that the army which does his
                    bidding is disproportionately Democratic.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Direct Taxation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on the proposed tax bill now before Congress. The bill proposes to
                    raise $30,000,000 by taxing all lands, lots of grounds, dwelling houses,
                    chattels, slaves, and stills.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Stupendous Swindling in Beef</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Bemoans the poor quality of the beef purchased for the Pennsylvania
                    volunteers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Noble Sentiments</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Suggests that those who write in support of the war should join the Army
                    and fight it, lest the public suspect their fervor is reserved for those battles
                    that others fight.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Right Talk</head>
                <origin>Boston Journal</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Transcript from a Republican journal which praises the Democrats for
                    putting party issues aside on the battlefield and saving party conflicts for
                    other arenas.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>A Few Plain Questions</head>
                <origin>Philadelphia Enquirer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Proposes a few questions regarding Sunday's panic over soldiers' payment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>One of the Effects of Civil War</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Report of a New York soldier and a Virginia soldier who were college
                    friends meeting in the midst of battle and not killing each other.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>First Congress of the Confederate States of America</head>
                <origin>Richmond Enquirer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"[T]he invader of our soil has been driven back, . . . our alters have been
                    purified and our homes secured from the ruthless hand of an unprincipled foe."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprints the report to the Confederate Congress of the Southern victory at
                    Manassas.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.07.31.03">
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Russell</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Died in Southampton twp. on July 26 at 69 years of age.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements and Chambersburg markets</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.07.31.04">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
