<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1861/pa.fr.vs.1861.06.12">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Colleen Doody</taggerName>
            <tagDate>1/10/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; second pass 5/5/97</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1861-06-12">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="06">June</month>
            <day>12</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>semi-weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.06.12.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>From Washington</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Miscellaneous news from Washington. The 1st Regiment of cavalry and the 2d
                    Regiment of dragoons of the U.S. Army have been ordered to the Chambersburg
                    area. The Pennsylvania troops have received their new uniforms and will
                    hereafter be as well dressed as any of the other troops.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>From Fortress Monroe</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Miscellaneous news from Fortress Monroe. The steamer State of Georgia
                    brought the Tenth New York regiment of National Zouaves to Fortress Monroe. Gen.
                    Butler has issued stringent orders to prevent depredations on private property.
                    Those citizens of Hampton who had their property damaged had the amount of the
                    damages refunded to them.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>From Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Federal troops would have advanced from Alexandria and Arlington if the
                    rebel forces hadn't also begun to move. A large force of Confederates is now
                    centered at Manassas Junction. Gen. Beauregard has assumed command of these
                    Confederate troops.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>A Skirmish</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A skirmish occurred near Hampton between Col. Duryea's regiment of Zouaves
                    and a party of rebels.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>From Washington</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is reported "upon high authority" that if England sides with the South,
                    the Emperor Napoleon will side with the North because he doesn't want England to
                    cripple her greatest maritime rival.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>One of Our Foreign Ministers in Trouble</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Board of Examiners, who have in their possession all of the manuscripts
                    of the despatches seized in the different principal cities of the Union, have
                    found that a prominent Minister gave intelligence to the Confederates. The
                    Minister will be recalled immediately.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>A Rebel Camp Dispersed in Kentucky</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>General Prentiss sent two companies to break up a camp of secessionists at
                    Elliott's Mills, Kentucky. They had already fled by the time the companies
                    arrived. Col. Wycliff protested against this invasion of Kentucky soil.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Preparations for Hostilities with Great Britain</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The federal government has decided to bring all the available naval vessels
                    into active service because of the threat of hostilities between Great Britain
                    and the U.S. The British appear to be using their navy to aid the Confederacy,</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Important Reports from Manassas Junction</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Confederates appear to have between 14,000 and 20,000 troops at
                    Manassas Junction. They are moving in men at a rate of three trainfuls a day.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>The Affair at Phillippi</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>More details about the skirmish at Phillippi.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Extracts from the London Press--The Uprising of New England for the Union</head>
                <origin>London Times</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Less than a century ago, Massachusetts and Virginia fought together to
                    promote rebellion. Now, Virginia fights for another rebellion while
                    Massachusetts supports the doctrines of legitimacy and toryism.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>Look</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>The European Powers Will Soon Decide</head>
                <origin>London Shipping Gazette</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The federal government has notified the European powers that it will hold
                    no intercourse with any state that recognizes the Southern Commissioners. This
                    action will force every government that has diplomatic relations with the U.S.
                    to make a decision on its future course.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>Look</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Independence of the Southern Government Acknowledged as DeFacto</head>
                <origin>London Post</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The recognition of the Confederacy by the European powers would give great
                    moral support to the South. While the powers appear reticent to anger the
                    federal government, they have also pointed out that de facto governments have
                    the right to be recognized.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>Look</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>London Telegraph</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Mr. Seward is anxious to prevent the European powers from recognizing the
                    South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>look</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>London Standard</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Standard holds itself aloof from both North and South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.06.12.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Glad to Hear It</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Gen. Patterson has taken charge of the Telegraph Office in Chambersburg and
                    has placed an operator there to supervise all the army-related dispatches. This
                    action pleases the Spirit, which believes that it will "put an effectual stop to
                    the lying sensation dispatches, and bogus news, furnished, from this point, by
                    some hangers-on to the skirts of the army who call themselves 'Reporters' for
                    the New York and Philadelphia papers."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>More Troops</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The First Regiment, Rhode Island Volunteers, has reached Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>News From Our Soldiers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The troops that left Camp Slifer last Friday and Saturday are now encamped
                    three-fourths of a mile north of Greencastle. Other troops that recently left
                    Chambersburg are on the road leading to Hagerstown.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Something Wrong</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We do not know whether it is "red-tape," or too much Whiskey, that
                    occasions this shameful neglect of the men, but from whatever cause it proceeds,
                    we hope to see it remedied speedily and effectually."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On Tuesday morning a number of companies from "Camp Chambers," near this
                        place broke the Guards and rushed to town to procure something to eat. These
                        met appear perfectly reckless and desperate and must become utterly
                        demoralized unless their wrongs are speedily righted. They complain bitterly
                        of the scarcity of provision--the meat, they say, is frequently putrid and
                        the bread never in sufficient quantity, and oftentimes none at all, which,
                        they state was the case all day Monday and Tuesday morning. The hungry men
                        would stand it no longer and made a rush to town for something to eat. We do
                        not know whether it is "red-tape," or too much Whiskey, that occasions this
                        shameful neglect of the men, but from whatever cause it proceeds, we hope to
                        see it remedied speedily and effectually.--We intend to stand up for the
                        rights of our volunteers and unless their condition is improved, and their
                        necessary wants supplied, we will be compelled to make an expose that may
                        occasion some fluttering among the "Brass buttons."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>On Tuesday a number of companies from "Camp Chambers" rushed into town to
                    procure food. They complained of the scarcity of provision and the poor quality
                    of the food in camp. The Spirit intends to stand up for the rights of the
                    volunteers and vows to expose any corruption in the procurement procedure if the
                    conditions are not improved.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/june61.html#6.12a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Difference</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A Republican "neighbor" lauded the Rhode Island Regiment that recently
                    arrived in Chambersburg as being "among the best equipped troops." The Spirit
                    points out that their uniforms cost $8 while the miserable clothing of the
                    Pennsylvania Volunteers cost $17. The Spirit asks what "our neighbor [has to]
                    say in extenuation for this sample of Republican management of our State
                    military affairs?"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Troops</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Sixteen regiments of Pennsylvania Volunteers, plus nine companies of
                    regulars, are encamped in or have recently left Chambersburg on their way to the
                    enemy lines.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Movements of Troops</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Almost every day and night trains are arriving in town loaded with horses,
                    provisions, and ammunition. The troops continue to arrive and depart.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Southern Papers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The stoppage of the mail from the Southern states has cut off the Southern
                    press. However, the Spirit doesn't believe that this is a great loss since these
                    papers didn't report on troop movements or any other army related information.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>Look</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>More Disgrace</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spirit is outraged that incompetent men are being appointed to command
                    the Pennsylvania troops. They direct the readers attention to the article in
                    column 4, "Appointments not fit to be Made," in which a Republican paper makes
                    the same complaint.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>A Good Sign</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"All experienced writers upon arms for soldiers denounce the use of pistols
                    for privates and ridicule the idea of knives." The volunteers should instead
                    rely on their bayonets in a close fight.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Coming Election</head>
                <origin>Juniata Democrat</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In the excitement over the coming of the war, everyone has forgotten about
                    the coming election. The Republicans have urged voters to forget about party.
                    The Juniata Democrat believes that this is a ruse to add strength to the
                    Republican party, which can no longer win voters with their sectional doctrines.
                    They urge every Democrat to "stand up for his country in its hour of trial, but
                    still cling to Democratic principles."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>Look</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>"No More Party"</head>
                <origin>LaSalle Standard</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Two or three weeks ago, the Republicans insisted that party issues had been
                    set aside in favor of unity. Now, however, it appears that Republicanism has
                    been resurrected as the party members call conventions and make nominations.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Western Reserve of Ohio, a well known abolitionist region, has "thus
                    far responded but feebly to the call for troops." The governor attempted to hide
                    this low turnout by "preventing the mustering into the service of the United
                    States of regiments raised in other quarters of the State, in order to give the
                    abolition corner a chance." However, the War Department ordered him to stop this
                    practice.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>A Scoundrel</head>
                <origin>New York Sun</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Charges have been made to the Secretary of War that one of the largest
                    contractors for the Pennsylvania Quartermaster General has also sold saltpetre
                    to the South. An investigation has been ordered.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Appointments not fit to be Made</head>
                <origin>Philadelphia Inquirer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Inquirer is outraged that incompetent men are being appointed to
                    command regiments. They believe that the Secretary of War is using the War
                    Department to benefit his followers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>Look</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Affairs at Harper's Ferry</head>
                <origin>Louisville Courier</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An extract from a letter written by a Southern volunteer encamped at
                    Harper's Ferry. In it, he discusses camp life and the fear that, if the Union
                    captures Manassas Junction, Harper's Ferry will be completely cut off.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>Look</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>A General Bankrupt Law Proposed</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A petition is circulating in Philadelphia that asks Congress to pass a
                    general act of bankruptcy similar to the one passed following the panic of 1837.
                    The text of the act is included.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>Look</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Tobacco</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Kentucky and other tobacco growing states will gain great advantage by not
                    seceding because they will not have to face the blockade. While the American
                    government doesn't tax tobacco, the European governments place heavy duties upon
                    it and receive a tremendous amount of revenue from tobacco sales.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>An Interesting Table</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spirit reprints a list, drawn from the 1860 census, of the number of
                    white males between the ages of eighteen and forty five who live in the free
                    states, border slave states, seceded states, and territories.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>The Passage of Troops over Railroads</head>
                <origin>Philadelphia Inquirer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A convention of officers of various Pennsylvania railroad companies agreed
                    to make an abatement of 33 percent of the usual charge for carrying troops or
                    provisions of war. However, all the railroads of the state have in their
                    charters a provision that states that troops and munitions of war shall be
                    carried at fifty percent of the usual rate. The editor questions who makes the
                    remaining seventeen percent.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Funeral of Senator Douglas</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Senator Douglas's funeral was held in Chicago and drew a large crowd.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.06.12.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>War Estimates</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Estimates how much the war will cost the government.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Beauregard's Farewell to Charleston</head>
                <origin>Charleston Courier</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Beauregard bids his farewell to Charleston and assures the Carolinians that
                    the South will be victorious.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sowers</ln>
                        <fn>Anna</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sowers</ln>
                        <fn>Hiram</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Anna Sowers died on May 16th at 23 years of age.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Frey</ln>
                        <fn>B. Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Died on June 7th at 28 years of age.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>Edward</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>E.D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Edward Reed died on June 6th at 22 years of age.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.06.12.04">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
