<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1861/pa.fr.vs.1861.06.19">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Colleen Doody</taggerName>
            <tagDate>1/12/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; second pass 5/6/97</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1861-06-19">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="06">June</month>
            <day>19</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>semi-weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.06.19.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Habeas Corpus Case</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Continuation of the opinion of the Chief Justice in the case of John
                    Meryman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Last Hours of Senator Douglas</head>
                <origin>Chicago Herald</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A description of Douglas's last hours, during which time he refused last
                    rites and left a final message for his children to obey the Constitution and the
                    laws of the land.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Jeff Davis to the Maryland Commissioners</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter from Jefferson Davis to the Maryland Commission in which he rejects
                    the suggestion that there be a general cessation of hostilities until Congress
                    can meet and negotiate a peaceful solution. He states that the South desires
                    peace, but that it "is at a loss how to reply without a repetition of the
                    language it has used on every possible occasion that it has presented itself
                    since the establishment of its independence."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>A New Patent Canteen for the Army</head>
                <origin>N.Y. Commercial</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Many of the New York troops have been provided with a new canteen that
                    works better than the old one. This design conforms better to the bottom and can
                    also be used as a coffee and tea pot.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>The Town of Romney</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Romney, Virginia has been thrust into the limelight because of the recent
                    battle fought there. It is in a village on the great Northwestern Virginia
                    turnpike which runs from Winchester to Parkersburg. It is about 35 to 40 miles
                    west of Winchester.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Positive Evacuation of Harper's Ferry</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The rebel forces evacuated their defensive works on the Maryland side near
                    Harper's Ferry and then burned the nearby bridges. They then retreated from
                    Harper's Ferry itself.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>The Western Virginia Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>At the western Virginia Convention, the business committee reported
                    resolutions for adoption that repudiated all allegiance to the Confederacy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Another Exploit on the Eastern Shore</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Major J.S. Morgan, of the thirteenth regiment, Brooklyn, brought his troops
                    to Annapolis. On the way, they were involved in a skirmish and captured 500
                    stand of arms.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Deserters Hung at Harper's Ferry</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Three members of the Boyd Guard were hung at Harper's Ferry for attempting
                    desertion.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Movements Near Washington--The Confederate Forces at Fairfax Court House</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A scouting party that went to Falls Church, Virginia was welcomed by the
                    residents, who want the village occupied by Federal troops. A man who escaped
                    from the rebels stated that there are only 700 men at Fairfax Court House.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>The Army Frauds</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The U.S. Grand Jury at Philadelphia has made a report relating to the army
                    frauds in the state of Pennsylvania. They state that the evidence points to
                    frauds having been perpetrated, but they have been so carefully concealed that
                    the Grand Jury cannot bring any charges. The Governor has, however, appointed
                    incompetent men to run the military departments.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Arrival of Gen. Harney</head>
                <origin>Philadelphia Inquirer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Brigadier General Harney arrived in Philadelphia from St. Louis.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.06.19.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Army Movements</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>All the soldiers that had been encamped in Chambersburg have left. The
                    Headquarters of the Generals has been shifted in Hagerstown. The rebels' retreat
                    from Harper's Ferry disappointed the Union troops and led to a change in Union
                    plans. In addition, it appears that a battle occurred at Falling Waters between
                    the troops under Gen. Cadwallader and the Virginia forces.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Letter from Camp Curtin</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The McClure Rifles arrived safely at Harrisburg and marched directly to
                    Camp Curtin. They haven't yet received their uniforms. Capt. Reilly "is
                    determined never to let his company be disbanded while there exists a single ray
                    of hope to get it into active service."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>Look</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>An Item for Business Men</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spirit encourages merchants to continue to advertise, even though the
                    economy is troubled and consumers are panic-stricken.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Bridge Burners</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Southern troops from Leesburg burnt four bridges on the Alexandria, Loudon,
                    and Hampshire Railroad.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Harrisburg cotton factory will be closed for a few days, which will
                    throw 300 hands out of work. The mill is shut because cotton is in short supply.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Pirates on the Chesapeake--Philadelphia Vessels Captured</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A privateer boarded four unarmed schooners in the Chesapeake, lowered the
                    Stars and Stripes, and trampled it underfoot.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Affairs in New Orleans</head>
                <origin>New Orleans Delta</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Discussion of economic conditions in New Orleans. Business has slowed
                    greatly and prices have increased.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>Look</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Beauregard on Capt. Ball's Comp'y</head>
                <origin>Washington Star</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Capt. Ball and his company, who were recently prisoners, have been ordered
                    to leave Virginia because they took an oath of allegiance to the Union. This
                    oath was a condition of their release. General Beauregard criticized them for
                    taking their oath, insisting that they should have remained prisoners to "induce
                    the Government to regard disunionists captured in arms against the United States
                    as prisoners of war."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Lieut. Siemmer</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lieut. Siemmer and his wife returned to Philadelphia. His wife's patriotism
                    and devotion at the time of the rebel attempt to seize Fort Pickens attracted
                    the admiration of the country. He is in poor health.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Senator Douglas's Successor</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Governor of Illinois appointed Orville H. Browning to fill the seat of
                    Senator Douglas. He was a Whig candidate for Congress. The Spirit is
                    disappointed that a Douglas Democrat wasn't appointed as a sign that "there is
                    no party now."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spirit is critical of the "rage for relics of departed heroes." The
                    flag which Col. Ellsworth seized before his death has been divided and the
                    pieces carefully preserved.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Important from the South and West</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Gen. Beauregard may be planning on retreating from Manassas Junction now
                    that Harper's Ferry has been abandoned. This would allow him to reinforce lines
                    near Fredericksburg or Warrenton Junction, which would be much more difficult to
                    attack.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Plan for a Western Attack on Richmond</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A semi-official source has told the Spirit that a plan exists for a western
                    attack on Richmond. Men would be brought from Ohio, Indiana, and the
                    Northwestern states and would arrive in Richmond by July 1st.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>The Latest from Fortress Monroe</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Miscellaneous news from Fortress Monroe.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>From Washington</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The rebel retreat from Harper's Ferry has greatly increased interest in
                    what the rebels will do next. All attention is being directed at Manassas
                    Junction.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>From Harper's Ferry</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>One messenger recently arrived from Harper's Ferry states that it is
                    deserted of all military. Another messenger states that a large body of men are
                    still there, stationed at Bolivar on the outskirts.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>All the Baltimore and Ohio Railroad buildings in Harper's Ferry were
                    burned. The bridge over the Potomac had been damaged, but the bridge over the
                    Shenandoah was still standing. The main body of the rebel troops that left
                    Harper's Ferry has gone to Winchester while a smaller group has gone to join
                    Henry Wise at Romney.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>From Point of Rocks</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The obstructions on the Baltimore and Ohio railroad at Point of Rocks have
                    been removed and the road to Harper's Ferry has been reopened.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>A Privateer Captured</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>The schooner Savannah, a privateer, arrived in New York with the Stars and
                    Stripes flying in triumph.</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary/>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Chambersburg Markets in column 6.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.06.19.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Virginia Plan of the Campaign</head>
                <origin>New Orleans True Delta</origin>
                <commentary>The Delta "has a very interesting letter from its special correspondent
                    at Richmond. Though reaching us in such a round-about way, it is nearly as late
                    as anything from newspapers sources which we have direct from Virginia. It is
                    certainly as important, and reads as though it were reliable."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Confederate army appears to have undergone a change in strategy. All
                    eyes are turned toward Manassas Junction. Some Southerners believe that
                    Alexandria was a feint to make important movements at Norfolk, Yorktown, or
                    Aquia Creek. General Lee, however, believes that there will be a great battle at
                    Manassas Junction.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>Look</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Grumbling at the South</head>
                <origin>Charleston Mercury</origin>
                <commentary>"Grumbling at the dilatoriness of military movements is not altogether
                    confined to the North. The Charleston Mercury, of the 2nd inst., is in a bad
                    way, and feels itself highly aggrieved by the Fabian policy of the Confederate
                    leaders."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Mercury criticizes the defensive strategy of the Confederate army. They
                    ask why more men weren't stationed at Alexandria and why more aren't at Manassas
                    now. They wonder if a third of the volunteers have been accepted into the army
                    and assert that a large army could drive every Yankee across the Pennsylvania
                    line.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>Look</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"How very consistent it is in the Republican Journals to doubt the fidelity
                    of men who have, all their lives, been Union men, and at the same time applaud
                    the appointments of Corwin Burlingame, Banks, and others, men who have been
                    praying for a dissolution of the Union for the last quarter of a century.
                    Consistent, we say!"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.06.19.04">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
