<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1861/pa.fr.vs.1861.05.25">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Colleen Doody</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1861-05-25">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day>25</day>
            <weekday id="SAT">Saturday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>semi-weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.05.25.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>From Washington</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The President and the Cabinet were present at a flag-raising ceremony at
                    the General Post-office Building. The President's raising of the flag met with
                    an enthusiastic cheer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>From the South</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A dispatch from Raleigh, N.C. states that the North Carolina convention
                    agreed to an ordinance of secession.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>From Baltimore</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"It is rumored that more arms are to be seized in the city."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Camp Located</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"Governor Curtin has located a camp at Farmers' and Merchants' Institute
                    grounds at this place. Four regiments are to encamp there and ten or twelve
                    companies are expected from Philadelphia during the week."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Supplies for Fortress Monroe</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"The steamer Bowman sailed today, for Old Point Comfort, with 10,000 feet
                    of lumber and a large quantity of hay and small stores."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Military Operations of the Government</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The rumors that the Union army will advance upon Virginia are not true.
                    General Scott won't give the order to move until the army is fully organized,
                    drilled, and equipped. The pro-Union voices in Tennessee continue to be heard,
                    but the government cannot take any action yet. The federal government will soon
                    gain control over Northern Missouri.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Secretary Seward's Soiree</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Secretary Seward held a successful soiree in honor of the officers of the
                    volunteer regiments.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Reported Secession Outrages in Indiana</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Three hundred secessionists in Indiana, led by a man named Dromgale, were
                    committing depredations against Unionists. However, a subsequent report
                    indicates that the men were actually a "band of desperados who have been
                    plundering and threatening the lives of the citizens."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Our Relations with Foreign Powers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The federal government has decided that "Any act of intervention which
                    affords direct advantage to the insurgent States, and which tends to hamper or
                    obstruct the action of our government will lead to the most decisive measures on
                    the part of the administration."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>The Funeral Ceremonies of Colonel Vosburgh</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The funeral ceremonies of Colonel Vosburgh commenced at twelve o'clock at
                    the Navy Yard in Washington. The President and members of the Cabinet were in
                    attendance.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Affairs in the Neighborhood of Harper's Ferry</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Report from inside the Confederate lines at Harper's Ferry--"The main
                    movement from Harper's Ferry on southern Pennsylvania will be made as soon as
                    offensive operations begin from Washington on South, or at Norfolk, along the
                    country road leading from Harper's Ferry along Pleasant Valley, through
                    Rohreraville, Boonesboro, and Waynesboro."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Reports from Baltimore</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The government seized a large cache of arms in Baltimore.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Movement of Troops</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"Two reconnaissances pushed southward from this point [Chambersburg]
                    yesterday. There is a report to-day that they penetrated the lines of the
                    confederate army and went deliberately through their camps."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>Look</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Secession of North Carolina</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>North Carolina has passed the ordinance of secession.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Arrival of Another Prize at Philadelphia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Niagara was captured while attempting to run the blockade. The ship is
                    believed to carry arms and munitions. The captain denied knowing anything about
                    the blockade or about the display of secession flags.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>The Firemen Zouaves--Acceptance of Com. Bartlett's Naval Brigade</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Firemen Zouaves were sworn in for the war by Brigadier General
                    McDowell. A deserter from Alexandria appeared in the Zouave camp and gave an
                    unfavorable account of conditions in the rebel camps.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Large Speculation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spirit notes that George Law has received a contract from the
                    government to supply the army with "twenty thousand beeves at eight cents per
                    pound, live weight." The contractors will realize a profit of $600,000. The
                    paper complains that "A few individuals are making princely fortunes at the
                    expense of the tax-payers of the country."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.05.25.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Military Visitor</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"Lieut. George Stitzel, of Company A, 2nd Regiment, is now on a visit to
                    his friends at this place. He was received with hearty greetings by his many
                    friends."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Law of Postage</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"The postage law is silent in reference to charging postage on semi-weekly
                    paper circulated in the county. Post Masters will, therefore, be good enough to
                    wait for the decision of the Postmaster General before taking any action on the
                    matter."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Eighth Regiment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The eighth regiment from Camp Slifer paraded through the streets of
                    Chambersburg, which "highly gratified" the citizens.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Broken Up</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The companies stationed at the Western Camp were dissolved and the men
                    returned to their homes. Some men have remained in camp in the hope that a
                    regiment for three years service can be recruited.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Other Side</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The New York Board of Aldermen has decided not to take the corporation
                    printing from the Day Book and Daily News and give it to the Lincoln papers. The
                    N.Y. Tribune, which "would monopolize all the pickings without doing any of the
                    fighting," is upset about this decision.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Ignoring Party</head>
                <origin>Holidaysburg Standard</origin>
                <commentary>The following is "rather a severe rebuke to those who are laboring to
                    vanish the Democratic party into thin air."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Criticizes the Republicans, who called for all Unionists to bury party, but
                    who have appointed their own men to high positions in the volunteer regiments
                    while ignoring more qualified Democrats.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Editorial Visit</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An editor from the Luzerne Union paid a visit to Camp Slifer and wrote that
                    Chambersburg, while only 15 miles away from Maryland, is "as strongly attached
                    to the Union as any people in the State. I must not omit to mention that
                    Chambersburg has a history in connection with the later stages of the slavery
                    excitement, that her citizens rarely allude to. It is said that here the
                    notorious John Brown first saw the light, while it is certain that he made it
                    the rendezvous of his conspirators previous to their attack upon Harper's
                    Ferry."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>Look</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Democratic Union Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A meeting of the Democratic Party of Luzerne county was held at
                    Wilkes-Barre on May 18th. There they passed resolutions that "have the ring of
                    the true metal and express in admirable terms, the sentiments of the Democracy
                    all over the country." In the resolutions, they vow to oppose both secessionists
                    and abolitionists while vigorously supporting President Lincoln in his battle to
                    protect the flag and the government.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>Look</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>"Knapsacks for Democrats"</head>
                <origin>Philadelphia Inquirer</origin>
                <commentary>"The fact is forcing itself upon the minds of all . . . that the
                    Democratic party is furnishing the bulk of the fighting element of the North."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Inquirer, a Republican paper, states that the men who opposed Lincoln
                    and the Republicans "are now found among the foremost in defense of the
                    government. . . They regard the exigency of the times as a paramount to partisan
                    distinctions."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>Look</look>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Army Correspondence--Letter from Camp Scott</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter from J.S.K. which states that many men in camp are sick. They remain
                    at Camp Scott, stuck in the mud. The men are all very religious and attend
                    services in the forenoon and afternoon on Sunday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>Look</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Georgia Folks</head>
                <origin>Southern Federal Union, Milledgeville, GA</origin>
                <commentary>"This is the kind of food Southern asperity is nourished with"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"The leading papers of the Lincoln party at the North declare that the
                    people of the South shall be butchered like dogs, and their property divided out
                    among the soldiers who fight for Lincoln."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>An Important Law</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"An act relative to Hucksters in the Counties of Berks and Franklin"
                    requires anyone who buys produce in Berks or Franklin counties with the intent
                    of selling it in another county to buy a license.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>The Point of Honor</head>
                <origin>National Intelligencer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter from James Buchanan in which he states that a military oath is
                    sacred. The men who took that oath swore to support the United States, not the
                    Constitution of their respective states.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Important Movement on the Part of the Government</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The federal government has seized all telegraphic dispatches which have
                    passed through the Northern states for the last twelve months. It is believed
                    that these will show that Jefferson Davis had an army of spies in New York and
                    elsewhere in the North.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>The Proposed State of New Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>States that New Virginia has abundant natural resources and predicts that
                    it will be a "new centre of emigration, enterprise and development astonishing
                    to Old Virginia."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Precautions--Hints to Farmers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges farmers to grow staple crops that are consumed by soldiers,
                    especially beans, peas, wheat, and cattle.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>The Latest--Southern War Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Southern troops are pouring into Virginia from Tennessee.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>From Fortress Monroe</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Gen. Butler and staff arrived at Fortress Monroe. It is understood that the
                    U.S. steamer Minnesota was to make an attack on the battery at Sewall's Point.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>From Washington</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The voting in Alexandria occurred on May 23rd. No one dares vote for the
                    Union since there are thousands of rebel troops stationed there. Lincoln stated
                    that there would be no invasion of the South before the autumn, when the army
                    would be well conditioned and supplied.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Allotment of Troops</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>List of the number of volunteer companies allotted to each Pennsylvania
                    county.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.05.25.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The English Press on the War</head>
                <origin>London Times</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Discussion of the rights of neutrals to trade with belligerents.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Commissioners from the Confederate States in London--Reported Interview
                    with Lord John Russell</head>
                <origin>Manchester Guardian</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Americans in London are generally convinced that the North will ultimately
                    triumph, but the South will have some initial success.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Gold from California for London</head>
                <origin>London Times</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"It is stated that policies of insurance are now being opened here for
                    $1,000,000 of California bullion from Panama to London, these consignments being
                    diverted from New York in consequence of the peril of captors."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Jefferson Davis' Letters of Marque in England</head>
                <origin>London Economist</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Because the South has no navy, they have issued letters of marque, which
                    "empower any individual to fit out a privateer with which he can annoy the
                    mercantile navy and in some small measure carry on a maritime war with the
                    North." These privateers have had an immediate effect on Northern ships.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Effect of the Blockade on Ship Charters Made in England</head>
                <origin>Shipping and Mercantile Gazette</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Discussion of what a British ship that has a charter to sail to a Southern
                    port should do when faced with the blockade.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Excitement in Paris on Account of the War</head>
                <origin>London Times</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The French are worried that their supply of cotton will be curtailed and
                    that the American market will be closed to French products.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.05.25.04">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
