<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1861/pa.fr.vs.1861.01.16">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Brian Erb</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1861-01-16">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day>16</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.01.16.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Character and Influence of Abolitionism</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Sermon from a Presbyterian Church in New York asserts that abolitionism has
                    no foundation in Scripture. Sermon occupies entire page and is continued on page
                    8. Bottom and right partially illegible.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.01.16.02">
            <pageNote>Poetry, fiction and anecdotes</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.01.16.03">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.01.16.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>News of the Week</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports the continued intransigence of Congress with regard to a compromise
                    solution to the secession crises. Item also reports results of secession crisis
                    in the seceded states.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Poverty of the South</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"A few weeks ago we published an editorial article with a view of removing
                    from the Northern mind the erroneous impressions which Republican papers and
                    orators have created in regard to the value of the South to the Union. The
                    poverty of the South is the tune that Northern Republican politicians are
                    everlastingly piping until it has became [sic] as vapid as the one 'the old cow
                    died on.'"</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A few weeks ago we published an editorial article with a view of removing
                        from the Northern mind the erroneous impressions which Republican papers and
                        orators have created in regard to the value of the South to the Union. The
                        poverty of the South is the tune that Northern Republican politicians are
                        everlastingly piping until it has became [sic] as vapid as the one "the old
                        cow died on." In their zeal for the cause of sectionalism they are ever
                        swaggering and boasting of the superiority of the North over the South, and
                        would fain make people believe that the South <emph rend="italic"
                        >grows</emph> nothing but "niggers," that they consume more than they
                        produce and have long ago eaten their masters out of house and lands, and
                        that the South is only kept up by the alms bestowed upon it by the North.
                        There are many sap-heads in the community who really believe all this. They
                        never examine for themselves but make up their opinions from the twaddle of
                        some abolition scribbler who would prepare their minds for a second John
                        Brown raid on the South. If they can only make it appear that our brethren
                        of the South are debased and in poverty they think they have performed a
                        noble deed; or if they can assist, in any way, in stealing a negro from them
                        their happiness is complete. What advantage, we would ask, can any one in
                        the North derive from engendering such unfraternal feelings? Does it make
                        the North happier or more prosperous? Must the business of the country be
                        destroyed--must the Union be dissolved--rather than give up the
                        gratification the North seems to find in heaping insult and injury on the
                        South? Tis is all wrong--wrong to the North as well as the South--and yet it
                        is the course pursued by the Republican party aided now and then by some
                        scion of Democracy whose political principles have been corrupted by reading
                        the New York <emph rend="italic">Tribune</emph> and kindred prints. The
                        Union Meetings held over the country show that the business men, who are the
                        men that get them up, understand their interest and know the fallacy of the
                        doctrines disseminated against the South by the abolitionists and their
                        aiders and abettors in the Democratic party. The business men know the
                        wealth and resources of the South and they know too that the North will be
                        the gainer by keeping a [sic] up reciprocal trade between these two portions
                        of our country.--Had they the settlement of the difficulties in their hands
                        they would not only save the Union but restore peace, happiness and
                        prosperity, to the whole country before the end of another week. This,
                        unfortunately for the country, the Republican party will not permit. The
                        crazy whims of fanatics and the clap-trap of politicians have obtained
                        ascendancy in the North and it will not budge an inch to save the business
                        of the country from ruin and the Union itself from dissolution. These are
                        the disunionists-- this the true disunion party. It is their
                        unconstitutional laws against the rights of the South, and their malignant
                        abuse of her people and their institutions, that have brought this trouble
                        on the country, and they would still go further and involve the nation in
                        war if they thought they could thereby do the South additional injury.</p>
                    <p>A writer of this class over the signature of "J"--the N accidentally
                        omitted--undertakes to show, in one of our town papers, that the little
                        belligerent State of South Carolina is not equal to the great State of
                        Pennsylvania which he admits is "<emph rend="italic">the first State in the
                            Union.</emph>" After a laborious effort at figure-work he makes known
                        the result, which nobody ever questioned, that "<emph rend="italic">the
                            resources of South Carolina cannot compare with our State!</emph>" This
                        is as fine a specimen of the "mountain in labor bringing forth a mouse" as
                        mental imbecility ever attempted. Having made this axiom in statistics
                            "<emph rend="italic">clearly evident</emph>" he should next demonstrate
                        that it was Jonah that swallowed the whale and not the whale that swallowed
                        Jonah. This proposition would be on a par with the one he has made so "<emph
                            rend="italic">clearly evident</emph>," and by the same wonderful process
                        of reasoning, he has so creditably displayed, he could, no doubt, as "<emph
                            rend="italic">clearly</emph>" demonstrate the one as the other. We would
                        not have felt ourselves called upon to take any notice of this "J" hawking
                        raid upon the South had we found it in a Republican journal. That would have
                        been its natural element and it might have foundered there, with all its
                        ridiculous blunders and misrepresentations undisturbed by us. But its
                        appearance in a paper making some slight pretensions to being Democratic
                        demands of us to apply the antidote to the poison intended to be infused
                        into the public mind. For the purpose of crying down the South, or
                        displaying his own ignorance, (we hardly know which, as he does not even do
                        Pennsylvania justice in the amount of her products) this abolition Democrat
                        jumbles up a mass of statistics and arrives at the conclusion that South
                        Carolina is "<emph rend="italic">four times</emph>" behind Pennsylvania and
                        therefore she is of no consequence to the Union. This doctrine will sound
                        new and strange to the Democracy of Franklin county and must diminish
                        confidence, if less were possible, in the source from whence it emanates.
                        Let us examine a few of his blunders--we do no intend taking up all of them
                        as the whole article is a tissue of stupid blunders from beginning to end,
                        and would be a disgrace to the merest tiro in arithmetic. He starts out by
                        making it appear that South Carolina is larger then Pennsylvania by giving
                        the number of acres of improved and unimproved land <emph rend="italic">in
                            farms</emph>. This is done evidently for the purpose of deception--to
                        create the impression that South Carolina is greater in territory than
                        Pennsylvania and therefore ought to equal her in products. Now any school
                        boy could have informed him that Pennsylvania is nearly twice as large as
                        South Carolina. In extent of territory Pennsylvania has 47,000 square miles
                        while South Carolina has but 28,000. In the number of acres of improved land
                        Pennsylvania more then doubles South Carolina--the former being set down at
                        8,628,619 acres and the latter at 4,072,651 acres. Is it fair is it honest
                        to offset the total "cash value of farms" in Pennsylvania against those of
                        South Carolina? This astute dealer in statistics next takes up the live
                        stock and displays about as much intelligence as the horses and mules he is
                        writing about. He values the horses and mules of Pennsylvania at $352,657,
                        when it would, perhaps, not be far short of their value to rate them at an
                        hundred times that amount. He commits the same ridiculous blunder, by taking
                        the <emph rend="italic">number</emph> of horses, &amp; c., in the State
                        for their <emph rend="italic">value</emph>, with the live stock of South
                        Carolina. He puts down the value of Oats raised in Pennsylvania at $646,144
                        and that of South Carolina 999,646 [sic] while South Carolina raises only a
                        little over two million of bushels and Pennsylvania over twenty-one million.
                        This is arithmetic with a vengeance! We might suppose this to be a
                        typographical error did not every item in the statement exhibit the same
                        stupidity. The next blunder we shall notice is one that was evidently made
                        willfully. He puts down the quantity of Sugar made in South Carolina 77
                        hogsheads when the statistics of that State show it to be 671 hogheads of
                        1000 pounds each. He commits a like error in relation to the Cotton of that
                        State by valuing it a $36 a bale of 400 pounds. We hope this valuation will
                        not create a panic in the Cotton market. Lincoln prices are low enough in
                        all conscience without pretended Democrats striving to bring them down
                        lower. Notwithstanding the low price of everything we find Cotton quoted, at
                        Charleston and New Orleans, last week, at 13 cents a pound, making the price
                        of a bale of Cotton $52 instead of $36. We might go on pointing out blunders
                            <emph rend="italic">ad nauseam</emph>, but the above will suffice to
                        show the bungling character of the whole article, and relieve us from giving
                        it the importance of a more extended notice.</p>
                    <p>In our recent article on the South we undertook to show that, in a business
                        point of view, it was important for the North to preserve the Union and
                        re-establish friendly business relations with the South. We presented a few
                        statistics to show that the Southern States were not as poverty-stricken as
                        was generally represented in the North, and not likely to starve if they
                        left the Union. We made no comparison with the view of showing that Southern
                        were superior to Northern States. We only desired to exhibit their wealth
                        and prosperity in a proper light by taking the great and flourishing State
                        of Pennsylvania as a standard for comparison. Our article will admit of no
                        other construction being placed upon it and why it should have exercised any
                        Democrat so much is not an easy matter to explain.</p>
                    <p>Let us, for the mere purpose of seeing how it looks, follow the example of
                        this abolition scribbler, which we admit is a bad one, and institute a
                        comparison between the leading Agricultural products, and Domestic
                        Manufactures, of South Carolina and Pennsylvania--keeping in mind that South
                        Carolina is one half smaller than Pennsylvania--and how do they foot up:</p>
                    <p>Pennsylvania.</p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Wheat 15,867,691 bushels at $1.00 a bushel</cell>
                            <cell>$15,867,691</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Corn 19,835,214 bushels at 50 cents a bushel</cell>
                            <cell>$9,917,607</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Oats 21,538,156 bushels at 30 cents a bushel</cell>
                            <cell>$6,461,446</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Potatoes Sweet 52,172 bushels at 60 cents a bushel</cell>
                            <cell>$81,803</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Potatoes Irish 5,980,732 bushels at 40 cents a bushel</cell>
                            <cell>$2,392,202</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Beans 55,231 bushels at 80 cents a bushel</cell>
                            <cell>$44,184</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Sugar 2,326,525 pounds at 10cents a pound</cell>
                            <cell>$232,652</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Domestic Manufactures - value of</cell>
                            <cell>$749,182</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>$35,196,307</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <p>South Carolina.</p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Wheat 1,066,277 bushels at $1.00 a bushel</cell>
                            <cell>$1,066,277</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Corn 16,271,454 bushels at 50 cents a bushel</cell>
                            <cell>$8,133,727</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Oats 2,322,155 bushels at 30 cents a bushel</cell>
                            <cell>$696,646</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Potatoes Sweet 4,337,469 bushels at 60 cents a bushel</cell>
                            <cell>$2,602,481</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Potatoes Irish 136,494 bushels at 40 cents a bushel</cell>
                            <cell>$54,597</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Beans 1,026,900 bushels at 80 cents a bushel</cell>
                            <cell>$821,520</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Rice 159,930,613 pounds at 5 cents a pound</cell>
                            <cell>$7,996,530</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Cotton 300,901 bales, of 400 lbs each, at 13 cents a pound</cell>
                            <cell>$15,646,852</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Sugar 671 hogsheads, of 1000 lbs each, at10 cents a pound</cell>
                            <cell>$67,100</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Domestic Manufactures - value of</cell>
                            <cell>$909,520</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>$37,987,250</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <p>In the above estimate we quote Sugar at 10 cents a pound. We are well aware
                        it is too high, but it is the price fixed upon it for Pennsylvania Sugar by
                        "J" and we give him the benefit of his Pennsylvania rates--what is sauce for
                        the goose is sauce for the gander. The other prices are also his, blunders
                        corrected. If we throw into the account the Iron of Pennsylvania her great
                        boast--estimated by "J" at $2,372,467, we still have a balance on the above
                        items in favor of South Carolina of $418,476. When we add to this her
                        exports, which are the wealth of a State--South Carolina exporting
                        $15,316,578 and Pennsylvania only $4,148,261--we find she is not so useless
                        in the Union as some abolition Democrats would try to make us believe. How
                        much better it would be to preserve our business and social relations with
                        her than to underrate her wealth and her worth and strive to drive her out
                        of the Union.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Ridicules the attempt by the Republicans to make the South appear poor and
                    weak. The article blames Republicans for precipitating the crisis by their
                    unwillingness to compromise. Article goes through column 4.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/jan61.html#1.16a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Admirers of Jackson</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Accuses current admirers of Andrew Jackson of hypocrisy, and asserts that
                    during his term the Federalists, who are now Republicans, denounced him.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Events at the South</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Asserts that while the South has legitimate grievances with the North that
                    deserve to be addressed, the problem of Federal forts on Southern property must
                    be resolved, for the forts are the legitimate property of the Union and must be
                    maintained as such. Item maintains that the President cannot relinquish the
                    forts without congressional permission.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Raven is Still Sitting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Accuses the congressional Republicans of intransigence on the secession
                    crisis.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.01.16.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The President's Message</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Buchanan expresses, among other things, his intention to enforce the
                    Constitution, taking no powers not delegated to him and fulfilling the duties of
                    his office.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Resignation of Secretary Thompson</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter from Secretary Thompson to James Buchanan announcing his
                    resignation. Also a letter from Buchanan accepting Thompson's resignation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Colestock</ln>
                        <fn>Z.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Isaac</ln>
                        <fn>Allison</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Diehl</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on January 10.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pike</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>17 month old Henry Pike died on January 13th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>The page includes advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.01.16.06">
            <pageNote>The page includes advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.01.16.07">
            <pageNote>The page includes advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.01.16.08">
            <pageNote>The sermon from the front page is continued on page 8. The remainder of page 8
                consists of advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
