<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1861/pa.fr.vs.1861.03.13">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Brian Erb</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1861-03-13">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day>13</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.03.13.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Inaugural Address of Mr. Lincoln</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"A resolve to procrastinate before committing himself is apparent
                    throughout."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Criticizes Lincoln's inaugural for being vague and dodging the necessity of
                    voicing a policy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Inauguration of Abraham Lincoln as President of the United States</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The Chief Justice (Taney) seemed very agitated and his hands shook
                    perceptibly with emotion."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Recounts the festivities of Lincoln's inauguration.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Question of Peace or War Brought to the Test</head>
                <origin>New York Herald</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"A plain and direct answer must be given to a plain question, which only
                    requires a 'yes' or 'no'."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>States that Lincoln's address failed to clarify the nation's future course
                    but has instead only added "smoke to the fog."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Important from Washington</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Lincoln is in favor of Seward's suggestion to appoint
                    Crittenden to the Supreme Court, but he does not want to draw the criticism of
                    the radical wing of his party.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Column 1 poetry. Bottom illegible.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.03.13.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The designs of Redpath, John Brown, Jr., and Fred Douglas, etc.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Alleges that Northern abolitionists are conspiring to consummate a war upon
                    the South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Poetry and fiction</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.03.13.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Mr. Lincoln's Whiskers and the Girls</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Accuses Lincoln of crass and frivolous behavior.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.03.13.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>News of the Week</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Includes many items of national news, including reaction to the Inaugural,
                    political maneuverings, news from Sumter, and news from the Southern states.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Our Turnpikes</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Our citizens are taxed heavily enough already without having this
                    additional load imposed upon them for the benefit of a few individuals who have
                    bought up nearly all the stock of the turnpike companies at a very low figure."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In our last issue we published an act recently passed relative to the
                        Turnpikes in our borough, with some comments, that we deemed appropriate,
                        thereon. Since then the <emph rend="italic">Times</emph> which professes so
                        much regard for tax payers has taken up its bludgeon in favor of the
                        Companies, and thinks that what has been done is about right, and that our
                        citizens ought to be taxed for the benefit of the stock-holders in the
                        Turnpike companies.</p>
                    <p>On a more thorough examination of this matter we are more firmly convinced
                        than ever that the course of those who got up and passed this bill, is
                        wholly indefensible and unjustifiable. It was not printed in either branch
                        of the Legislature- -no copies of it were sent to our borough authorities or
                        any citizen of the place--nor were the people, whose rights are invaded by
                        this bill, informed in any manner in relation to it, or given any chance to
                        remonstrate against it.</p>
                    <p>The principal argument, (if it may be dignified with the name of argument,)
                        used by the <emph rend="italic">few interested</emph> in the bill, is that
                        the Turnpike companies are only bound by their charters to make their roads
                            <emph rend="italic">to the borough line</emph> and not to <emph
                            rend="italic">the centre of the borough</emph>. If they are not bound to
                        make their roads to the centre of the diamond, and have a <emph
                            rend="italic">right</emph> to stop at the borough line, why was it
                        necessary to get an act of Assembly authorizing them to abandon those parts
                        of their roads in the borough limits. And besides this, our borough limits
                        have been extended very considerable since the turnpikes were constructed,
                        and who then is to make the roads between the old and new borough lines? The
                        tax-payers of the borough, <emph rend="italic">of course</emph>, and that is
                        the object of the passage of this bill. Our citizens are taxed heavily
                        enough already without having this additional load imposed upon them for the
                        benefit of a few individuals who have bought up nearly all the stock of the
                        turnpike companies at a very low figure.</p>
                    <p>In early times the Legislature of the State felt very anxious to open up the
                        country, and cause its speedy settlement. One of the medes adopted for this
                        purpose was the building of <emph rend="italic">Turnpikes</emph>, and to all
                        such enterprises the State contributed liberally by taking stock.</p>
                    <p>On the 24th of February, 1806 an act was passed for the building of a
                        Turnpike road <emph rend="italic">from Harrisburg, through Carlisle,
                            Chambersburg, Bedford, &amp;c. to Pittsburgh</emph>. The road was to
                        be <emph rend="italic">piked</emph> 22 feet wide with stone, gravel, or some
                        other proper substance and <emph rend="italic">permanent</emph> bridges were
                        to be erected over all streams.</p>
                    <p>On the 31st of March, 1807, a Supplement to the above act was passed, which
                        says--"That for the purpose of making an artificial or Turnpike road <emph
                            rend="italic">from Harrisburg to Pittsburgh through</emph> Carlisle,
                        Chambersburg, Bedford, &amp;c., six companies may be incorporated--one
                        to make that part of the road in <emph rend="italic">Cumberland
                        county</emph>--one, <emph rend="italic">that in Franklin</emph>--one, that
                        in Bedford--one, that in Somerset--one, that in Westmoreland--and one that
                        in Allegheny. The State subscribed largely to the stock of each of these
                        companies, but the roads were not made because of the smallness of the
                        individual subscriptions. The <emph rend="italic">great object</emph> in
                        view evidently was a <emph rend="italic">continuous road</emph> from
                        Harrisburg to Pittsburgh.</p>
                    <p>On the 9th of March, 1814, an act <emph rend="italic">Supplementary</emph> to
                        the acts on this subject was passed, the first section of which says "That
                        for the purpose of making a Turnpike FROM HARRISBURG TO PITTSBURGH"--5
                        companies may be incorporated, viz.: One to make the road from Harrisburg to
                        Chambersburg--one from Chambersburg to Bedford, and so on. This is the act
                        under which the roads were made, and the act under which they have been kept
                        up for almost half a century, but it is now revealed for the first time that
                        because the acts read from <emph rend="italic">Harrisburg to
                        Chambersburg</emph> and from <emph rend="italic">Chambersburg to
                        Bedford</emph> that, therefore, these companies are not bound to make their
                        roads further than our borough lines! That this is the true construction of
                        the law no one, we presume, will make himself so ridiculous as to attempt
                        seriously to argue. The <emph rend="italic">builders</emph> of the road
                        constructed the act to mean the centre of the town, but the <emph
                            rend="italic">repairers</emph>, more wise than they, have pretended to
                        discover at this late day that it means the borough lines, although the act
                        says not one word about borough lines, but provides expressly for "<emph
                            rend="italic">a turnpike from Harrisburg to Pittsburgh</emph>."</p>
                    <p>The Legislature of the State wanted a road from Harrisburg to Pittsburgh.
                        They first chartered <emph rend="italic">one</emph> company to make it. That
                        failed. They then authorized one for each county, under which the road would
                        have been made "<emph rend="italic">through</emph>" the whole length of our
                        town. That failed also. They then passed the act of 1814, under which the
                        roads were made, which provides for a road the whole distance <emph
                            rend="italic">from Harrisburg to Pittsburgh</emph>. How could that road
                        be made <emph rend="italic">continuously</emph>, if any company was to stop
                        short of a point that would connect its road with the next. Besides the 3d,
                        4th, 5th, 6th and 7th sections of the act of 1814, when providing for the
                        organization of the 5 companies, says of each that it shall have the <emph
                            rend="italic">powers and be subject to the duties</emph> of the Company
                        of 1806, among which was the making of a <emph rend="italic"
                        >continuous</emph> road, as stated, <emph rend="italic">through</emph> the
                        borough of Chambersburg, &amp;c.</p>
                    <p>These several companies put their own construction on this law by commencing
                        their roads <emph rend="italic">at the centre of our diamond</emph>,
                        exacting toll, putting up milestones measuring from the centre of town, and
                        keeping those portions of their roads in repair for nearly fifty years past.
                        They now want to palm them on the borough and have had an act quietly passed
                        through our Legislature for that purpose. Will our citizens stand it? Will
                        they tamely submit to being burdened with this extra load of taxation
                        without raising a finger, or uttering a word against the iniquitous act and
                        those who have been instrumental in having it passed?</p>
                    <p>We find on examination that the road from Harrisburg to this place cost $234,
                        479, of which the State paid $106, 202 53--and individuals $75,5 55. The
                        road from here to Bedford cost, if we are rightly informed, something over
                        $300, 000--of which the State paid $216, 056 72. Thus near $325, 000 of the
                        peoples money was contributed to build these roads--and the stock has since
                        gone into the coffers of the companies, or into private hands, at about
                            <emph rend="italic">one dollar for fifty</emph> originally paid, and yet
                        after getting this much from the public, these grasping corporations want to
                        compel that public to keep up their roads!</p>
                    <p>The latest argument we have heard advanced to justify the passage of this act
                        is that the Stone bridge over the Conococheague Creek was not built by the
                        company-- that it is a <emph rend="italic">county</emph> bridge built in
                        1810 or 12. This may be so. We have not hunted up the facts in the case. If
                        it be true then it is the more shame for the turnpike company, that after
                        using the bridge for almost fifty years to now refuse to keep it up. If the
                        bridge was built by the county it was just that much expense saved to the
                        Bedford Company. Their report to the Governor in 1820 says that their road
                        is 55 miles and 3 perches long, commencing at the public square in the
                        Borough of Chambersburg and ending in the centre of the Borough of Bedford.
                        They would therefore, be compelled to build a bridge over the Conococheague
                        had they not found one ready for their use. They have ever since used it,
                        and kept it in repair, but now a new order of things is to be introduced and
                        the tax-payers of the borough are expected to acquiesce without a murmur, in
                        this invasion on their rights.</p>
                    <p>We might present many other reasons why this bill should not be allowed to
                        stand as a law but, will only add for the present, that its operation will
                        entail several hundred dollars per year expenses on the borough, and
                        further, there is no other borough on the line of the road, from Harrisburg
                        to Pittsburgh that is required to make their roods. The whole road <emph
                            rend="italic">is</emph> kept up, and <emph rend="italic">must be</emph>
                        kept up by the Turnpike Companies.</p>
                    <p>We will have something more to lay before our readers on this subject, next
                        week, and, perhaps, some curious developments in relation to the management
                        of some of these roads that may prove interesting to a portion of the
                        stock-holders.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>News and opinion regarding the Turnpike act.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/march61.html#3.13a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>An Office Seeker</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that John M. Pumeroy, a former Chambersburg resident, is an
                    applicant for the position of Naval Officer at Philadelphia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Carl Schurz</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Accuses Pennsylvania Republicans of Know-Nothingism in their opposition of
                    Carl Schurz's appointment as Minister Resident to Sardinia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>A Crisis at the "Times"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Alleges that the Times is angry that the Spirit published Lincoln's address
                    first.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Acknowledgments to Ex-Senator Bigler</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Shares Crittenden's praise of Ex-Senator Bigler.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Affairs in Washington</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>News regarding Fort Sumter and office seekers filing applications for
                    office.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Basis of Adjustment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Transcript of the entire series of resolutions adopted by the committee of
                    thirty-three.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>George Washington</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Fortune having thrown me in the favorite county (Augusta Co., VA) of
                    Washington, where he said he could plant the flag of freedom and find an
                    invisible rampart in the noble sons of Western Virginia."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter writer lauds the accomplishments of Washington.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.03.13.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Dental Surgeon</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J.S. Trout received the Degree of Doctor of Dental Surgery.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Donation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McHenry</ln>
                        <fn>B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>B. McHenry wishes to thank his Fayetteville Friends for their valuable
                    donation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Re-Vaccination</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"M. Heminokx has detailed to the Belgian Academy of Medicine the results of
                    the re-vaccinations put into force at the prisons of Ghent and Vilvorde, the
                    subjects together amounted to one thousand and six hundred and sixty."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--M. Heminokx has detailed to the Belgian Academy of Medicine the results of
                        the re-vaccinations put into force at the prisons of Ghent and Vilvorde, the
                        subjects together amounted to one thousand and six hundred and sixty. Of
                        these, three hundred and seventy-nine, or sixteen per cent., were vaccinated
                        with success; there were in seven hundred and sixteen manifest traces of a
                        prior vaccination, and four hundred and seventy one exhibited marks of
                        small-pox. Of the seven hundred and sixteen, sixteen per cent., and of the
                        four hundred and seventy-one, forty six per cent. were vaccinated with
                        success. The author's conclusions, from these and other cases, are as
                        follows:</p>
                    <p>First, the re-vaccination of subjects who have been well vaccinated produces
                        generally but very few useful effects; second, persons who have been the
                        subjects of variola have much more cause to be re-vaccinated than those who
                        have undergone proper vaccination; third, re-vaccination is successful in
                        proportion to the length of time which has elapsed since the first
                        vaccination or the attack of variola; fourth, until the age of twenty-five,
                        it is generally useless; fifth, from that age to thirty-five it gives rise
                        to useful effects in a certain number of individuals, but this number is so
                        extremely small, that without proscribing it in such persons, it need not be
                        recommended to them; sixth, after thirty-five, it becomes a sure
                        preservative, and consequently necessary; seventh, its failure at one period
                        furnishes no reason for not having recourse to it at other epochs, as there
                        is no reason to suppose that the receptivity may not return between the one
                        and the other operation.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Gives information about vaccinations. Article nearly illegible.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/march61.html#3.13b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Who They Are and What They Are</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Gives a brief biographical sketch of each of Lincoln's cabinet members.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>How</ln>
                        <fn>Westly</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flood</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barney</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on February 14th in Shippensburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reichard</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Died on February 16th of scarlet fever, aged 8 years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reichard</ln>
                        <fn>Hannah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Hannah M. Reichard, sister of Sarah, died on February 24th, also of scarlet
                    fever. She was 21 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingerd</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingerd</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary Catharine died on March 10th, aged 2 years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flinder</ln>
                        <fn>Anna Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Died on February 26th, aged 80 years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Senseny</ln>
                        <fn>Jeanette</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Senseny</ln>
                        <fn>A.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Senseny</ln>
                        <fn>Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jeanette died on March 2 of scarlet fever, aged 6 years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.03.13.06">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.03.13.07">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.03.13.08">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>News regarding the secession crisis, including information from the seceded
                    states and the border states.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Blockade of the Southern Ports</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The British government gives notice that it will not respect a blockade of
                    the Southern Ports unless it is made effectual.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>A Detected Insurrection</head>
                <origin>Richmond Enquirer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Richmond Enquirer</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports discovery of an alleged slave insurrection in Acadia County.
                    scarcely legible, including origin and trailer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Repeal of the Tonnage Tax</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports the repeal of the Tonnage Tax.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Pennsylvania Legislature</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Gives the occupational composition of the Pennsylvania Legislature.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
