<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1861/pa.fr.vs.1861.08.03">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Brian Erb</taggerName>
            <tagDate>04/09/61</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 5/13/97</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1861-08-03">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="08">August</month>
            <day norm="03">3</day>
            <weekday id="SAT">Saturday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>semi-weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.08.03.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1-6</column>
                <head>Letter from Gen. Wool</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Military reports in the form of letters and dispatches between military
                    commanders, mostly regarding the loss at Manassas.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.08.03.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Gen. McClellan</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Praises the appointment of Gen. McClellan to be in charge of military
                    affairs at Washington.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The True Union Party</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Let the Democratic party maintain its organization everywhere--stand by
                    the Union--condemn the abominabe [sic] doctrine of Secession, and while
                    upholding the Government in the War, fearlessly condemn the corruptions of the
                    present Administration and its attempts to trample on the Constitution and the
                    rights of the people."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Democratic party has ever maintained the proud position of being the
                        sincere friend of the Union. It has never expressed itself as being in favor
                        of "letting the Union slide." It possesses the same ardent devotion to the
                        Union to-day that it has ever exhibited, and is ready to pour out its best
                        blood in upholding that glorious Union. It is not now, or never, has been, a
                        Union party for the North, or a Union party for the South, but for the WHOLE
                        UNION. For the sake of the Union it has joined hands with its political
                        opponents, to enable the Government to put down rebellion, that the Union
                        may be restored; but in doing this it has not agreed to adopt the principles
                        of the Chicago platform by any means. The Democratic party draws a wide
                        distinction between supporting the Government and sustaining the corruptions
                        of the present Administration, and detests Republican principles now as
                        cordially as it ever did. It holds that the Chicago platform has broken up
                        the Union and that it cannot be restored or maintained by standing on that
                        rickety concern. Let the Democratic party maintain its organization
                        everywhere--stand by the Union--condemn the abominabe [sic] doctrine of
                        Secession, and while upholding the Government in the War, fearlessly condemn
                        the corruptions of the present Administration and its attempts to trample on
                        the Constitution and the rights of the people.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Defends the Democratic party as the true Union party in the North.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The War Tax</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The odious War Tax...does not even meet with the approbation of the
                    Republicans in Congress. The Times is ready to gulp down the abominable measures
                    of Lincoln's Administration that honest Republicans themselves revolt at."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spirit takes the Chambersburg Times to task for its support of the War
                    Tax.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Thanks</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McPherson</ln>
                        <fn>Edward</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnston</ln>
                        <fn>Philip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Spirit thanks McPherson and Johnston for Congressional documents.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Assailants of the Democratic Party</head>
                <origin>Harrisburg Patriot and Union</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Criticizes Republicans and the papers that support them as corrupt.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Jeff Davis's Threats</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter from Jeff Davis to Lincoln requesting an exchange of prisoners and
                    complaining that Southern prisoners are being treated as criminals rather than
                    POWs.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Ultra Press</head>
                <origin>Baltimore American</origin>
                <commentary>"The leading presses thus properly alluded to are the Tribune, the
                    Times, and the Independent. Unable to rule, they are, as always, ready to ruin."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Alleges that ultra-Republican papers of the North are fueling the flames of
                    war as much as the secessionist papers of the South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>A Republican Member . . .</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"All abolitionists ought to have a halter slipped around their necks the
                    moment they open their mouths on the subject of abolishing slavery anywhere at
                    this critical moment."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"A <emph rend="italic">Republican</emph> Member of Congress presented a bill
                        before that body, a few days ago, asking to have slavery abolished in all
                        territory in Virginia now taken in possession by the Federal troops. Of
                        course, it is laid by for the present. Such acts as this in the halls of
                        Congress will not help the cause of the Union, but do much to weaken it.
                        This is not the time to talk about abolishing slavery, in or out of
                        Congress. All abolitionists ought to have a halter slipped around their
                        necks the moment they open their mouths on the subject of abolishing slavery
                        anywhere at this critical moment. They have the Government to sustain and
                        the Union to reconstruct which should be done at all hazards.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that some Republicans are advocating the abolition of slavery in
                    areas of Virginia held by Federal troops. The Spirit disagrees with this course
                    of action.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Peace Resolutions</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spirit reprints the text of the resolutions presented to the House of
                    Representatives by Congressman Cox of Ohio. Mr. Cox proposed that Congress
                    appoint a commission made up of seven Northerners who would meet with a similar
                    commission appointed by the Confederate Congress. These men would confer and
                    attempt to "bring about a reconstruction of the national unity." The resolution
                    was not approved.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.08.03.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>How a Mason was Preserved from the Fury of a Rebel Mob</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Tells the story of a Petersburg, Virginia man who expressed some sympathy
                    with the Federal forces in Baltimore and was almost killed by an angry mob until
                    rescued by his Masonic brothers. They locked him in a tomb until the crowd could
                    be eluded.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="j">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>A List of Grand and Traverse Jurors</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patton</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf>Sr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brinkley</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clark</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cauffman</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donald</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Detwiler</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnston</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kindig</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keasey</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lesher</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lowrey</ln>
                        <fn>Curtis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mackey</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mateer</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn>Alex</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Metcalf</ln>
                        <fn>Christian</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCleary</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richards</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shearer</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stouffer</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sollenberger</ln>
                        <fn>Israel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Witmore</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zody</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bitner</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Black</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barkdoll</ln>
                        <fn>Matthias</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barkdoll</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bitner</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>Solomon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Croft</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davison</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bitner</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dosh</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dull</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flickinger</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Abraham</ln>
                        <fn>Frantz</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grossman</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hastings</ln>
                        <fn>Allen</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoke</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoss</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoover</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henninger</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Haulman</ln>
                        <fn>D.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hurst</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Irwin</ln>
                        <fn>Matthew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johns</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jacoby</ln>
                        <fn>Jonathan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jordan</ln>
                        <fn>Leonard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kirkpatrick</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keyser</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kuhn</ln>
                        <fn>Emanuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGarvy</ln>
                        <fn>Patrick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn>John G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Plough</ln>
                        <fn>Ephraim</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rankin</ln>
                        <fn>James C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rosenberry</ln>
                        <fn>Ephraim</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shade</ln>
                        <fn>Jno.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Small</ln>
                        <fn>Jeremiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snively</ln>
                        <fn>Melchi</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingert</ln>
                        <fn>A.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilhelm</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walk</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingert</ln>
                        <fn>A.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>List of jurors.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Military reports, columns 1 &amp; 2; markets and statement of the Bank of
                Chambersburg, column 2; advertisements, columns 3-6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.08.03.04">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
