<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1861/pa.fr.vs.1861.06.26">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Colleen Doody</taggerName>
            <tagDate>1/16/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; second pass 5/7/97</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1861-06-26">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="06">June</month>
            <day>26</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>semi-weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.06.26.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>From St. Louis</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A battle took place between Union House Guards under Capt. Cook and a large
                    body of secessionists. Governor Jackson of Missouri is fleeing with about 500
                    men.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>From Williamsport</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The rebel force that left Harper's Ferry is reported to be encamped at
                    Stevenson's Depot near Winchester.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The New Virginia Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Summary of actions taken by the new Virginia convention, including
                    disbursement of public revenue, construction of a military road, and
                    organization of state militia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>From the Seat of War</head>
                <origin>Washington Star</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Gen. McDowell has advanced his lines four miles toward Fairfax Court House.
                    The Confederate camp is two miles away from the Federal encampment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Approaching Trial of Mr. Merriman</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Witnesses have been summoned to go before the Grand Jury in the case of Mr.
                    Merriman. The Grand Jury is composed of "unconditional Union men."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Kentucky Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"It is generally conceded that all the Union candidates for Congress are
                    chosen in the various districts, with the exception of the First district, where
                    H.C. Barnett, the Secession candidate, is undoubtedly elected."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>More Secession Masked Batteries Erected Near Alexandria</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Confederates have one or two masked batteries near Springfield station.
                    In addition, the troops' pay has been delayed because regimental officers were
                    unable to get their rolls into shape. This problem has been straightened out, so
                    the regiments should soon receive their pay.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Indiana Regiment Entrenched at Cumberland</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Col. Wallace of the Indiana Regiment has entrenched himself on the north
                    side of Bedford to await the approach of the rebel army from Romney. The
                    Confederates returned to Romney upon learning of Wallace's presence.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>From Gen. Cadwalader's Division</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Neither C.O. Bowman nor the private of the Eighth Pennsylvania Regiment
                    have been heard from since they were taken prisoner near Williamsport.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Report from Alexandria</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Alexandria remains quiet, "not even a rumor afloat."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>From Washington</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Miscellaneous war news from Washington. Senator Andrew Johnson made a
                    speech in which he "eloquently combatted Secession as a heresy, destructive of
                    the Government, which should be effectually crushed out. The war now in
                    progress, he contended, was not of the North against the South, but as conducted
                    by the Government for the perpetuation of the Union, the maintenance of the
                    Constitution and the enforcement of the laws, made in pursuance of that
                    instrument."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>From Fortress Monroe</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The rebels are concentrating a large force at Yorktown. The excessive heat
                    has been very trying for the troops.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Treason to Favor Peace!</head>
                <origin>Newark Mercury and Newark Journal</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Opposing articles in the Mercury and Journal. The Mercury criticizes the
                    "little knot of traitors in this city" who have begun holding peace meetings.
                    These provide aid to the enemy. The Journal castigates the Mercury for calling
                    peace advocates "traitors" and states that the right to peaceably assemble and
                    fight government tyranny is in no way traitorous.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>Look</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Kentucky and the Union</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Mr. Crittenden defined his position on the present conflict during his
                    campaign for Congress. He stated that he wanted the war to end, but he didn't
                    want a war of subjugation. Instead, the South should present its demands to
                    Congress and Congress should attempt to redress the Southern grievances. He
                    declared himself loyal to the Constitution, not to Lincoln.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>Look</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A Union meeting in Trenton, Missouri, adopted resolutions expressing
                    devotion to the Constitution and the government.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"Lieut. Tyler, U.S.A., who was arrested a night or two since for uttering
                    sentiments at variance with the popular feeling of the country on the war
                    question and handed over to the military authorities, has taken the oath of
                    allegiance at the Brooklyn Navy Yard."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Peace Movement in Connecticut</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>After a peace resolution was introduced in the Iowa legislature, a
                    virtually identical bill was proposed in the Connecticut legislature. The
                    resolution states that they are opposed to the war and want hostilities to end.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>Look</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Troops from further South continue to pour into Richmond. The Confederate
                    forces believe that the rebel men posted in the Shenandoah Valley will protect
                    Manassas Junction and Richmond from any attack from the west.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>Look</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A new night telegraph has been invented for the use of the army and navy.
                    This allows direct communication at night between men who are up to fifteen
                    miles apart.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.06.26.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>What Can be Done for the Country</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spirit is "warmly in favor of adjusting our troubles by other means
                    than the sword." They agree with Mr. Crittenden's recent statements.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>Look</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The "Subjugation" of Maryland</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spirit claims that it is impossible to listen to the Maryland
                    secessionists without "mingled feelings of contempt and indignation. Their
                    everlasting whining about the 'subjugation' of their State is the poorest
                    exhibition of manhood that ever has come under our observation." Maryland wasn't
                    really subjugated, as the secessionists claim, because the federal government
                    had the right to send its troops through the state on their way to Washington.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>Look</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Three Months [sic] Soldiers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The period of enrollment for the three-month volunteers will expire in
                    about two weeks. The Spirit fears that their poor treatment and their dislike of
                    their officers will cause many of the volunteers to not re-enlist.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>Look</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>War News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A Spirit correspondent visited Williamsport and Hagerstown and found
                    "everything pertaining to the army at a dead lock. Everybody seemed to be
                    waiting for something to turn up but nobody could tell when or where a move
                    would be made."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Personal</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spirit once again pleads for money.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Reserve Corps</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Four regiments of the Pennsylvania reserve corps will form a permanent
                    encampment on the grounds of Camp Slifer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Baggage Wagons</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The area's railroads are constantly kept busy freighting supplies for the
                    army. Even so, a large number of baggage wagons pass through the county every
                    day loaded with stores for the troops.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>German Democratic Paper</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spirit has just received the first Harrisburg and Lancaster Democrat,
                    which is a German newspaper published by Messrs. Ripper, Kuhn and Haas. Mr.
                    Ripper is a former partner of the publisher of the Spirit. "He is the right man
                    in the right place. We know him to be a good German scholar, a first-rate
                    printer, a sound Democrat and an honest man."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Judicial Conferees</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Democratic Nominating Convention of Bedford County appointed Hon. W. P.
                    Schell, John G. Hartley and Oliver E. Shannon Judicial Conferees. They will meet
                    with similar Conferees from Franklin, Fulton, and Somerset counties to put in
                    nomination a suitable candidate for President Judge of the district.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Telegraph Complete</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Telegraph line from this place to Hagerstown, for the use of the army is
                        now complete and in working order. The first message passed over the wire on
                        Friday last.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The army telegraph line from Chambersburg to Hagerstown has been completed.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/june61.html#6.26a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Bedford Resolutions</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spirit draws its readers' attention to the declaration of principles
                    set down by the Democrats of Bedford County. According to the paper, the
                    principles "embody the true doctrine--the doctrine of the Constitutional Union
                    men of the country--the only true and consistent friends of the Union."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>Look</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Resolutions</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Text of the resolutions adopted by the Democrats of Bedford. In them, they
                    condemn sectional parties and pledge their loyalty to the Constitution.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Fire</head>
                <origin>Greencastle Pilot</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hade</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fotzinger</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zeigler</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Last Monday afternoon a fire broke out in the Foundry building of Messrs.
                    Bradley, Crowell &amp; Keller. Two houses were also destroyed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>March of Two Regiments</head>
                <origin>Harrisburg Patriot and Union</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Col. Wallace and his men were in a critical situation in Cumberland.
                    Reinforcements were sent to him immediately.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Chambersburg markets in column 6.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.06.26.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Tribute of Respect</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Pat Valley Lodge of the I.O.of O.F. passed a resolution in honor of the
                    late Samuel C. Deardorff.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Plans at Washington</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It appears that the administration wants to end the war as quickly as
                    possible, even if that means calling four or five hundred thousand men into
                    service. Gen. Scott is reticent to rush them into the field, however, because
                    they won't be well trained.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Howe</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sevenz</ln>
                        <fn>Levi</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allison</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on June 18th in Greenvillage.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Creigh</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCleary</ln>
                        <fn>Charlotte</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on June 20th in Mercersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Deaths are illegible.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.06.26.04">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
