<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1861/pa.fr.vs.1861.10.02">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Brian Erb</taggerName>
            <tagDate>04.17.96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 6/6/97</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1861-10-02">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="10">October</month>
            <day norm="02">2</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.10.02.01">
            <pageNote>Various items of national and military news.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.10.02.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>West Point Academy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that many officers and political leaders on both sides of the
                    conflict graduated from West Point.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Letter from Prince Napoleon assessing the war. Items of national and military
                news. Columns 5 and 6 are a short story by Charles Dickens.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.10.02.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Party and No Party</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Criticizes Republicans who wish to erase the opposition of the Democrats in
                    the name of the Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Columns 1 and 2 are the remainder of Dickens story.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.10.02.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Are you Ready?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The issue is forced upon you, to decide in favor of Democracy or of
                    Sectional Black Republicanism and Abolition."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In a few days the time for holding the annual election will be here. It comes
                        this year on Tuesday, Oct. 8th. Remember the day and be prepared to do your
                        duty to your country and your party. Matters of great importance for the
                        present and the future will be decided on that day. The acts and doings of
                        the State Administration will be endorsed or condemned. The flag of the good
                        old Union-loving Democratic party will be thrown to the breeze in triumph;
                        or will continue to trail in the dust. If it trails, sectionalism,
                        Abolitionism and fanaticism will triumph.</p>
                    <p>Fellow Democrats, the issue is upon you. It must be met, and should be met in
                        a spirit of exalted patriotism and devotion to country; whilst you have
                        given men and money without stint, to put down and rebuke the sectionalism
                        of the South, rise in the majesty of your power and rebuke at the ballot box
                        the sectionalism of the North.</p>
                    <p>The issue is forced upon you, to decide in favor of Democracy or of Sectional
                        Black Republicanism and Abolitionism.</p>
                    <p>The cry of "no party," is one of the most flimsy devices of the enemy, to
                        gull the people, whilst this and other similar schemes are continually
                        prated around by the Republican party; they are at this very time more
                        intensely and uncompromisingly partizan than they have every been in the
                        past. And in the very face of these unblushing protestations of 'Union' and
                        'no party,' they have offered and are now most industriously laboring and
                        planning by all means in their power for the election of a ticket composed
                        entirely of partizans of the strictest sect, whose greatest recommendation
                        is their devotion to Republicanism--their opposition to Democratic men and
                        measures.</p>
                    <p>Is there anything in the nominees of that party to induce Democrats to
                        support them? Is there anything in their principles or the acts of their
                        State or National Administration, that entitles them to a preference over
                        Democratic candidates?</p>
                    <p>We most unhesitatingly say there is not. We present to you a ticket of which
                        any party should be proud. Men well known to you, and we believe very
                        favorable know. Men eminently qualified for the positions for which they are
                        offered. Men of ability and character, and the foulest enemy dare not
                        dispute it. Men whose lives have been devoted to the good of the country and
                        for the supremacy of the laws--men, in whose hands the interests of the
                        people will be safe.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges Democrats to turn out to vote.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Judgeship of our District</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reilly</ln>
                        <fn>Wilson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nill</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Urges the election of Reilly over Nill and asserts Wilson Reilly's moral
                    qualities and his patriotism as reasons for his election. Much of article
                    illegible.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Up and at Them!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Democrats be about on Tuesday next and show those who would break up your
                    party that it is not dead or dying."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges Democrats to vote on Tuesday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>A Masked Battery</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"In order to gull Democrats into voting for him, Nill says he is just as
                    good a Democrat as he ever was! The Republicans, of course, believe him and are
                    trying to bestow on him a ten year office as a reward for his fidelity to the
                    Democratic Party!"</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nill</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Urges Democrats not to fall for the Union dodge, as it is just a Republican
                    trick.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Not Fit for a Judge</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"If ever a party had occasion to cry out 'save me from my friends' it is
                    the Republican Party of Franklin County at this day."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nill</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Asserts that Nill, the phony Union candidate, was appointed a judge in
                    Chester County and was removed for incompetency.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Stand by Your Party</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Do your duty manfully by your party and support its ticket--the WHOLE
                    TICKET."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges all Democrats to support the ticket.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Missouri</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lambastes the management of occupied territory in Missouri by Gen. John
                    Fremont, particularly his abolitionist policies with regard to slaves
                    confiscated from rebels.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Judicial</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Ross Forward of Somerset Co. arrived in Chambersburg and
                    declared himself an independent candidate for the Judgeship. He is a Republican
                    who is dissatisfied with the "bogus union-saver ticket".</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Look Out for Them</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nill</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reilly</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Warns of those who will attempt to sway Democrats into voting for Nill.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Judicial Conference</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the Republican conferees from Bedford County nominated Nill
                    for the Judgeship despite instructions to vote for Alex King.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Be Active--Be Watchful</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Let no Democrat be deceived into voting for Nill."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nill</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary/>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Sure Enough</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nitterhouse</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nill</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Asserts that some Republicans are dissatisfied with the "mongrel ticket" of
                    Nill and Nitterhouse and would prefer not to vote at all.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.10.02.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>President Judgeship</head>
                <origin>Bedford Gazette</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reilly</ln>
                        <fn>Wilson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Praises the choice of Wilson Reilly to head the Democratic ticket.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Colestock</ln>
                        <fn>T. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keller</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ward</ln>
                        <fn>Annie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Keller and Annie Ward married on September 4.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yost</ln>
                        <fn>Adam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kahler</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Adam Yost and Elizabeth Kahler married on September 26. Miss Kahler is from
                    Cumberland county.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Talbert</ln>
                        <fn>Tilman</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bohn</ln>
                        <fn>Rosanna</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Tilbert Talbert and Rosanna Bohn married on September 26.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fletcher</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Alrick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fletcher</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fletcher</ln>
                        <fn>Mary V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary Fletcher died on September 27 at age 8 months.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maxwell</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maxwell</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maxwell</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Daniel Maxwell died on September 28 at age 22 years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel Wilson died on September 17 at age 71.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Various endorsements of Wilson Reilly and other Democratic candidates from
                papers around the district</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.10.02.06">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.10.02.07">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.10.02.08">
            <pageNote>Items of national news and advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
