<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1861/pa.fr.vs.1861.04.24">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Brian Erb</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1861-04-24">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day>24</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.04.24.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>THE WAR!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Many important items of news are reported. 1. Union troops arrived in
                    Chambersburg after being driven from Harper's Ferry in Virginia. 2. News
                    regarding the wavering status of Maryland including the declaration of martial
                    law in Baltimore and the death of two Massachusetts soldiers at the hands of
                    rioters. 3. News regarding the raising of Federal troops. 4. The secession of
                    Virginia is reported. 5. Many items relating to the opening of hostilities in
                    Norfolk and Harper's Ferry including the seizure of Federal properties in
                    Virginia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Bridges Burned in Maryland</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports railroad bridges burned by Secessionists in Maryland with the
                    object of preventing the movement of Federal Troops.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Latest</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports movement of Massachusetts troops.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Latest from Baltimore</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that any attack on Fort McHenry will be repelled with force that
                    may include the shelling of Baltimore.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Harbor Police at New York</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the harbor police will inspect cargoes leaving New York and
                    prevent the departure of contraband for the South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Excitement at Boston</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The war feeling is becoming more intense every hour all over New England."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports the agitated state of the citizens of Boston relative to the death
                    of two soldiers at the hands of a Baltimore mob.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Ohio</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"It was unanimously resolved that the last dollar and the last man that
                    Zanesville could raise would be given to sustain the Government."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the largest public meeting ever held in Zanesville, Ohio met
                    in support of the Government. Item also reports the raising of troops in Ohio.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Much news of war preparations.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.04.24.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>War Feeling in Chambersburg</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"All...declared that forbearance was no longer patriotism and that
                    secession must be humbled and the Union restored-peaceably if we can, forcibly
                    if we must."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>WAR-FEELING IN CHAMBERSBURG</p>
                    <p><lb/>GREAT UNANIMITY AND ENTHUSIASM. <lb/>Men and Money Freely Offered.
                            <lb/><emph rend="italic">THE TOWN DECORATED WITH FLAGS</emph>.
                        <lb/>PUBLIC MEETING OF CITIZENS.</p>
                    <p>ELOQUENT AND PATRIOTIC SPEECHES.</p>
                    <p>All Parties Uniting on a Common</p>
                    <p><lb/>Platform to Maintain the Consti- <lb/>tution and the Laws.</p>
                    <p>Chambers Artillery and Several Com- <lb/>panies from the County will leave
                        <lb/>To-Morrow Morning for <lb/>Washington City.</p>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">PUBLIC SUPPER TO THE SOLDIERS.</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>Union Pole-Raising in the Pub. Square.</p>
                    <p><lb/>THE FEELING OVER THE STATE.</p>
                    <p>CHAMBERSBURG, April 18, 1861.</p>
                    <p>The Union feeling pervading this entire community is most unanimous and
                        enthusiastic. There is but one sentiment--one purpose--one determination
                        among men of all political parties, and that is, to stand up for the
                        Government and sustain it in all efforts to put down rebellion and
                        re-establish the Union.</p>
                    <p>A large and enthusiastic meeting of citizens of all political parties was
                        held in the Court House on last evening to adopt measures necessary for the
                        exigencies of the times.</p>
                    <p>Hon. WILSON REILLY was called to the chair and B. B. Henshey appointed
                        Secretary.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Reilly on taking the chair made a powerful and patriotic address which
                        was received with deafening applause. He stated his readiness to support the
                        Government by every means at his disposal and his willingness to shoulder a
                        musket and march to the field of battle if needs be to save the flag of his
                        country from dishonor.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Reilly was followed by a number of other speakers, called out by the
                        meeting, all of whom declared that forbearance was no longer patriotism and
                        that secession must be humbled and the Union restored--peacably if we can,
                        forcibly if we must. Among the speakers expressing these sentiments were
                        Messrs. Brewer, Sharp, Douglas on the Democratic side, Messrs. Rowe,
                        McCauley, Steward, Cook and others of the Republicans. The utmost harmony
                        and good feeling prevailed at the meeting.</p>
                    <p>AN INCIDENT.--Capt. P. B. HOUSAM, commander of the Chambers Artillery,
                        appeared in the meeting, for the purpose of stating a matter of business,
                        and his appearance was greeted with three of the heartiest cheers we ever
                        heard in a public assemblage.</p>
                    <p>The following committee were appointed on General Regulations, viz: D. W.
                        Rowe, Sam'l Shryock and W. C. Eyster.</p>
                    <p>Committee on Contributions: J. Allison Eyster, J. W. Douglas and James Nill.</p>
                    <p>Committee to supply Pocket Bibles to our soldiers: Ex-Sheriff Brown, I. H.
                        McCauley and A. N. Rankin.</p>
                    <p>HOME GUARDS.--About fifty persons then went forward and recorded their names
                        as volunteers to form a company for home protection, and to qualify
                        themselves in military tactics to enable them to enter the army if their
                        services should be required.</p>
                    <p>The meeting wound up with nine cheers for the Chambers Artillery, and a like
                        number for the speakers who had so patriotically addressed the meeting.</p>
                    <p>A complimentary supper will be given to the Chambers Artillery by our
                        citizens this evening.</p>
                    <p>The Chambersburg Artillery, about one hundred and fifty strong, will leave
                        to- morrow at 8 o'clock for Washington city. They are mustered into service
                        for three months. The prayers and best wishes of all good citizens for their
                        safe return go with them.</p>
                    <p>We are informed that a fund of several thousand dollars has already been
                        subscribed to aid the families of the absent soldiers should they need it,
                        during the service of the men from their homes.</p>
                    <p>The officers of the company are Capt. P. B. Housum; 1st Lieut., John Doebler;
                        2nd Lieut., Mathew Gillan; 3d Lieut., George Miles. Colonel Stumbaugh will
                        aceompany the Chambers Artillery and take command of the Regiment as soon as
                        formed.</p>
                    <p>We have just learned that Capt. Charles T. Campbell has received a commission
                        and authorized to form a Field Battery to be attached to this regiment of
                        volunteers.</p>
                    <p>A Union Pole about one hundred and twenty feet high, with the American Flag
                        at the top, is being erected in the centre of the Public Square. The Diamond
                        is now crowded with an enthusiastic mass of People.</p>
                    <p>The Chambers Artillery will parade this afternoon all the men intending to
                        march with the company will be out.</p>
                    <p>The stars and stripes are flying from all the public houses and a great many
                        private residences. Our people are manifesting their loyalty to the
                        Constitution and the Government in the hour of its danger in the most
                        patriotic manner.</p>
                    <p>We hear from all parts of the State of the rapid enlistment of troops to
                        supply the quota of Pennsylvania, while enthusiastic meetings of the people
                        are being held to assert the authority of the government, and aid in the
                        vindication of the National honor.</p>
                    <p>The War Feeling in Chambersburg. <lb/>(<emph rend="italic">Continued from
                            second page.</emph>)</p>
                    <p>On Thursday last after the Union Pole was raised in the Public Square a large
                        assemblage of ladies, on the veranda of the Franklin House, sung the "Star
                        Spangled Banner" with fine effect, calculated to arouse the patriotism of
                        every heart that heard those soul-stirring strains.</p>
                    <p>Messrs. Reilly, Stumbaugh, McClure, Brewer, Everett, Stinger and Welsh were
                        called out and respectively addressed the vast multitude collected on the
                        occasion. All spoke in strains of the loftiest patriotism and expressed
                        their determination to stand by the Flag of their Country. The speakers were
                        all heartily cheered during the delivery of their addresses and the greatest
                        joy prevailed.</p>
                    <p>The Departure of the Chambers Artillery on Friday morning last was one of the
                        most impressive and affecting scenes that has ever occurred in this place.
                        The fathers, mothers, brothers, sisters, wives and children of the
                        volunteers, together with the entire population of the place, were collected
                        at the Depot to bid farewell to the gallant band and witness their
                        departure. The members of the company seemed much less affected at parting
                        than their friends. While almost every eye in the vast throng was bathed in
                        tears the soldiers seemed in the most joyous spirits and cheered their
                        friends with words of consolation and hope.</p>
                    <p>This company numbered about one hundred and fifty men. Since leaving here
                        they have been divided into two companies, Lieut. Doebler taking command of
                        the second company formed. We are informed that Col. Stumbaugh has been
                        elected as Colonel of the regiment, and Maj. J. T. Hoskinson appointed as
                        Quartermaster. The company encamped at "Camp Curtin" near Harrisburg. The
                        men were all in excellent health and good spirits.</p>
                    <p>During Saturday night the company, together with several thousand troops,
                        were transported on the Railroad to within twenty miles of Baltimore. The
                        bridges at this point were destroyed and the track of the road torn up and
                        the troops could proceed no further. The latest rumor we have here is to the
                        effect that our men will return to Harrisburg and be sent to Washington by
                        way of Philadelphia.</p>
                    <p>Capt. C. T. Campbell's Company of Light Artillery is filling up fast. He now
                        has nearly an hundred men enlisted. They will remain here till ordered off
                        on duty. He has two cannon and is drilling his men actively day and night.
                        They are quartered in the Franklin Hall.</p>
                    <p>A Rifle Company under the command of Capt. John S. Eyster has been formed and
                        now numbers over fifty members. A large German company of able-bodied men
                        has also been formed within a few days numbering about sixty members. The
                        ranks of the Home Guards are filling up fast and will be divided into
                        several companies. The Home Guards have tendered their services to the
                        Governor to march if needed.</p>
                    <p>Our citizens have contributed very liberally to meet all expenses attendant
                        on the war-like movements going on among us. We understand that a sum
                        amounting to nearly ten thousand dollars has been subscribed. The County
                        Commissioners, we learn, are ready to subscribe twenty thousand dollars to
                        arm this county and place it in a position to aid the Government or resist
                        invasion.</p>
                    <p>On Sunday last a very fine body of men, under command of Capt. Walker, from
                        Fannettsburg, arrived in this place. This company numbers about sixty men,
                        and more of their neighbors are expected here, to join them. There was a
                        number added to their ranks while passing through Strasburg. These men are
                        quartered in the Court House. They are under efficient officers who are
                        drilling them for active service.</p>
                    <p>Gen. McAllen has advertised for a thousand men to fill a regiment from this
                        county. From present indications he will have no trouble in obtaining that
                        number and as many more. Our people are aroused and there is no difficulty
                        here in obtaining men and money to carry on the war.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reilly</ln>
                        <fn>Wilson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henshey</ln>
                        <fn>B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewer</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharp</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Douglas</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rowe</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCauley</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Steward</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shryock</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>J. Allison</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Douglas</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nill</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Ex-Sheriff</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCauley</ln>
                        <fn>I.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rankin</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Housum</ln>
                        <fn>P.</fn>
                        <sf>Capt.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doebler</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillam</ln>
                        <fn>Mathew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miles</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports a large and enthusiastic meeting of Chambersburg citizens
                    expressing support for the Union and the Government. Both Democrats and
                    Republicans united in this sentiment. Several committees were assembled to look
                    after local contributions to the war effort. Also the Chambersburg Artillery
                    have been mustered into service and are preparing to leave for Washington. News
                    from the entire state reports similar enthusiasm and the raising of troops.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/april61.html#4.24a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Glorious News! The Old Dominion Loyal!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports the mistaken belief that the Virginia Convention negated the
                    Secession Ordinance by a majority of thirteen. Item also reports that ex-Senator
                    Bigler declared that, while opposed to the Administration on questions of
                    policy, he is unequivocally in favor of sustaining the government.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>THE WAR!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Dispatches from Washington detailing items of news relating to the
                    consummation of war. These items include the progress of mustering troops, the
                    allocation of funds for the war effort, and news from the border states,
                    particularly Maryland. Also reported is the mistaken assumption that Virginia
                    will remain in the Union and muster troops for the Federal cause.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Battle at Charleston</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>More details regarding the engagement at Sumter.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The War Feeling in the South</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Items from the various Southern States report unanimity of feeling and
                    support for the Confederacy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Pennsylvania Militia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Pennsylvania will soon have met its troop quota and will have
                    many to spare.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Munitions of War at Savannah</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that a large amount of contraband is arriving at Savannah.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Items of news from Northern states asserting the prompt answering of Lincoln's
                call for troops.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.04.24.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Stealing Copper Bolts From a Navy Yard</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Eight employees of the Brooklyn Naval Yard were caught stealing copper
                    bolts from the Yard.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Why should black companies and regiments be exposed in war when niggers
                    are worth $1,500 apiece."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the South will not arm blacks for the war effort.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Items from Northern states regarding the quick response to Lincoln's call for
                troops. Remainder of page 3 anecdotes and ads.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.04.24.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Stand by your Flag</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges all citizens of every political persuasion to support the Union war
                    effort.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Be a Soldier</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Encourages all men to become soldiers for the cause of the Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Ready, Aim, Fire</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"While we considered them friends, we battled for their rights in the
                    Union, but when they determined to break up the Union and array themselves as
                    enemies against us, we are their enemies."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"Every man in the community should set his house in order and be ready to
                        meet any event, and assume any duty, that may be required of him in the
                        present struggle to maintain the Constitution and Laws of his country.--The
                        danger is at hand, even at our very doors, and before everything we hold
                        near and dear as patriots is snatched from us we should take the stand that
                        will encourage the timid and cheer on the brave. A formidable band of
                        traitors have broken up the Union and made war against the government. While
                        we considered them friends we battled for their rights <emph rend="italic"
                            >in the Union</emph>, but when they determine to break up the Union and
                        array themselves as enemies against us, <emph rend="italic">we are their
                            enemies</emph>. They are no longer of our household but enemies up in
                        arms against us. Let us then be up and doing and crush the monster before it
                        crushes us. Let us be watchful on every side and allow no man to slumber at
                        his post while the flag of his country is in danger. Let the watch-word of
                        all be--"READY, AIM, FIRE."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Accuses the Confederacy of making war on the Union and urges everyone to
                    uphold his or her duty as a patriotic citizen.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/april61.html#4.24b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Organization of the Militia of the United States</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Presents an abstract of the laws of the United States regarding the raising
                    of militia units.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Spirit</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Responds to a letter writer to another paper who pointed out that the
                    Spirit, in spite of its support for Breckenridge, displayed the Stars and
                    Stripes. The Spirit asserts that it was the first paper in town to do so.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Town Meeting and Supper to our Volunteers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chambers</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nill</ln>
                        <fn>Jason</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wunderlich</ln>
                        <fn>D.K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Housum</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCauley</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewer</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doebler</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharp</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nichols</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports a town meeting held in Chambersburg along with a farewell supper
                    for the volunteers who were preparing to leave for Washington.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Pole Raising</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"On Saturday afternoon last the people resident in and around "Greenwood,"
                    united in the raising of a beautiful pole, bearing high up on its slender stem
                    our national flag, 13 stripes and 34 stars."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On Saturday afternoon last the people resident in and around "Greenwood,"
                        united in the raising of a beautiful pole, bearing high up on its slender
                        stem our national flag, 13 stripes and 34 stars. The Pole stands 85 feet out
                        of ground, and proudly throws abroad to the breeze an elegant banner gotten
                        up by the Ladies of the place. His Excellency Governor George Wolff
                        superintended the raising, and under his careful management no accident
                        occurred to mar the pleasure of the occasion. Democrats and Republicans
                        participated with hearty good will in hoisting up the "Flag of the Free."</p>
                    <p>Spirited addresses were delivered by W. S. Everett and I. H. McCauly
                        Esq.,--after that the assemblage adjourned with three times three for "The
                        Union and her Flag."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Everett</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCauley</ln>
                        <fn>I.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports the raising of a flag pole in Chambersburg along with the Stars and
                    Stripes.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/april61.html#4.24c</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>War Feeling in Chambersburg (continued from front page)</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reilly</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewer</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Everett</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stinger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Welsh</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doebler</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>More reports of activities in Chambersburg demonstrating the unanimity of
                    feeling with regard to the support of the Union war effort.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Proclamation of the Governor</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Governor's proclamation calls the state legislature into special session.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Blockade of the Southern Ports. Proclamation from President Lincoln.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports the proclamation of Lincoln announcing a blockade of the Southern
                    ports.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Proclamation of the President of the Southern Confederacy--Commission of
                    Privateers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Jeff Davis's proclamation requests the services of any owners of private
                    vessels who may wish to aid the Confederacy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Resolutions</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCauley</ln>
                        <fn>I.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Transcript of the resolutions adopted at the Chambersburg Town Meeting.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.04.24.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Our Office</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stouffler</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that Samuel Stouffler, one of the heads of the Spirit office, has
                    left with the Chambers Artillery.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Court Proceedings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Downey</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolff</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Galwis</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillam</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boggs</ln>
                        <fn>Thaddeus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Piper</ln>
                        <fn>Polly</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dyersan</ln>
                        <fn>D. James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dyersan</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rogers</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewer</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ruby</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Della</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowman</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A list of cases settled in County Court.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Pennsylvania Volunteers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that two companies have been raised in Chambersburg and two more
                    will be ready in five days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Colestock</ln>
                        <fn>Z.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gelwiz</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bechtel</ln>
                        <fn>Annie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on April 18 .</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Oaks</ln>
                        <fn>Katie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tritle</ln>
                        <fn>L. Winter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Philips</ln>
                        <fn>Sam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on April 18.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fry</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dosert</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on April 18.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shaffer</ln>
                        <fn>Maragret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shaffer</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shaffer</ln>
                        <fn>Martha</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Margaret Shaffer died on April 8, aged 21 years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKeehan</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Died on April 19 of consumption, aged 21 years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stewart</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Stewart died on April 15, aged 90 years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.04.24.06">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.04.24.07">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.04.24.08">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Responses to the President's Call for Troops</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The governors of many Northern states responded quickly to Lincoln's call
                    for troops. The quick response is cited as evidence that the North is ready and
                    willing to commit itself to a war to restore the Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Border Slave States</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that it appears that Virginia will secede. However, the people of
                    Western Virginia are pro-Union and will take up arms to resist secession. The
                    item also reports that Union feeling in Maryland is strengthening.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Alabama</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the South is borrowing money to increase the army.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The War Spirit in the South</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Asserts that the troops are easily raised and money readily lent for the
                    Confederate war effort.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Pennsylvania</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that Pennsylvania's war preparations are well under way.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Massachusetts</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A meeting of Democrats in Boston resolved to support the Government.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Excitement at New York</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that several New York newspapers, including the Express, the Day
                    Book, and the Daily News, were threatened by crowds that demanded they display
                    the Stars and Stripes outside their offices.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Forts in North Carolina Captured</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the Governor of North Carolina has seized all the Federal
                    Forts in that state.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Various items regarding military preparations.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
