<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1861/pa.fr.vs.1861.06.22">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Colleen Doody</taggerName>
            <tagDate>1/15/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; second pass 5/7/97</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1861-06-22">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="06">June</month>
            <day>22</day>
            <weekday id="SAT">Saturday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>semi-weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.06.22.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Rebellion</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A lengthy telegraph from Gen. Robert Schenck reporting on a rebel attack
                    upon his men at Vienna, Virginia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Important Order</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>General McDowell released an order forbidding any Union soldier from
                    arresting any secessionist who was not "at the time in arms against the United
                    States." In addition, no soldier could enter any house or confiscate any
                    property from a secessionist who was not actively engaged in hostilities against
                    the Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Military Appointment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"A son of Joseph Coolridge of Boston, who married a grand daughter of
                    Thomas Jefferson, has received a Major's commission in the regular army. He has
                    uncles and cousins in the Secession ranks."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Another Appointment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Edward L. Smith, a young lawyer from Reading, Pennsylvania, has been
                    appointed Captain in the regular army.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>How the Harvey Despatches Were Discovered</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An account of how the government discovered Harvey's treacherous
                    dispatches.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Important from Missouri--300 Rebels Killed</head>
                <origin>Democrat</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An account of the battle at Booneville. The Union troops defeated a
                    Confederate force, causing Gov. Jackson to flea.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Later from Fortress Monroe</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Three hundred Zouaves under Lieut. Col. Warren left to reconnoiter the area
                    near Great Bethel and up the route to Yorktown.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Large Preparations for Carrying Troops</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Arrangements have been made to carry troops through Baltimore, over the
                    Lebanon Valley and Northern Central Railroad, at the rate of twenty-five car
                    loads a day. The same number will go over the Camden and Amboy and Philadelphia
                    and Wilmington Railroads.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>From Western Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A man who had travelled from Richmond to Grafton reports that there are
                    rumors that reinforcements for the Rebel army would be sent into western
                    Virginia immediately. The Confederates are pressing all the men into the ranks.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>The Rebel Troops on the Mississippi</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A man who had travelled from Mobile and Memphis to Chicago reported that
                    there were 30,000 well-armed Confederate troops encamped between Vicksburg and
                    Cairo.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>The Geography of Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Explanation of the geography of Virginia focusing on Harper's Ferry and
                    Manassas Junction.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>News from the South</head>
                <origin>Philadelphia Inquirer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A gentleman from Lynchburg, Virginia who was in Philadelphia on tobacco
                    business told a reporter that troops continue to pour into Virginia from all the
                    Confederate states. They are well armed, and most of their officers had been
                    trained at military academies.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Our Soldiers Must be Taught to Take Care of Themselves</head>
                <origin>N.Y. Scientific American</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Details the key information a soldier must know to survive, including the
                    ability to cook, to endure thirst, to perform first aid, and to camp.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.06.22.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Personal</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Valley Spirit states that it needs money very badly. The editors beg
                    their patrons to pay the paper what they owe and also lend it any money they
                    can.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>Look</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Swear Him In</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spirit insists that Horace Greeley be made to take the oath of
                    allegiance to the U.S. because he made a slanderous and disloyal assault on the
                    flag in 1854.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>No Help for Them</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spirit criticizes the American papers that called for war with England
                    and Europe. It is now clear that no European power is going to help the South,
                    as the Spirit predicted.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Arms for State Troops</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>According to the Harrisburg Telegraph, the federal government has notified
                    the governor of Pennsylvania that it will provide the state with 10,000 stand of
                    arms.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>News from the Army</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The men who had been encamped at Chambersburg have moved to Hagerstown,
                    Funkstown and Williamsport.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>A Millerite Secessionist</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spirit satirizes John B. Floyd, who issued a pronouncement to the
                    people of his department, "which comprises the magnificent one-horse town of
                    Wythesville." According to his statement, "nothing but the want of arms prevents
                    the gallant band of traitors under his command from cutting their way clear to
                    the North Pole."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"Col. Williamson, of the sicklow Brigade, has sworn that 'the Tribune must
                    not and should not be circulated among the soldiers at Camp Scott.'"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Franklin Letters</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Philadelphia Press complained that the Chambersburg Postmaster wouldn't
                    honor the frank of W. D. Kelley, who allowed all his friends to send their mail
                    using his franked envelopes. The Spirit argues that the Postmaster did the right
                    thing because his actions conformed to the strict letter of the law.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Diplomatic Dinners, &amp;c.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spirit criticizes the people in Washington who enjoy the lavish state
                    balls and diplomatic dinners that are reported in the papers. It argues that, in
                    these times of strife and economic distress, "the persons engaged in them [balls
                    and parties] should set an example of abstemiousness."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>New Democratic Daily</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The leading Democrats of Philadelphia have decided to start a new
                    Democratic daily in that city. It will be under the editorial control of Messrs.
                    Welsh and Glossbrenner. According to the Spirit, "Such a paper is badly needed,
                    and will receive, we believe, at this time, a hearty support."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The British Army allows its soldiers to frank their own letters. The Spirit
                    believes that Congress should adopt this practice for American soldiers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>County Treasurer</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The letter recommends that the name of William Cline of Southampton
                    township be presented to the people of the county for the office of county
                    treasurer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Washington Star</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"The President, in consequence of the pressure of public business, is
                    obliged to decline receiving any more visitors from this time until the opening
                    of the next session of Congress."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Defense of Col. Bendix</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Adjutant L. Schaffner, of Col. Bendix's Regiment, defends the Colonel's
                    behavior at the battle of Great Bethel, when Bendix's men mistakenly fired on
                    other Union soldiers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Heavy Taxes</head>
                <origin>New York Sun</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Taxes for next year are estimated at $14,000,000. Since there is an adult
                    male population in New York of only 200,000, each man will pay an average of
                    $70.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Still at It!</head>
                <origin>Richmond Examiner</origin>
                <commentary>"The Examiner editors are incorrigible. Hear how the Examiner berates
                    the Federal troops."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Examiner says "Take them all in all their forces are as precious a set
                    of rascals as could be scraped together with a fine tooth comb from the
                    pot-houses and hell holes of the North. They have been fertilized by filth and
                    grown up, fresh and unmitigatedly wretched from the mire of municipal
                    corruption."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The most severe blow the U.S. government has received since the beginning
                    of the war was the treason of General Twiggs in Texas. He surrendered troops,
                    arms, money and forts to the rebels, thus providing them with enormous material
                    aid.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Fairfax Station should not be confused with Fairfax Court House. The former
                    is located on the Orange and Alexandria Railroad about 18 miles from Alexandria
                    while the latter is 14 miles from Alexandria. Likewise, Manassas Gap and
                    Manassas Junction are two different places, the former being in the Valley,
                    about 60 miles away from the Junction.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"Beware of one, two and three dollar bills on the Farmers' and Drovers'
                    Bank of Waynesburg, Green county. That Bank has, as yet, issued no small bills,
                    and all that are in circulation are forgeries."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>The Army Clothing Frauds</head>
                <origin>Lancaster Examiner</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Grand Jury in Pittsburgh made presentment that Emanuel Frowenfeld,
                    Maurice Frowenfeld, Asher Frowenfeld, Abraham Frowenfeld, Joseph Morganstern,
                    Louis Morganstern and Charles Neal intended to cheat and defraud the state of
                    Pennsylvania with their contract for army clothing.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Fort Pickens</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Confederate troops are making great preparations for the capture of
                    Fort Pickens, which commands the best harbor in the Gulf.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>The Wheeling Convention</head>
                <origin>Washington Star</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The introduction of resolutions favoring a division of the state of
                    Virginia was the work of a single member, who himself opposed the action but was
                    merely following the wishes of a public meeting held in his county.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.06.22.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Advance of Troops to the Capitol</head>
                <origin>Washington Chronicle</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A chronological list of the troops that have arrived in Washington.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Gen. Patterson's Column</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>List of the troops under the command of Major General Robert Patterson,
                    which have been brigaded and organized.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Secession Annulled</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The convention of the western counties of Virginia passed a resolution
                    declaring the secession proceedings of the Richmond Convention void and making
                    all state offices vacant that were filled by seceders. This is far preferable to
                    a division of the state.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1861.06.22.04">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
