<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1869/va.au.vv.1869.11.18">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>09/30/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1869-11-18">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="11">November</month>
            <day norm="">18</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1869.11.18.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1869.11.18.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Manufactures and Schools</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>At first view, this seems rather an odd conjunction of subjects, but, upon
                        consideration, they are not so entirely dissimilar as would generally be
                        supposed. In one sense, a school bears a strong analogy to a manufacturing
                        establishment, the teacher being the artisans--the undisciplined pupils, the
                        raw material--and the educated young man or woman the fabric! And when we
                        look at the skill required in the artificer--the nature and value of the
                        material to be worked up, and the inestimable importance of the results to
                        be attained, in converting immature, thoughtless, and often wayward boys and
                        girls, into cultivated, refined, and reflecting gentlemen and ladies all
                        must concede that it is a branch of industry which should stand at the head
                        of all human employments.</p>
                    <p>But it is not our purpose to run this parallel between education and
                        manufactures.--We classed them together, merely because they are both
                        intimately connected with the prosperity of our town.</p>
                    <p>From present prospects, we are led to believe, that, at no distant day, the
                        Chesapeake and Ohio R.R. will be extended to the coal-fields, 50 miles west
                        of the White Sulphur; And very soon thereafter, to the Ohio River. As part
                        of the projected improvement, a new and short line of railway is to be
                        constructed, from some point on the present road, near Shadwell Mills,
                        through Fluvanna and Goochland, to Richmond, thus cutting off about 36
                        miles, and reducing the distance from Staunton to Richmond, to about 100
                        miles.</p>
                    <p>The importance of these improvements to Staunton, can hardly be over
                        estimated. We will then be on the line of the great through trade and travel
                        from East to West, and West to East. In ten years from the completion of
                        these great improvements we shall probably, have fifty or a hundred trains
                        of cars per day instead of four. But the advantages, resulting from this
                        through trade and travel, (important as they doubtless will be) will bear no
                        comparison with those which will result from bringing the coal, iron, and
                        timber of our country into close relations.--These three articles are the
                        most important elements in many branches of manufacture--coal is needed to
                        smelt the iron, and to generate the steam-power, necessary to operate the
                        machinery, and iron and timber are the raw materials for the manufacture of
                        all kinds of agricultural implements, wagons, carts, hoes, spades, locks and
                        many other articles which we need not enumerate.</p>
                    <p>Of timber we have an abundant supply and of the very best quality. Hickory,
                        white oak, ash, walnut, and white and yellow pine abound, in almost every
                        part of the country. Iron ore, in inexhaustible quantities, has been found
                        in our mountains, both east and west of us. Of late, an active spirit, not
                        only of enquiry, but of development, has manifested itself in regard to our
                        mineral resources. The first fruit of this spirit, has been the erection, by
                        a wealthy Maryland Company, under the auspices of our enterprising and
                        esteemed fellow citizen, L. Sibert, of a large furnace, in Buffalo Gap, on
                        the line of the R.R. and within ten miles of Staunton. This is to be
                        followed by a twin furnace, of the same size, at the same place, and
                        ultimately, by a Rolling-mill.</p>
                    <p>Another company from N.Y. has bought the McBride survey of 24,000 acres, a
                        few miles beyond Buffalo Gap, near the summit on which they propose to erect
                        similar works. These furnaces--to say nothing of Forrer's Works, and the
                        Estelline and Bath Furnaces, a little further on, and the three furnaces in
                        Rockbridge and Alleghaney, recently bought, and to be operated by Huster
                        Clymer and his partners, will furnish all the iron that may be needed by a
                        dozen large manufacturing establishments.</p>
                    <p>The only thing then wanting will be coal. This will, within two years at
                        most, by supplied from the mines in Greenbrier, Gauley and the Kanawha, of a
                        quantity much better than any they have in Baltimore; and, as we have every
                        reason to believe, at a cost much less than the Baltimore manufacturers have
                        to pay.</p>
                    <p>When this is done, the three great elements of manufacturers will be brought
                        into contact, and it will be the fault of our own people, if they are not
                        blended together, in the manufacture of all kinds of implements &amp;c.,
                        which are produced from these materials.</p>
                    <p>If any one doubts whether there would be a market for such productions of
                        industry and skill, let him go to our depots on the railroad, in the summer
                        and early autumn, and see the thousands upon thousands of dollars worth,
                        that are imported and sold. How much better would it be, for all classes of
                        our people, if all this money were kept, and expended among ourselves!</p>
                    <p>So much for the material manufactures.--Let us now say a word in regard to
                        the educational and moral manufacture of enlightened and elevated Christians
                        gentlemen and ladies, from the crude material that is annually brought to
                        our schools!</p>
                    <p>Situated as Staunton is, in a healthful and beautiful region, exempt from
                        malaria and epidemic diseases; in a country abounding in supplies--midway
                        between the University, on one hand, and Washington College, and the
                        Military Institute, on the other, and in close proximity to the world
                        renowned Watering places of Virginia, it has peculiar advantages as a centre
                        of female education, for the Southern, and will soon have, for the Western
                        and Middle States.</p>
                    <p>It is now accessible from the North East, and South, by railroads already
                        built, and soon will be for the West, by the extension of the Chesapeake
                        &amp; Ohio R.R. Young gentlemen coming to either the colleges above
                        named can bring their sisters, and leave them here, and then go to the
                        College of their choice. Parents, too, when they come to the Springs, can
                        accompany their daughters to this point, or if they be already here can
                        visit them, in going to and from the Watering places west of us. Here, the
                        young ladies will have the assurances of good health and exemption from the
                        annoyance of beaux, and other malign influences, which might, in a less
                        favored locality, distract their minds from their studies!</p>
                    <p>These are no mere conjectural advantages. They have been verified by actual
                        experiment. We already have three female schools, of the highest order, in
                        our town, under the patronage of the Episcopal, Presbyterian and Methodist
                        denominations. All the schools have, by their admirable management, so
                        effectually commended themselves to public favor, that we believe, they are
                        all now filled to the extent of their means of accommodation.</p>
                    <p>The "old fogy" idea of jealousy, between these schools, has been completely
                        exploded. The enlightened principles know, that the more schools we have,
                        the better. Each, instead of injuring, tends to stimulate the others to
                        greater effort and diligence. And we believe that those having charge of the
                        existing schools, would be gratified if the Baptists, Lutherans, and
                        Catholics, would each establish similar schools.</p>
                    <p>We venture, then, to urge our fellow citizens of these denominations, to
                        bestir themselves, to carry that desirable object into effect. We do so, not
                        only for the benefit of their children, but for the promotion of the general
                        cause of education, and the advancement of the interests of the town. There
                        is no good reason why we should not have six or seven hundred young ladies
                        educated here annually.</p>
                    <p>If this were the case, it would be hard to over-estimate the advantages that
                        would flow from it. Two or three hundred thousand dollars, expended every
                        year, in a community like ours would make a marked difference in every
                        branch of business. Such an outlay would promote all classes of society.
                        Farmers, merchants, grocers, milliners, mantua- makers, and shoe-makers,
                        would all receive their share. And besides the immediate expenses of the
                        pupils, there would be important advantages to our Hotel-keepers, from the
                        numerous visitors, friends and relatives of the pupils, who would be
                        attracted by the presence of so many young ladies.</p>
                    <p>We can hardly persuade ourselves, that the Baptists, Lutherans, and Catholics
                        are more indifferent in regard to education, or less enterprising than other
                        denominations. They are only a little slow in their movements. Our purpose
                        in writing this article is, to spur them up, by calling their attention to
                        the necessity of prompt and energetic action.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The author discusses both the increase in manufactures and the various
                    denominational female academies to illustrate the growth and future prosperity
                    of Staunton. In typical fashion, the great wealth in the area's natural
                    resources is discussed. Further, several examples of how these resources can be
                    applied to new manufactures, such a blast furnaces, is described. Female
                    academies illustrate an additional source of economic prosperity. Simply based
                    on an influx of pupils, expenditures will undoubtedly rise.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1869.11.18.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that the employees of the boot and shoe factory of Hendry
                    Brothers and Fagan on Augusta Street are on strike for higher wages.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Fire</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pane</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The blacksmith shop of James Pane was destroyed by fire on Friday night.
                    "Pane is an honest and industrious colored man, and, therefore, a sum sufficient
                    to re-build his shop has been subscribed by our citizens."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Stonewall Band</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We feel confident that the people of Staunton and vicinity will rejoice to
                        learn that this old and popular band of Music has been reorganized by the
                        adoption of a constitution and by-laws for its government, and the election
                        of the following officers: President, E.M. Cushing; Secretary and Treasurer,
                        S.C. Baskins; Leader, Prof. A.J. Turner, and Assistant Leader, T.M. Turner.
                        This band was organized several years before the war, and during the war it
                        served faithfully and efficiently up to the surrender of Lee's army at
                        Appomattox Court-house, since which time it has had no regular
                        organization.--The Messrs., Turner, father and son, are accomplished
                        musicians, and we have no doubt that the band, under their able leadership
                        will soon be enabled to afford to our citizens a number of musical
                        entertainments worthy of its ancient reputation. With all our hearts, we say
                        let the band be liberally encouraged.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cushing</ln>
                        <fn>E. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baskins</ln>
                        <fn>S. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turner</ln>
                        <fn>A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turner</ln>
                        <fn>T. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>This article offers a brief description of the Stonewall band, recently
                    reorganized and expected to bring great delight to the citizens of Staunton.
                    Included is a list of newly elected band officers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shover</ln>
                        <fn>Henry P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schwartz</ln>
                        <fn>Stacy A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shumate</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>See</ln>
                        <fn>C. S. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Henry P. Shover and Miss Stacy A. Schwartz, both of Augusta, were married
                    at Thomas Shumate's near Fishersville on November 10th by the Rev. C. S. M. See.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hawpe</ln>
                        <fn>J. W. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boone</ln>
                        <fn>Amanda</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boone</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hawes</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. W. T. Hawpe of Greenville and Miss Amanda Boone, daughter of Daniel
                    Boone of Rockingham, were married at the residence of the bride's father near
                    Port Republic on November 3rd by the Rev. Hawes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>E. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barry</ln>
                        <fn>Mattie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>W. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>E. M. Brown, formerly of Staunton, and Miss Mattie Barry of Georgia were
                    married in Georgia at the residence of Col. W. J. Anderson on October 2nd.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phelps</ln>
                        <fn>E. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carrington</ln>
                        <fn>Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Herr</ln>
                        <fn>William L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Morgan</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. E. P. Phelps of Staunton and Mrs. Jane Carrington of Texas were
                    married at the residence of William L. Herr on October 16th by the Rev. J. B.
                    Morgan.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Southards</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Andrew J. Southards died in Staunton of consumption on November 4th. He was
                    83 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGuffin</ln>
                        <fn>Anna Givens</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGuffin</ln>
                        <fn>Sue M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGuffin</ln>
                        <fn>D. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Anna Givens McGuffin, daughter of D. C. and Sue M. McGuffin, died at Fort
                    Lewis, near Staunton, on November 8th. She was 10 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wise</ln>
                        <fn>Julia E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Callaghan</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wise</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Julia E. Wise, daughter of Charles Callaghan and wife of David Wise,
                    died at Milboro on October 25th. She was 39 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1869.11.18.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
