<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1869/va.au.vv.1869.03.25">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>09/16/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1869-03-25">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day norm="">25</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1869.03.25.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1869.03.25.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Valedictory</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garber</ln>
                        <fn>A. M.</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A. M. Garber, Jr., takes leave of the public as editor of the Valley
                    Virginian. In his farewell address, he makes clear that he has not had control
                    over content for several months, and does not agree with everything that has
                    appeared on the editorial page.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Evils of Intemperance</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>There are every day occurrences that call to our minds the evil and
                        depressing effects of drink. It is Whiskey that has taken the glow of health
                        from the cheek, the lustre from the eye, strength from the limbs and
                        vitality from the blood. It is Whiskey that has entered the temple of
                        thought and dethroned reason--that has taken the beam of intelligence from
                        the eye--has bribed the tongue to utter falsehoods--broken the ties of
                        friendship, has made the indulgent father a brute and the affectionate
                        mother a fiend that has filled our prison houses with men whose business has
                        been crushed and broken up by the too free use of ardent spirits.</p>
                    <p>What a fearful record indeed, and what a wide field for the display of
                        christian virtues. Let us unite the many examples that come up before us and
                        take warning in time, for fear of death and destruction may come upon us
                        when we least expect. One thing is certain, no man can prosper and become a
                        good member of society who continues a course of dissipation. It gives us
                        great pleasure to notice the efforts made by the old and new associations of
                        Friends of Temperance of our town. May they continue to flourish, and may
                        the good effects of their teachings be visible in our community a thousand
                        fold.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article supports the efforts of the Friends of Temperance. Whiskey,
                    the author states, is at the heart of a number of social, intellectual, and
                    financial shortcomings. It causes people's businesses to fail, it effects
                    reason, and "bribes the tongue" to speak falsehoods. The time to do away with
                    the evil of drink has arrived, particularly since death can come at any time.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Lorenzo S. Sibert</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>This gentleman viewed as an inventive genius is one of the most remarkable
                        men in the Old Dominion. Let us glance at a few chapters in his history for
                        the past eight years. In 60 or 61 he invented a gun, which far surpassed any
                        previous invention; and it would have been of incalculable service to the
                        greatest of Generals, Lee, during the late unpleasantness, but for some
                        light fingered gentlemen, belonging to that superior race of men, known by
                        the euphonious appellation of Yankee, who purloined the model from the
                        patent office at Washington. Within the past few months he has also invented
                        innumerable useful articles, the most prominent of which being manganese
                        steel; and for the manufacture of which he has formed a co-partnership with
                        some large capitalists, and is making extensive preparations. It is the
                        design of the company to erect about fifty dwellings for the accommodation
                        of laborers who are daily making application to them for employment.</p>
                    <p>They propose erecting four or five large furnaces in the near future, which
                        will render necessary the employment of hundreds of artisans, and, of
                        course, a portion of the application which they are now receiving, meet with
                        favor.</p>
                    <p>In selecting managers for the company Mr. Sibert has displayed judgment which
                        would be flattering to a man of the most exalted ability and
                    penetration.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lauding the virtues of inventor Lorenzo Sibert, the author points out one
                    important invention that could have helped the Confederate cause, and another
                    invention that will certainly benefit post-war Virginia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p> The Richmond <emph rend="italic">Whig</emph> says: "There are many cheering
                        indications of the approach of better times in Virginia. The lines drawn by
                        the war are beginning to grow faint, and passions that raged with violence
                        are fast cooling down. Party ties are rapidly loosening, while personal
                        bitterness is every hour diminishing. Men who have been divided by a gulf
                        that seemed impassable have come together in familiar converse, and are
                        beginning to learn that they have more in common than they believed
                        possible. All good men, all reflecting men, all who have a stake in the
                        community, and who desire to re-establish order, tranquility and prosperity
                        in the State, begin to realize that past troubles and differences should no
                        longer divide them, since such divisions will be the means of handing over
                        to corrupt and incompetent men the control of our affairs. There is, indeed,
                        no reason who men of integrity, character and intelligence, whatever may
                        have been their past difference, should longer stand in opposition to each
                        other. Virginia needs the help of all her sons, native and adopted. They
                        must lock shields, and, with faces to the front, stand shoulder to shoulder
                        in the good cause.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article, reproduced from the Richmond Whig, looks to the future with
                    optimism. The author suggests that time has come for reconciliatory efforts. All
                    those who in the past have had differences should come together to work against
                    oppressive people who desire to control Virginia. Only then, can Virginians once
                    again enjoy peace and prosperity.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1869.03.25.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Circuit Court</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fultz</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burnett</ln>
                        <fn>W. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>David Fultz qualified as judge of the district including Augusta before W.
                    A. Burnett, N. P. His predecessor Judge Sheffey is planning to move to
                    Baltimore.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Charlottesville Chronicle</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Rev. Tyree is now leading a revival at the Baptist Church in
                    Charlottesville.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cease</ln>
                        <fn>M. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Evans</ln>
                        <fn>D. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper bids farewell to M. S. Cease and D. E. Evans, two "esteemed
                    citizens" who are taking leave of Staunton. "They are kind-hearted genial
                    gentlemen, and of the most obliging dispositions. May they be blessed with an
                    ample abundance while inhabitants of mundanity, and when they are transplanted
                    to another world may it be the one in which those dwell who have crossed the
                    'Valley of The Shadow of Death' and stand triumphantly on the further shore."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Conference Appointments</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hott</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Virginia Annual Conference of the United Brethren in Christ appointed
                    J. W. Hott preacher for Churchville.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Valley Railroad Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tate</ln>
                        <fn>William M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hotchkiss</ln>
                        <fn>Jed</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>Bolivar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fultz</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echols</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>A. H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>J. Marshall</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickle</ln>
                        <fn>Robert G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gallaher</ln>
                        <fn>H. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>C. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hogshead</ln>
                        <fn>M. W. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grattan</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mauzy</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lynn</ln>
                        <fn>W. H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crockwell</ln>
                        <fn>J. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>Marshall</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>W. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hansberger</ln>
                        <fn>R. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>William F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bruce</ln>
                        <fn>G. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>Chesley</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guy</ln>
                        <fn>R. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craig</ln>
                        <fn>J. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parkins</ln>
                        <fn>I. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A group of citizens met at the Court House to appoint a delegation to
                    travel to Baltimore to lobby that city for a $1,000,000 subscription to the
                    stock of the Valley Railroad Company.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Military Appointments for Augusta Co.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The following appointments were made in Augusta: Samuel A. East replaced
                    William A. Burnett as Clerk of the County Court; R. D. Sears replaced Joseph N.
                    Ryan as Clerk of the Circuit Court; William Armstrong replaced James Wilson,
                    William Link replaced Thomas J. Burke, W. W. Clinedinst replaced George A.
                    Bruce, F. M. Finley replaced Absalom Koiner, John H. Dalhouse replaced John L.
                    Ellis, John Silor replaced A. A. Mcpheeters, William W. Thomas replaced W. F.
                    Smith, William Gibson, Jr., replaced Lewis Bumgardner, George Reubush replaced
                    William T. Rush, Joseph A. Miller replaced James F. Hite, Henry Mish replaced B.
                    O. Ferguson, William Morgan replaced B. F. Hailman, and Joseph T. Mitchell
                    replaced B. F. Points as Magistrates; Erasmus L. Houff replaced John G. Stover,
                    and Henry B. Jones replaced Thomas M. Donoho as Commissioner of the Revenue; J.
                    H. B. Shultz replaced George M. Apple, George L. Archart replaced Adam Rusmisel,
                    John K. Kayser replaced William M. Bush, Jacob Ewing replaced A. T. Grooms,
                    James F. Davis replaced E. J. Bell, and William A. Reed replaced John H. Heizer
                    as Constables; Joseph A. Miller replaced James E. Beard, and Benjamin M. Lines
                    replaced Fred Burns as Overseers of the Poor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roots</ln>
                        <fn>Junius F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Croft</ln>
                        <fn>Mary A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>See</ln>
                        <fn>C. S. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Junius F. Roots and Mrs. Mary A. Croft, both of Augusta, were married near
                    Christian's Creek on March 16th by the Rev. C. S. M. See.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bolen</ln>
                        <fn>J. Edwin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hopewell</ln>
                        <fn>Sallie T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carson</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. Edwin Bolen and Sallie T. Hopewell were married in Mt. Solon on March
                    21st by the Rev. Thomas C. Carson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCorkle</ln>
                        <fn>John S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>Mary J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hogshead</ln>
                        <fn>Elijah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoge</ln>
                        <fn>P. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John S. McCorkle and Mrs. Mary J. White were married near Middlebrook at
                    the residence of Elijah Hogshead by the Rev. P. C. Hoge.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Graham</ln>
                        <fn>J. W. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Graham</ln>
                        <fn>Lizzie J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pearson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. W. T. Graham of Greenville, Augusta County, and Miss Lizzie J. Graham of
                    Missouri were married in Missouri on March 4th by the Rev. Pearson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swoope</ln>
                        <fn>Washington</fn>
                        <sf>Sr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Washington Swoope, Sr., died at his residence at Swoope's Depot on March
                    11th. He was 73 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eidson</ln>
                        <fn>Bettie J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eidson</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Bettie J. Eidson, daughter of Henry Eidson of Augusta, died suddenly
                    in Baltimore on March 19th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huffner</ln>
                        <fn>Anna M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huffner</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Anna M. Huffner, maiden daughter of the late Michael Huffner, died on North
                    River near Mt. Solon on March 15th. She was 67 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Litten</ln>
                        <fn>Abram</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Abram Litten died on Middle River below Spring Hill on March 16th. He was
                    87 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1869.03.25.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
