<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1869/va.au.vv.1869.02.18">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>09/15/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1869-02-18">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day norm="">18</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1869.02.18.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1869.02.18.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Present Duty of Virginia Statesmanship</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p> It must be apparent to every thinking mind, that a new State Government for
                        Virginia will be created in the immediate future. It is equally inevitable,
                        that the Government will be established on the basis of negro suffrage.
                        Should the Underwood Constitution, as it stands, be voted on and defeated,
                        this, while it may <sic>pospone,</sic> it will not prevent the establishment
                        of a "reconstructed" Government; nor will it prevent "negro suffrage" from
                        being incorporated into the new constitution. Many political elements will
                        influence the formation of this new government, entirely beyond the control
                        of the hitherto governing classes of Virginia. These new political elements
                        may not be legitimate, may even be revolutionary usurpation, but they are
                        fixed and unalterable political facts, powerful political influences, which
                        will certainly shape and modify the fundamental laws under which all the
                        interests of all the people of Virginia must find protection, or destruction
                        for years to come. It is now the duty of political statesmanship, to deal
                        with all the elements that will constitute the formation of the new
                        Government, not as principles, but as facts, and so to deal with these facts
                        as will secure for the people of Virginia the best constitution and the best
                        Government possible under the existing circumstances.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The author informs his reader that, whether they may like it or not, the
                    fact remains that "negro suffrage" will be a component of reconstructed
                    Virginia. Time has come for the political classes of Virginia to acknowledge
                    this fact, accept it, and work for the best possible constitution under "the
                    existing circumstances."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Gen. Lee's Position</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article argues that Gen. Lee is in favor of the "New Movement," though
                    its political opponents try to keep that fact from the public.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Radical Party</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p> It is a fact not to be disguised that the party is daily receiving large
                        accessions to its strength in Richmond, from those who want office--many of
                        those too who are "going over" now are men who held respectable if not high
                        stations among us. <lb/><emph rend="italic">Richmond Correspondence to the
                            Index.</emph></p>
                    <p> There are men in Augusta county, we are sorry to say, who have prostituted
                        themselves by joining the Radical party, or in other words, have become
                            <emph rend="italic">scalawags</emph> through choice. What a fall to be
                        sure, and what a change to come over men who, at one time, not only gloried
                        in being called rebels but were among the first to proclaim their
                        secessionist proclivities.</p>
                    <p>What is the object of all this? We answer, office. Mr.
                        Blood-and-Thunder-kill-all-the-yankees wants and office and does not care
                        how he gets it. Now we do not consider such men fit associates of the honest
                        union men, through and through, and must confess our surprise that they are
                        tolerated by them.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The author of this article exposes the political self-interest of the white
                    southerner who has joined the Radical party. These scalawags are seen by their
                    former associates as betraying the South for the sake of office. Adding further
                    insult, the author illustrates that many of these men were once the most
                    vehement supporters of secession.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Petersburg Index says: "Whenever the measure of the late political
                        movements in Virginia shall be correctly taken--their originators and
                        participators will obtain credit for having accomplished much which is as
                        yet unacknowledged, the assailants of those who commenced and have carried
                        on the recent effort for pacification, have, without exception, lost sight
                        of one important point in stating or arguing what has been done. Let it be
                        remembered that when the Richmond Conference assembled, Congress, according
                        to the best authority, was about to order an election in Virginia--an
                        election which offered the Underwood Constitution with no alternative to
                        this people. So the Republican State Committee had announced, and to this
                        belief the Conservative Committee assembled in December. As to the result of
                        an election held at the time then proposed, and under the circumstances then
                        obtaining, there can be no doubt. We should have passed under the abominable
                        yoke of the Constitution referred to, having the additional certain
                        infliction of officers to execute its provisions who would have been chosen
                        altogether from that class from whom Virginia, and Virginians of all parties
                        and races, have most to fear--the impudent, unprincipled carpet bag element
                        of which Wells is the master-spirit and the truest representative.</p>
                    <p>This was the fate to preserve the State from which the "new movement" was
                        undertaken. And certainly some degree of success has attended the effort.
                        The election has not been had--and every day which passes is a day gained--a
                        day in which reason and interest, and the thousand natural influences which
                        will at last produce harmonious reconstruction, are at work to render more
                        improbable the fastening of an oppressive fraud upon the people of Virginia.
                        We think that in the intervals of abuse our opponents might at least do the
                        Conference and its Committee the justice to admit this much.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article reproduced from the Petersburg Index illustrates the success
                    of the "new movement" in staving off the passing of the "Underwood
                    Constitution." Wells, the "truest representative" of oppressive carpetbag
                    politicians, is described as both impudent and unprincipled.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>General Stoneman appointed the following magistrates for Augusta County:
                    Samuel Landis replaced William Crawford; Zachariah Colbreath replaced John J.
                    Ellis; Robert Terril replaced George A. Bruce; Frank N. Myers replaced J. Y.
                    Bell; John Wissler replaced William Chapman; David Myers replaced S. B. Finley;
                    Elijah Curry replaced D. N. Vaughan; Charles Bates replaced Joseph D. Patterson;
                    John A. Blune replaced William J. Sterrett; Henry R. Eakle replaced James D.
                    Craig; Alexander Anderson replaced E. M. Curshing; John Smith replaced John M.
                    Huff; Samuel Cline replaced Theophilus Gamble; Jacob Bean replaced Joe W.
                    Cahoon; William Showalter replaced J. Marshal McCue; George A. Sherry replaced
                    James Wilson; James F. Maupin replaced Charles C. Francisco; Jacob Stover
                    replaced Absalom Koiner; David Fink replaced Henry Edson; Henry Rippitoe
                    replaced William W. Montgomery; David Fishburner replaced William D. Anderson;
                    Abner Shumake replaced T. J. Burke; David L. Snyder replaced Christy Minny;
                    Militus G. Jones replaced John C. Rivercombe. In other appointments, Robert G.
                    Bickle replaced Ira Benedict as member of the Staunton council; John H. Johns
                    replaced Joseph Wilson as overseer of the poor for Augusta.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1869.02.18.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Inauguration</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper sarcastically reports that "a number of the Colored Aristocracy
                    of Staunton" are preparing to go to Washington for the inauguration. They are
                    having "fine clothing made up." "You bet they will be able to hold their own."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Baptist Church</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The extended revival at the Baptist Church ended on Sunday. 28 new people
                    joined the church during the meetings.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>National Life Insurance Company</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phillips</ln>
                        <fn>Reuben T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reuben T. Phillips has been appointed agent of the National Life Insurance
                    Company for the district that includes Augusta.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Magann</ln>
                        <fn>Merritt W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stover</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>See</ln>
                        <fn>C. S. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Merritt W. Magann of Nelson County and Miss Elizabeth Stover of Augusta
                    were married near Stuart's Draft on February 4th by the Rev. C. S. M. See.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Catlett</ln>
                        <fn>Nannie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Nannie Catlett died in Staunton on February 15th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Poe</ln>
                        <fn>U. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>U. D. Poe died on February 10th at his residence near Spring Hill. He was
                    62 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cleary</ln>
                        <fn>Nicholas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Nicholas Cleary died on February 12th after a short illness of congestion
                    of the lungs. He was 53 years old. Cleary studied law and served as a judge in
                    California where he earned distinction. After returning to Washington, he was
                    sent to China as a US Navy Storekeeper. "Judge Cleary was a ripe scholar, gifted
                    with strong mental powers. He was social, witty and generous, and by all his
                    natural instincts a high toned gentleman. Although comparative a stranger in
                    Staunton, his funeral was attended by an unusually large concourse of the most
                    respectable citizens of the place." The Catholic Schools all paid their
                    respects. He is survived by a young wife.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1869.02.18.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
