<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1869/va.au.vv.1869.09.02">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>09/29/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1869-09-02">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day norm="">2</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1869.09.02.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1869.09.02.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Legislature Elect, and the Iron-clad Oath</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p> If we are to judge from the tone of the Northern press--that is, the liberal
                        portion of it, Radical Democratic and Conservative, we are of opinion that
                        the sentiment of the country is much against the position Gen. Canby has
                        taken. The <emph rend="italic">Tribune</emph> and the <emph rend="italic"
                            >Times,</emph> both leading Radical journals of New York are outspoken
                        and denounce the forcing of the oath on legislators fairly elected by the
                        people. The <emph rend="italic">State Journal,</emph> the Radical organ of
                        Virginia, has given birth to the report that Gen Canby has issued a circular
                        to the members elect, asking whether they can take the iron-clad oath, and
                        requesting a response. As yet no replies have been received at
                        head-quarters, and the military overseer is at a loss how to act. His
                        quandary arises from the fact that to require a member of the Legislature to
                        take an oath of any kind there must first be a creation to the Legislature;
                        the body must be informally organized, otherwise the man chosen by the
                        people is a mere individual, free from the requirements of the tyrannical
                        order. Presuming even that there is an organization of the Legislature by
                        the appointment of a temporary chairman and clerk, we are at a loss to know
                        how the military commander can manage to get before a body of lawfully
                        chosen and not yet completely organized?--Should he go in person he will
                        render himself liable to be arrested as a trespasser upon the meeting of
                        individuals who have lawfully met for the purposes of consultation on
                        affairs of State. The office he holds is unknown to the constitution of the
                        State, and he is not, like the Governor, armed with the privilege of sending
                        a message. How then, we ask, is he to administer the oath? Some say he can
                        send his aid with a squad of soldiers to drive the members out. Should he
                        attempt such high-handed game, he must drive out <emph rend="italic"
                        >all</emph> --those who can and those who cannot take the oath; thus
                        breaking up the Legislature and laying the violence of such proceedings at
                        his own door. The Baltimore <emph rend="italic">Commercial</emph> says--</p>
                    <p>"It remains with the Legislature of Virginia whether it or General Canby
                        shall carry the point of this oath-taking. A form and resolute body of men
                        cannot be intimidated, and though they may be outraged by the use of force,
                        their defeat by that instrumentality will be their triumph."</p>
                    <p> The comments of the N. Y. <emph rend="italic">Tribune</emph> are to the
                        point, and reflect the sentiments of the people of all parties. It says--</p>
                    <p>"We protest against this programme as involving perfidy, iniquity, and a most
                        stupendous blunder. The only party that can be harmed by it is (as in
                        Georgia) that which conceived and executed it. We have an overwhelming
                        Republican majority in the Senate, so that there is not the poor rascally
                        excuse of necessity to perpetuate it. It is calculated to alienate the
                        Walker Republicans permanently from the National party and give the
                        Democrats such an advantage everywhere as the Georgia blunder gave us last
                        Fall. It is a resort prompted by the mortification of defeat; but the
                        Republicans of the whole country cannot afford to sacrifice themselves on
                        the alter of Well's discomfiture."</p>
                    <p>The same paper also adds that the Government of Virginia, under a new
                        constitution is in no proper sense provisional, Gen. Canby has no part nor
                        lot therein, whether by law of Congress or State Constitution. His effort to
                        interfere and to dictate will be repugnant to that sense of legislative
                        independence which is so relished by the American people.</p>
                    <p> The Baltimore <emph rend="italic">Commercial</emph> uses the following
                        language--</p>
                    <p>It is now most probable that there will be no session of the Legislature
                        until after the Congress assembles. We have no fear that the Congress will
                        insist upon so mean a piece of perfidy. The motive is not sufficient for an
                        act of such dishonor. There is nothing to gain by such a stupendous blunder,
                        and it will not be perpetuated. But if in this we are mistaken, we think
                        there will be found in the Virginia Legislature men firm enough to place
                        General Canby in the attitude of employing his bayonets to drive away the
                        Legislature of Virginia. And better than that, there is nothing that could
                        happen to the Legislature.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The primary focus of the article is to illustrate the mood of the majority
                    of the country concerning the iron-clad oath. The author suggest that most
                    liberals, radical Democrats, and conservatives are against it. He rejects the
                    position of General Canby, who proposes that elected legislators should be able
                    to take the oath. Any efforts to enforce the oath will be "repugnant" to
                    "legislative independence."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Another Outrage</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports an alleged assault by a black man upon a white woman in
                    Middleburg, Virginia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1869.09.02.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Catholic Fair</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A fair to raise money for the Catholic schoolhouse being erected on the
                    grounds of St. Francis Church will begin on September 8th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Rev. Dr. Munsey lectured on "Man" before a crowd of 200 at the
                    Methodist Church. All were "pleased and instructed by the peculiar manner and
                    rare eloquence of the learned divine."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Steam Sash and Blind Factory</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shome</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The newly erected Steam, Sash, and Blind Factory is adding to the
                    industrial importance of Staunton. Mr. Shome's company is located on the
                    railroad in the western suburbs of Staunton. Shome is "a man of great business
                    energy and employs none but experienced hands. His machinery is of the latest
                    and most approved invention and works with great accuracy and rapidity."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheets</ln>
                        <fn>David T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huff</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>David T. Sheets and Miss Sarah C. Huff, both of Augusta, were married on
                    August 10th by the Rev. C. Beard.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fry</ln>
                        <fn>Newton A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Eugene A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Newton A. Fry and Miss Eugene A. Brown, both of Augusta, were married in
                    Waynesboro on August 16th by the Rev. C. Beard.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bush</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Terrell</ln>
                        <fn>Martha</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richardson</ln>
                        <fn>W. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Alexander Bush and Miss Martha Terrell, both of Augusta, were married in
                    Waynesboro on August 19th by the Rev. W. T. Richardson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schreckhise</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Schreckhise died on North River on August 18th. He was 72 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ewing</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jacob Ewing died in Spring Hill on August 27th. He was 63 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1869.09.02.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
