<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1869/va.au.vv.1869.09.16">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>09/29/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1869-09-16">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day norm="">16</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1869.09.16.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1869.09.16.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p> The State <emph rend="italic">Journal</emph> says that Hon. A.H.H. Stuart
                        and Col. John B. Baldwin are spoken of for the U.S. Senate, in "Democratic
                        circles;" but, it says, the "Walker Republicans" deprecate the movement, and
                        propose Franklin Stearns and John F. Lewis. We think that, so far from
                        deprecating "the movement," the "Walker party" would, in the event of the
                        removal of their disabilities, elect to the U.S. Senate the first named
                        gentlemen. And why? </p>
                    <p>First. Because they are two of the most able and distinguished personages in
                        the State, and their election to the honorable position would be attended
                        with the most pleasant results.</p>
                    <p>Second. Because it is to their untiring energy and lofty patriotism, more
                        than anything else, that we owe the separate submission, to the voters of
                        the State, of the rejected clauses of the New Constitution.</p>
                    <p>Third. Because they were the first to inaugurate the movement which resulted
                        in the complete overthrow of the Wells party, the utter demolition of
                        extreme Radicalism in this State; the triumph of the Walker party.</p>
                    <p>Yes, they exerted every effort to wrestle the State from the grasp of the
                        plunder-loving carpet-bagger, and unprincipled scalawag, and that, too,
                        without a single ray of hope of reaping any reward, so far as the filling of
                        fat offices was concerned. And now, that hitherto wrecked ship of State has
                        unfurled her sails and thrown them to the breeze, and is now being wafted
                        back into the "glorious Unum" without, seemingly, any further opposition, we
                        are of opinion that the press of the State should accord them the praise
                        they so eminently deserve, if the Legislature cannot reward them in a more
                        solid manner--by electing them to the U.S. Senate.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>A. H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The author praises the several virtues of Stauntonians Stuart and Baldwin,
                    arguing that they deserve seats in the U.S. Senate. These men, founders of the
                    "new movement," are owed heavily by the people of Virginia for ridding the state
                    of the Wells party and the objectionable clauses of the new Constitution.
                    Without them, the author suggests, the state would more than likely still be
                    under the control of carpetbaggers and unprincipled scalawags.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>How are you Mr. Tukey</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p> Mr. Tukey, ex-Freedmen's Bureau agent, and carpet-bag landed in our town on
                        Tuesday last. It will be remembered that this distinguished C.B. was the
                        opponent of J.C. Southall, Esq, for a seat in the Convention held in 1867,
                        and was defeated. He conceived the idea that is was morally impossible for a
                        gentleman that had figured so long and successfully in the political world
                        to be defeated in a fair election, and so contested the seat of his
                        distinguished antagonist, but without avail. Nothing daunted, he packed up
                        his portable goods, took passage on the Chesapeake and O. R.R. and in due
                        time reached the County of Caroline, where the negro majority was large,
                        and, consequently, where he thought the attempt to enter, by means of the
                        said negro majority, the House of Delegates, would be as easy as it would be
                        for an adept in the art of "lifting" to relieve you of a ten dollar bill,
                        when you <sic>were'nt</sic> "looking." But, alas for the hopes of the
                        subject of this article, he never was permitted to carry his imposing and
                        dignified form into the House of Delegates--Oh! no, he was again defeated.
                        Now he is perambulating about the country, reviewing the scenes of past
                        defeat, preparatory to his final departure from a State that would not
                        gratify his ambitious soul by cleaving him to a position that would afford
                        him the means of subsistence, and consequently, obviate the necessity of his
                        longer haranguing the negroes. O, ye gods and little fishes! <emph
                            rend="italic">can't</emph> you help poor Tukey to an office?</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tukey</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Southall</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Heavy with sarcasm, this article alerts the citizens of Staunton of the
                    arrival of carpetbagger and ex-Freedman's Bureau agent, Mr. Tukey. Illustrating
                    his office-seeking exploits, the author suggests that he is up to his usual
                    tricks.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1869.09.16.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Catholic Fair</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Catholic Fair raised $850 toward rebuilding St. Francis School-house.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Gipsies</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A number of this "fortune-telling tribe" have been encamped near Staunton
                    "plying their vocation among the race of Sambo and Dina."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tams</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guy</ln>
                        <fn>R. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Drake</ln>
                        <fn>D. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spitler</ln>
                        <fn>Wayne</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Staunton Musical Association has been reorganized and officers elected.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Post-Office Removed</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bagby</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sears</ln>
                        <fn>Ed H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Noon</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stover</ln>
                        <fn>Willie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Post Office has moved to the building on Augusta Street recently
                    erected by B. F. Bagby. Ed H. Sears and "his popular assistant" J. A. Noon will
                    continue to efficiently serve the public. "Our youthful little friend, Willie
                    Stover, has a weakness for waiting on ladies which we hope they will indulge."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dooley</ln>
                        <fn>James H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>May</ln>
                        <fn>Sallie O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elder</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weed</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Fr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James H. Dooley of Richmond and Miss Sallie O. May, formerly of Luenburg,
                    were married in Staunton at the residence of Maj. Elder on September 11th by the
                    Rev. Father Weed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kent</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn>Virginia F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Joseph F. Kent of Wythe and Miss Virginia F. Peyton of Staunton were
                    married at the residence of Col. John B. Baldwin on September 11th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clemmer</ln>
                        <fn>Trusie E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lantz</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John M. Baylor of Middlebrook and Miss Trusie E. Clemmer of the vicinity
                    were married on September 9th by the Rev. J. Lantz.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shiplett</ln>
                        <fn>Ella</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shiplett</ln>
                        <fn>Eliza</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shiplett</ln>
                        <fn>Givens</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Ella Shiplett, daughter of Givens and Eliza Shiplett, died on August 30th.
                    She was 1 year old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn>George M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. George M. King died at the Mountain Top House on September 3rd. He was
                    31 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1869.09.16.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
