<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1869/va.au.vv.1869.07.15">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>09/27/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1869-07-15">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day norm="">15</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1869.07.15.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1869.07.15.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>After the Battle</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p> The press all over the country, with the exception of the ultra-Radicals of
                        the Forney stamp, congratulate the old State of Virginia on the triumphant
                        victory she has gained over carpet-bag invaders and unprincipled scalawags.
                        "All hail!" comes form every quarter, industry and enterprise are turning
                        their faces hither, State stock is on the rise, and peace and plenty are
                        already the boon of the patriots who bravely repelled the
                        <sic>onslough</sic> of the enemy. And is it not a Waterloo defeat? Walker's
                        majority is put down at between 25,000 and 30,000, and the majority in the
                        Legislature on the joint ballot at 60. we have also elected five members of
                        Congress out of eight. But the greatest victory of all is the triumph over
                        principle that, had they been established, would have proven a strain upon
                        the escutcheon of an ancient and honorable State. The hateful clauses in the
                        new constitution are blotted out, and, though there are yet objectionable
                        portions left, yet the instrument is far preferable to bayonet rule. We need
                        not fear but the old State will now go "marching on" to prosperity; for the
                        weak attempt to subvert her free policy has failed for ever, for the beaten
                        party can never rally again; they are routed horse, foot and dragoons--their
                        leader has migrated, and they have no nucleus around which to gather.</p>
                    <p> In its despair the Washington <emph rend="italic">Chronicle</emph> (one of
                        Forney's <sic>dalies</sic>) exclaims: "All is not lost in Virginia. Congress
                        holds the key." This is a broad hint that Congress will overturn the
                        election, and decree a new one.--Let the usurpers dare attempt so
                        high-handed a game--indignant cries will ring from the confines of the land
                        to its very centre. They have acted outside the constitution long
                        enough--and the people are beginning to be sick of the rule of fifth-rate
                        men and money-bags. Has not the policy recommended by President Grant been
                        adhered to by the Walker party, and is he not the head and front of the
                        dominant party? Was not the election quiet and orderly though bloodshed was
                        anticipated by many? From the mountains to the seaboard order reigned on
                        that eventful day, and we have yet to read the record of a single fraud
                        worthy of notice. But as a defeated candidate remarked on the day of the
                        election when he was compelled to swallow his own words: "All's fair in
                        politics." We presume the Radicals who "hold the key," think it best to keep
                        alive party rancor, and to educate the ignorant colored race to hatred of
                        the Southern whites. Unfortunately for their policy, the colored people have
                        shown more good sense than the God-forsaken emissaries sent among them by
                        Northern Radicals. They have been made to see, and now stand in the sunlight
                        of Truth. They know who their true friends are, and who will keep them from
                        want and hunger. It will be a folly--an outrage to attempt to re-reconstruct
                        Virginia, and the "key" which Congress holds will be of no more use than
                        that of the Bastille after the building was razed to the ground. The people
                        of the State have quietly submitted to the wishes of the ruling power--they
                        have lowered their heads and humbly solicited peace. Will it not be granted
                        them? Or is the Old Mother of States to cower, like the unruly Julianna,
                        every time her lord Duke lifts the terrible key to her? Virginia has gone as
                        far as she can without the loss of honor, in carrying out the measure of the
                        existing government.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The author of this congratulatory article rejoices in the results of the
                    recent election. He joins his fellow Virginians and "all quarters" of the United
                    States in celebrating the demise of carpetbag and scalawag rule. Although
                    Radicals claim to hold the "key" in Congress, the author is not anxious
                    regarding a possible nullification of the election results. Further, the new
                    constitution passed with many, although not all, of the objectionable clauses
                    removed. Together, the changes resulting from the outcome of the election has
                    lifted the spirits of Virginians and made a promise of future peace and
                    prosperity.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>A Denunciation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper asserts the ex-President Johnson holds President Grant in "utter
                    contempt."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Reconstruction of Virginia</head>
                <origin>Statesman</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p> Some doubt has been expressed whether, now that the Virginia elections go
                        for the Conservatives, Congress will consent to the admission of the State.
                        It shows estimation in which the honor of Congress is held that such a doubt
                        should be expressed. It would be entirely in keeping with its past course
                        and the temper of the Radical party towards the South, to act in such a
                        way.--When the bill empowering Gen. Grant to direct the late election was
                        before the Senate, and Morton, of Indiana, offered the amendment requiring
                        the States mentioned to accept the Fifteenth Amendment to the Constitution
                        before being admitted, Senator Trumbull protested against the imposing of
                        new conditions, saying it had been done before and then, when the States had
                        complied, new terms were imposed, and he feared it might be in the present
                        case. Morton replied to Mr. Trumbull, and said it was absolutely necessary,
                        to the settlement of the negro question, that the Fifteenth Amendment should
                        be adopted, and that the voice of the States embraced in the bill would be
                        necessary to its adoption, and therefore there would be no danger of terms
                        being imposed. If the votes of Virginia, Mississippi and Texas should be
                        essential to that end, they may be admitted. But we have no other guarantee
                        of Radical good faith than party interests.--The Radicals have no moral
                        sense as a party, and stop at nothing for party purposes. Their only
                        principle, beyond their interests, with reference to the South, is malignity
                        and vengeance. They purposely play with their victim, as a cat does with a
                        mouse, exciting hopes that are never intended to be realized. Has Virginia
                        been grasping at a delusion and a snare.<emph rend="italic"
                    >Statesman</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article questions the good faith of the Radical party. Since the
                    Conservative victory in the recent elections, there are those who believe
                    Congress will not allow Virginia to be readmitted to the Union. Congress
                    requires that Virginia first adopt the Fifteenth Amendment. But the issue here
                    is trust. Even if the amendment is adopted, past experience with Radicals
                    suggests that they may suddenly impose new terms. The author is highly skeptical
                    and believes Radicals' only principle is self-interest.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1869.07.15.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>C. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John W. Harris, son of Dr. C. R. Harris of Staunton, made the list of
                    distinguished students at the University of Virginia. "Mr. Harris distinguished
                    himself in his examinations in the school of Medicine and graduated in the chair
                    of Medical Jurisprudence."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The M. E. Church South</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kramer</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Services of the Methodist Church South will be held on alternate Sundays at
                    the Baptist Church. The Rev. George Kramer will preach at the Methodist Church
                    on Sunday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Rejoicings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Walker party celebrated their victory last Friday night. They built a
                    bonfire on Garber's Hill opposite the American Hotel that illuminated the spires
                    of Staunton. They also fired off rockets and fireworks.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCutchen</ln>
                        <fn>James R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>L. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Ms.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilmore</ln>
                        <fn>Harvey</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James R. McCutchen and Miss L. E. Baylor, daughter of Mr. David Baylor,
                    were married near Summerdean on June 24th by the Rev. Harvey Gilmore.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>Eugene</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>W. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>M. V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Eugene Anderson, infant son of Col. W. D. and M. V. Anderson, died on July
                    8th. He was 23 days old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pritchard</ln>
                        <fn>Cora Temple</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pritchard</ln>
                        <fn>J. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pritchard</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Cora Temple Pritchard, daughter of J. T. and Mary Pritchard, died in
                    Staunton on Friday. She was 1 year old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kramer</ln>
                        <fn>Pearce</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kramer</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kramer</ln>
                        <fn>Jennie F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Pearce Kramer, infant son of the Rev. George and Jennie F. Kramer, died in
                    Staunton on Friday. He was 9 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1869.07.15.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
