<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1869/va.au.vv.1869.06.24">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>09/26/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1869-06-24">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="06">June</month>
            <day norm="">24</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1869.06.24.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1869.06.24.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Statesmen Wanted</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p> One of our contemporaries remarks that "One of the greatest calamities to
                        the country which arise from the continued practical exclusion of the
                        Southern States from the Union, is the loss to it of the genius for
                        statesmanship and the conduct of affairs by which the South has always been
                        eminently distinguished." We are not so young but that we can remember
                        vividly the soul-stirring eloquence of Henry Clay, the deep logic and
                        patriotism of John C. Calhoun, the biting sarcasm and originality of John
                        Randolph and the impressive appeals of Preston. In remoter times there were
                        Washington, Jefferson and Madison, whom history delights to honor. Up to the
                        time when the recent unhappy war desolated the Southern fields, the nation
                        looked to the strength of the Southern arm and the wisdom of the Southern
                        brain in its times of trial. But for Washington the first revolution would
                        have proved a failure; but for Jefferson the world would not have read with
                        admiration the declaration of rights which gave rise to that revolution. The
                        fiery eloquence of Patrick Henry stirred up the chivalry of the colonists
                        and filled the ranks of the Northern as well as Southern rebels. Virginia
                        led the way to the union of States and was one of the last to leave that
                        Union. It is allowed even by the bitterest enemies of the South that the
                        weight of political talent was on the side of the South. "When sectionalism
                        threatened collision," says the <emph rend="italic">Statesman,</emph> "the
                        resources of Southern statesmanship were always equal to the emergency and
                        some felicitous compromise carries the ship of State in safety by the edge
                        of the breakers."</p>
                    <p>Where now are those giant minds that controlled the destiny of this once
                        great and glorious nation? They exist among the shadows of the past. And
                        what kind of statesmen are now moulding the "model republic" to suit their
                        own sordid purposes and carry out the political dogmas of a vile and
                        tyrannical party? Would not the ghost of the great Northern "expounder of
                        the constitution," Webster, shrink back into the mist of oblivion, were it
                        now to visit the hall of its former triumphs of eloquence? Sumner, Butler,
                        Wade, Logan, and a host of other pretenders now shape the genius of the
                        Republic, and keep out Southern intellect and energy, through sheer
                        jealously and a fear that treachery may be exposed to the people--the
                        suffering people. "The very sight is portentous of woe--those lean and
                        ill-formed kind, who have eaten up the fat, fleshed and well favored; those
                        empty and blasted ears of corn, which devoured the good and full ears. And a
                        Senate which was once Roman in its dignity and power, and on the very spot
                        where the Southern giants once stood, we now see, as representatives of the
                        South, narrow-browed, stunted, evil-eyed adventurers and scalawags, who look
                        like a combination of the Wandering Jew and Impenitent Thief. And this at a
                        juncture when the country needs more than ever, especially in the state of
                        our foreign relations, its best statesmanship."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article suggests that statesmen, possessing all the genius of the
                    Southern mind, step forward and reclaim the South's preeminent place in the
                    Union. Politics, once dominated by Southern intellectual giants, is now run by
                    the weak-minded. The author calls for the wisdom of the "Southern brain" in the
                    spirit of Washington and Jefferson, Calhoun and Clay, to speak up and rid the
                    country of a "vile tyrannical party."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Register!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper makes a last appeal to the citizens of Augusta to register and
                    vote in reply to a correspondent who asserted the Valley Virginian lagged behind
                    other local papers in this crucial task.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>The Fourth of July</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>State Conservative Committee, <lb/> June 21, 1869. </p>
                    <p>To the Conservatives of Virginia greeting</p>
                    <p>We congratulate you on the cheering signs of Conservative success in all
                        quarters of the State. We have a proposition to make, which we hope will be
                        acceptable to all. The forth of July of this year comes on Sunday. Of yore,
                        when this contingency occurred, the great event of that day was treated with
                        appropriate honors on the Saturday preceding. Another signal redemption, we
                        trust, is about to crown our hopes and efforts, fit to be associated with
                        the other, and fondly commemorated in the future. When the sun sets on the
                        6th of July let it go down on a regenerated land. May Virginians have done a
                        deed which will drive out forever the base and venal adventurers who swarm
                        over the land "harassing our people and eating out their substance," and
                        restore to our beloved State legitimate civil rule. Then, to rouse and
                        animate all to the great work, let barbecues with mass meetings be held on
                        the 3rd of July, throughout the State, where neighbors will meet neighbors,
                        in the old Virginia hearty way, and pledge themselves to each other, that
                        with zeal, energy and determination, they will labor until after the
                        election for this happy consummation.</p>
                    <p> By order of the Committee <lb/> R.T. Daniel, Chairman </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The author connects the celebration of the Fourth of July with a promise of
                    political redemption in the upcoming election. He recommends that people meet
                    the Saturday before the Fourth, pledge themselves to one another, and continue
                    to work until the election has been decided in their favor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1869.06.24.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The ladies of the M. E. Church South are holding a dinner and fair today.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Dog Tax</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that the town council has proposed a $1 tax on all male
                    dogs and a $10 tax on all female dogs to help solve the town's "dog question."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Ho! For the Springs</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper declares that the packed passenger cars passing through Staunton
                    on the Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad suggest that the Springs are once again
                    doing a thriving business.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Masonic</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Masonic Order the world over is celebrating St. John's Day. In
                    Staunton, the brotherhood will be out with banners, regalia, and musical bands.
                    The Rev. Dr. Finley will deliver an address and a dinner will be served at the
                    Virginia Hotel.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Augusta Female Seminary</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnston</ln>
                        <fn>W. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Amelia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baird</ln>
                        <fn>Esther</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Link</ln>
                        <fn>Nannie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The 1868-69 session of the Augusta Female Seminary closed last Wednesday.
                    Col. W. P. Johnston addressed the audience. Three young ladies received full
                    graduation diplomas: Amelia Brown, Esther Baird, and Nannie Link.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Concert</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The music pupils of the Wesleyan Female Institute performed to a large
                    crowd in the hall of the Deaf, Dumb, and Blind Institution.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Up and Doing</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>A. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>H. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A large crowd gathered at the Court House on Tuesday night to listen to the
                    speeches of A. B. Cochran and H. M. Bell, candidates for the House of Delegates.
                    "The gallery was well filled with colored people, who listened attentively. The
                    speeches were well received and we hope the advice given the colored voters by
                    Maj. Bell will be followed."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>A Hint</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reminds so-called gentlemen that rowdyism at public gatherings,
                    "particularly when there is a majority of ladies," is unbecoming. "At concerts,
                    particularly those given by the pupils of female schools, they should make it a
                    point to be very circumspect. Cat-calls and loud talking will not be tolerated
                    by a refined audience."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>Alex B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>H. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>Marshall</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A meeting at the Court House on the upcoming election aroused conservatives
                    to the importance of victory. Joseph Waddell was endorsed for Senate, and Alex.
                    B. Cochran, H. M. Bell, and Marshall Hanger were endorsed for the House of
                    Delegates.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Masonic Hall</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hewitt</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Masonic Lodge Number 13 has gone to much expense to furnish and decorate
                    their lodge room. A carpet made to order with masonic emblems covers the floor,
                    and wood-work, paint, and paper decorate the walls.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Register! Register!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper issues a plea for subscribers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Sprinkler</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cease</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Cease's sprinkler has been making Staunton much more pleasant on dry, dusty
                    days. It cuts down on dust by keeping the streets watered.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Resolutions of Thanks</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ross</ln>
                        <fn>C. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J. I. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>G. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Covell</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>C. R. Ross, president of the Colporteur's Convention, issues a resolution
                    of thanks to the Rev. J. I. A. Miller of the Evangelical Lutheran Church; the
                    Rev. G. B. Taylor; the proprietors of local hotels and railroads; and Maj. J. C.
                    Covell, principal of the Deaf, Dumb, and Blind Institute, for their hospitality
                    and aid.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>A Youthful Genius</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Rev. R. A. Holland of Trinity Church, Baltimore, preached before a
                    large audience at the M. E. Church. The paper praises his oratory.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Convention of Superintendents of Insane Asylums</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stribling</ln>
                        <fn>Francis T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scheffer</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The 23rd annual meeting of the Association of Medical Superintendents of
                    American Institutions for the Insane was held at Staunton's Virginia Hotel.
                    Professionals from around the country met to discuss aspects of their work.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that up to this date, 268 whites and 84 black have
                    registered in the county.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1869.06.24.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
