
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1868/pa.fr.fr.1868.03.11">

    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>

        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>05/09/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>

        <address>
<city>Chambersburg</city>
<county>Franklin</county>
<state>Pennsylvania</state>
</address>

        <date n="1868-03-11">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day>11</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
    </header>

    <paperBody>

        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.03.11.01" exists="no">



            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.03.11.02" exists="no">

            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Another Railroad Talk</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A meeting of the citizens of Washington and Quincy townships was held in
                        Waynesboro, some days ago, at the instance of the friends of the railroad
                        which it is proposed to build from that town by way of Quincy, Funkstown and
                        Fayetteville to an intersection with the Cumberland Valley road at Scotland
                        or Chambersburg. Assuming the general desirability and practicability of the
                        road to either terminus as aspects of the project so easily to be
                        established as to be well nigh fully evident on a moment's consideration, we
                        wish to call the attention of the business men of Chambersburg and its
                        immediate vicinity to the importance of hearty co-operation in the
                        enterprise and of securing, thereby, the full measure of the benefits which
                        the road will bring to the county capital if it be made to terminate at that
                        point. That the road will be built from Waynesboro to a junction, there is
                        no doubt; the necessities of existing business concerns and the pressure of
                        possibilities in the south-eastern townships compel this belief: where that
                        junction shall be made is in the hands of our readers.</p>
                    <p>The true and lasting interests of the whole county, in our judgment, point to
                        Chambersburg as the proper terminus. The shiretown ought to be the heart of
                        the shire, whence the arteries course to the extremities--the focus in which
                        the returning currents centre; when it is not, the community is an
                        undeveloped organism, without life or force. Such, to-day, is our
                        condition--we lack unity, co-operative power--we are slumbering amidst
                        possibilities which one day will, by their realization for Carlisle's or
                        Hagerstown's benefit, reproach our blindness. It is safe to say that the
                        county of Franklin comprises with itself as many of fair fields for exertion
                        as any county in our famous commonwealth or any equivalent area in the
                        Union. Our fertile soil is the theme of common boast, our water power has
                        but one rival in the State, our iron now commands a <sic>premiun</sic> in
                        the world's market, yet we have, for lack of unity--because of want of
                        combined action--but barely entered on the development of the soil's
                        resources. It is a truth that the eastern townships of Washington, Quincy,
                        Guilford and Green, as they abut upon the South Mountain or climb its
                        slopes, are well nigh simply masses of iron ore. Larger deposits of hematite
                        are not to be found in the State; yet the efforts of Caledonia and Mont Alto
                        have done little more than discover them in thirty years of labor. This much
                        they have done, and made, by doing it, present development easy and
                        immediately profitable. It is apparent that the opening, to its full extent
                        by capital and labor, of these immense mineral deposits will completely
                        change the face of both country and society in the eastern half of the
                        county. What Schuylkill and its neighboring counties are in coal; Franklin
                        will soon become in iron. The smoke of furnaces will becloud the
                        mountain-side for miles--artisans will congregate by hundreds--the re-action
                        of manufactures on agriculture and the harmonious working of both, will
                        enrich, as they quadruple, the members of the community. The town, if bound
                        to this growth by the bands of speedy intercourse, will share it in equal
                        measure. From it, either at wholesale or in parcel, will come the supplies
                        of that thrift--to it will be borne the thousand products of its labors. The
                        welfare of the country is the life of the town and the building up of the
                        town is inseparable from the growth of the country. We think it,
                        accordingly, good policy on the part of the business men of Chambersburg to
                        even strain their energies in aiding this road to completion, and seeking,
                        by liberal contributions to its building, to turn the balance, now hanging
                        very evenly, in favor of an intersection here rather than at a point which
                        will lead all the wealth and all the benefits of the road, by an obscure
                        outlet, below Scotland, to foreign towns and to the warehouses and pockets
                        of foreign capitalists. We hope a meeting will speedily be called and prompt
                        action taken.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Report on a meeting of railroad magnates in Franklin county that made a
                    case for establishing a terminus at Chambersburg. The paper points out that
                    Chambersburg has very rich iron deposits and needs a railroad to exploit
                    transportation of that precious mineral. Therefore, the paper urges the town's
                    leaders to take prompt action before other towns vie for the road.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Republicans, Are You Ready?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper urges Republicans to mobilize for the spring elections. The
                    editors warn that Democrats are ready to take advantage of Republicans "wherever
                    they are not watchful and active."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="l">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Congressman</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">To the Editors of the Franklin Repository</emph>.</p>
                    <p>Please permit one of your patrons, through the columns of your paper, to call
                        the attention of the Republicans of the 16th Congressional District, and
                        more particularly of Franklin county, to the fact that the campaign of 1868
                        is about opening, and already the opposite parties are making the
                        preliminary arrangements for the coming great battle, and notwithstanding we
                        are passing through momentous times, and all the people are keeping their
                        eyes steadily fixed on Washington city, let not the Republicans forget that
                        they too must cast about and make proper arrangements for the coming
                        contest. Amongst other things, we shall be called upon to select some one as
                        the Congressional standard bearer of this district, and it would seem
                        fitting that the Republicans of Franklin, who have strong claims, if indeed
                        they are not entitled to name the candidate for the district, and in this
                        view, would it not be proper to name a gentleman well qualified to fill the
                        highest responsible trust committed to the keeping of a Congressman, and not
                        desiring to do injustice to any of the very many who are both worthy and
                        fully capable to fill said position, let me suggest the name of a gentleman
                        of spotless character, high scholastic attainments, affable manners, a ready
                        and able speaker, exceedingly practical, persevering and energetic in
                        everything he undertakes, an indefatigable laborer in the Republican party,
                        a soldier with a good record, and deservedly popular wherever known. Such a
                        man is Col. George P. Weistling, of Quincy township, Franklin county. If
                        nominated, there can be no doubt of his election, and in the discharge of
                        the duties devolving on a member of Congress, he will be found to reflect
                        honor on those whom he will represent, with great credit to himself. A
                        REPUBLICAN VOTER.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter from a local Republican who wishes to nominate Col. George Weistling
                    for Congressman for the 16th district.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.03.11.03" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Young Men's Christian Association</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>S. H. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gaff</ln>
                        <fn>J. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A meeting was held in the basement of the M. E. Church to plan the
                    establishment of a Young Men's Christian Association in Chambersburg. Rev. S. H.
                    C. Smith presided as chair and J. R. Gaff was elected secretary. A committee was
                    appointed to draft a constitution. The paper stresses the importance of such an
                    association that would aim at "the intellectual and religious improvement of its
                    members." They also plan to establish a reading room that would be a boon to the
                    entire community.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Fannettsburg Lyceum</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Noble</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wineman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McAllen</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Montgomery</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilhelm</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seibert</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Fannettsburg has been holding a regular lyceum over the winter. The
                    organization hosts lectures, debates, and readings and publishes a literary
                    paper called "The Olio." They also hold "dialogues, declamations, tableaux,
                    charades, etc." Proceeds go to the hall.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Railroad Committee Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Amberson</ln>
                        <fn>William S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wertz</ln>
                        <fn>H. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Good</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Small</ln>
                        <fn>E. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Winger</ln>
                        <fn>E. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heller</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Knepper</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wertz</ln>
                        <fn>H. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Philips</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sanders</ln>
                        <fn>Levi</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Geiser</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Douglas </ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bear</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Amberson</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Funk</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The committee to support the proposed railroad from Scotland to the
                    Maryland line met in Waynesboro. William S. Amberson was elected president and
                    Joseph W. Miller, secretary. The committee reported the tonnage for Washington
                    and Waynesboro at 15,000 tons and Quincy 4,000 tons. On motion of H. C. Wertz, a
                    committee was appointed to receive stock subscriptions. The following were
                    chosen: Henry Good, E. J. Small, E. B. Winger, John Heller, Peter Knepper, H. E.
                    Wertz, John Philips, Levi Sanders, Daniel Geiser, Joseph Douglas, Henry Baer, J.
                    J. Miller, W. S. Amberson, John Funk.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Large Yields</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillan</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deitz</ln>
                        <fn>G. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heckman</ln>
                        <fn>D. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>C. Gillan of St. Thomas delivered 125 bushels of clover seed to the
                    warehouse of G. A. Deitz. D. H. Heckman of Hamilton delivered 60 bushels.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Green Township</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>John S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sollenberger</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fishburn</ln>
                        <fn>Philip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mahon</ln>
                        <fn>N. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sleighter</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wallace</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thomson</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wallace</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper declares that the meeting of the "friends of Grant and Curtin" in
                    Scotland was the largest ever held in that place. Isaac Miller presided. The
                    following men were nominated for town offices: John S. Myers for assessor; Peter
                    Sollenberger for supervisor; Philip Fishburn and N. K. Mahon for school
                    director; Henry Sleighter for auditor; William Wallace, Jr., for town clerk;
                    William Thomas for judge; Joseph Wallace for inspector.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Building Association Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Five shares of stock of the Chambersburg Building Association were sold,
                    one at an advance of $1.75 per share, the other at $2.05 per share. Association
                    money sold at 32 percent premium. </summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hershberger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Maj. Hershberger exhibited his panorama of the burning of Chambersburg in
                    Fannettsburg on March 5th. The hall was crowded and a band played music to
                    accompany the work.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Appeal</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>I. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The congregation of Middle Spring Church refuse to ratify the decision of
                    the Presbytery to sever the connection between the Rev. I. N. Hays and their
                    church. The congregation do not wish to give up their pastor and are appealing
                    the decision.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Professor Elected</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gerhart</ln>
                        <fn>E. V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harbaugh</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Rev. E. V. Gerhart will replace the late Rev. Dr. Harbaugh as professor
                    of Didactic Theology at the Mercersburg Theological Seminary.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ricker</ln>
                        <fn>Cyrus M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Murphey</ln>
                        <fn>N. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crane</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Cyrus M. Ricker of Franklin and Miss N. P. Murphey of Indiana were married
                    in Illinois on December 10th by the Rev. Mr. Crane.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vantries</ln>
                        <fn>Harriet</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vantries</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Harriet Vantries, wife of Dr. John Vantries, died in St. Thomas on
                    March 10th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>Barbara</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Barbara Young, wife of John Young, died at Camp Hill on March 2nd. She
                    was 53 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn>John R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John R. King died in Montgomery on February 29th. He was 77 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.03.11.04" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

    </paperBody>
</hwp>
