<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1868/pa.fr.fr.1868.07.22">

    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>

        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>05/16/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>

        <address>
<city>Chambersburg</city>
<county>Franklin</county>
<state>Pennsylvania</state>
</address>

        <date n="1868-07-22">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day>22</day>
            <weekday id="WED ">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
    </header>

    <paperBody>

        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.07.22.01" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.07.22.02" exists="no">

            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The County Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In two weeks from to-day the Republican party of Franklin County will meet in
                        Convention to nominate a County ticket, and to elect conferees whose duty it
                        will be, with those from the other counties comprising the Legislative,
                        Senatorial, Congressional and Judicial Districts, to name our candidates for
                        these several offices. We have several times, during the short period the
                        REPOSITORY has been under our management, called the attention of the party
                        to the grave duty which the selection of the ticket imposes on them; and so
                        greatly does the success of our party in the county and district hinge upon
                        the perfect performance of this duty, that we cannot refrain from adding a
                        few words more even at the expense of being guilty of repetition.</p>
                    <p>Since the nomination of Grant and <sic>Colfaxe</sic> by our National
                        Convention, as especially since Seymour and Blair have been nominated by the
                        Democracy, have the prospects and confidence of the Republicans been
                        brightened and restored in a remarkable degree. The Party has been united
                        everywhere, and an earnestness and vigor infused into it to which it has
                        been a stranger since the days when threatening treason and Democratic
                        disloyalty bound as together as one man for the safety of the country. In a
                        like degree have the nominations made at New York discouraged and
                        disaffected the Democratic ranks. Like a sudden flash of lightning or a
                        terrible convulsion, it seems to have dazed their understandings and sent
                        their wits a wool gathering. The leaders stand appalled and speechless, and
                        grope about as if lost. The reckless political gamblers, who could nominate
                        an original anti-war man and rebel-sympathizer like Seymour for President,
                        and a notorious and offensive revolutionist like Blair for Vice President,
                        may well startle the people, just emerging from the blasting effects of four
                        years of civil war. When Grant, who conquered the friends of Seymour, says,
                        as the candidate of the Republican party, <emph rend="italic">"let there be
                            peace" and financial prosperity and integrity</emph>; and Seymour and
                        Blair say by authority of the Democratic party, let there be <emph
                            rend="italic">Repudiation</emph>, let there be <emph rend="italic"
                            >Revolution</emph>; these things mean something which we can all
                        understand and appreciate. If the people deliberately vote for and elect
                        these repudiators and revolutionists they cannot say that they were
                        deceived, as the Republican party was in the election of Johnson.</p>
                    <p>So far the action of the leaders of both parties has been greatly in our
                        favor. That of the Republican party has been steadfast, wise and
                        conciliatory. Men of undoubted patriotism, honesty and statesmanship have
                        been chosen by the people, not by politicians, as their candidates. That of
                        the Democratic party has been tumultuous, unsettled and revolutionary.
                        Instead of desiring to secure peace, prosperity and the conciliation of all
                        parts of the country, the Democratic convention strove to arouse the
                        prejudices and passions of the conquered States, to destroy the confidence
                        of the people in the government, and nominated the exponents of the very
                        sentiments which created the war as their candidates.</p>
                    <p>It is now left with us to take advantage of the blunders of our enemies, and
                        win a glorious victory. By proper and judicious nominations in county and
                        district throughout the State, the Republican party can carry the election
                        triumphantly in October, and wipe out the stigma of defeat which our own
                        apathy and dissatisfaction brought upon us last fall. Let the primary
                        elections on the 1st day of August be fully attended, and let the best men
                        who can be found be sent as delegates to the Convention on the following
                        Wednesday. Let them come resolved to make us the strongest and best county
                        ticket possible, one that will honor the party and carry strength and
                        confidence with it, and its election will be as assured as the rising of the
                        sun. This must be the work of the people, not of cliques and "rings." It
                        must be the work of the country people and the towns acting harmoniously for
                        the good of the party, and not the result of hostile factions striving to
                        secure or defeat the nomination of some special pet. There are not less than
                        three persons before the people in the district seeking the nomination for
                        Congress. One of this number will in all probability be our candidate. We do
                        not deem it our duty in advance of the convention to discuss the merits or
                        demerits of any of them, but simply suggest that it will be for the
                        delegates to express the will of the county in the convention and name its
                        choice for that honorable and responsible position. We have no doubt that
                        they will weigh well the work that is before them, and ask, not who is most
                        entitled to this gift, but who will be the ablest and best servant of the
                        people of this district in the National Councils. If this rule be adopted by
                        our County Convention in the nomination of the entire ticket, the people
                        will be satisfied, our candidates will be elected, our county will be
                        rescued from the Democracy, and we will have done our duty in the grand
                        conflict of principles and error.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper announces the forthcoming meetings for Republican nominations for
                    county offices. The editors express great satisfaction at the national
                    nominations so far and predict that the Republicans will do very well while the
                    Democrats will flounder in confusion. The article urges unity among the party to
                    nominate the best men and secure Franklin county for the Republicans.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Chicago vs. New York</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>These two cities are not the representatives of the two great political
                        parties of the country. Chicago is perhaps the most distinctively American
                        city in the whole Union. It is a real child of the Great West, and breathes
                        the pure, invigorating air of the prairies. It has a live, active American
                        population, and was eminently a proper place from which to declare the
                        candidates of the Republican party for the Presidency and Vice Presidency.
                        The candidates themselves are representative men of the West, who have each
                        made themselves a name in our history, the one in the halls of legislation,
                        the other in the field. But they are not only representative men of the
                        West. No two men of our day have done more to establish the supremacy of the
                        political principles of the Republican party than they.</p>
                    <p>On the other hand, there was logical consistency in selecting New York as the
                        place in which to nominate the candidates of the Democratic party. New York
                        is least American of all our cities, as is the Democratic party least
                        American in its politics. It is the great Commercial Metropolis of the
                        United States, and is afflicted with all the corrupting influences peculiar
                        to commercial centres. Its population is largely made up from foreign
                        elements, whose intelligence and sympathies belong to an age and country
                        which have nothing in common with this age, nor with our people.</p>
                    <p>The candidates there put in nomination for the offices of President and Vice
                        President are the exponents of exploded ideas and semi-barbarism and in this
                        aspect are also truly representative men. They are mere politicians, who
                        never rise to the level of a principle, and therefore offer nothing about
                        which the sympathies of loyal men can cluster and cling. Their lives have
                        been barren of results, and if they have ever moved forward at all, it was
                        because even the Democratic party advanced and they had to keep pace with
                        it.</p>
                    <p>The contrast between the two parties, and their several candidates and the
                        manner in which each was nominated, is great enough to impress every one.
                        For example: the Republican party had virtually made its nomination months
                        before the Convention met. The masses of the loyal people had designated
                        with unmistakable directness the men whom they would make their standard
                        bearers. The delegates to Chicago but gave formal significance to their
                        choice. Whereas, when the Democratic Convention met in New York, the party
                        was drifting helplessly without principles and without a candidate. The
                        grave and responsible task of finding a candidate was left entirely to the
                        politicians. As many aspirants were announced as there are States in the
                        Union and almost as many and diverse platforms as there were candidates. Men
                        who had been active, open traitors during the war, and are no less traitors
                        still, did not hesitate to dictate the policy of the party. Old fossils
                        whose bones were thought to moulder in the political graves they had dug for
                        themselves years ago, came forth and jabbered over the dead issues that had
                        been <sic>burried</sic> with them. They came to welcome their erring
                        brethren and assure them of their sympathy in the lost cause. The
                        politicians had a nice job on hand and they had no wish to consult the
                        people. For six days they fought and wrangled, and when each faction
                        despaired of nominating its own candidate, and was unwilling that any other
                        should be nominated, a new man was agreed upon. He was not exactly a new
                        man, but was as good as new, having been politically dead since 1863, when
                        hostility to the war killed him.</p>
                    <p>The reputation of the Republican candidate is more than national; that of the
                        Democratic candidate is merely local.--General Grant is known throughout the
                        whole civilized world as the greatest military Captain of the age. Horatio
                        Seymour is known in New York and the States adjoining, as a scheming
                        politician. His notoriety comes chiefly from his sympathy with the
                        rebellion, and with the New York riots in 1863, which grew out of the
                        encouragement he gave to the rebels. General Grant is in favor of universal
                        peace and harmony, and supports such measures as will secure them. Horatio
                        Seymour was always opposed to the war to suppress the rebellion, and is now
                        opposed to peace. The Soldiers and Sailors Convention, which met at Chicago,
                        declared in favor of Grant, and the Republican Convention wisely approved of
                        their choice. The Democratic Convention refused to listen to the wishes of
                        the Soldiers and Sailors at New York, and nominated a man whom they despised
                        and whose nomination they received with disgust. The nomination of Grant met
                        the hearty approval of the Republicans everywhere, while that of Seymour is
                        nowhere satisfactory. Disgusted Democrats are coming over to Grant every
                        day, and the leaders of the Democracy are discouraged and dispirited.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper contrasts Grant and Seymour as candidates for President. The
                    editors assert that the former represents the choice of the people and the pride
                    of the West while the latter represents the choice of greedy politicians,
                    traitors, and a city of foreigners. </summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>What the Platform Means</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper charges that Democratic candidate Seymour plans to stand by the
                    Pendelton Platform that advocates debt repudiation. "It is not asking much, only
                    that the solemn covenant of the Government made with her citizens in an hour of
                    peril, shall be deliberately broken. The farmers of Franklin County who loaned
                    the Government their earnings, when without their patriotic assistance it must
                    have succumbed to the hosts of treason, will have a splendid opportunity this
                    fall to say whether they intended to make a gift to the United States, or
                    whether they expect to be paid in the spirit of the contract. The small
                    bondholders who loaned their daily earnings to suppress treason will be pleased
                    to know that the same spirit of treason assembled in New York, demands that
                    these loans shall be declared worthless."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="l">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Congress</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">To the Editors of the Franklin Repository.</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>Two weeks ago I gave you for publication a brief article upon the
                        Congressional nomination, in which I spoke temperately, as I believed, of
                        the claims of Col. Wiestling, Gen. Koontz and Mr. Cessna, the only gentlemen
                        whose names had theretofore been mentioned publicly in connection with the
                        subject of my communication.</p>
                    <p>I was of the opinion that a free and full discussion of a subject so
                        important to all the people, was eminently proper and at all times
                        desirable, and that it could be indulged in without excitement or acerbity.
                        It seems, however, that I have given offence to at least one person. This
                        was not my desire, and I regret--not what I wrote--but that any one should
                        have causelessly taken exception, for I appreciate as much as any person can
                        the importance of harmony in our party.</p>
                    <p>A writer apparently in the interest of Col. Wiestling and hostile to Mr.
                        Cessna, assails my views in your last issue. He even pretends to know my
                        identity, as if that has anything to do with the subject under discussion.
                        If I cared, I might guess at his identity; but what good could this do? I
                        care much more to know what he says.</p>
                    <p>He seems to deny my right to write and yours to publish any views relating to
                        the nomination for Congress that are not in advocacy of Col. Wiestling, and
                        thinks the exploded copperhead doctrine of State rights has somehow in a
                        diluted form found lodgment here in the shape of County rights. Now I
                        propose to tell my assailant frankly that I know of no County rights that
                        are not Patent rights. The difference between us seems to be that
                        "Republican" thinks Col. Wiestling has preempted the Republican nomination
                        to the seat in the next Congress, so far as this county is concerned, whilst
                        I regard the right to such nomination as open and debatable by all the
                        electors of the Republican party in the five counties.</p>
                    <p>Col. Wiestling is said to be a candidate for Congress. So far, so good. He is
                        a candidate either because he desires to be or because some friends desire
                        that he shall be, possibly for both reasons. Thus far, all is well again. It
                        is a laudable ambition to want to go to Congress, and there can be no
                        objection to a man's friends urging him for a position to which he may
                        himself lawfully aspire. But how and why at this stage of Col. Wiestling's
                        candidacy are all the Republicans in Franklin county committed to his
                        support? Why am I assailed as a bickerer for expressing the belief that
                        there are other soldiers in the county as much deserving its support, or
                        that a gentleman living in another county would just now make a stronger and
                        better candidate than any we could name from our midst? How has the argument
                        been exhausted, the discussion foreclosed in advance of the Convention? If
                        the Republican party of Franklin county is governed by a directory, let the
                        directory nominate a full ticket, and not devote its attention solely to
                        Congress. Our farmers would possibly be glad to be relieved of the public
                        duty of attending a Convention in the season of harvest. Are we to come up
                        to the support of Col. Wiestling, or any other man, as volunteers, or are we
                        to be whipped in by an oligarchy? Verily if we are all to be conscripted,
                        Col. Wiestling is an appropriate leader, because his chief military service,
                        as I happen to know, consisted in the organization of drafted men. If the
                        party is to have no choice and be allowed no discussion, it is well enough
                        for Col. Wiestling's <sic>fugleman</sic> to talk of furnaces and railroads,
                        for, in addition to their conveniences for melting up and running over, they
                        are fond of having their own way, like other corporations and monopolies.</p>
                    <p>There is no question that Somerset and Bedford counties have had a fair
                        proportion of judicial honors. Judge Tod, who was appointed in 1824, was, I
                        believe, a Bedford man, and Judge Thompson, commissioned in 1827, although
                        born in Franklin county, was at the time of his appointment residing in
                        Bedford. Judge Black, appointed in 1841, was, as is well known, a citizen of
                        Somerset. At the first election for President Judge, in 1851, Francis M.
                        Kimmell, of Somerset was chosen. He ran as an independent candidate, and,
                        although supported by the Democrats generally, he was not the adopted
                        candidate of either party. The first person chosen President Judge of this
                        district as the candidate of a political party, was Hon. James Nill, of
                        Chambersburg, the nominee of the Republicans in 1861. Upon the death of
                        Judge Nill in 1864, the Republicans of this county presented no candidate,
                        but supported for the nomination Hon. Alex King, of Bedford, our present
                        able and esteemed President Judge. The accumulation of <sic>businesss</sic>
                        during the war, as well as the increase of causes in the district, having
                        made an additional law Judge a necessity, the late legislature created the
                        office and the Governor commissioned Hon. D. Watson Rowe. Before his party
                        here has had an opportunity to formally present him as its candidate for
                        election this fall, the Republicans of both Somerset and Bedford counties
                        have made him their choice. Whilst the nomination of Judge Rowe by those
                        remote counties may be due mainly to the admirable qualities he possesses
                        for the judicial position, their action in anticipating his own county was
                        nevertheless generous to the party here. The truth is that the history of
                        the judicial district presents nothing discreditable to the Western
                        counties, and exhibits no eagerness to carry off the honors of the bench.</p>
                    <p>To claim, therefore, that Franklin county is entitled now to the nomination
                        for Congress on the ground that she has been deprived of her full share of
                        judicial honors, is uncandid, and especially unfair to Judge Rowe, who
                        needs, as I have stated, but the vote of his own county to nominate him.</p>
                    <p>"Republican" may sneer at the number of Mr. Cessna's supporters, but he will
                        soon appreciate their strength. They compose nine tenths of the Republican
                        voters in the county. Mr. Cessna has a very large acquaintance among our
                        people, and, besides serving numbers of citizens as counsel in important
                        suits, has spoken in almost every township. As a tribute to his earnestness
                        in the cause, it may be mentioned that at no time within the past three or
                        four eventful years has Mr. Cessna failed to respond to an invitation to
                        address meetings amongst us. At the tables and bars of our hotels, in our
                        stores and shops, on our streets and at our doors, in villages and at cross
                        roads, wherever people congregate and converse, Mr. Cessna's name is
                        mentioned in connection with the Republican nomination to Congress, and
                        indeed in this county no one else seems to be seriously contemplated. It is
                        not hard to tell why this is so. The masses have an instinctive perception
                        of the right man for the right place. They know that in John Cessna are
                        powers which when called forth will energize the whole canvass, and whilst
                        carrying him away ahead of his Democratic competitor, will secure the
                        success of every other man upon our ticket. We want a live candidate, an
                        aggressive man, one who will deal not only blow for blow, but annihilate the
                        enemy on every field. The people appreciate the importance of the campaign
                        upon which they are entering and the energy with which the Democrats will
                        battle to regain the power of which they have been so long deprived. Not
                        only the people of the district but the people of the State desire and
                        expect the nomination of Mr. Cessna, and the faction or clique that
                        compasses his defeat in violation of the wishes of the party at large will
                        incur a responsibility that they may wish they had not shouldered. FRANKLIN.</p>
                    <p>JULY 13, 1868.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"Franklin" writes an article expressing his support for John Cessna for
                    Congress. He is upset that other contributors scolded him for not supporting
                    Col. Wiestling. The writer says he believes the nomination should remain an open
                    question until the people decide rather than have it shoved down citizen's
                    throats by party hacks.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="l">
                <column>07</column>
                <head>The Somerset Herald</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koontz</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wiestling</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cessna</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>"Franklin" writes to reply to the Somerset Herald, who attacked his
                    dismissal of Gen. Koontz as a congressional candidate, and to "Republican" who
                    was upset that he overlooked Col. Wiestling. "Franklin" favors John Cessna.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="l">
                <column>08</column>
                <head>The Congressional Nomination</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"Wayne" writes the paper to advocate Mr. Koontz's renomination for Congress
                    on the principle that it is best not to swap horses in mid-stream. "The
                    Republican party has not yet fully established the great principles upon which
                    it is now engaged, the reconstruction of this Republic upon a right basis, and
                    the successful restoration of every part of the Union; nor has it succeeded,
                    judging from the action and affiliation of the New York Convention, in
                    convincing the people of the North, that the war to suppress the rebellion was
                    right and just on our part, that the rebels forfeited their civil and political
                    rights, and they can only be restored to them upon such conditions as the nation
                    may prescribe for its future safety and property." The representatives working
                    on these issues should be allowed to finish the job.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="l">
                <column>08</column>
                <head>District Attorney</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bonebrake</ln>
                        <fn>Emanuel J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>"Washington" writes to suggest Emanuel J. Bonebrake as Republican candidate
                    for District Attorney. He argues that Bonebrake is a devoted Republican and an
                    excellent lawyer and orator.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="l">
                <column>08</column>
                <head>Senatorial Candidate</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCauley</ln>
                        <fn>I. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>"Many Hamilton Republicans" write to suggest I. H. McCauley for nomination
                    as Republican candidate for the State Senate.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="l">
                <column>08</column>
                <head>District Attorneyship</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"Many Union Men" write to suggest S. W. Hays for nomination as Republican
                    candidate for District Attorney for Franklin County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.07.22.03" exists="no">

            <div type="o">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Death of James Lesley, Esq.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper announces with sorrow the death of James Lesley, long-time
                    cashier at the Bank of Chambersburg. The obituary includes an account of his
                    life and career in banking. He served as US consul at Lyon during the Lincoln
                    administration, and was a member of Chambersburg's Presbyterian Church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Railroad Matters</head>
                <origin>Hagerstown Mail</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reprints an article from the Hagerstown Mail that reports that
                    harvest season has put on hold plans for promoting railroad projects in Franklin
                    County. The proposed road to Mercersburg, that will form a link "in the great
                    chain from the National Capital to the Lakes," is on solid footing. The citizens
                    of that town have formed a committee and raised $60,000 for its construction.
                    The article also advocates extension of the Cumberland Valley road to
                    Williamsport.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Agricultural Fair</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilbert</ln>
                        <fn>H. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deitz</ln>
                        <fn>George A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heyser</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A group of citizens has acquired some land on which to hold a county fair
                    at Chambersburg. They are now hard at work improving the grounds. The paper
                    exclaims that with so many prominent agriculturalists in town, the project is
                    long overdue.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>A Pleasant Occasion</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snively</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper reprints a notice that Isaac Snively, an Antrim native and Adams
                    Express Company officer in Pittsburgh, recently received recognition for his
                    business achievements. "He was a member of the gallant 126th Penna. Vols. and
                    left his position in Pittsburgh in 1862 to volunteer in defense of his country."
                    He is about to leave for an extended tour of Europe.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davison</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mellinger</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cleverstone</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ilginfritz</ln>
                        <fn>Isaiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pratner</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pensinger</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wunderlich</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eby</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pense</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Boys in Blue of Antrim organized recently in Greencastle and elected
                    officers. They will meet weekly.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>S. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rowe</ln>
                        <fn>D. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lt. S. W. Hays has been elected to replace Col. D. W. Rowe as Franklin
                    representative to the Pennsylvania Soldiers and Sailors State Central Committee.
                    Rowe stepped down on account of his official duties.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George Eyster, president of the local Grant and Colfax club, announces that
                    the organization will meet at their new hall in the building of Jacob N. Snyder
                    on the public square.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hollowell</ln>
                        <fn>William E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stouffer</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>P. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William E. Hollowell and Miss Sarah M. Stouffer were married in
                    Chambersburg on July 15th by the Rev. P. S. Davis.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spencer</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Thomas Spencer died at his residence in Chambersburg on July 16th after
                    suffering a lingering illness. He was 69 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stouffer</ln>
                        <fn>George H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George H. Stouffer died in Greencastle on July 10th. He was 22 years old.
                    "The deceased was a young man of promising talents and exalted moral and
                    Christian character. During his sickness he manifested great Christian
                    resignation." He died without a struggle and with a "radiant smile." He leaves a
                    wife to mourn his loss.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huber</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. Samuel Huber died on July 12th at Rocky Spring. He was 86 years old.
                    "For over fifty-five years he gave evidence of a christian life, and for more
                    than half a century declared the Gospel of Christ from the pulpit. He was
                    humble, amiable and unassuming in deportment; patriotic, a lover of liberty, a
                    philanthropist and a christian; bold, ardent and zealous in promulgating the
                    cause of christianity among his fellow-men." He was a good minister, citizen,
                    and beloved grandfather.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.07.22.04" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

    </paperBody>
</hwp>
