
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1868/pa.fr.fr.1868.10.14">

   <header>
      <title>Franklin Repository</title>

      <tagger>
         <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
         <tagDate>05/24/06</tagDate>
         <tagNote/>
      </tagger>

      <address>
<city>Chambersburg</city>
<county>Franklin</county>
<state>Pennsylvania</state>
</address>

      <date n="1868-10-14">
         <year>1868</year>
         <month norm="10">October</month>
         <day>14</day>
         <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
      </date>
   </header>

   <paperBody>

      <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.10.14.01" exists="no">

         <div type="l">
            <column>07</column>
            <head>Teachers' County Institute</head>
            <origin/>
            <commentary/>
            <trailer/>
            <names/>
            <summary>"Lichnus" writes the Repository to complain about the recent teachers'
               institute. He complains that most of the time was "spent in the reading of lengthy
               essays by teachers who had applied for Professional Certificates." He denounces the
               "prosy, stereotyped lectures," and objects to a spelling match that was held.
               "Lichnus" believes that the prize system in education should not be encouraged.</summary>
            <note/>
            <look/>
         </div>

         <pageNote/>
      </page>

      <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.10.14.02" exists="no">


         <div type="e">
            <column>01</column>
            <head>How the Battle was Waged</head>
            <origin/>
            <commentary/>
            <transcript>
               <p>The party of the Union has reason to congratulate itself upon its honest and manly
                  conduct during the campaign just closed. Representing the patriotic masses, whose
                  daring and sacrifices saved the nation, when in extremities such as no other
                  nation ever survived, headed by leaders who guided it by wise counsels and
                  surpassing generalship, and composed almost entirely of brave hearts who carried
                  the bayonets and loaned the money, who nursed the wounded, and prayed for the dear
                  old flag; it was consistent with its history when it dealt frankly with the people
                  and rested its hopes of triumph upon their good sense and loyalty. It was guilty
                  of no subterfuge, equivocations or evasions. It held up its open palm and swore
                  fidelity to the cause of freedom, right and honesty, feeling justified by God and
                  good men.</p>

               <p>As it was frank in its avowal of policy, it was proudly fearless in its choice of
                  standard bearers. No doubtful men were taken as its representatives, only such as
                  were fully committed by repeated acts of public fame, only such as had rendered
                  the country great service. Our State ticket was headed by gallant soldiers, who
                  have proved their capacity for civil positions, by three years' honest and
                  efficient official conduct. Our county ticket was composed of the best of our
                  citizens, the majority of whom have done hard duty under the stars and stripes,
                  before the murderous fire of Southern Democrats. The canvass was conducted in
                  harmony with the high character of our principles and candidates. We met the
                  issues fairly, and dealt with our opponents honorably. We held them to their
                  record which gave them their platform, their candidates and their chief support.
                  We merely repeated against them as a reproach in the North, the demerits which are
                  held to be their great glory among their rebel masters South, and which in their
                  secret hearts they feel to be their crowning excellence. The men who could accept
                  their nominees and platform from villains who murdered and starved their loyal
                  fellow-citizens, who stole their horses and burned their homes, - men who could
                  walk side by side in procession through our streets with fellows boasting that
                  they had visited us before as rebel raiders, and discoursed rebel airs from the
                  very instruments enlivening rejoicing copperheads who groaned Grant as a butcher,
                  joining hands of fellowship with parties that were not ashamed of having sojourned
                  among us as spies, and furnished copies of the map of our county to rebel
                  commanders: these men had no cause to complain when they were told that their
                  sympathies were against the nation in the war, as their avowed principles show
                  they are against the justice honesty and the peace of the country now.</p>

               <p>On the other hand how shameless was the cause of our opponents. Low appeals to low
                  prejudices - proud, wealthy, educated white gentlemen warring with the degraded
                  black men, whom they falsely set up as a rival - orators in broadcloth and fine
                  linen, whose dainty hands were never soiled by labor, and who never earned a penny
                  by the sweat of their brow, groaning with hypocritical agony at the bloated
                  bondholders, and high taxation (which, indeed, they alone <emph rend="italics"
                     >feel</emph>, as it bears upon their luxuries, which only the government taxes,
                  and they would have the poor share taxation equally with the rich;) and inwardly
                  smiling at the blind faith of their trusting hearers - stay-at-home substitute
                  speculators attempting to strip the laurels from Grant, Sherman, Sheridan and
                  Thomas, to bind them upon the brows of Lee, Hampton and Forrest, and to make their
                  'white boys in blue' ashamed of the cause they supported and the gallant leaders
                  who won it. Such were the dishes and cooks appearing at Democratic and rebel
                  entertainments. They but yielded fruit after their kind. The Copperhead papers
                  even outdid their orators. Brick Pomeroy, brutal and impious, is their pride and
                  pattern. The wit, not the will, was wanting to make the Spirit quite as gross.
                  With a bad taste we would not have expected from its editors, it indulged in
                  coarse personalities harmless to all but the utterers, and enjoyed by none whose
                  approval is of worth. How these orators and editors could have the impudence to
                  ask their opponents to "give a lift" to the foot that was kicking them may be
                  answered when we can explain how a kicked and scoffed Republican could lose the
                  self-respect that an adherence to principle begets, and place his hands under the
                  heels of these ambitious vaulters to help them into position and power. The author
                  of "The History of an Atom" might inform us how!</p>

               <p>The Republican party has nothing to be ashamed of, then, but the quality of its
                  foe. With pride it looks back upon the manner in which the battle was fought; and
                  taking inspiration from its illustrious leader, it resolves, "to fight it out on
                  this line."</p>
            </transcript>
            <trailer/>
            <names/>
            <summary>This article is a very general defence of the Republican party and attack on
               the Democrats. Republicans are portrayed as gallant soldiers with heroic intentions,
               while Democrats are all vile traitors who still work to destroy the Union through
               economics and legislation.</summary>
            <note/>
            <look/>
         </div>

         <div type="l">
            <column>03</column>
            <head>That $115,000</head>
            <origin/>
            <commentary/>
            <trailer/>
            <names/>
            <summary>A. K. M'Clure writes the Repository to refute charges printed in the National
               Intelligencer that he received $115,000 from New England to use in influencing
               Pennsylvania political races.</summary>
            <note/>
            <look/>
         </div>

         <pageNote/>
      </page>

      <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.10.14.03" exists="no">

         <div type="a">
            <column>01</column>
            <head>Republican Meetings</head>
            <origin/>
            <commentary/>
            <transcript>
               <p>There was a large meeting of Republicans in Chambersburg on Thursday evening, the
                  8th inst. Previous to the meeting, a torch light procession paraded our streets.
                  Sergt. Seiders acted as Chief Marshal. There were over six hundred men in
                  procession, who were greeted from the sidewalks and windows and cheers, waving of
                  handkerchiefs, &amp;c. Addresses were delivered by Genl. Hawley, of
                  Connecticut, and Col. A. K. M'Clure.</p>

               <p>The Republicans of Southampton township were addressed in Fairview, in front of
                  the Hotel of William Holtry, by Mr. John M'Dowell and Lieut. S. W. Hays, on
                  Tuesday evening of last week.</p>

               <p>Capt. Norris and Geo. Chambers, Esqs., addressed the Republicans of Guilford
                  township, on Wednesday evening, the 7th inst.</p>

               <p>On the same evening Maj Calhoun, of Kentucky, Jere. Cook and I. H. M'Cauley,
                  Esqs., spoke at Bussart's School House, in Hamilton township.</p>

               <p>Col. M'Gowan, Jere. Cook and J. B. Cessna, Esqs., addressed a meeting of over
                  three hundred, Republicans and Democrats at Upton, on Friday evening, the 9th
                  inst.</p>

               <p>Maj Calhoun, of Ky., and Capt. Norris, of Penna., addressed a Republican meeting
                  in the Court House, in Chambersburg, on the same evening.</p>

               <p>Saturday last was a proud day for the loyal people of Mercersburg. As one man they
                  rallied for the interests of their country. Montgomery, Peters, Welsh Run,
                  Greencastle and Waynesboro were present with large delegations. Capt. James C.
                  Patton was Chief Marshal, and had as Assistants Samuel Shartle, of Welsh Run; J.
                  W. Runkin, Corner; Capt. R. H. Boyd, of Upton; Luther Benedict, of Bridgeport, and
                  R. S. Lindis and J. A. Hyssong, of Mercersburg. Major R. S. Brownson was chairman
                  of committee of arrangements.</p>

               <p>The procession formed about 11 A.M., and marched through the streets preceeded by
                  the Chambersburg Silver Cornet Band. Old citizens said there never was so many
                  people in their town before. The streets were crowded with enthusiastic
                  spectators, who sent up cheer upon cheer as the brave Boys in Blue or Grant and
                  Colfax clubs passed, bearing banners with mottoes that pleased them. Many of the
                  houses were handsomely decorated with evergreens and flags. Houses were thrown
                  open for the accommodation and entertainment of visitors, and those who had the
                  good fortune to be present will not soon forget the kindness of their hospitable
                  hosts and hostesses. Quiet and good order was preserved throughout the entire day,
                  with one or two exceptions of drunken Copperheads, who yelled frantically for
                  Seymour, Gen. Lee and Jeff. Davis.</p>

               <p>The meeting in the afternoon was held in Ritchey's woods. On motion, Hon. J. O.
                  Carson was elected as President, and the following gentlemen Vice Presidents;
                  Joseph Winger, of Clay Lock Hall; Maj John Rowe, of Greencastle; J. S. Gsell, of
                  St. Thomas; John S. Hassler of Loudon; John H. Thomas, of Warren; C Metcalf, of
                  Montgomery. For Secretaries, Wm Adams, of Montgomery; John D. Scott, of Peters; J.
                  M. Philips, of Warren, and S. M. Bowels, of Welsh Run. Dr. T. G. Apple opened the
                  meeting with a prayer. Addresses were then delivered by Genl. Hawley and Col. A.
                  K. M'Clure. Col. M'Clure's speech was able and eloquent. His reference to the dead
                  heroes from that portion of our county, who had died for the old Flag, or been
                  starved to death in rebel prisons, brought fears to many eyes. With three cheers
                  for Col. M'Clure, the meeting adjourned. In the evening there was a torchlight
                  procession and a general illumination of the town. Capt. R. H. Boys, of Upton, was
                  Marshal Speeches were delivered in front of M'Afee's Hotel, by Col Black, Genl.
                  Hawley, Col. McClure and Lieut. S. W. Hays. The large crowd dispersed about 10:30
                  P.M., determined to work earnestly for the election of his entire ticket.</p>

               <p>We might add that the most attractive feature of the day was a large wagon,
                  tastefully decorated, containing thirty seven handsome young ladies. The wagon was
                  drawn by four fine looking horses, owned by Mr. Moses Gingerich, of Peters
                  township.</p>
            </transcript>
            <trailer/>
            <names>
               <name>
                  <ln>Hawley</ln>
                  <fn/>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf>Gen.</pf>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>M'Clure</ln>
                  <fn>A. K.</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf>Col.</pf>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Holtry</ln>
                  <fn>William</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>M'Dowell</ln>
                  <fn>John</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Hays</ln>
                  <fn>S. W.</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf>Lt.</pf>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Norris</ln>
                  <fn/>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf>Capt.</pf>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Chambers</ln>
                  <fn>George</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Calhoun</ln>
                  <fn/>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf>Maj.</pf>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Cook</ln>
                  <fn>Jere</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>M'Cauley</ln>
                  <fn>I. H.</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>M'Gowan</ln>
                  <fn/>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf>Col.</pf>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Cessna</ln>
                  <fn>J. B.</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Norris</ln>
                  <fn/>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf>Capt.</pf>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Patton</ln>
                  <fn>James C.</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Shartle</ln>
                  <fn>Samuel</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Rankin</ln>
                  <fn>J. W.</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Boyd</ln>
                  <fn>R. H.</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf>Capt.</pf>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Benedict</ln>
                  <fn>Luther</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Findlay</ln>
                  <fn>R. S.</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Hyssong</ln>
                  <fn>J. A.</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Brownson</ln>
                  <fn>R. S.</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf>Maj.</pf>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Carson</ln>
                  <fn>J. O.</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Winger</ln>
                  <fn>Joseph</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Rowe</ln>
                  <fn>John</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf>Maj.</pf>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Gsell</ln>
                  <fn>J. S.</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Hassler</ln>
                  <fn>John S.</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Thomas</ln>
                  <fn>John H.</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Metcalf</ln>
                  <fn>C.</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Adams</ln>
                  <fn>William</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Scott</ln>
                  <fn>James D.</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Philips</ln>
                  <fn>J. M.</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Bowels</ln>
                  <fn>S. M.</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Apple</ln>
                  <fn>T. G.</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf>Dr.</pf>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Hays</ln>
                  <fn>S. W.</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf>Lt.</pf>
               </name>
            </names>
            <summary>This report describes the Republican Mass Meeting in Chambersburg announced in
               the prior week's paper. </summary>
            <note/>
            <look/>
         </div>

         <div type="a">
            <column>02</column>
            <head>Death of Col. Stitzell</head>
            <origin/>
            <commentary/>
            <transcript>
               <p>This gallant officer, late of the 11th Penna. Cavalry, died in Reading, Pa., on
                  Saturday morning, the 31st ult. We learn from a Reading paper that he arrived in
                  that city on Friday, the 25th ult., from New York and put up at the American
                  House. He had been unwell for some time and expected to remain at the Hotel until
                  Monday and then proceed to Lancaster. On Sunday he was not so well and on Monday
                  morning he was not able to be out of his room, having become prostrated so much
                  from coughing through the night. He was taken charge of by the Masonic Fraternity
                  of the city and received every attention that could be given him. But he grew
                  worse. Nature had exhausted itself, and he lingered until Saturday morning, 31st
                  ult., when he ceased to exist. On Monday his remains were taken to Lancaster,
                  accompanied by a committee of Masons from that city. At Lancaster his remains were
                  taken charge of by the Masons of that city and interred in the cemetery at that
                  place. During the Mexican war Col. Stitzell enlisted in Chambersburg in the
                  regular army, under Gen. C. T. Campbell, and after serving ten years returned to
                  this place. At the outbreak of the late rebellion, he again entered the army as 2d
                  Lieutenant of company A, 2d Penna. (three month) volunteers, and at the expiration
                  of his term of service, in connection with Gen. Samuel Spear, recruited company D,
                  11th Penna. Cavalry, of which he became Captain. Subsequently he arose to the
                  command of the regiment, which position he filled with honor as a gallant and
                  brave officer.</p>
            </transcript>
            <trailer/>
            <names/>
            <summary>This obituary recounts the death and most important deeds of Colonel Stitzell.</summary>
            <note/>
            <look/>
         </div>

         <div type="a">
            <column>02</column>
            <head>Military</head>
            <origin/>
            <commentary/>
            <transcript>
               <p>The Zouave Company lately raised in this place, under command of Capt. Geo. W.
                  Skinner, attended the fair last week, and presented quite a fine appearance in
                  their red caps, blue jackets and shirts and red pantaloons. A large majority of
                  the members are veterans of the late war. They had a poll established on the fair
                  grounds to ballot for a name for the organization, which resulted in a favor of C.
                  M. Duncan, Esq. The following is the result of the balloting:</p>

               <p> Capt. Samuel M. M'Dowell......20<lb/> C. M. Duncan, Esq............185<lb/> Col.
                  James G. Elder...........54<lb/> T. B. Kennedy, Esq.............5<lb/> County of
                  Franklin............67<lb/> Col. F. S. Stumbaugh..........16<lb/> Col. P. B.
                  Housum............133<lb/> Col. B. F. Winger.............41<lb/> Capt. H.
                  Easton...............41<lb/> Col. George B Weistling.......18<lb/> Col. A. K.
                  M'Clure............16<lb/> Gen. C. T. Campbell..........154<lb/> Maj. John L.
                  Ritchey...........3<lb/> Chambersburg...................6<lb/> Lieut. H
                  Fortescue.............3<lb/> Capt. John E Walker............4<lb/> Col. W. D.
                  Dixon..............21<lb/> Capt. John H. Walker...........4<lb/>
                  Scattering.....................7</p>
            </transcript>
            <trailer/>
            <names/>
            <summary>This record contains the vote count for a new name for the "Zouave Company,"
               seemingly a group of veterans.</summary>
            <note/>
            <look/>
         </div>

         <div type="a">
            <column>02</column>
            <head>Chang and Eng</head>
            <origin/>
            <commentary/>
            <trailer/>
            <names/>
            <summary>The "celebrated Siamese Twins" were on "exhibition" at the fair grounds last
               week. They married twin sisters from North Carolina, and are hoping to visit Paris
               soon.</summary>
            <note/>
            <look/>
         </div>

         <div type="a">
            <column>02</column>
            <head>The Female College</head>
            <origin/>
            <commentary/>
            <trailer/>
            <names>
               <name>
                  <ln>Wilson</ln>
                  <fn>Sarah</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
            </names>
            <summary>Sarah Wilson of St. Thomas donated $10,000 toward the establishment of a
               women's college in Chambersburg. Greencastle is also vying to get the college, and
               backers in that town have raised $14,500.</summary>
            <note/>
            <look/>
         </div>

         <div type="s">
            <column>03</column>
            <head>Married</head>
            <origin/>
            <commentary/>
            <trailer/>
            <names>
               <name>
                  <ln>Hoover</ln>
                  <fn>A. W.</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Rohrer</ln>
                  <fn>Elizabeth A.</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Schneck</ln>
                  <fn/>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
               </name>
            </names>
            <summary>A. W. Hoover and Elizabeth A. Rohrer, both of Franklin, were married on October
               6th by the Rev. Dr. Schneck.</summary>
            <note/>
            <look/>
         </div>

         <div type="s">
            <column>03</column>
            <head>Married</head>
            <origin/>
            <commentary/>
            <trailer/>
            <names>
               <name>
                  <ln>Sweigert</ln>
                  <fn>John</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Bowers</ln>
                  <fn>Rachel</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Davis</ln>
                  <fn>P. S.</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf>Rev.</pf>
               </name>
            </names>
            <summary>John Sweigert of Antrim and Miss Rachel Bowers of St. Thomas were married in
               Chambersburg on October 5th by the Rev. P. S. Davis.</summary>
            <note/>
            <look/>
         </div>

         <div type="s">
            <column>03</column>
            <head>Married</head>
            <origin/>
            <commentary/>
            <trailer/>
            <names>
               <name>
                  <ln>Brookings</ln>
                  <fn>David</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Reasner</ln>
                  <fn>Kate</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Davis</ln>
                  <fn>P. S.</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf>Rev.</pf>
               </name>
            </names>
            <summary>David Brookings and Miss Kate Reasner, both of Guilford, were married in
               Chambersburg on October 6th by Rev. P. S. Davis.</summary>
            <note/>
            <look/>
         </div>

         <div type="s">
            <column>03</column>
            <head>Married</head>
            <origin/>
            <commentary/>
            <trailer/>
            <names>
               <name>
                  <ln>Herr</ln>
                  <fn>John H.</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Lane</ln>
                  <fn>Matilda</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Davis</ln>
                  <fn>P. S.</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf>Rev.</pf>
               </name>
            </names>
            <summary>John H. Herr and Miss Matilda Lane, both of Greencastle, were married at Boyd's
               Hotel on October 8th by the Rev. P. S. Davis.</summary>
            <note/>
            <look/>
         </div>

         <div type="a">
            <column>04</column>
            <head>Latest News! Pennsylvania Republican by a Decided Majority. Franklin County
               Redeemed.</head>
            <origin/>
            <commentary/>
            <trailer/>
            <names/>
            <summary>A. K. M'Clure telegraphs the Repository with early news that state elections
               appear to have gone well for the Republicans.</summary>
            <note/>
            <look/>
         </div>

         <div type="a">
            <column>04</column>
            <head>The Vote of Franklin County</head>
            <origin/>
            <commentary/>
            <transcript>
               <table>
                  <row>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>Governor, '66</cell>
                     <cell>--- </cell>
                     <cell>S Judge, '67</cell>
                     <cell>--- </cell>
                     <cell>Aud. Gen, 68</cell>
                     <cell>--- </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>Geary</cell>
                     <cell>Clymer</cell>
                     <cell>Williams</cell>
                     <cell>Sharswood</cell>
                     <cell>Hartranft</cell>
                     <cell>Boyle</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Antrim........</cell>
                     <cell>545</cell>
                     <cell>521</cell>
                     <cell>495</cell>
                     <cell>502</cell>
                     <cell>46</cell>
                     <cell>---</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Chamb'g N W...</cell>
                     <cell>379</cell>
                     <cell>216</cell>
                     <cell>367</cell>
                     <cell>235</cell>
                     <cell>142</cell>
                     <cell>---</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Chamb'g S W...</cell>
                     <cell>297</cell>
                     <cell>275</cell>
                     <cell>268</cell>
                     <cell>276</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>---</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Concord.......</cell>
                     <cell>29</cell>
                     <cell>105</cell>
                     <cell>30</cell>
                     <cell>196</cell>
                     <cell>---</cell>
                     <cell>---</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Dry Run.......</cell>
                     <cell>121</cell>
                     <cell>99</cell>
                     <cell>119</cell>
                     <cell>106</cell>
                     <cell>---</cell>
                     <cell>---</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Fayetteville..</cell>
                     <cell>284</cell>
                     <cell>224</cell>
                     <cell>250</cell>
                     <cell>202</cell>
                     <cell>17</cell>
                     <cell>---</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Greenvillage..</cell>
                     <cell>215</cell>
                     <cell>112</cell>
                     <cell>174</cell>
                     <cell>120</cell>
                     <cell>108</cell>
                     <cell>---</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Guilford......</cell>
                     <cell>207</cell>
                     <cell>224</cell>
                     <cell>188</cell>
                     <cell>193</cell>
                     <cell>12</cell>
                     <cell>---</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Hamilton......</cell>
                     <cell>128</cell>
                     <cell>173</cell>
                     <cell>106</cell>
                     <cell>184</cell>
                     <cell>---</cell>
                     <cell>58</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Letterkenny...</cell>
                     <cell>165</cell>
                     <cell>249</cell>
                     <cell>153</cell>
                     <cell>207</cell>
                     <cell>---</cell>
                     <cell>---</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Lurgan........</cell>
                     <cell>112</cell>
                     <cell>147</cell>
                     <cell>88</cell>
                     <cell>148</cell>
                     <cell>---</cell>
                     <cell>---</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Loudon........</cell>
                     <cell>93</cell>
                     <cell>113</cell>
                     <cell>80</cell>
                     <cell>107</cell>
                     <cell>---</cell>
                     <cell>37</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Metal.........</cell>
                     <cell>166</cell>
                     <cell>98</cell>
                     <cell>127</cell>
                     <cell>85</cell>
                     <cell>---</cell>
                     <cell>---</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Montgomery....</cell>
                     <cell>249</cell>
                     <cell>181</cell>
                     <cell>213</cell>
                     <cell>193</cell>
                     <cell>44</cell>
                     <cell>---</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Orrstown......</cell>
                     <cell>80</cell>
                     <cell>149</cell>
                     <cell>65</cell>
                     <cell>147</cell>
                     <cell>---</cell>
                     <cell>62</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Peters........</cell>
                     <cell>175</cell>
                     <cell>52</cell>
                     <cell>134</cell>
                     <cell>56</cell>
                     <cell>84</cell>
                     <cell>---</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Quincy........</cell>
                     <cell>247</cell>
                     <cell>305</cell>
                     <cell>225</cell>
                     <cell>292</cell>
                     <cell>---</cell>
                     <cell>54</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Southampton...</cell>
                     <cell>69</cell>
                     <cell>82</cell>
                     <cell>45</cell>
                     <cell>67</cell>
                     <cell>---</cell>
                     <cell>26</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Sulphur Spring</cell>
                     <cell>34</cell>
                     <cell>41</cell>
                     <cell>33</cell>
                     <cell>39</cell>
                     <cell>---</cell>
                     <cell>---</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>St. Thomas....</cell>
                     <cell>167</cell>
                     <cell>227</cell>
                     <cell>148</cell>
                     <cell>210</cell>
                     <cell>---</cell>
                     <cell>60</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Washington....</cell>
                     <cell>351</cell>
                     <cell>259</cell>
                     <cell>316</cell>
                     <cell>302</cell>
                     <cell>75</cell>
                     <cell>---</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Warren........</cell>
                     <cell>61</cell>
                     <cell>56</cell>
                     <cell>51</cell>
                     <cell>50</cell>
                     <cell>---</cell>
                     <cell>---</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Welsh Run.....</cell>
                     <cell>135</cell>
                     <cell>178</cell>
                     <cell>98</cell>
                     <cell>135</cell>
                     <cell>---</cell>
                     <cell>---</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>______</cell>
                     <cell>______</cell>
                     <cell>______</cell>
                     <cell>______</cell>
                     <cell>______</cell>
                     <cell>______</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>4299</cell>
                     <cell>4106</cell>
                     <cell>3773</cell>
                     <cell>3962</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                  </row>
               </table>

               <p>Judge Rowe's majority in Antrim is 105, and Col. Dixon gains 57 in St. Thomas.</p>

               <p>We believe the whole of the county ticket is safe, except S. W. Hays, who is
                  probably elected by a small majority.</p>

               <p>Republican gains in the county, so far as heard from, in Chambersburg and 9
                  townships, 260.</p>

               <p>Both Capt. Walker and Capt. Sheibly are doubtless elected by handsome majorities.</p>

               <p>Hon. John Cessna, though badly cut in Chambersburg and Quincy by the Weistling
                  faction, will be triumphantly elected.</p>

               <p>If Mr. Hays, our candidate for District Attorney is defeated, as we fear he may
                  be, the same patriotic faction has the doubtful honor of effecting it.</p>
            </transcript>
            <trailer/>
            <names/>
            <summary>This table contains the vote count for Franklin county including some basic
               analysis comparing these results to previous years.</summary>
            <note/>
            <look/>
         </div>

         <pageNote/>
      </page>

      <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.10.14.04" exists="no">


         <pageNote/>
      </page>

   </paperBody>
</hwp>
