
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1868/pa.fr.fr.1868.08.19">

    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>

        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>05/17/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>

        <address>
<city>Chambersburg</city>
<county>Franklin</county>
<state>Pennsylvania</state>
</address>

        <date n="1868-08-19">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="08">August</month>
            <day>19</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
    </header>

    <paperBody>

        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.08.19.01" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.08.19.02" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Death of Thaddeus Stevens</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper sorrowfully reports the death of Thaddeus Stevens and eulogizes
                    his career and accomplishments.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>What Do They Mean?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We have said before that the success of the Democratic party means
                        revolution, and, we believe, proved it also by the acts and declarations of
                        the leaders of that party. It might be deemed too strong to declare that the
                        Democratic platform means revolution, because platforms are intentionally
                        couched in such general terms as to mean specifically nothing or generally
                        almost anything. These must be construed in the light of the acts and
                        declarations of the parties who make them, in order to get at their intent
                        and meaning.</p>
                    <p>The first demand of the Democratic platform is this: "Immediate restoration
                        of all the States to their rights in the Union under the Constitution and of
                        civil government to the American people." Other things being equal, this
                        seems most fair and unobjectionable. The normal condition of the States to
                        the General Government being unimpaired, that is, the duties which the
                        States owe to the government, faithfully performed, they are entitled to all
                        the rights which the government guarantees to American citizens. This
                        correlative relation of rights and duties having been broken up by the
                        rebellion of the Southern States, to understand the import of the first
                        demand of the Democratic platform, we must inquire what is the meaning of
                        "immediate restoration," what are the "rights of the States," and what does
                        the Convention understand by "civil government?"</p>
                    <p>For at the same time that the Democratic Convention was making this demand
                        through its leaders in Convention for "immediate restoration," the
                        Democratic party in Congress were unanimously resisting the immediate
                        restoration of the rebel States, and violently protesting against the
                        efforts of the Republican party to do so. It is evident therefore that the
                        Democratic party means by "immediate restoration" a different thing from
                        what the people mean.</p>
                    <p>Now we see the need of the acts and declarations of the Democratic leaders,
                        to explain their meaning. Perhaps their highest authority is Gen. Frank P.
                        Blair, who is the Democratic candidate for Vice President, and was a Union
                        Soldier during the Rebellion. As their candidate his views must be taken as
                        authoritative, so long as they are not repudiated by the party who nominated
                        him. He says in a letter to the Convention: "We must have a President who
                        will execute the will of the people <emph rend="italic">by trampling into
                            dust the usurpations of Congress known as the reconstruction
                        acts."</emph></p>
                    <p>Here is a key, then, which unlocks the door to the meaning of this section of
                        the Democratic platform. Immediate restoration means that the rebel States
                        shall come back into the Union in precisely the same condition as they were
                        before they rebelled; that the fact that they rebelled, and waged a bloody
                        war during four years, and set up a bastard government whose corner stone
                        was human slavery, and sacrificed half a million of the best lives of the
                        land, and squandered countless treasures, and impoverished a whole nation,
                        shall be blotted out. But is this all? No. It means further that the people
                        shall declare the immortal principle that all men are free and equal is a
                        lie, that the Heaven insulting sin of slavery is right, that treason is
                        honorable and just, that traitors must be rewarded. and that we who fought
                        to defeat the rebellion and support the Government are criminals. It means
                        that we must turn back, and marching ruthlessly over the graves of our
                        comrades, who gave themselves a willing sacrifice to their country, declare
                        that they died as the fool dieth.</p>
                    <p>That is what the Democratic party means to do. But how do they propose to get
                        a President who will trample the reconstruction acts of Congress into the
                        dust? Wade Hampton, who made the nomination of Blair, tells us. At a
                        ratification meeting in New York, he declared that his party must seize the
                        polls in the South, and have only the white vote cast. Then he added: "I
                        want you all to register an oath, that when they do vote their vote shall be
                        counted, <emph rend="italic">and if there is a majority of white votes, that
                            you will place Seymour and Blair in the White House in spite of all the
                            bayonets that shall be brought against them."</emph></p>
                    <p>This is charmingly simple. If the negro vote is against the Democratic
                        candidates it must not be counted, but the white vote, even in those States
                        which have rejected the generous proposition of Congress, must be, and the
                        New York mob must register an oath that it shall be counted. Many persons
                        might regard such declarations as incendiary and revolutionary, but we
                        assure them they are not. Being in the latitude of the Northern States, they
                        are exceedingly mild, especially when we reflect that they were addressed to
                        Gov. Seymour's "friends."</p>
                    <p>When Hampton and his friends got back into the enchanted land of secessiondom
                        they talked out fully and plainly. Ex-confederate Governor Vance, of North
                        Carolina, returning home, addressed a <emph rend="italic">Democratic</emph>
                        meeting at Richmond and said: "He could talk more familiarly of the wrongs
                        of the South here than at the North. Whereupon he declared himself still "a
                        rebel" and assured his hearers that <emph rend="italic">what the Confederacy
                            fought for could be won by the election of Seymour and Blair."</emph> We
                        of the North believed all along since the war that what they fought for the
                        verdict of battle had decided against them forever.</p>
                    <p>If the resolution demanding "Immediate restoration of all the States to their
                        civil rights in the Union under the Constitution, and of civil government to
                        the American people," means anything, then, it means the success of Seymour
                        and the rebellion over Grant and the Union, or as ex-Gov. Wise declared in
                        his speech, it means nothing, because since the candidates are acceptable to
                        the rebels, the platform is of no account at all. "He did not care for the
                        platform. It told a lie in its first resolution. <emph rend="italic">It said
                            secession was dead; that was not so. Secession was more alive than ever.
                            He supported the nominees, and especially Blair, because he had declared
                            that he would assume military power."</emph></p>
                    <p>The conclusion from these undisputed facts is this, and we solemnly declare
                        it: The Democratic party deliberately oppose the whole plan of legal
                        reconstruction, and demand "immediate reconstruction" instead. Gen. Blair
                        suggests how this is to be done, and makes the otherwise meaningless
                        platform mean something. He did this in a letter to the Convention, and
                        thereupon he was at once nominated. The Convention, without a dissenting
                        voice, accepted his construction and endorsed it. And since the Convention,
                        not a Democratic speaker, North or South, has dissented from it.</p>
                    <p>If we have written a single word that is not true, we ask our readers to
                        disbelieve it; but if otherwise, we pray them to reflect upon the awful
                        consequences that must result from the election of Seymour and Blair, from
                        the success of the Democrats and rebels.</p>
                    <p>If there be men of patriotism among the Democratic ranks, who are not willing
                        to fight for the Confederacy under a new name, we entreat them to come
                    out.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper viciously attacks the negative Democratic policies towards the
                    reconstruction acts. The editors label the Democrats as united with the rebels
                    and insist that a Democratic victory would erase everything Union soldiers died
                    for. The article also points out how prominent rebel generals and governors gave
                    speeches endorsing the Democratic platform.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Honor to the Country's Defenders</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The leaders of the Democratic party of Franklin county, through their journal
                        and their public speakers, strive to deceive the public into the belief that
                        they were in favor of the war to suppress the rebellion and sustain the
                        government, and that they are desirous to reward meritorious soldiers by
                        bestowing on them civil offices. They do this in order to secure the
                        suffrages of those who have been soldiers, and thereby swell the ranks of
                        the Democracy. Nothing is more false and more completely exploded by the
                        facts themselves than this assumption. It is a little more than three years
                        since the war closed, and what was left of our gallant and patriotic armies
                        returned to their homes. Since then, is it the Democratic or the Republican
                        party which has rewarded them? We ask the attention of soldiers to the
                        facts.</p>
                    <p>Col. J.G. Elder was wounded while fighting at the head of his regiment in the
                        battle of Fredericksburg, so that he will be maimed for life. When he had
                        recovered from his wounds, the Republicans of Franklin county elected him
                        County Treasurer. Capt. John Doebler, wounded in the arm in the same bloody
                        engagement, was elected County Sheriff. His term of service expires this
                        fall.</p>
                    <p>Sergt. Harry Strickler, who lost an arm in the same charge with Col. Elder
                        and Capt. Doebler, is now filling the second term of the office of Register
                        and Recorder.</p>
                    <p>Sergt Thad. M. Mahon, a gallant soldier who fought in many bloody battles and
                        was badly wounded, is our present efficient Clerk of the Courts.</p>
                    <p>These men were all disabled by wounds received in fighting the battles of
                        their country. Col. Stumbaugh, who raised the 77th Penna. Regiment and led
                        it gallantly during a part of the war, was twice elected to the State
                        Legislature.</p>
                    <p>Major John Hassler was a Lieutenant in the 158th Penna. regiment, and after
                        his term of service was elected County Treasurer.</p>
                    <p>So much in the past. How is it with the Republican ticket recently nominated?
                        Out of six county nominations four are made from the army, Lieut. Josiah W.
                        Fletcher was nominated for Sheriff, Lieut. S. Wilson Hays for District
                        Attorney, Captain Elias K. Lehman for Director of the Poor, and Captain
                        Joseph W. Winger for Auditor. Out of four nominations made for the District
                        ticket three come from the army. Col. D. Watson Rowe has been nominated for
                        Additional Law Judge, Col. W. D. Dixon for Senator, and Captain J.H. Walker
                        for Assembly. Of this number Lieut. Josiah Fletcher and Capt. John H. Walker
                        were both seriously wounded during their term of service.</p>
                    <p>Now how does the record stand on the part of the Democrats of Franklin
                        county. There is no necessity to conceal anything in this inquiry. The truth
                        is sufficiently damaging. Col. B. F. Winger, was bought over to the
                        Democratic party by the promise of a nomination for the Assembly, and
                        strangest of all the party fulfilled its promise. He has been renominated
                        for the same position. It is true he was a soldier, but his nomination was
                        the price of his apostacy and not in lieu of his services to his country.
                        Capt. Geo. W. Skinner was nominated by the Democratic party for County
                        Treasurer and at present fills that office. He was a good and true soldier
                        we have no doubt, but how much did that fact assist in securing his
                        nomination. We answer none at all. Lieut. G. W. Welsh, the only soldier who
                        asked a nomination of the party at their recent convention was defeated by a
                        man who had been no soldier, was opposed to the war and had already filled
                        the office two terms. Such is the sympathy that the Democratic party feels
                        toward those who defeated their friends in the South.</p>
                    <p>Soldiers read this record, reflect upon it, and when you deposit your votes
                        on the second Tuesday of October vote with the political party which has
                        proved itself to be the soldier's friend.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper appeals to Union veterans to look at the contrast between the
                    Republican and Democratic nominations for office. The Republicans nominated many
                    former soldiers for various offices while the Democrats nominated barely any
                    soldiers. The article lists the names of the Republican candidates and asks
                    veterans to vote for their fellow soldiers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Democracy of Chambersburg have had a meeting, and Sharpe has made a
                        speech. Sharpe is one of the best of Democratic speakers in Franklin county,
                        and in order to understand how well the Democracy manage not to see and know
                        the truth one should go to hear him. He spoke just one hour and a half to
                        the most apathetic assembly; if a hundred men make an assembly, that we have
                        ever beheld; but Sharpe is a man of determination and whether it be hard
                        work or easy, pleasant or irksome, when his task is set he does it. Nothing
                        short of an earthquake would have brought him to a halt until that speech
                        was made, and indeed some of the Democracy looked as if a small earthquake
                        would have been a decided relief.</p>
                    <p>To our great surprise we gather from the speech that the Democracy, though
                        they have new candidates, have no new ideas. That the Republican party were
                        the cause of the rebellion, that they made the National debt, that they are
                        responsible for the heavy taxes, that they are oppressing their dear
                        Southern brethren, and that, worst of all crimes, they have set the colored
                        race free, is the bill of indictment. Upon this, as we gather it from Mr.
                        Sharpe's speech, the Democracy propose to go before the country. As the
                        people have heard all this stuff a hundred times before and know how
                        fallacious it is, it would be useless to reproduce it here. They may be
                        compelled to listen to it repeatedly during the campaign, and we will not
                        annoy them now.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Sharpe of course thoroughly understands Grant's character, at least we
                        should think so from the remark he made. He told his audience that that
                        matchless soldier had written in his letter of acceptance "let there be
                        peace." That, said the speaker with immense gravity, is "cant." It was the
                        observation of a man of keen penetration who had scrutinized Gen. Grant's
                        public acts and words with skill and care, and had made the profound
                        deduction that this was "cant."</p>
                    <p>A singular phenomenon in natural history is Mr. Sharpe's extraordinary fear
                        of the Negro race, and we wonder that it has not attracted the attention of
                        some of our Savans. Whether it is the superiority of intellect, the
                        comeliness of person or the prowess in arms of this oppressed race that he
                        so much fears we know not, but we do know that in competition with the
                        Democratic party in some respect or other, Mr. Sharpe foresees only the most
                        disastrous consequences to his party. Dry your tears and banish your fears,
                        Mr. <sic>Shrape</sic>; there is still hope for the Democracy. We once heard
                        a colored man say that negroes had their preferences as well as
                    Democrats.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors ridicule a recent Democratic gathering while expressing some
                    respect for the speaker, Mr. Sharpe. The article claims that the Democrats have
                    no new ideas and will continue to repeat their old charges for the rest of the
                    campaign.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.08.19.03" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Court Proceedings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The following cases were disposed of last week:</p>
                    <p> QUARTER SESSIONS.</p>
                    <p>Commonwealth vs John Isenberger, <emph rend="italic">alias</emph> John Toms.
                        Assault and Battery, on oath of Elizabeth Traer. Defendant plead not guilty.
                        Verdict guilty, and sentenced by the Court to pay a fine of one cent and
                        costs of prosecution.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs Same. Surety of the Peace, on oath of Elizabeth Traer. Case dismissed
                        and the prosecutrix sentenced by the Court to pay the costs of prosecution.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Same. Assault and Battery, on oath of Susannah Heist. Defendant
                        plead not guilty. Verdict guilty, and sentenced by the Court to pay a fine
                        of one cent and costs of prosecution, and undergo an imprisonment in the
                        county jail for a period of one month.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Same. Surety of the Peace, on oath of Susannah Heist. Case heard and
                        the Court sentenced the defendant to pay the costs of prosecution.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Henry Null. Surety of the Peace, on oath of Lewis K. Morrison.
                        Defendant plead guilty, and was sentenced by the Court to pay the costs of
                        prosecution, and to give bond in the sum of $100 to keep the peace toward
                        Lewis K. Morrison especially, and also toward all good citizens.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Wm. Boyd. Assault, on oath of Jas. Martin. A true bill. Defendant
                        pleaded guilty, and was sentenced by the Court to pay a fine of twenty-five
                        cents and costs of prosecution.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Isaac Newman. Horse Stealing, on oath of Wm. Stitzell. A true bill.
                        Defendant plead not guilty. Verdict guilty, and sentenced by the Court to
                        pay a fine of $1 and cost of prosecution, and undergo an imprisonment in the
                        Eastern penitentiary, by separate and solitary confinement at hard labor,
                        for a term of three years, to commence from the 13th day of August, 1868.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Same. Horse Stealing, on oath of Joseph Pheil. Defendant plead
                        guilty, and was sentenced by the Court to pay a fine of $1 and costs of
                        prosecution, and undergo an imprisonment in the Eastern penitentiary, by
                        separate and solitary confinement at hard labor, for a period of two years,
                        to commence at expiration of his first sentence.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Frank Ely. Surety of the Peace, on oath of Samuel Worley. Defendant
                        plead guilty, and was sentenced by the Court to pay the costs of
                        prosecution, and to give bail in the sum of $100 that he keep the peace
                        toward all good citizens, and especially toward Samuel Worley.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Susan Howard. Keeping a Bawdy House, on oath of Frank Jones. A true
                        bill.--Defendant plead not guilty. Verdict guilty, and sentenced by the
                        Court to pay a fine of one dollar, costs of prosecution and to undergo an
                        imprisonment in the county jail for a period of one month.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Wm. Fahnestock. Assault and Battery, on oath of M. W. Houser. A true
                        bill.--Defendant plead not guilty. Verdict not guilty, and the county to pay
                        the costs.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Wm. R. Sturgeon. Assault with intent to commit Rape, on oath of Wm.
                        Rosenberry. A true bill. Defendant plead not guilty. Verdict not guilty of
                        first count in indictment, but guilty of the second in manner and form as he
                        stands indicted, and was sentenced by the Court to pay a fine of one cent,
                        costs of prosecution and to be imprisoned in the county jail one day.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Jacob J. Spesard. Furnishing Liquor to Minors, on oath of Wm. B.
                        Raby. Defendant plead not guilty. Verdict not guilty, and that the defendant
                        pay one cent of the costs of prosecution, remainder of costs to be paid by
                        the prosecutors, Wm. B. Raby and John R. Smith.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Geo. Mellinger. Surety of the Peace, on oath of Ann Burkholder.
                        Defendant sentenced by the Court to pay costs of prosecution and give
                        security in the sum of $100, that he keep the peace toward all good
                        citizens, and especially toward Ann Burkholder.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Wm. Hartman. Assault and Battery, on oath of A. Krider. A true bill.
                        Defendant plead not guilty. Verdict not guilty, and prosecutor pay costs of
                        presentation.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Frank Myers. Adultery, on oath of Frank Jones. A true bill.
                        Defendant plead not guilty. Verdict not guilty, and the costs to be divided
                        between the defendant and prosecutor.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Frank Jones. Assault and Surety of the Peace, on oath of Susan
                        Howard. Defendant plead guilty, submitted the decision of the Court, and was
                        sentenced to pay a fine of five dollars and costs of the prosecution.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Jno. Trostle. Assault and Battery, on oath of Catharine Washabaugh.
                        A true bill. Defendant plead not guilty. Verdict not guilty, and that the
                        costs be equally divided between the defendant and prosecutrix.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Catharine Hanes. Surety of the Peace, on oath of Jno. Trostle. Case
                        dismissed and the prosecutor to pay the costs.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Nancy Traer and Elizabeth Traer. Assault and Battery, on oath of
                        John Isenberger. Not a true bill, and the prosecutor to pay costs of
                        prosecution.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Nolle prosequies</emph> were entered in the following
                        cases:--Com. vs. John S Palsgrove; Com. vs. Geo. Rock--two suits; Com. vs.
                        Andrew Freeman; Com. vs. Ferdinand Evans; Com. vs. R. W. Ramsey, et al.; Com
                        vs. Andrew Freeman; Com. vs. Jacob B. Besore; Com. vs. Henry Wilson; Com.
                        vs. Samuel Neikirk; Com. vs. George Blue, et. al.: Com. vs. Michael Miller;
                        Com. vs. William Tarner; Com. vs. Henry Shirk; Com. vs. James A. Miley; Com.
                        vs. Tip Savage; Com. vs. Wm. Jones; Com. vs. P.D. Ostrander; Com. vs. Luther
                        Benedict, et. al.; Com. vs. Frank M. Andrews; Com. vs. James Alexander: Com
                        vs John Bartley.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Peter Trexel. Larceny, on oath of H. S. Miller. Defendant pleaded
                        guilty and was sentenced by the Court to pay a fine of one cent and costs of
                        prosecution, and undergo imprisonment in the county jail for a period of one
                        day.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Geo. Metz. Malicious Mischief, on oath of Benj. Uglow. Defendant
                        pleaded not guilty. Verdict not guilty, and the prosecutor to pay the costs.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Ambrose Welsh. Assault and Battery, on oath of Jacob J. Spesard.
                        Defendant pleaded not guilty. Verdict guilty, and sentenced by the Court to
                        pay cost of prosecution and a fine of twenty-five cents.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Same. Larceny, on oath of Jacob J. Spesard. Defendant pleaded not
                        guilty. Verdict not guilty.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. John Miller. Burglary; on oath of Benj. Zarger. <sic>Defendent</sic>
                        pleaded not guilty. Verdict not guilty.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Isenberger</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Toms</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Traer</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heist</ln>
                        <fn>Susannah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Null</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Morrison</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyd</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newman</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stitzell</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pheil</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ely</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Worley</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Howard</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fahnestock</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sturgeon</ln>
                        <fn>William R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rosenberry</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spesard</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Raby</ln>
                        <fn>William B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>John R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mellinger</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burkholder</ln>
                        <fn>Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hartman</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Krider</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trostle</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Washabaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanes</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Traer</ln>
                        <fn>Nancy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Traer</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Isenberger</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palsgrove</ln>
                        <fn>John S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rock</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Freeman</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Besore</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Neikirk</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blue</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tarner</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shirk</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miley</ln>
                        <fn>James A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Savage</ln>
                        <fn>Tip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ostrander</ln>
                        <fn>P. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Benedict</ln>
                        <fn>Luther</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Andrews</ln>
                        <fn>Frank M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Alexander</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bartley</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trexel</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>H. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Metz</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Welsh</ln>
                        <fn>Ambrose</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spesard</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zarger</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Report of the proceedings of the county court, listing cases and verdicts.
                    Most of the cases were minor crimes and the defendants usually received light
                    sentences. </summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>C. V. Railroad to Williamsport</head>
                <origin>Hagerstown Mail</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Surveyors have finished laying out the proposed line that will extend the
                    Cumberland Valley Railroad to Williamsport. Property-owners along the line have
                    agreed on rates for damages. The Cumberland Valley Company, which owns the
                    Franklin Railroad Company, will oversee the work.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Railroad</head>
                <origin>Village Record</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The survey of the proposed Scotland and Mont Alto Railroad has not yet been
                    made, and the article demands that citizens endeavor to find out why. The
                    project is too important to let delays get in the way.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The members of the Franklin County Bar pass resolutions of sympathy and
                    respect upon the death of Thaddeus Stevens.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that the Fair Grounds "present a lively appearance."
                    There are between 20 and 25 hands working on erecting buildings, tracks, and
                    grading. The main building has been completed, and stalls will go up in the
                    coming days. The fencing is finished and the track has been tested and found to
                    be "one of the finest in the State." All these efforts will ensure that Franklin
                    County has a fair second to none in the state.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Camp Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bishop</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yaukey</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. M. Bishop announces that the United Brethren in Christ will hold a camp
                    meeting on the grounds of John Yaukey beginning on August 28th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Appraisement of Damages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The commission for the appraisement of war-damage claims has divided
                    Franklin into several districts in order to better hear all claims on their next
                    visit. They also stress that there is no charge for blank claim sheets. The
                    Repository will print and distribute 2,500 forms for free. The commissioners
                    will meet at Mercersburg on September 8th; Waynesboro on the 10th; Chambersburg
                    on the 11th; and Shippesnburg on the 15th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Clure</ln>
                        <fn>A. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cessna</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Republicans of Chambersburg held a large and enthusiastic meeting at
                    the Court House. Col. A. K. M'Clure addressed the crowd. John Cessna was not
                    able to attend due to his wife's illness.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Lellan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chambers</ln>
                        <fn>W. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Monumental Association held an open-air concert on the grounds of Mr.
                    and Mrs. William M'Lellan. The grounds were lit with Chinese lamps, and a large
                    crowd attended. Water and ice cream were served before a storm cut short the
                    festivities. The event raised $100. The next will be held on the grounds of W.
                    L. Chambers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn>Lyman S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mahon</ln>
                        <fn>T. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Etter</ln>
                        <fn>A. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hess</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dessinger</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garver</ln>
                        <fn>M. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyler</ln>
                        <fn>Frank B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chambers</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Republicans of Scotland held a meeting to organize a Grant and Colfax
                    club. Lyman S. Clarke and T. M. Mahon spoke. Officers were elected, including A.
                    H. Etter, president. Resolutions were passed supporting Grant and resolving to
                    "fight it out" alongside "loyal men" and the Boys in Blue against the
                    "copperhead ticket."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A correspondent of a Pittsburgh paper reports from Graeffenburg Springs
                    that crops in Franklin and surrounding counties turned out well, and now that
                    the harvest is over, attention is turned to the fall elections. "Old soldiers
                    who fought under Grant are disgusted with the Seymour ticket," he asserts.
                    "Democracy this year means war--rebels trying to get power to give pensions to
                    the widows and orphans, wives and children of the rebel soldiers who tried to
                    destroy our government, but the soldier understands it and can't be cheated. I
                    am told by those who know that Franklin county is sure for 250 for Grant."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Republican Meeting in Waynesboro</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>J. W. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Amberson</ln>
                        <fn>J. Burns</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rogers</ln>
                        <fn>Volney</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>S. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>F. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Republicans of Waynesboro held a large meeting chaired by Dr. J. W. M.
                    Wright. Resolutions mourning the death of Thaddeus Stevens and supporting the
                    Republican county ticket were passed. A number of addresses were made by
                    prominent local Republicans. A meeting is scheduled for the 22nd to form a Grant
                    and Colfax club.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The town of Chambersburg observed the funeral of Thaddeus Stevens by
                    tolling bells and closing all places of business. The Boys in Blue flew their
                    headquarters flag at half mast as a tribute of respect for "the good works of
                    the deceased." "A general feeling of sadness and sorrow over the death of this
                    great patriot and statesman was everywhere manifested."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Daily Prayer Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A daily Union Prayer Meeting will be held in the rooms of the Young Men's
                    Christian Association beginning September 1st.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wanamaker</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George Eyster and W. H. Wanamaker announce that the members of the Grant
                    and Colfax club will meet this evening in their hall above Snider's store.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyer</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phreaner</ln>
                        <fn>Emma E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnes</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jacob Eyer and Miss Emma E. Phreaner, both of Upper Strasburg, were married
                    on August 11th at the National Hotel in Chambersburg by the Rev. S. Barnes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Holmes</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Margaret S. Crawford, wife of Holmes Crawford, died on August 9th at
                    the house of her brother-in-law, Joseph Crawford. She was 81 years old, and had
                    been a member of the Falling Spring Presbyterian Church for 57 years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1868.08.19.04" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

    </paperBody>
</hwp>
