<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd' -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1859/va.au.ss.1859.10.11">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Jeff McClurken</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/15/95</tagDate>
            <tagNote>2nd Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1859-10-11">
            <year>1859</year>
            <month norm="10">October</month>
            <day>11</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1859.10.11.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>A Brown-Stone Front as the Means of Grace; By Henry Ward Beecher</head>
                <origin>The Independent</origin>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <commentary>"The following capital article by Henry Ward Beecher, on 'Modern
                    Conveniences and First Class Houses' we take the liberty of transferring from
                    the Independent for the benefit of such of our readers as do not see that
                    paper."</commentary>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article by Henry Ward Beecher. He argues that a nice house does not always
                    equal grace from God. He discusses mishaps that can occur in house with all the
                    modern conveniences.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote>parts of page are very faint, almost impossible to read.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1859.10.11.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Export of Slaves from Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt>"The consequence will be a steady and constant drain of slaves and for
                    every one that goes out a white man from the North will in all probability come
                    into Virginia and the neighboring states. It requires no prophetic vision to
                    foresee the result of this kind of operation in the course of time. Is it not the
                    true interest of Virginia and the South generally to oppose the acquisition of
                    territory, that her slaves may remain in her own limits, instead of being
                    exported by thousands to supply the wants of new slave territory."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The immense exodus of slaves from Virginia and North Carolina is beginning to
                        attract the attention of the press, and serious apprehensions are expressed
                        as to the effect upon the agricultural interests of these States. The
                        "Petersburg Express" states that in Eastern Virginia the places of the
                        thousands of slaves who are annually sold for the cotton fields of Alabama,
                        Mississippi, Arkansas and Texas, are not filled by other laborers, which so
                        disables that section of the State from working its lands profitably, as of
                        necessity to retard seriously its progress and prosperity. In view of the
                        extensive and costly system of internal improvements now in operation and
                        under construction in this State, a new impetus has been given to
                        development and production, an adequate supply of labor is demanded, and yet
                        we are continually subjected to a drainage of our slave labor to supply the
                        wants of the extreme Southern States.</p>
                    <p> The subject is certainly one of the very highest importance to the people,
                        especially the slave owners of Virginia, and should receive earnest
                        attention and calm deliberation. It opens up a wide field of enquiry as to
                        the probable consequences of this drainage upon the border slave States, not
                        only as it may effect their material progress, but especially as to their
                        political bearings. The effect upon the agricultural interests of the State,
                        though of course important, is not the matter of highest public concern.
                        Where labor is in great demand, it will gradually find its way, and the
                        experience of other States establishes the fact that agricultural interests
                        may prosper, and every other branch of industry and enterprise flourish when
                        there is no slave labor. Eastern Virginia may suffer temporary inconvenience
                        by a diminution of slaves, because her wants are not widely known; but when
                        her necessities become so pressing that she is forced to seek labor,
                        laborers will be found in abundance flocking to her uncultivated fields. But
                        it will be white labor--white labor of the North, and of foreign countries.
                        It seems to us that this is the striking aspect of the question. As slave
                        laborers are diminished white laborers, anti-slavery by education and from
                        interest, will supply their place, and it becomes a question of prominent
                        interest what is to be the effect of the exchange upon the cherished and
                        peculiar institution of slavery.--Negroes will continue to be sold at
                        enormous prices as long as they are needed in the Cotton States, where white
                        labor will not answer the purpose. Slave dealers will buy and transport them
                        from the border States to the extreme States just as long as they commend
                        [sic] high prices, and we agree with the "Express" that there seems to be no
                        prospect of their receding. The consequence will be a steady and constant
                        drain of slaves, and for every one that goes out a white man from the North
                        will in all probability come into Virginia and the neighboring States. It
                        requires no prophetic vision to foresee the result of this kind of
                        operation, in the course of time.</p>
                    <p> Taking this view of the matter under consideration, it becomes a question
                        for the reflection of the people, and the grave deliberation of political
                        assemblies, what can be done to remedy the evil? The owners of the cotton
                        and sugar plantations of the extreme South would prefer to obtain their
                        labor upon cheaper terms by reopening the African slave trade, and there are
                        doubtless those in our own State who would resort to this inhuman traffic
                        for the purpose of "providing for the great and growing deficiency" of
                        negroes to work the tobacco and grain-fields in Eastern Virginia. However
                        effectual this remedy might be, we are loth to believe that any considerable
                        portion of the people would sanction such a movement, even under cover of
                        the Jesuitical plea that "the end justifies the means."</p>
                    <p> There is still another question brought into view by the consideration of
                        this subject which may assume a different phase from that which it presents
                        in the abstract, when contemplated in connection with the exodus of slaves
                        from Virginia. We allude to the acquisition of territory. When the demand
                        for slaves is already so great, as to effect the constant and perceptible
                        diminution of slaves in the border States, how many would be left in a few
                        years if that demand were quadrupled by the acquisition of Cuba, or other
                        extensive territory requiring slave labor? Is it not the true interest of
                        Virginia and the South generally to oppose the acquisition of territory,
                        that her slaves may remain in her own limits, instead of being exported by
                        thousands to supply the wants of new slave territory?</p>
                    <p>These are questions of practical importance and should be decided according
                        to the dictates of common sense. There are many in the State of Virginia and
                        throughout the Southern States-- men whose devotion to the interests of the
                        South are above suspicion--who conceive that the permanency of the
                        institution of slavery can only be secured by confining slave labor to its
                        present limits. Not preventing it by prohibiting laws, Wilmot provisos, or
                        even Squatter-sovereignty, from going wherever the Constitution and the laws
                        entitle it to go; but voluntarily declining, as a matter of policy and
                        interest, to take it outside of the area upon which the negro now toils.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <commentary/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Editorial about drain of slaves from Virginia and North Carolina to the
                    Cotton South. The editorial argues that this process is harmful to the border
                    states because it is likely that each slave sold will be replaced by a white
                    man, probably from the North and probably anti-slavery.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/ssoct59.html#10.11a</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <commentary/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Spectator is quarreling with the Vindicator over what the Spectator has
                    said about Douglas and Seward.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>A Farmer</trailer>
                <commentary/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter complains that the Town council put a toll gate east of the
                    cemetery, not west as had been agreed upon. Also protests the erection of the
                    toll gate at all. Illuminates conflict between town and country.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1859.10.11.03">
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <commentary/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCartney</ln>
                        <fn>W.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spitler</ln>
                        <fn>Jason</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunter</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on October 6.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <commentary/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brooke</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheets</ln>
                        <fn>Albert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Helvey</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married at M. E. Parsonage, Gospel Hill on October 6.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <commentary/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wasson</ln>
                        <fn>J.L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bryson</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wade</ln>
                        <fn>Medorah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wade</ln>
                        <fn>H.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Wade from Bath County; married on September 13.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <commentary/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitmore</ln>
                        <fn>Bettie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitmore</ln>
                        <fn>Nancy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Bettie Whitmore died on October 1, age 27.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>A.; Richmond Dispatch please copy</trailer>
                <commentary/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paul</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paul</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paul</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Susan P. Paul died on October 3, age 20. Long flowery obit.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Markets in column 2</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1859.10.11.04">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
