<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'& -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1859/va.au.ss.1859.08.02">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Jeff McClurken</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/15/95</tagDate>
            <tagNote>2nd Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1859-08-02">
            <year>1859</year>
            <month norm="08">August</month>
            <day norm="02">2</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1859.08.02.01">
            <pageNote>Advertisements and miscellaneous stories</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1859.08.02.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Course of the Opposition</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <commentary/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lays out Opposition platform--disapproval of Charleston Convention and
                    desire to stay out of slavery agitation.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Counterfeit Bank Notes</head>
                <origin>Baltimore Sun</origin>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <commentary/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Baltimore Sun reports circulation of counterfeit notes, purporting to be
                    from the Central Bank of Virginia at Staunton.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Washington College; Lexington, August 1st 1859</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Yours very truly; J. L. Campbell</trailer>
                <commentary/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn>J.L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announcement of Campbell's intention to prepare a report for the State
                    Agricultural Society on Augusta's resources and possible improvements in
                    cultivation.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>"Your old friends, Many Voters; N. B. Have you noticed how remarkably
                    liberal the Council are going to be to the Hotels, for we are told they intend
                    placing a lamp post opposite each of them? Generous fellows-ain't they! M. V."</trailer>
                <commentary/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter complaining about Staunton town council plan to fill in the wells
                    and replace them with public hydrants.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Negroes Hung--One Burnt at the Stake</head>
                <origin>St. Louis Democrat</origin>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p> A correspondent of the St. Louis Democrat, writing from 
                    Marshall, Saline county, Missouri, on the 26th ult., says: Some time 
                    ago, you will recollect, a negro murdered a gentleman named Hinton, near 
                    Waverly, in this county.  He was caught after a long search, and put to 
                    jail.  Yesterday he was tried at this place and convicted of the crime, 
                    and sentenced to be hung.  While the Sheriff was conveying him to prison 
                    he was set upon by the crowd and taken from that officer.  The mob then 
                    proceeded to the jail and took from thence two other negroes.  One of 
                    them had attempted the life of a citizen of this place, and the other 
                    had just committed an outrage upon a white girl.  After the mob got the 
                    negroes together, they proceeded to the outskirts of the town, and 
                    selecting a proper place, chained the negro who killed Hinton, to a 
                    stake, got a quantity of dry wood, piled it around him, and set it on 
                    fire!  Then commenced a scene which for sickening horrors has never been 
                    witnessed before in this, or perhaps any other place.</p>
                    <p>The negro was 
                    stripped to his waist, and barefooted.  He looked the picture of 
                    despair--but there was no sympathy felt for him at the moment.  
                    Presently the fire began to surge up in flames around him, and its 
                    effects were soon made visible in the futile attempts of the poor wretch 
                    to move his feet.  As the flames gathered around his limbs and body, he 
                    commenced the most frantic shrieks and appeals for mercy--for death--for 
                    water!  He seized his chains--they were hot, and burnt the flesh off his 
                    hands.  He would drop them and catch at them again and again.   Then he 
                    would repeat his cries; but all to no purpose.  In a few moments he was 
                    a charred mass--bones and flesh alike burnt into a powder.  Many, very 
                    many of the spectators, who did not realize the full horrors of the 
                    scene until it was too late to change it, retired disgusted and sick at 
                    the sight. May Marshall never witness such another spectacle.</p>
                    <p> The ends 
                        of justice are surely as fully accomplished by the ordinary process 
                        of law as by the violence of an excited populace.</p>
                    <p> If the horrors of 
                        the day had ended here, it would have been well, but the other negroes 
                        were taken and hung--justly, perhaps--but in violation of law and good 
                        order.  They exhibited no remorse.  One of the simply remarked, "that he 
                        hoped before they hunt him they would let him see the other boy burnt!"</p> 
                    <p>The Saline County Herald, edited by Mr. Geo. W. Allen, formerly of this 
                        county, confirms the above, and gives and account of the hanging of 
                        another negro by the people.  On a Monday, the 18th, a little girl of 
                        Arrow Rock, Saline county, who was in company with another little girl, 
                        and some little boys, returning from gathering blackberries, was picked 
                        up in the road by a negro fellow and carried into the woods, and there 
                        most brutally treated.  Mr. N.H. Huston was the first to arrive at the 
                        place, but not in time to arrest the scoundrel.  He was subsequently 
                        arrested, and upon an examination before a Committee--and after his 
                        guilt was made apparent, he was taken and hanged on Monday night, and 
                        his body was permitted to remain upon the tree until Tuesday morning.  
                        The burning and hanging in Marshall occurred on Tuesday.</p>
              </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <commentary/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes a lynching of a black man, who was burnt at the stake by a mob in
                    Marshall, Saline County, Missouri. The victim allegedly murdered a white man.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/ssaug59.html#8.2b</note>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>For the Spectator: "Camp Meetings"</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript><p>Messrs. Editors:--The lovers of peace and good order will 
                    appreciate the motive which prompts this communication.  Far back, in 
                    the early history of this country, when its population was sparse, and 
                    churches few and far between, a necessity prompted the large and 
                    promiscuous assemblages at certain places, for religious exercises, 
                    known as "Camp- meetings."--Families removed to such places in their 
                    wagons, and either used them as places in which to lodge, or erected 
                    temporary huts or cabins, to be used during the continuance of the 
                    meeting. This was a period of our history when the people appreciated 
                    such opportunities, and to a greater or less degree profited, it may be, 
                    by them.--That day has long since passed away. Churches have so 
                    multiplied everywhere in our Valley, at least, as to do away with a 
                    necessity for such assemblages.  The Methodist denomination was the 
                    first to introduce them, but for some years past they have yielded to an 
                    enlightened public sentiment and abandoned them.  The character of 
                    the crowds which were drawn together, made up in a great degree of all 
                    that is most repulsive in society, and from great distances very often, 
                    hastened this feeling of opposition and prejudice against them.  The 
                    mischief done on such occasions very far over balanced any good.  The 
                    Sabbath has been almost entirely ignored, the peace and good order of 
                    society violated by drunkenness, profanity, fighting, huckstering, 
                    lewdness, and in short, by the perpetration of almost every crime.  The 
                    families of those en camping on the ground, especially in the females, 
                    have had such an amount of drudgery and labor to perform in cooking and 
                    providing for the entertainment of their many friends and acquaintances, 
                    as to make it next to impossible they should enjoy any of the benefits 
                    of public worship.  The neighborhood selected for such a meeting, regard 
                    it with anything but a feeling of comfort, and always desire it shall 
                    for the future be abated as a nuisance.  Contiguous land holders 
                    suffer in the throwing down their  fences, trespassing on their 
                    fields and crops, robbing their orchards and hen roosts, corrupting 
                    their slaves and ignoring their rights of every kind.--The business of 
                    the Courts is much increased and a conscienscious grand juror finds much 
                    to engage his attention.</p>
                    <p> In view of this state of public sentiment and 
                        the results of the Camp Meetings, as we read their history in the past, 
                        you will feel surprise, Messrs. Editors, to learn that an effort is on 
                        foot to institute them again, on the part of some of our Methodist 
                        friends.  I say some, for I feel well assured, but few of them enter 
                        heartily into the idea. One of their clergy with intemperate zeal 
                        insists a Camp Meeting must and shall be held "altho  a devil should be 
                        find behind every tree," to use the language which dame Rumour 
                        attributes to him; I am aware she is sometimes mendacious, but in this 
                        instance she approximates very closely, I presume, to the truth.  He 
                        urges, too, that it be held hard by a church of another denomination, 
                        when, I doubt not, other situations might readily be had, where no 
                        conflict or interference with other denominations could be feared.  
                        Should such meeting be held, may we not hope that the amount of good may 
                        very far counterbalance the evil, and in such an event no one will more 
                        heartily rejoice than CONSERVATOR.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Conservator</trailer>
                <commentary/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Diatribe against Camp Meetings. The Spectator believes that they are
                    destructive of adjoining property, breed crime, and are ignorant of the Sabbath.
                    Article threatens an Anti-meeting movement.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/ssaug59.html#8.2</note>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Top of the page is a bit obscured by headline from the other side</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1859.08.02.03">
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <commentary/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClune</ln>
                        <fn>R. Lewis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Buchanan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on July 28.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <commentary/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McElheney</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burwell</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Burwell of Lewisburg, married there on July 28.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Markets in column 2; Outside wedding, deaths</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1859.08.02.04">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
