<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- !DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd' -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1859/va.au.ss.1859.11.22">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Jeff McClurken</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/15/95</tagDate>
            <tagNote>2nd Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1859-11-22">
            <year>1859</year>
            <month norm="11">November</month>
            <day>22</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote>Note that there was no November 15 edition.</editionNote>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1859.11.22.01"><div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>For the Spectator; Agriculture of Augusta County</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>J. L. Campbell</trailer>
                <commentary/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Part of continuing series. This section: Hay and Pasture, Varieties,
                    Seeding, Watered meadows</summary>
            </div><pageNote>&gt;Bottom corner dark, almost unreadable</pageNote>&gt; </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1859.11.22.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Military Movements</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <commentary/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waters</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hay</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The West Augusta guard was briefly summoned to Charlestown on November 19
                    because of fears that some of Brown's supporters might attempt to help him
                    escape.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/ssnov59.html#11.22a</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Tide Police</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <commentary/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Editorial endorsing the upcoming Opposition convention as Virginia's
                    bulwark against rising tides of sectionalism. The Opposition trusts that its
                    members will not succumb to Republican anti-slavery. Article discusses problem
                    of slave drain.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Nicholas C. Kinney</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <commentary/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>Nicholas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Obituary for Kinney, former clerk of Augusta circuit court and War of 1812
                    veteran.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Excitement at Charlestown</head>
                <origin>Harpers Ferry, Washington</origin>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript><p>Harper's Ferry, November 17.--There is considerable excitement here 
                    and at Charlestown in regard to the numerous cases of incendiarism 
                    occurring. There were five barns and outhouses burnt to-day in the 
                    neighborhood of Charlestown, and we learn that in consequence of this 
                    Colonel Davis, who was placed in charge of the military at Charlestown, 
                    has telegraphed to Governor Wise requesting immediately two companies of 
                    cavalry to aid in arresting all suspected parties found lurking in the 
                    neighborhood.</p>
                    <p> Second Despatch.--There are numerous exciting rumors here relative 
                        to an attempted rescue being contemplated. One rumor says there are some 
                        two or three hundred men armed with Sharp's rifles encamped near 
                        Berryville, near Charlestown, but doubtless it is unfounded. A messenger 
                        has been sent to ascertain the facts, but has not yet returned.</p>
                    <p> Washington, November 17.--Owing to dispatches received from 
                        Charlestown, Governor Wise has ordered three hundred men and two pieces 
                        of artillery to leave Alexandria at day break for Charlestown. The 
                        Richmond forces will probably leave on an express train at an early 
                        hour. This prompt action is understood to be in response to the request 
                        made by Col. Davis, at Charlestown, for troops to aid in arresting the 
                        incendiaries who infest that section of the State and other obnoxious 
                        individuals.</p>
                    <p> Harper's Ferry, Nov. 18.--The messenger sent last night from this 
                        place to Charlestown, to ascertain the truth or falsity of the exciting 
                        rumors that have been circulating through this region, touching 
                        incendiary attempts to destroy the property of citizens of Jefferson 
                        county, and of anticipated attempts to rescue the condemned prisoners 
                        now confined in jail there, did not return until about 4 o'clock this 
                        morning.</p>
                    <p> It appears that when he reached the outskirts of Charlestown he was 
                        stopped by some of the guards, who were on the watch for suspicious 
                        individuals, and detained for some two and a half hours before he could 
                        be permitted to enter the village. The military had been ordered out, 
                        and  were guarding all the roads in anticipation of an attack, by 
                        whom, or from what quarter, is not stated. The night, however, was 
                        passed undisturbed.</p>
                    <p> The only fact gathered is that a very large fire had been burning at 
                        a distance of some four miles from Charlestown, the exact locality of 
                        which was not known.</p>
                    <p> There were any amount of rumors afloat, and a considerable amount of 
                        nervous excitement manifested by the citizens.</p>
                    <p> Second Despatch.--Evening--The excitement here last night was caused 
                        by the burning of a wheat stack about three miles from Charlestown. The 
                        military and populace were called to arms, and the wildest terror 
                        prevailed among the people, the supposition being that Col. Davis had 
                        some information of approaching danger. The panic of the people extended 
                        to Col. Davis, and a messenger was sent by him to the Ferry with a 
                        despatch for the Governor, calling for two companies of cavalry. This 
                        morning the fire was found to have been the work of an unknown 
                        incendiary, but no person could be found in the county on whom 
                        suspicion could rest.--There are now one thousand men under arms and no 
                        enemy to be found for them to encounter.--The troops from Alexandria 
                        arrived at Charlestown this afternoon, and those sent by the Mayor of 
                        Winchester are expected tomorrow morning.</p>
                    <p> The Baltimore and Ohio Railroad Company have sent Col. A. P. Shutt 
                        with an armed posse to Harper's Ferry, to guard the bridge and the 
                        property of the company at that point.</p>
                    <p> There is much dissatisfaction expressed both here and at Charlestown 
                        at the precipitate action of Col. Davis in sending despatches for 
                        troops, instead of first sending out a posse to inquire into the cause 
                        of the fire. They think they have been made to appear in a ridiculous 
                        light before the country, and they are more than half right on that 
                        point.</p>
                    <p> 10 P. M.--Despatches just received from Charlestown say that there 
                        is no cause for alarm, and there has been no evidence of any kind of an 
                        attempt to rescue the prisoners. Some four or five suspicious 
                        characters were traced and driven off. The whole alarm is perfectly 
                        ridiculous and without foundation. Washington, Nov. 18.--The government 
                        today ordered two thousand pounds of powder to be sent to Harper's 
                        Ferry's with a large number of Minie rifle bal's and some howitzer 
                        shells from the Washington Arsenal.</p></transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <commentary/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Series of dispatches from Harpers Ferry and Washington about possible
                    insurrections stemming from John Brown's raid. People are really on edge.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/ssnov59.html#11.22b</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Arrest of a Suspected Insurgent</head>
                <origin>Memphis Enquirer</origin>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript><p>It has already been mentioned that a Dr. Wm. A. Palmer has 
                    been arrested at Memphis, Tenn., of suspicion of being connected with 
                    the Harper's Ferry business. The Memphis Enquirer says:</p>
                    <p> It seems that Palmer has been a resident of this vicinity for a 
                        number of years past; that he married a lady residing near town, but 
                        procured a divorce some months since on account of domestic 
                        difficulties, and has since that time boarded at the Redford House, 
                        where he was arrested. Palmer is a man about 40 years of age, very 
                        respectable in appearance, five feet eight inches in height, slightly 
                        stooping, and hesitates somewhat in his speech.</p>
                    <p> It appears that some two weeks ago, during the excitement of the 
                        Harper's Ferry insurrection, a gentleman, seated in a railroad car 
                        between Baltimore and Philadelphia, on his way to New York, observed a 
                        man on a seat near him closely muffled, appearing to use every means 
                        possible to prevent recognition, and shield himself from observation. On 
                        the arrival of the train at a station, the man hurriedly gathered up 
                        and left the car. The attention of the gentleman who had previously 
                        noticed his movements was attracted to a number of letters and papers on 
                        the floor beneath the seat, which had accidently been dropped in his 
                        haste. He gathered the papers, but the car at that moment starting, he 
                        was obliged to return to his seat, with the documents in his possession. 
                        They proved to be two letters and a small memorandum. This being, as 
                        stated, at the time when the whole community was aroused to the 
                        movements of the insurrection, the defeat and imprisonment of its 
                        leader, and the letter being addressed to John Brown, connected with the 
                        suspicious movements of the man in whose possession they had been, 
                        excited his curiosity not a little. The idea flashed on his mind that he 
                        had in his possession something which would throw light on this subject. 
                        He accordingly perused the open letter, which greatly confirmed his 
                        suspicions. On his arrival in New York he addressed Gov. Wise of 
                        Virginia, an anonymous letter, enclosing the documents, stating the 
                        circumstances connected with his possession of them, and his suspicion. 
                        On their receipt Gov. Wise immediately forwarded them to Gov. Harris, 
                        who thought the matter of sufficient importance to demand an 
                        investigation. He accordingly dispatched John B. Church, of Chattanooga, 
                        to this city, who arrived some time last week, and after various 
                        inquiries and investigations arrested Palmer as previously stated.</p>
                    <p> The court room during his examination was densely crowded, and a 
                        great deal of excitement was manifested. After a thorough examination 
                        into all the facts of the case, Palmer was required to enter into bonds 
                        of $2,500 for his appearance at the District Court, in default of which 
                        he was committed to prison.</p>
                    <p> The letters were addressed respectively to Captain J. Brown, 
                        Harper's Ferry, and to Wm. Horner, the former being signed by Lawrence 
                        Thatcher, and dated Memphis, October 3, 1859, the latter by Mary Horner, 
                        at Chambersburg, October 20, being an entreaty that William, her 
                        husband, would not go to Harper's Ferry. The writer of the letter signed 
                        Lawrence Thatcher, and addressed to Captain Brown, says: "I have just 
                        completed my tour through the Southern States, and am now on my way to 
                        Kentucky.--In my last letter to you, I mentioned that I should give the 
                        States of Tennessee and Arkansas a thorough scouring. I did so, and am 
                        satisfied that of all the States in the South, Tennessee and Arkansas 
                        are the best fitted to make the first strike in." He also states that on 
                        arriving at Memphis he had an interview with Palmer, who sympathized 
                        with Captain Brown. He (Palmer) had made arrangements to take five 
                        hundred or a thousand slaves off to the swamps of Indiana. That he had 
                        friends in Cincinnati who had promised to have one of the largest and 
                        swiftest steamers on the river sent to tie up and wait for them at the 
                        mouth of the Hatchie river, under the pretence of undergoing 
                        repairs.</p></transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <commentary/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Details the arrest of another Harpers Ferry conspirator, Dr. William A.
                    Palmer, in Memphis.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/ssnov59.html#11.22c</note>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>For the Spectator; Virginia Central Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>A Stockholder</trailer>
                <commentary/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter complaining about the "old fogy" management and policies of the
                    Virginia Central Railroad, which the writer believes is very expensive and
                    poorly scheduled.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Northern Sentiment</head>
                <origin>National Intelligencer</origin>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The New York correspondent of the National Intelligencer, in his letter of 
                    the 14th inst., sustains the views which we presented last week in 
                    regard to the sentiments of the Northern people about the Harper's Ferry 
                    affair. He says: "The Express speaks wisely and well when it advises 
                    calmness and contempt, rather than angry recrimination towards the ultra 
                    editors and preachers in the North who fulminate violent diatribes in 
                    the South and manifest maudlin sympathy for John Brown and his guilty 
                    followers. It is right in the declaration that expressions of sympathy 
                    for the treasonable outbreak at Harper's Ferry, and those engaged in it 
                    as the chief actors, are confined principally to certain leading 
                    politicians and fanatical literateurs, who in no way express the 
                    sentiments of the mess of the Northern people. It protests against 
                    holding the conservative men of the country responsible for the 
                    extremists of the North; and it repeats what can be confirmed by 
                    indubitable proof, that  there are three- quarter of a million of 
                    voters in the Free States, disgusted alike with both the Republican and 
                    Democratic parties, who have remained at home at the recent State 
                    elections. It is to be hoped the assertion will be verified that these 
                    voters will be heard from in 1860, in such a manner as to give practical 
                    evidence that no merely sectional man or sectional party can receive at 
                    the hands of the people an election for the first office in the 
                    Government.</p></transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <commentary/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Report on Northern opinion of John Brown and raid, claiming that the
                    majority of people are not so sympathetic as their leaders make them out to be.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/ssnov59.html#11.22d</note>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>More Anon.</trailer>
                <commentary/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter expressing hope that new county surveyors will make sure that public
                    roads are made thirty feet wide.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote>This page is somewhat faint.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1859.11.22.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Excitement at Charlestown, VA</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Charlestown is still in an uproar after the Harper's Ferry raid because
                    many of its inhabitants believe that some of Brown's men are still in the
                    vicinity.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/ssnov59.html#11.22e</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <commentary/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richardson</ln>
                        <fn>X.J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shuby</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miser</ln>
                        <fn>Julia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on November 13.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <commentary/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>See</ln>
                        <fn>C.S.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Black</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moffitt</ln>
                        <fn>M. Cornelia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married at Locust Hill on November 17.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <commentary/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keller</ln>
                        <fn>Sophia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keller</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sophia Keller died at age 96. She was a member of the German Reform
                Church.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Tribute of Respect</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <commentary/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickle</ln>
                        <fn>Adam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waters</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn>F.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Tribute for Bickle, War of 1812 veteran, from the West Augusta
                Guard.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Tribute of Respect</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <commentary/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>Nicholas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waters</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn>F.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Tribute of respect for Kinney, War of 1812 veteran, from the West Augusta
                    Guard.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Tribute of Respect</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <commentary/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>Nicholas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Michie</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander H.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Tribute of respect for Kinney from the members of the Staunton
                Bar.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Markets in column 2.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1859.11.22.04">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
