<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1860/pa.fr.vs.1860.03.07">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Jeff McClurken</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/22/95</tagDate>
            <tagNote>2nd Pass; Andy Morris did first pass.</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1860-03-07">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day norm="07">7</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.03.07.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Democratic State Convention: The Democracy of the State in Council</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary/>
                <note>Henry D. Foster nominated for governor; delegates chosen for Charleston
                    Convention.</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.03.07.02">
            <pageNote>Poetry, stories, moral tales</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.03.07.03">
            <pageNote>Poetry and advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.03.07.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Illness of Judge Black</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Judge Black, the Valley Spirit's candidate for President, has fallen ill.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Mr. McPherson's Speech</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Attacks speech by Pennsylvania Congressman McPherson, which blamed the
                    Democrats for sowing seeds of disunion, and goes on to give general distinctions
                    between Democrats and Republicans.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>To the Editor</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Truth</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Attacks the Franklin Transcript for its opposition to Buchanan and for its
                    abolitionist sentiment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Experience in the North</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Serialized letters between uncle and nephew as nephew explores the North.
                    The nephew is an abolitionist, and his uncle seeks to convince him of the error
                    of his ways.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Seward's Speech</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Somewhat sympathetic article to Seward, stating that if anybody could
                    rescue the Republicans it would be Seward. However, his effort has generally
                    been a failure.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.03.07.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Valuation of Franklin County</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The Board of Revenue Commissioners which meet tri-ennially to determine
                    the valuation of all taxable property, in the several counties of the
                    Commonwealth, and adjust and equalize the same, had the following proceedings
                    before it while Franklin County was under consideration."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--The Board of Revenue Commissioners which meet tri-ennially to determine the
                        valuation of all taxable property, in the several counties of the
                        Commonwealth, and adjust and equalize the same, had the following
                        proceedings before it while Franklin County was under consideration.</p>
                    <p>The assessed valuation returned to the Revenue Board, by the Commissioners of
                        this county, as the assessment for 1860 amounted to $11,043,877. To this sum
                        the Board added one million of dollars as the Valuation for Franklin County,
                        making the total valuation upon which the tax for the next three years would
                        be assessed $12,043,877.</p>
                    <p>This action of the Board seemed unjust to Franklin County when compared with
                        the valuation at which other counties of the Commonwealth, of greater wealth
                        and population, are rated. Mr. Eyster, County Commissioner, together with
                        Messrs. McLellan, Nill, McClure and Rowe, appeared before the Board, and by
                        their representations convinced them of their unfairness in adjusting the
                        valuation of Franklin County. The Board thereupon struck off half a million
                        of dollars leaving the actual valuation for 1860 at $11,548,877, which is a
                        reduction on the previous valuation of 1857 of $1,525,307. and consequently
                        effecting a reduction on our State Tax of $3,781.25.</p>
                    <p>We have always contended that Franklin County was rated too high, in
                        comparison with other counties, and thereby compelled to pay an unjust
                        proportion of State Tax. As the valuation now stands we are placed on a more
                        equal footing with other counties, and tax-payers should feel themselves
                        under obligations to the gentlemen through whose instrumentality the
                        reduction was effected.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLellan</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nill</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rowe</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Franklin County delegation protested to Board of Revenue Commissioners over
                    the county's valuation of taxable property.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/march60.html#3.7b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Extension of the Borough</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"At a meeting of the Town Council, on Monday evening last, it was
                    determined to extend the borough lines so as to admit the portion of Guilford
                    township praying to be annexed."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--At a meeting of the Town Council, on Monday evening last, it was determined
                        to extend the borough lines so as to admit the portion of Guilford township
                        praying to be annexed. An Ordinance to this effect was unanimously passed by
                        the Council and will be published in the papers, of this place, the present
                        week. We described the boundary of the territory, desiring to be admitted,
                        in an article published in the <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph>, on the
                        Extension of the Borough, a few weeks ago. We extend the hand of welcome to
                        Kerrstown, Broad-Lane, Ripper's Point, Clarksville, &amp;c., and trust
                        they will deport themselves with becoming dignity since we have extended the
                        egis of our municipal authority over them. Couldn't we have some bon-fires
                        over the "consolidation?"--This triumph over Old Fogyism certainly deserves
                        some public demonstration.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Town Council agreed to extend borough lines to include portions of Guilford
                    Township.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/march60.html#3.7a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Shryock</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Mr. Shryock is unquestionably an able lecturer, and without making any
                    pretensions in that line, will mix up as much genuine wit and sound philosophy
                    in his discourse as can be found in the efforts of any of the popular lecturers
                    of the day."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--Our esteemed townsman Mr. J. K. Shryock delivered a lecture before the
                        citizens of Hagerstown, recently, that we are happy to perceive is "cracked
                        up" in the most complimentary manner by the papers of that place. Mr.
                        Shryock is unquestionably an able lecturer, and without making any
                        pretensions in that line, will mix up as much genuine wit and sound
                        philosophy in his discourse as can be found in the efforts of any of the
                        popular lecturers of the day. We are glad to find his talents and social
                        qualities as highly appreciated abroad as they are at home.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shryock</ln>
                        <fn>J.K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. K. Shryock gave a lecture in Hagerstown.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/march60.html#3.7c</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Woolen Goods</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel White, proprietor of Franklin Woolen Factory, left a sample in the
                    Valley Spirit offices.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Handsome Monument</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beatty</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beatty</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James King constructed handsome marble statue for grave of Catharine
                    Beatty.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Franklin Hall</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sanford</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Minstrel company visited Chambersburg, and Valley Spirit approved of both
                    the show and the behavior of the black troupe in general.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Accident</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trostle</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Daniel Trostle was thrown from his sulky.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Poor House</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woods</ln>
                        <fn>Richard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>This article covers the decision to remodel and improve building for
                    blacks.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Accident</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nelson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A wagon was upset and passengers hurt.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Tavern Stand Sold</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Welsh</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trostle</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reilly</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary/>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Anonymous Present</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Senseny</ln>
                        <fn>A.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Son of Dr. Senseny received a pony as an anonymous present.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Singular Accident</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>West</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A child of Samuel West choked on a cherry.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Dead</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnston</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Johnston, late County Commissioner, died after a short illness.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Public Schools</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shoemaker</ln>
                        <fn>P.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Superintendent Shoemaker visited the borough's schools and pronounced them
                    excellent.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Census of 1860</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Knowledge to be treasured in the archives of the government, and in after
                    years to furnish contrast and comparisons, for deducing sound rules in the
                    administrations of government, and promoting the general welfare of the people."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Waynesboro</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Encourages all citizens to fully disclose all information to the census
                    takers, and not to be suspicious of the process because of fears of taxation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Justice of the Peace</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Relsher</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel Relsher will be a candidate for Justice of the Peace in the South
                    Ward.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bishop</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ebersole</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Unger</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married at Pleasant Street Parsonage, March 1.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roth</ln>
                        <fn>G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tritle</ln>
                        <fn>J.G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tritle</ln>
                        <fn>Lydia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married in Chambersburg, February 14.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn>J. Smith</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGowen</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Geyer</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married at bride's father's house, February 28.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McElroy</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McNew</ln>
                        <fn>Boyle</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henrock</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on March 1.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phillips</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClelland</ln>
                        <fn>J.P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoke</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married at Franklin Hotel, February 29.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phillips</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rebber</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lightcap</ln>
                        <fn>Mary C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married at bride's parent's residence, March 1.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phillips</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heller</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>Barbary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married March 1.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bitner</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bitner</ln>
                        <fn>Christian</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Died of typhoid fever on February 24 at age 40.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>illegible at bottom of page</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.03.07.06">
            <pageNote>Moral stories and advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.03.07.07">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Woman's Advantages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>List of advantages women have over men.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Hints to Parents</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Advises treating children with love and tenderness.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Poetry and advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.03.07.08">
            <pageNote>Travelogue, non-fiction, for-sale advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
