<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1860/pa.fr.vs.1860.11.14">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Jeff McClurken</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/22/95</tagDate>
            <tagNote>2nd Pass; Colleen Doody did first pass.</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1860-11-14">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="11">November</month>
            <day>14</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.11.14.01">
            <pageNote>Stories</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.11.14.02">
            <pageNote>Stories and poems</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.11.14.03">
            <pageNote>Stories and advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.11.14.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Fifteen States are without a President--they took no part in his election,
                    and refuse their consent to come under an administration founded upon a
                    sentiment hostile to their social system. A contemporary remarks--'It remains
                    for the fifteen slave States to say whether the Union shall continue, or whether
                    by secession this confederacy of thirty-three States shall be reduced to
                    eighteen.'"</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The election is over and so far as the grand result is concerned there is no
                        longer any suspense. The North has rolled up a decisive majority for ABRAHAM
                        LINCOLN as President, and HANIBAL [sic] HAMLIN as Vice President of the
                        Nation. It is the first time in the history of the country that its national
                        head has been elected by a purely sectional vote. What the result of this
                        sectional triumph will be it is not difficult to conjecture. Fifteen States
                        are without a President--they took no part in his election, and refuse their
                        consent to come under an administration founded upon a sentiment hostile to
                        their social system. A contemporary remarks--"It remains for the fifteen
                        slave States to say whether the Union shall continue, or whether by
                        secession this confederacy of thirty-three States shall be reduced to
                        eighteen. That occurring, it will then have to be determined whether the
                        Middle States will consent to remain in association with the New England
                        States, and whether the empire of the Northwest will remain as it is, or set
                        up for itself. Let disintegration once begin, and no man can tell where it
                        will stop."</p>
                    <p>While we fear the worst results to the nation from the election of LINCOLN we
                        still trust that the threatened calamity may be averted--that He who holds
                        the destiny of nations in His hands and whose high prerogative it is to
                        change curses into blessings and to extract good from evil may turn aside
                        the danger in our way, and our glorious union still remain--</p>
                    <p>"Giant aggregate of nations; <lb/>Glorious whole of glorious parts, <lb/>
                        Unto endless generations <lb/> Live united, hands and hearts! <lb/> Be it
                        storm or summer weather, <lb/> Peaceful calm or battle jar, <lb/> Stand in
                        bounteous strength together, <lb/> Sister States, as now ye are." </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Abraham Lincoln has won a decisive victory in the North, the first time a
                    president has been elected by a purely sectional vote. As a result of Lincoln's
                    victory, "Fifteen states are without a President--they took no part in his
                    election, and refuse their consent to come under an administration founded upon
                    a sentiment hostile to their social system."</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/nov60.html#11.14a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Vote of Franklin County</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The apathy which has existed in the Democratic party since our defeat in
                    October has allowed the Republicans to have things pretty much their own way."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The following table exhibits the vote for Presidential Electors in this
                        county. It will be seen that the Republicans have carried the county by a
                        largely increased majority over the vote at the October election. The apathy
                        which has existed in the Democratic party since our defeat in October has
                        allowed the Republicans to have things pretty much their own way. We are
                        only surprised that the Democracy turned out as well as they did with defeat
                        again staring them in the face. They have done nobly--they deserve success.
                        Though defeated they have by their votes proclaimed their devotion to their
                        party, and their country, and that is something to be proud of--something to
                        fall back on--a rallying point for a future victory.</p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Districts Republican</cell>
                            <cell>Breckinridge</cell>
                            <cell>Douglas</cell>
                            <cell>Bell</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>C'burg, N. Ward</cell>
                            <cell>355</cell>
                            <cell>63</cell>
                            <cell>72</cell>
                            <cell>11</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>C'burg, S. Ward</cell>
                            <cell>287</cell>
                            <cell>48</cell>
                            <cell>133</cell>
                            <cell>10</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Antrim</cell>
                            <cell>488</cell>
                            <cell>263</cell>
                            <cell>152</cell>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Concord</cell>
                            <cell>31</cell>
                            <cell>94</cell>
                            <cell>3</cell>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Dry Run</cell>
                            <cell>100</cell>
                            <cell>95</cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Fayetteville</cell>
                            <cell>308</cell>
                            <cell>142</cell>
                            <cell>5</cell>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Greenvillage</cell>
                            <cell>196</cell>
                            <cell>62</cell>
                            <cell>44</cell>
                            <cell>1</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Guilford</cell>
                            <cell>196</cell>
                            <cell>73</cell>
                            <cell>79</cell>
                            <cell>1</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Hamilton</cell>
                            <cell>146</cell>
                            <cell>63</cell>
                            <cell>41</cell>
                            <cell>1</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Letterkenny</cell>
                            <cell>190</cell>
                            <cell>183</cell>
                            <cell>6</cell>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Loudon</cell>
                            <cell>103</cell>
                            <cell>85</cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>1</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Lurgan</cell>
                            <cell>112</cell>
                            <cell>135</cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Montgomery</cell>
                            <cell>283</cell>
                            <cell>120</cell>
                            <cell>3</cell>
                            <cell>29</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Metal</cell>
                            <cell>160</cell>
                            <cell>75</cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>1</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Orrstown</cell>
                            <cell>101</cell>
                            <cell>103</cell>
                            <cell>1</cell>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Peters</cell>
                            <cell>140</cell>
                            <cell>88</cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>3</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Quincy</cell>
                            <cell>238</cell>
                            <cell>210</cell>
                            <cell>35</cell>
                            <cell>6</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>St. Thomas</cell>
                            <cell>176</cell>
                            <cell>127</cell>
                            <cell>13</cell>
                            <cell>4</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Southampton</cell>
                            <cell>75</cell>
                            <cell>52</cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Sulpher Spring</cell>
                            <cell>42</cell>
                            <cell>45</cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Warren</cell>
                            <cell>58</cell>
                            <cell>65</cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Washington</cell>
                            <cell>341</cell>
                            <cell>252</cell>
                            <cell>18</cell>
                            <cell>13</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Welsh Run</cell>
                            <cell>105</cell>
                            <cell>128</cell>
                            <cell>9</cell>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Total</cell>
                            <cell>
                                <emph rend="bold">4151</emph>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <emph rend="bold">2515</emph>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <emph rend="bold">622</emph>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <emph rend="bold">76</emph>
                            </cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Table of vote totals for Franklin County. The county voted overwhelmingly
                    Republican.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>Look</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Douglas in a New Role</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Douglas has proposed to save the Union by making a pro-Union speech in the
                    South. "As he has not received the vote of any State in the Union, . . . his
                    efforts at Union-saving will at least have the merit of disinterestedness to
                    recommend them."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>United States Senator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A number of Republicans are scrambling for the Pennsylvania Senate seat,
                    including A. K. McClure and John W. Forney.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Its Days are Numbered</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt> "Republicanism under the rule of LINCOLN will be but short-lived--its days
                    are already numbered, it will die by its own hands ere four years roll around.
                    It is now intoxicated with a victory which it has not the inherent strength to
                    achieve--it is only <emph rend="italic">accidentally successful</emph>, for the
                    moment, through division and dissension in the Democratic party." </excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Republicanism under the rule of LINCOLN will be but short-lived--its days are
                        already numbered, it will die by its own hands ere four years roll around.
                        It is now intoxicated with a victory which it has not the inherent strength
                        to achieve--it is only <emph rend="italic">accidentally successful</emph>,
                        for the moment, through division and dissension in the Democratic party. Its
                        success cannot be regarded as a true expression of the public
                        sentiment--when that turns up right, which it is sure to do, the Democracy
                        will once more regain its ascendancy as the righteous head of the Nation. We
                        extract from the columns of a contemporary the following sensible comment on
                        the difficulties which will beset the incoming administration: "LINCOLN's
                        Electoral majority will not be overwhelmingly large--only decisive. but he
                        will have against him reliable and controlling majorities in both houses of
                        Congress. He will only have the negative power conferred by the veto. From
                        active aggressive mischief he will be restrained by these majorities.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Lincoln will be beset in the beginning of his administration, should he
                        indeed be destined to have an administration, by three formidable
                        difficulties.</p>
                    <p>The first will be to satisfy the South.</p>
                    <p>The second will be to retain his popularity and influence with the two
                        divisions of his party--the rampant Abolitionists, and the more moderate
                        Anti-Slavery men.</p>
                    <p>The third will be the distribution of the patronage and the spoils. A million
                        of hungry, half-famished men, with mouths stretched, will be clamoring for
                        place and plunder. All expect something, while few can get anything.</p>
                    <p>On these last two rocks he is destined to split, and that in a short time
                        after this inauguration."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Republican victory did not really represent the "true expression of the
                    public sentiment." Republicanism will not last beyond Lincoln's first term.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>A Crumb of Comfort</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spirit criticizes the Times for pretending to be Democrats and voting
                    for "a bogus ticket for the purpose of defeating their party."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Clean Thing</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"In eight townships in this county there was not a single straight-out
                    Douglas ticket voted, although each district in the county was well supplied
                    with the bogus tickets by the Douglas managers in Chambersburg. The Democracy of
                    Franklin County is not just so easily corrupted as the Chambersburg straight-out
                    Douglas clique imagines."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Straight-Out Fraud</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The "pretended withdrawal of the straight-out Douglas ticket was a cheat
                    and a sham, and . . . the advocacy of the Reading Ticket by the Times was
                    hypocritical to the last degree of meanness."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Lincoln's Army</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Republican office seekers are on the march looking for spoils.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Lincoln's Cabinet</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>After seeing the list of Lincoln's proposed Cabinet, the Spirit believes
                    that the Lincoln administration will not follow the conservative course that was
                    promised during the campaign.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Election Returns</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Pennsylvania voted for Lincoln by a large majority--probably 60,000 to
                    70,000 votes. The Spirit will publish the official vote total next week.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>A Storm Brewing</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lincoln's rumored letter that is designed to sooth the nerves of
                    Southerners has angered Greely and the Abolitionists. They want to "push on the
                    'irrepressible conflict' to the bitter end."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Presidential Election--Triumph of the Sectional Party--Lincoln and Hamlin
                    Elected</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Preliminary electoral college totals.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>The Next Congress</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Republicans will not have a majority in Congress. The Democrats will
                    have a 125 to 109 majority in the House and a majority of 8 in the Senate. This
                    includes Southern representatives.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Railroads</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Chambersburg has not gotten past the talking stage in its desire to build a
                    railroad. The Spirit points out that the small town of Edenburg, with a
                    population of 1000, has built ten miles of railroad.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Water Suit</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The "Water Suit" between Mr. Sol Haber and J. J. Kennedy, "in which this
                    entire community seemed deeply interested," was terminated. The jury found in
                    favor of the plaintiff for $513. The defendant's counsel asked the Spirit to
                    make no comment on the proceedings because the verdict will be appealed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.11.14.05">
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McHenry</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Diehl</ln>
                        <fn>Adam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zook</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on November 8.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Philips</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foltz</ln>
                        <fn>M.A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Etter</ln>
                        <fn>Charlotte</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on November 6th at the German Reformed Parsonage.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Philips</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Alexander</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elightfoot</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on November 8th at the German Reformed Parsonage.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Philips</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dittman</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vanderau</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on November 8th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bunn</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bunn</ln>
                        <fn>Miles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Margaret Bunn died on November 9th, aged 78 years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCardy</ln>
                        <fn>David Edgar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCardy</ln>
                        <fn>R.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCardy</ln>
                        <fn>Martha</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>David Edgar died on November 7th, aged 6 months.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Stories and advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.11.14.06">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.11.14.07">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.11.14.08">
            <pageNote>Stories and advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
