<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1860/pa.fr.vs.1860.04.25">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Jeff McClurken</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/22/95</tagDate>
            <tagNote>2nd Pass; Andy Morris did first pass.</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1860-04-25">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day>25</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.04.25.01">
            <pageNote>Non-fiction, general political commentary on national issues</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.04.25.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The End of a Woman's Caprices</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Fictional story of a woman who would not tell her suitor if she loved him
                    or not. When he leaves, she finds that she truly misses him. He returns in
                    disguise, she admits her love, he reveals himself, and they marry.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Poetry, fiction</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.04.25.03">
            <pageNote>Poetry and advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.04.25.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Not Very Consistent</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that Republicans supporting the investigation of Buchanan and not
                    that of Senator Sanborn, who allegedly contributed money to John Brown, are
                    hypocrites.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>National Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"This is the most important party convention that ever assembled in this
                    country."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Expresses hope that the party will unify behind a conservative ticket, but
                    fears that it will not.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Defining Its Position</head>
                <origin>Philadelphia Evening Journal</origin>
                <commentary>Cites approvingly the evidence that conservative men, who are not
                    necessarily Democrats, can unite together against the "Black Republicans."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Journal announces that it supports the Constitutional Union party, but
                    its main principles are opposition to sectionalism and abolitionism. It vows to
                    fight the Republicans at every turn.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Mr. Buchanan's Letter to Gov. Walker</head>
                <origin>Pennsylvanian</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprints and commentary of an 1857 letter written by Buchanan, brought in
                    front of the Covode Investigating Committee, which shows Buchanan agreeing to
                    the Lecompton Constitution. Both the Valley Spirit and the Pennsylvanian argue
                    that there is nothing damning revealed in the letter.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>By Telegraph For The Valley Spirit From Charleston</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Summary of events at opening day of Democratic National Convention in
                    Charleston, Virginia. Bickering over seating New York and Illinois delegations
                    ties up the convention, but reporter predicts that the convention will adjourn
                    on schedule.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.04.25.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Hotel Changes</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"As quite a number of our Public Houses have recently changed proprietors
                    it may be of some advantage to persons visiting this place to know how they are
                    at present conducted."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--As quite a number of our Public Houses have recently changed proprietors it
                        may be of some advantage to persons visiting this place to know how they are
                        at present conducted.</p>
                    <p>Ex-Sheriff Brown, who recently took the stand on East Market Street, kept by
                        Keyler &amp; Bradley, is doing an excellent business, and all who put up
                        at his house speak of it as being kept in the very best manner.</p>
                    <p>The "White Swan Hotel," lately conducted by Foltz &amp; Miller, is now in
                        the hands of Messrs. Weist &amp; Grove. This house had formerly a very
                        large run of custom which has been considerably increased under the present
                        proprietors.--It is now kept in the best style and affords a comfortable and
                        convenient stopping place for all persons visiting town. The accommodations
                        at this house are of the first class and charges moderate.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Reilly, we understand, is doing a fair share of business at the stand
                        formerly kept by Mr. D. Trostle, on West Market Street. We are informed by
                        persons who have put up at his house that it is kept in a very cleanly and
                        orderly manner--that his table is provided with the best the market can
                        afford--that the house throughout is well furnished, and that the
                        proprietor, and every one employed about the establishment, is attentive and
                        obliging. We have no doubt that Mr. Reilly will regain the custom this house
                        formerly had as he is determined to spare no exertion in conducting it in a
                        manner that will gratify and give entire satisfaction to its patrons. Give
                        him a call and you will find his house comfortable and pleasant and his
                        charges reasonable. We refer our readers to his advertisement in to-day's
                        paper.</p>
                    <p>The "Franklin House," the principal Hotel in the place and which has recently
                        been so admirably conducted by Messrs. Hutchinson &amp; McKenzie, will,
                        we learn, shortly change proprietors. Mr. Jas. Reamer well known over the
                        country as one of the best Hotel keepers in the United States will take
                        charge of this popular house. Under the management of Mr. Reamer this house
                        will be placed on an equality with any first class city Hotel, and will
                        doubtless attract, by the very superior manner in which it will be kept, a
                        large share of the patronage of the traveling public, as well as become a
                        favorite place of resort for a majority of all others who visit our town on
                        business or pleasure.</p>
                    <p>Our Hotel accommodations are, we believe, equal, if not superior, to those of
                        any other town in the State, while our terms are considerably less. A
                        knowledge of this fact should, we think, induce many to become sojourners
                        with us and our town a place of summer resort for the parched up denizens of
                        our cities.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Ex-Sheriff</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bradley</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keyler</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foltz</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weist</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reilly</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trostle</ln>
                        <fn>D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hutchinson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKenzie</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reamer</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Article detailing recent changes in ownership of hotels in Chambersburg,
                    which compliments all the establishments it mentions.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/april60.html#4.25a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Military Visit</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Honsum</ln>
                        <fn>P.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieutenant</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Colonel</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Chambers Artillery made an excursion to Greencastle, and the Valley Spirit
                    praises the company for its equipment and its discipline.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Kysters' Improvement</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kyster</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Kyster and Bro's made an addition to the Storeroom to gain additional
                    display space.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Once More.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The Town Council have been "standing the raps" for some time about the bad
                    condition of the crossing, on Market Street, near the Post Office. We are now
                    informed that the Gas Company, in digging to find a leak in one of their pipes,
                    caused these cavities that, in bad weather, have made this crossing so
                    unpleasant."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--The Town Council have been "standing the raps" for some time about the bad
                        condition of the crossing, on Market Street, near the Post Office. We are
                        now informed that the Gas Company, in digging to find a leak in one of their
                        pipes, caused these cavities that, in bad weather, have made this crossing
                        so unpleasant. The Gas Company have, heretofore, been very prompt in making
                        repairs, whenever they have disturbed the condition of the streets or
                        pavements, and we hope, in this instance, so great a nuisance, caused by
                        them, will not be overlooked any longer.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors removed the blame of the bad condition of Market street from
                    the Town Council to the Gas Company, which had done some digging and did not
                    fill in the holes.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/april60.html#4.25b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Fast Driving</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--Our Town Council have published an ordinance against fast driving or riding
                        through our streets. It does not seem, however, to be much regarded, for we
                        have noticed some tall specimens of fast horsemanship on our streets since
                        its promulgation. An example will be required to be made of somebody before
                        the law is respected.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Town Council's ordinance against fast driving does not appear to be heeded.
                    The Spirit asks that an example be made of somebody to instill respect for the
                    law.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/april60.html#4.25c</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Charleston Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that an extra edition will be published with news of the
                    Democratic National Convention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="j">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Court Proceedings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dysart</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strock</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sechrist</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carbaugh</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bitner</ln>
                        <fn>Geo.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jack</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Early</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Findlay</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chambers</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewer</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>List of cases disposed during second week of court of common pleas.</summary>
                <note>Law partnerships not tagged</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Philips</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mouetz</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maloy</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on April 10.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Washbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Washbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Upton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Ann Washbaugh died at age 42 after a painful disease.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hambright</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Died on April 13 at 81 years of age.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.04.25.06">
            <pageNote>Moral stories, aphorisms, advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.04.25.07">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.04.25.08">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>A Negro in a Bad Box</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Story of an escaped slave who attempted to be smuggled out of the South by
                    getting in a box and being shipped to Ohio.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Riding on a Rail</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Story of a man in Tennessee who allegedly insulted the honor of the women
                    of the state and barely escaped being lynched.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements, legal notices</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
