<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1860/pa.fr.vs.1860.07.18">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Jeff McClurken</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/22/95</tagDate>
            <tagNote>2nd Pass; Colleen Doody did first pass.</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1860-07-18">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day>18</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.07.18.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Speech of the Hon. James Nill Delivered Before the Douglas Club of
                    Chambersburg, Pa., July 7, 1860</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Discusses the Democratic Convention at Charleston and criticizes the
                    actions of the secessionists.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>The Unlucky Lincoln</head>
                <origin>The Detroit Free Press</origin>
                <commentary>States that Lincoln so disgraced himself in Congress that he had to
                    retire temporarily until the voters had forgotten him.</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>States that Lincoln's opposition to the Mexican War prolonged the fighting,
                    gave comfort to the enemy, and caused the deaths of many additional American
                    soldiers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>An Oration, Delivered on the 4th of July, Before the Ger. Ref. Sunday School
                    of Loudon, By Wm. S. Stenger, Esq.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reflections on the American Revolution in honor of the Fourth of July.
                    Toward the end, Stenger questions whether the freedoms won in the war will be
                    destroyed because "One section of our land is arrayed, in bitter hostility,
                    against the other."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.07.18.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Democratic Platform</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprint of the platform adopted by the Democratic Conventions at Cincinnati
                    [in 1856], Charleston, and Baltimore.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.07.18.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Douglas</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Poem lauding Douglas over Lincoln.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.07.18.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Water Works</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"What are dollars and cents in comparison to the comforts and security
                    derived from an abundant supply of this pure element. None but the miserable
                    hoarder of dollars will say aught against a project so conducive to the health
                    and happiness of mankind."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--A large and highly respectable meeting of the citizens of this place
                        convened at the Court House on Thursday evening last, for the purpose of
                        getting an expression of opinion favorable to the construction of Water
                        Works. It has been a habit in this place, after every fire, to call a town
                        meeting and agitate this subject. This may have a good result in shaping
                        public opinion for the future, but for the present it has effected nothing.
                        A resolution offered at the meeting <emph rend="italic">that we have Water
                            Works</emph> was passed unanimously, and another that the <emph
                            rend="italic">borough authorities build them</emph> also passed without
                        a dissenting voice. The Council were then instructed to make the necessary
                        survey and estimates for the construction of the works, and report at a
                        subsequent meeting to be called by them for that purpose. This was the sum
                        total of the business transacted by the meeting. The Borough Council, in
                        compliance with the request of the meeting, met on Monday evening last, and
                        appointed I. H. McCauly, Esq., Chief Burgess, and James King and Calvin M.
                        Duncan, Esqs., members of the council, a committee to carry out the wishes
                        of the citizens expressed at the meeting.--These gentlemen will engage the
                        services of a competent engineer and enter upon their duties at once. This
                        important matter could not have been intrusted in more judicious and
                        competent hands than those selected by the Council. Thus far, everything
                        looks favorable--what the end will be we will not undertake to predict.</p>
                    <p>We ought to have water-works and if we do not construct them in our own day,
                        and enjoy their advantages, our posterity most assuredly will. The locality
                        is most favorable for constructing the works and supplying the town, through
                        all seasons of the year, with a sufficiency of the best and purest water for
                        all public and domestic purposes. A trifling additional borough tax, for a
                        few years, will meet the expense, which no good citizen will grumble at when
                        he can enjoy the invaluable blessing of an abundance of pure and wholesome
                        water, for drinking, cooking, washing, bathing, cleansing the streets and
                        every other useful and healthy purpose to which water may be applied; and
                        last, though not least, a sufficiency to protect his property in case of
                        fire. What are dollars and cents in comparison to the comforts and security
                        derived from an abundant supply of this pure element. None but the miserable
                        hoarder of dollars will say aught against a project so conducive to the
                        health and happiness of mankind.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCauly</ln>
                        <fn>I.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Esq.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burgese</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Chief</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duncan</ln>
                        <fn>Calvin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Esq.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A meeting was held in the Court House to gather opinions on whether a Water
                    Works should be built. The meeting requested that the Borough Council study the
                    possibility of building Water Works. The Spirit editor favors the building of
                    these works.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/july60.html#7.18d</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.07.18.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Late Fire</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We now have the best evidence before us that our town is infested with
                    petty thieves and let us go to work to remedy the evil in the best way we can."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--We regret to state, for the credit of our town, that a considerable amount
                        of pilfering took place during the progress of the late fire at the
                        residence of Mr. Ott, Deckelmayer and Dittman. Mr. Deckelmayer lost a large
                        amount of goods--barrels of Crackers, bags of nuts, boxes of figs and
                        raisins, jars of candies, and many household articles. Mr. Dittman had also
                        many articles stolen among which was an excellent gun. Mr. Ott was also a
                        sufferer in this way to a considerable amount. We now have the best evidence
                        before us that our town is infested with petty thieves and let us go to work
                        to remedy the evil in the best way we can. Could not our Fire Companies
                        detail a police force of their best and most reliable men to remove and take
                        charge of goods at the time of a fire--stand guard over them and allow non
                        to handle them but themselves. The Hook and Ladder Company might readily
                        undertake this service, as they, we understand, have a large company and
                        could best spare their men from their apparatus. The men detailed in this
                        service should wear a badge to designate them, and should be sworn in as
                        special constables and have power to make arrests of all found pilfering.</p>
                    <p>We hope some member of the company will bring this matter up at their next
                        meeting and have this desirable measure carried out.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Report of the pilfering that occurred at the site of the fire at the homes
                    of Mr. Ott, Mr. Deckelmayer, and Mr. Dittman.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/july60.html#7.18a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Nearly a Fight</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Report of a fight that took place between seven black women over one black
                    man, described as an "Adonis."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Price of Gas for Street Lamps</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Allentown has fewer lights and pays only $3 per thousand feet. What makes
                    the difference?"</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--Allentown has thirty gas street lights, and pays $3 per thousand feet;
                        Easton seventy-five lights, $3 per thousand feet; Pottsville, seventy-three
                        light, $3 30 per thousand feet; Reading, forty-three lights $2 87 per
                        thousand feet; Harrisburg, seventy-three lights, $2 50 per thousand feet;
                        Lancaster, one hundred lights, $3 per one thousand feet; Norristown,
                        seventy-three lights, $2 50 per thousand feet.</p>
                    <p>Chambersburg has thirty-seven lights and pays about $4 per thousand feet.
                        Pottsville and Chambersburg pays the highest price for Gas. Allentown has
                        fewer lights and pays only $3 per thousand feet. What makes the
                    difference?</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A complaint that Chambersburg pays a higher price for gas for its street
                    lamps than do other nearby towns.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/july60.html#7.18b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Census</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We think the borough proper will show a considerable increase in
                    population since last Census, though several townships already taken exhibit a
                    large falling off in the county."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--The Census Marshals are now actively engaged in taking the Census of
                        Franklin county. Several townships have already been taken and they now have
                        commenced operations in the borough. The districts added to the borough from
                        Hamilton and Guilford have been taken and found to have increased our
                        population seven hundred. We think the borough proper will show a
                        considerable increase in population since last Census, though several
                        townships already taken exhibit a large falling off in the county.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the census marshals are actively engaged in taking a census of
                    Franklin County and predicts that the borough will show a considerable increase
                    in population since the last census.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/july60.html#7.18c</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Heavy Blasting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The blasts are not sufficiently covered to prevent large pieces of rock
                    from endangering the lives of those living near. Quite a large piece passed
                    through the window of the academy, and had the school been in session, death, in
                    all probability, would have resulted."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--The workmen engaged in widening 3d Street, between Market and Queen,
                        detached with three blasts, on Saturday last, about thirty perch of rock.
                        The vast body of rock there is fast disappearing before the force of powder.</p>
                    <p>One thing should be guarded against by the workmen. The blasts are not
                        sufficiently covered to prevent large pieces of rock from endangering the
                        lives of those living near. Quite a large piece passed through the window of
                        the academy, and had the school been in session, death, in all probability,
                        would have resulted.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that workmen are blasting rock in order to widen 3rd Street.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/july60.html#7.18e</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Hagerstown Seminary</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--At the recent Commencement of this excellent school for females, presided
                        over by our late accomplished and esteemed fellow townsmen Rev. WM. F.
                        EYSTER, we observe by the Hagerstown papers that an excellent composition or
                        essay, on English Literature, the production of MISS MARY LAUBACH, step-
                        daughter of Mr. B. F. Nead, of this place, was read by her, which elicited
                        the warmest praise for the beauty of its style, and the just and happy
                        thoughts and views it embodied.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Laubach</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nead</ln>
                        <fn>B.F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Mary Laubach read her composition on English Literature at the
                    Commencement exercises at the Hagerstown Seminary.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/july60.html#7.18f</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Grand Exhibition of Wire-Walking</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heyser</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Prof. Price will give an exhibition of tight-wire walking on July 23rd
                    between Fisher's Motel and Heyser's Drug Store.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Douglas and Johnson Club</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rowe</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reilly</ln>
                        <fn>Wilson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamsher</ln>
                        <fn>B.Y.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brand</ln>
                        <fn>A. Jackson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Diehl</ln>
                        <fn>J.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClintock</ln>
                        <fn>J.P.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keyser</ln>
                        <fn>H.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillan</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rowe</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duncan</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Douglas and Johnson Club met on the previous Saturday and decided to
                    meet regularly every Saturday evening.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Water Works!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heyser</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reilly</ln>
                        <fn>Wilson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fletcher</ln>
                        <fn>J.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>F.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A meeting of the citizens of Chambersburg for the purpose of ascertaining
                    the probable cost of building a water works occurred on July 12th. The meeting
                    recommended that a water works be built.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Music! Music!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>H.B. Hatnick has recently opened a music store.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Spanish and Mexican Coins</head>
                <origin>Pennsylvanian</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Spanish and Mexican fractions of the dollar will no longer be exchanged for
                    their nominal value for new money at the mint. The mint had followed this
                    practice in order to remove these depreciated coins from circulation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Water Works</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"Justice" writes in his letter to the editor that he thinks that the town
                    fathers need to let people know about the debt situation of the town in light of
                    the proposals for a water works.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.07.18.06">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.07.18.07">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.07.18.08">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Letter from Hon. Reverdy Johnson of Maryland</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reverdy Johnson declines the invitation of the Douglas Ratification Meeting
                    while criticizing the secessionists for their actions at the conventions.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
