<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1860/pa.fr.vs.1860.12.26">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Jeff McClurken</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/22/95</tagDate>
            <tagNote>2nd Pass; Colleen Doody did first pass.</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1860-12-26">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="12">December</month>
            <day>26</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote>Issue has only four pages.</editionNote>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.12.26.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Letter of the Hon. Howell Cobb to the People of Georgia, on the Present
                    Condition of the Country</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Very long letter from Cobb in which he states that the "Object which the
                    black republican party has in view is the ultimate extinction of slavery in the
                    United States." He believes that he must "impress upon you [the people of
                    Georgia] the hopelessness of any remedy for these evils short of secession."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.12.26.02">
            <div type="l">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Rev. R. J. Breckinridge on the Political Crisis</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>States that "the time is past when I can do anything towards directing the
                    passions of our countrymen."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>News of the Week</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>South Carolina voted to sever all connection with the Federal Government
                    and declared the state out of the Union. The Republicans continue to refuse to
                    make any compromises to save the Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Union Dissolved</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The Democratic party maintain that our government was formed by white men
                    to be controled [sic] by whitemen for the prosperity and happiness of their
                    race. The Republican party contend that the negro is entitled to equality with
                    the white man--that he must be included and recognized in all our institutions,
                    and have a vote and voice in all our state and national affairs. This is the
                    question--this the delusion that has dissevered and ruined the country and
                    threatens to involve the white man in bloodshed."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The death-knell of our glorious Union is resounding through the land. The
                        present United States are dissolved, broken up--the noblest Government on
                        the face of the earth, with all its elements of wealth, prosperity,
                        happiness and power, have at length been sacrificed by the madness of
                        fanaticism. Every honest and unprejudiced mind must see, and acknowledge
                        with a feeling of mortification, the true source of our national troubles
                        and deep disgrace. To narrow it down the cause must appear as absurd as the
                        Lilliputian war about the end at which the egg should be broke before it is
                        eaten. The Democratic party maintain that our government was formed by white
                        men to be controled [sic] by whitemen for the prosperity and happiness of
                        their race. The Republican party contend that the negro is entitled to
                        equality with the white man--that he must be included and recognized in all
                        our institutions, and have a vote and voice in all our state and national
                        affairs. This is the question--this the delusion that has dissevered and
                        ruined the country and threatens to involve the white man in bloodshed. Must
                        we lose our own freedom in an attempt to free the negro? It ought to require
                        but a very trifling amount of common sense to settle this question justly
                        and forever, but then--</p>
                    <p>"Faith, fanatic Faith, once wedded fast To some dear falsehood hugs it to the
                        last."</p>
                    <p>Northern fanaticism rules the hour--sectional hate and abolition rage have
                        goaded the South to that point where forbearance ceases to be a virtue, and
                        impel them to demand that they be allowed peaceably to withdraw from a
                        confederacy in which they have the equality or safety. Even this poor boon
                        is to be denied them if the wishes of their implacable enemies prevail. They
                        must be coerced to stay where they are and put up with all the wrongs and
                        continually heaped upon them and not dare to <emph rend="italic"
                        >resist</emph> or <emph rend="italic">avoid</emph> the assaults on their
                        Constitutional rights. The North may violate the Constitution, and resist
                        the Laws of Congress, and then appeal to its "higher laws" in justification
                        of its <emph rend="italic">treason</emph>, but for the South there is no
                        appeal--the gibbet and the bayonet are the remedies proposed to subdue her
                        into obedience to the mandates of a Constitution that a northern "higher
                        law" has trampled under foot time and again.</p>
                    <p> The South demands nothing more than equal rights in the Union. To this she
                        is entitled but northern fanaticism is in the ascendancy and all her appeals
                        have been insultingly and doggedly denied. Her next and only resort is <emph
                            rend="italic">secession</emph>, but the moment that is proposed the long
                        smothered howl for her blood wells up. The Republican party, backed by a few
                        renegade Democrats, are clamoring for an army to murder our brethren of the
                        South, and for what?--because they will not consent to consider the negroes
                        their equals? Could madness go further? Has it come to this that we must be
                        forced to remain in an abolition confederacy and consider negroes our equals
                        or be shot down like dogs?--Strange and fearful are the times upon which we
                        have fallen and no mortal eye can see whither we are drifting. If the flames
                        of civil war are once kindled in the land who can tell where it will
                        end--who can say what destruction of life and property it will involve?
                        Heaven forbid it and grant our rulers wisdom to devise measures to avert so
                        great a calamity to the whole nation. If we cannot live together in peace
                        let us part in peace and not stir up civil strife and imbrue our hands in
                        the blood of our fellow-citizens. No matter what may be the stagnation in
                        business--no matter what States may secede--save us from that greatest of
                        all calamities civil war--the most terrible, relentless and inhuman of all
                        wars. If we solemnly reflect on the destruction we are about to draw down
                        upon us it must make us pause in time and put forth every effort to create
                        harmony--reestablish fraternal feeling among our countrymen and restore the
                        Union.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spirit bemoans the fact that the Union is dissolving. The crux of the
                    disagreement is that the Democrats "maintain that our government was formed by
                    white men to be controlled by white men for the prosperity and happiness of
                    their race." The Republicans, however, argue that the black man "is entitled to
                    equality with the white man."</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/dec60.html#12.26a</note>
                <look>Look</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>The South Carolina Sovereign Convention--Secedes from the Union</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The minutes of the meeting that voted for secession.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>Look</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Rumors from Washington</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A number of short rumors, including General Scott's efforts to conciliate
                    the states and Cass' resignation letter.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Why the Black Republicans Want War</head>
                <origin>Pennsylvanian</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>States that the Republicans want Buchanan to start a war so that Lincoln
                    won't be blamed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Slight Fire</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>There was a small fire in the Baptist Church, but it was discovered before
                    it had made much headway.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huber</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKesson</ln>
                        <fn>S. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wood</ln>
                        <fn>T. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Banker</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clark</ln>
                        <fn>L. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>S. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hutton</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nead</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hutz</ln>
                        <fn>H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hicks</ln>
                        <fn>Speakman</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harnsher</ln>
                        <fn>B. Y.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>An election was held for Directors of the Farmers and Mechanics Savings
                    Bank.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Cumberland Valley and Franklin Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Statistics for the railroads. The Franklin Railroad runs from Greencastle
                    to Chambersburg and from Hagerstown to Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.12.26.03">
            <div type="s">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingert</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoover</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on December 20th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Howe</ln>
                        <fn>Wesley</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Immel</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on December 18th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Colestock</ln>
                        <fn>Z. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brubaker</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brandt</ln>
                        <fn>Elnora</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married December 6th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deatrich</ln>
                        <fn>W. R. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Branthaver</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sollenberger</ln>
                        <fn>Susannah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on December 20th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hetrick</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Died on December 16th, aged 36 years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.12.26.04">
            <pageNote>Advertisments</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
