<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1860/pa.fr.vs.1860.02.08">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Jeff McClurken</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/22/95</tagDate>
            <tagNote>2nd Pass; Andy Morris did first pass.</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1860-02-08">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day norm="08">8</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.02.08.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>The Present State of the Indians</head>
                <origin>Boston Post</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"There are others who, though not classified in the census, have less to do
                    with our civil affairs than the black man and the red man; we refer to the most
                    radical classes of Abolitionists, and the Mormons."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article based on report of Secretary of the Interior, December 1859, and
                    report of Commissioner of Indian Affairs.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.02.08.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Home Affections</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes feelings elicited by home, and holds the sanctity of private life
                    as a measure of the morals of a community.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>She Works For a Living</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Elevates working girls over women of fashion as potential brides.</summary>
                <note>Bottom of page illegible.</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Poetry and fiction</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.02.08.03">
            <pageNote>Poetry, history, advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.02.08.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>A Speaker Elected</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Gov. Pennington of New Jersey was elected as Speaker of the House, "a
                    gentleman who has had art enough to keep his Black Republican principles from
                    sticking too far out through his skin," and attacks the three "anti-Lecompton
                    Democrats" (Hickman, Haskin, and Adrain) who supported Pennington over John
                    McClernand.</summary>
                <note>Three columns given to associated stories.</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Trial of Stephens at Charlestown, VA</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Report from the trial of Stephens, one of the Harper's Ferry suspects, who
                    was found guilty.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Crowded Out</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Local news appears on page four, due to crowded state of advertising.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="j">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Sales of Personal Property</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Binkley</ln>
                        <fn>C.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zollinger</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Breckinridge</ln>
                        <fn>Nancy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coover</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Landis</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pence</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mestzer</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strine</ln>
                        <fn>Philip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zollinger</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoeffner</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Oyter</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Furguson</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>List of people who have personal property up for sale.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.02.08.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Sale of Personal Property</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>M.A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>Edward</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allen</ln>
                        <fn>Josiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Knisely</ln>
                        <fn>J.D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Continued list of personal property sales.</summary>
                <note>Some names illegible.</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Real Estate</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burkholder</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burkholder</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Knopper</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sales of real estate</summary>
                <note>Some names illegible</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phillips</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keyser</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Elder</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>German Reformed Church is holding a public service, intended for all
                    regardless of denomination, for the benefit of the relief of the poor of the
                    town.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Shocking Accident</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"On Wednesday morning last one of the workmen employed at the Straw Paper
                    Manufactory of J. Heyser, Esq., at this place, accidently fell into one of the
                    large vessels used for steaming straw and was scalded in a most horrible
                    manner."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--On Wednesday morning last one of the workmen employed at the Straw Paper
                        Manufactory of J. Heyser, Esq., at this place, accidently fell into one of
                        the large vessels used for steaming straw and was scalded in a most horrible
                        manner. From the account given of the occurrence, by the man, it would
                        appear that he struggled in the boiling lime water some five or six minutes,
                        there being no one present to assist him out, and that after gaining the
                        edge of the vessel he fell back again into the heated liquid and received a
                        second scalding. His body, legs, and left arm, are scalded in the most
                        shocking manner, the skin being stripped off the greater portion of the
                        surface and the flesh deeply burnt. The extent and severity of the scalding
                        renders his recovery very improbable. Mr. Heyser had the injured man at once
                        removed to his home, in the most careful manner, and has ever since been
                        unremitting in his humane attentions--supplying every necessity and comfort
                        that the condition of the man, or his family, requires.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heyser</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Employee at J. Heyser's Straw Paper Manufactory was badly scalded; Heyser
                    removed the man to his home and "has ever since been unremitting in his humane
                    sentiments."</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/feb60.html#2.8a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Franklin Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We go for holding Corporations to a strict responsibility in all
                    matters--small as well as great--for where they get in a finger they are apt to
                    thrust in the whole hand."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--It gives us great pleasure to announce to our patrons and the traveling
                        public generally that this road is fully completed between our town and
                        Greencastle, and that a train of Cars, for carrying passengers and freight,
                        commenced running, regularly on Monday last. The train will leave the Depot
                        of the Cumberland Valley Railroad at 11 o'clock and 25 minutes each morning,
                        immediately after the arrival of the first train from Harrisburg, and arrive
                        at Greencastle at 12 o'clock and 10 minutes--noon.--Leaving Greencastle at 1
                        o'clock and 40 minutes it will reach here again at 2 o'clock and 20 minutes
                        in time to connect with the second train for Harrisburg. All persons
                        desiring to get into the cars must go to the C. V. R. R. Depot, as the train
                        will not stop at any of the streets in town. The owners of the road
                        confidently expect to have it fully completed to Hagerstown by the 1st of
                        March. The rails were all laid some weeks since, and there are only about
                        six or seven miles yet to ballast. Considerable delay has been caused by the
                        company concluding to ballast it with <emph rend="italic">stone</emph>,
                        instead of earth. Had the latter material been used the road might have been
                        finished several months since, and quite a large sum of money saved; but the
                        company, wisely we think, concluded to use stone instead of earth for
                        ballast. It will cost them more at present but the additional outlay will be
                        more than made up by its greater durability, and adaptation to the purposed
                        designed. This road when completed, will have no superior in the Union, in
                        any respect. The road bed is firmly packed by the settling of twenty
                        years--the bridges are of the best dressed stone--the route almost straight,
                        and the grades very easy. It will no doubt, when regularly run with two
                        trains of passengers and freight cars each way, daily, prove a great
                        convenience to the people of this country and Washington County, Maryland,
                        and we trust that it may well remunerate those who have embarked their
                        capital in its construction. But we regret to see that the company, in the
                        outset, are about to violate the law in an important particular. We allude
                        to the charges for carrying passengers. According to the schedule published
                        passengers to Marion--six miles distant will be charged 25 cents--and to
                        Greencastle--11 miles distant 40 cents. Now the 14th Section of the Act
                        incorporating the Franklin Railroad Company, approved March 12, 1832, says
                        that the rates for transportation shall be "on all goods &amp;c., any
                        sum not exceeding four cents per mile, per ton for toll, and three cents per
                        ton per mile for transportation, <emph rend="italic">and for the
                            transportation of passengers not exceeding three cents per mile for each
                            passenger</emph>." This restriction has never been repealed that we know
                        of, and the very last Act passed in relation to this road--the Act too under
                        which the Company is not organized--approved the 3d day of February
                        1859--says in Section 3d, that the company shall have all the rights and
                        privileges, and <emph rend="italic">be subjected to all the
                        restrictions</emph> imposed upon the Franklin Railroad Company, the
                        Chambersburg and Hagerstown Railroad Company, and the Chambersburg,
                        Greencastle, and Hagerstown Railroad Company. These several Companies are
                        all the same viz:--The old Franklin Railroad Company--and all of them, so
                        far as we can find by a close examination of the legislation in their favor,
                        are prohibited charging more than <emph rend="italic">three</emph> cents per
                        mile for carrying passengers. The <emph rend="italic">legal</emph> fare,
                        therefore, to Marion could not be over 18 cents--nor to Greencastle 33
                        cents.--We doubt not, however, that the traveling public would willingly
                        stand 20 cents to Marion and 35 cents to Greencastle, but <emph
                            rend="italic">more</emph> ought not to be demanded of them. <emph
                            rend="italic">The</emph> 5 <emph rend="italic">cents excess</emph> will
                        be as good to the traveler as to the company, and in a year will amount to
                        quite a large sum, which our people have more right to than this
                        corporation.</p>
                    <p>We cannot see why this increased rate is demanded. It is as far to
                        Shippensburg as it is to Greencastle, and yet but 35 cents are charged to
                        the former place, while 40 are asked to the latter. The owners of the
                        Franklin Railroad cannot urge the expenditure they have made and the poor
                        prospect of its being remunerative. They should bear in mind that this road
                        cost the people of our county nearly $100,000 twenty years ago, and that
                        they have derived no benefit from it since--that it was sold to its present
                        owners for $5,500, when the iron upon it was worth more than double that
                        sum. They should, therefore, ask no more than the law allows for discharging
                        a public duty <emph rend="italic">voluntarily</emph> assumed. We go in for
                        holding Corporations to a strict accountability in all matters--small as
                        well as great--for where they get in a finger they are apt to thrust in the
                        whole hand, and if in the present instance they find the people refuse to
                        pay their demands, or resort to the Court for redress, they cannot under the
                        circumstances think hard of them for so doing.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Railroad between Chambersburg and Greencastle has been completed, but the
                    rates to the new destination are disproportionately higher than to other
                    destinations. Warns about predatory corporations.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/feb60.html#2.8b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Admitted</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGrath</ln>
                        <fn>T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>McGrath was admitted to the bar.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Death of Hon. Joel Jones</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>Joel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Joel Jones, former mayor of Chambersburg and Judge of the District Court,
                    died at age 64.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Includes statement of finances of Franklin County, three columns.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.02.08.06">
            <pageNote>Poetry, stories, and advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.02.08.07">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Loveliness</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Posits that a woman's heart is the true measure of her beauty.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Poetry and advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.02.08.08">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Negroes of the North</head>
                <origin>Cincinnati Enquirer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Speculation as to what will happen in Ohio if and when the expected influx
                    of free blacks takes place. Predicts that blacks will concentrate in certain
                    towns and drive whites from office unless states pass more stringent restrictive
                    laws.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Market information from Chambersburg and Baltimore, legal notices.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
