<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1860/pa.fr.vs.1860.08.01">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Jeff McClurken</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/22/95</tagDate>
            <tagNote>2nd Pass; Colleen Doody did first pass.</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1860-08-01">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="08">August</month>
            <day norm="01">1</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.08.01.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Cattle Disease</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Any man who to, save a few dollars, sells a diseased steer, that it may
                    spread this terrible disorder through new districts, or who has it slaughtered
                    for food to be eaten by persons whose health may be seriously injured by it,
                    deserves severe punishment, and will cover himself with lasting infamy."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A paragraph printed in our local columns, yesterday, which was copied from
                        the Doylestown <emph rend="italic">Democrat</emph>, stated that the dreaded
                        cattle disease has appeared in the vicinity of Philadelphia, and that some
                        of the victims of it had been slaughtered and sold in our market. This
                        intelligence is of an alarming character, and it is to be hoped that prompt
                        measures may be taken to inquire into its truth, and to effectually prevent
                        the calamities which would inevitably result from this distemper.</p>
                    <p>A notable example of this course which honorable and magnanimous
                        cattle-owners should pursue, was furnished by a gentleman of New Jersey,
                        who, in 1857, discovered that the pleuro-pneumonia had broken our in a
                        valuable herd of imported cattle he possessed, and although they were valued
                        at $10, 000, he immediately had them all killed, and thus, by a very heavy
                        individual pecuniary loss, he saved the section in which he resided, and the
                        country generally, many thousands of dollars.</p>
                    <p>It is the duty of every man who discovers that his cattle are afflicted with
                        this disorder to completely isolate them from all other herds, and, if he
                        cannot see a reasonable prospect of curing them, having them killed and
                        buried. Where this is done in good faith there is no doubt, we think, that
                        the Legislature of the State would be willing to compensate the owner for
                        their loss, as has already been done by Massachusetts and many of the
                        European Governments. Any man who to, save a few dollars, sells a diseased
                        steer, that it may spread this terrible disorder through new districts, or
                        who has it slaughtered for food to be eaten by persons whose health may be
                        seriously injured by it, deserves severe punishment, and will cover himself
                        with lasting infamy. He who, to shield himself from a comparatively trifling
                        loss, assists to disseminate a destructive calamity, deserves the reproach
                        and scorn of every right minded citizen.</p>
                    <p>But now, when the disease, if it exists in the neighborhood at all, is
                        necessarily confined to but a very few localities, it can be easily arrested
                        if a proper spirit is evinced. Let all the afflicted cattle be properly
                        isolated or killed, and the expense, which in the infancy of the disease
                        would be but trifling, will, we doubt not, be cheerfully born by our State
                        Legislature, when the facts are fully brought to its notice.</p>
                    <p>Owners of affected cattle should not hastily conclude that their only escape
                        from loss is to sell their stock, and thus to rapidly widen the circle of
                        infection. On the contrary, while that course may lead them into serious
                        difficulties, there is another one far more just and honorable, and probably
                        equally remunerative, open to them, in destroying their diseased stock and
                        appealing to the Legislature for relief.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The "dreaded cattle disease" appeared around Philadelphia and some of the
                    slaughtered victims have been sold in the Chambersburg market. The paper
                    encourages any farmer who has infected cattle to isolate and slaughter them.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/aug60.html#8.1g</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Senator Douglas at Troy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Douglas gave a speech at Troy, NY in which he defended non-intervention and
                    opposed both abolition and secession.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.08.01.02">
            <pageNote>Stories and poetry</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.08.01.03">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.08.01.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Notice to the Patrons of the Valley Spirit</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Requests that people pay their subscription fees in advance because the
                    editors are burdened with debt from the purchase of the paper.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Modest Assumption</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Amos G. Bonsall, the editor of the Juniata Register, has stricken the names
                    of Richard Vaux and J.R. Crawford from the electoral ticket because they refused
                    to agree to the proposed compromise of the State Democratic committee. The
                    Spirit criticizes Bonsall for this action, saying that he "must imagine that he
                    is the Democratic party."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Meeting of the Douglas Club</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Douglas Club will meet on Saturday evening, August 4th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Republican County Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Republican County Nominating Convention is scheduled to meet soon. The
                    Spirit believes that the convention will only rubber stamp the candidates that
                    the leadership has chosen.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Skies are Brightening</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Douglas-Johnson ticket is increasing in strength and popularity, even
                    in the South, according to the Spirit.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>The Opposition Democracy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that, despite what the Republican papers claim, the German-American
                    newspapers are supporting the Douglas-Johnson ticket.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Bogus Letter</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Harrisburg Telegraph published a bogus letter that was supposedly
                    written by Gen. Foster, the Democratic candidate for governor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Douglas Convention at Harrisburg</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vaux</ln>
                        <fn>Richard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGrath</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Owen</ln>
                        <fn>Joshua</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carson</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>Hendrick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>J.R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rowe</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Byrns</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Masser</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mitchell</ln>
                        <fn>Ira</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Painter</ln>
                        <fn>Israel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cummings</ln>
                        <fn>A. Boyd</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nill</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rowe</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>G.N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Haldeman</ln>
                        <fn>R.J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Esq.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>H.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ward</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>H.L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Esq.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilmore</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Esq.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Esq.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doyle</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brand</ln>
                        <fn>A. Jackson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A meeting of 300 friends of Douglas met in Harrisburg on July 25th. They
                    pledged to support the regular Democratic slate. In addition, they protested the
                    actions of the Democratic State Committee meeting held at Philadelphia on July
                    2, 1860, because it is breaking up the party.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.08.01.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Connelsville and Allegheny Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The New York agent who surveyed the area for a possible railroad line
                    proclaimed himself pleased with the prospects and facilities for making a road.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Fire Buckets</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Protection Hook and Ladder Company wants to obtain all the old leather
                    fire buckets so that they can be repaired and readied for use.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Shameful Conduct</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"On Sunday last, at the time of the funeral of Miss Smith, a number of
                    persons male and female desecrated the Cemetery grounds in a most shameful
                    manner. They trampled over the graves, broke down the shrubbery, plucked the
                    flowers and showed their bad-breeding and ill-manners in every possible way."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--On Sunday last, at the time of the funeral of Miss Smith, a number of
                        persons male and female desecrated the Cemetery grounds in a most shameful
                        manner. They trampled over the graves, broke down the shrubbery, plucked the
                        flowers and showed their bad-breeding and ill-manners in every possible way.
                        Such human hyenas should be excluded from the grounds altogether, and as
                        many of them are known we hope the Directors will give instructions to the
                        Keeper to not allow them to enter the grounds again, even should they come
                        with a funeral. There is a severe law against depredations of this kind and
                        we cannot see what delicacy the Directors need have in enforcing it. Make an
                        example of a few of them and the rest may be deterred from exercising their
                        evil propensities, in such a place when they know that fine and imprisonment
                        will be the consequence.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Some people who were attending the funeral of Miss Smith "desecrated the
                    Cemetery grounds in a most shameful manner." The paper hopes that the cemetery
                    directors will bar them from the grounds.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/aug60.html#8.1a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Water Works Broke Down</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt> "The redoubtable "Major" who prevents our citizens for "kicking up a
                    dust," had a smash <emph rend="italic">down</emph> the other day." </excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--The redoubtable "Major" who prevents our citizens for "kicking up a dust,"
                        had a smash <emph rend="italic">down</emph> the other day.</p>
                    <p>After having carefully loaded the "merchine" preparatory to a squirt, he was
                        wending his way to the field of labor, when down came the water works--that
                        is the reservoir, out went plug, and away went the water. The major nothing
                        taunted, took the "Spread Eagle Water Works" to a shop and had repairs made
                        and will "Skute" again if we don't soon have a rain.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The local water works broke down temporarily.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/aug60.html#8.1b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>A Complaint</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We are informed by a respectable gentleman, that at a certain Post Office,
                    in this county, our papers have been withheld from subscribers and that these
                    same papers, with the subscribers names thereon, were afterwards sold to a store
                    keeper for wrapping paper."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--We are informed by a respectable gentleman, that at a certain Post Office,
                        in this county, our papers have been withheld from subscribers and that
                        these same papers, with the subscribers names thereon, were afterwards sold
                        to a store keeper for wrapping paper. We are in possession of the evidence
                        to substantiate fully this charge, and are determined, if it occurs again,
                        to prosecute the Postmaster and have him punished to the full extent the law
                        provided for such offenders.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper has been informed that some copies of the Spirit were withheld
                    from subscribers at a certain Post Office and were afterward sold as wrapping
                    paper. If this happens again, the Spirit promises to prosecute the Postmaster.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/aug60.html#8.1c</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Heavy Wind and Rain Storm.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The wind blew fearfully--lightening vivid--thunder tremendous and the rain
                    fell in torrents. Nor serious damage done except to the Corn crop, which it made
                    dreadful long in the stalk and thick in the ears."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--Last Thursday night at a little past 11 o'clock, we had a touch of a
                        Tornado. The wind blew fearfully--lightening vivid--thunder tremendous and
                        the rain fell in torrents. Nor serious damage done except to the Corn crop,
                        which it made dreadful long in the stalk and thick in the ears.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Mention of a storm, including a tornado, last Thursday, which damaged the
                    corn crop.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/aug60.html#8.1e</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Accident.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"[A young lad] slipped and fell and one of the sharp points of the iron
                    railing caught in the fleshy part of his thigh producing a very frightful
                    looking, though not considered dangerous, wound."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--On Tuesday morning last a young lad, nephew of W. H. McDowell, Esq., of
                        this place was visiting in company with his aunt, the Cemetery grounds
                        attached to the Presbyterian Church, when he mounted on top of an iron
                        railing for the purpose of examining a monument. While in this position he
                        slipped and fell and one of the sharp points of the iron railing caught in
                        the fleshy part of his thigh producing a very frightful looking, though not
                        considered dangerous, wound.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDowell</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Esq.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A report of the nephew of W. H. McDowell impaling his thigh on the iron
                    fence of the cemetery.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/aug60.html#8.1f</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Outrageous</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Within the last few days some villianous scamps, who may be found daily
                    and nightly loafing on the corners of our streets have been amusing themselves
                    by spitting Tobacco juice on the Ladies' dresses as they pass along."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--Within the last few days some villianous scamps, who may be found daily and
                        nightly loafing on the corners of our streets have been amusing themselves
                        by spitting Tobacco juice on the Ladies' dresses as they pass along. These
                        scoundrels are being watched--and by-the-way had better leave town--and if
                        caught will be severely dealt with. No punishment would be too severe to
                        inflict upon them. Why cannot our High Constable disperse the gangs that
                        nightly congregate on our street corners, or arrest these vagrant loafers.
                        Is he afraid of his popularity?</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Recently, some men have been leaning on street corners and spitting tobacco
                    juice at ladies as they pass by. The Spirit wants the High Constable to disperse
                    these gangs.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/aug60.html#8.1d</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.08.01.06">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.08.01.07">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.08.01.08">
            <pageNote>Stories and Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
