<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1860/pa.fr.vs.1860.12.12">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Jeff McClurken</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/22/95</tagDate>
            <tagNote>2nd Pass; Colleen Doody did first pass.</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1860-12-12">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="12">December</month>
            <day>12</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.12.12.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>President's Message</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Very lengthy State of the Union message of President Buchanan. In it, he
                    discusses the current political crisis and the danger of sectional parties.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.12.12.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01-06</column>
                <head>[none]</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Continuation of Buchanan's State of the Union address.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.12.12.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01-02</column>
                <head>[none]</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Conclusion of Buchanan's State of the Union address.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.12.12.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>News of the Week</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Secession sentiment is rapidly spreading in the South, while the North is
                    beginning to wake up to the danger. The South demands that the Personal Liberty
                    Bills be repealed. Congress cannot be counted on to solve the current
                    difficulties, since they are busy wrangling amongst themselves. The financial
                    situation remains poor. The Homestead bill passed the House and is now before
                    the Senate.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Pennsylvania</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Although Pennsylvania has a reputation as a conservative state, it still
                    has a Personal Liberty law on the books. The Spirit urges the legislature to
                    repeal this law because it is breaking up the Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The President's Message</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Analysis of Buchanan's state of the Union speech, which contained "wise and
                    patriotic recommendations."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>The Gospel According to St. Beecher</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Criticizes Henry Ward Beecher's "perversion of the language used by St.
                    Paul to the Centurion."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Shall We Have Civil War?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The horizon looks gloomy. South Carolina is in earnest. She is bent on
                    setting up for herself before a Black Republican President shall be set up over
                    her. It is not to be supposed that she does not take into her calculations a
                    matter of such vital importance as the possession of the forts that command the
                    harbor of her chief city. She will pour out her blood to get them, and we must
                    give them up or keep them at the cannon's mouth; or else we must take some
                    measures to win her back to the Union, and to satisfy her and all the Southern
                    States that they can remain in it with safety and honor."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Is the country to be subjected to the horrors of civil war? We hardly see how
                        the calamity can be averted as things are going. South Carolina is going out
                        of the Union, and all or nearly all the other Southern States will in time
                        follow her, if the Northern States do not repeal their aggressive laws. So
                        far as expression has been given to Republican sentiment, it favors a
                        dissolution of the Union rather than the abandonment of the Republican
                        programme of [sic] making the States "all slave or all free," which is
                        understood to mean that they shall all be free.</p>
                    <p>The danger of a war is just as imminent if South Carolina goes out alone as
                        if she goes in company with all the rest of the slave holding States.
                        Perhaps it would be nearer the mark to say that there would be less danger
                        of war if the whole fifteen Southern States went out together, than if one
                        of them went alone. For if all of them went together, there would be no
                        alternative but to acknowledge their independence at once and concede them a
                        place among the great powers of the world, and conclude a treaty of
                        friendship with them, and surrender to them all the government forts and
                        arsenals within their limits.</p>
                    <p>But if South Carolina were to go out by herself, there is no probability
                        whatever that Congress would recognize her independence. What then? Fort
                        Moultrie and Castle Pinckney command the harbor of Charleston.--Their full
                        and complete possession by South Carolina is essential to her existence as
                        an independent power. She never can call herself independent till her own
                        troops garrison them. Nor can she get them without the effusion of blood,
                        for it will be the duty of the President to maintain possession of them with
                        the troops of the United States.</p>
                    <p>The horizon looks gloomy. South Carolina is in earnest. She is bent on
                        setting up for herself before a Black Republican President shall be set up
                        over her. It is not to be supposed that she does not take into her
                        calculations a matter of such vital importance as the possession of the
                        forts that command the harbor of her chief city. She will pour out her blood
                        to get them, and we must give them up or keep them at the cannon's mouth; or
                        else we must take some measures to win her back to the Union, and to satisfy
                        her and all the Southern States that they can remain in it with safety and
                        honor.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spirit states that it cannot see how civil war will be averted as
                    things are going, especially if Northern states don't repeal their "aggressive
                    laws."</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/dec60.html#12.12a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Congressional</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Senator Iverson "proclaimed the fixed purpose of five Southern States to go
                    out of the Union before the 4th of March, and that nothing could prevent it."
                    When the Senate formed a committee relating to the secession difficulty, Mr.
                    Hawkins of Florida "expressed the view that the time for compromise had passed
                    forever."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Discharge of Workmen</head>
                <origin>Harrisburg Patriot</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>W. O. Hickock discharged 27 men last Saturday. Both Wilson &amp;
                    Brothers and the Harrisburg Car Factory also laid off workers since orders from
                    the South have ceased. The Patriot wonders how those workers who supported the
                    Republicans feel now.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.12.12.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Money Wanted</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spirit urges its subscribers to pay their bill because the paper was
                    "never more in need of money and never more in earnest in dunning our patrons."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Hope He May Get It</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spirit hopes that Capt. W. W. Sellers of the Fulton Republican gets the
                    position of Sergeant-at-Arms in Harrisburg because he greatly deserves it.
                    However, the paper believes that the Republican party is controlled by a "set of
                    blood-leeches who hang on the skirts of the party." These men pay little
                    attention to merit when choosing office holders.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Stolen Horse</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Mr. John Ford, of Shippensburg, got his stolen horse back after the thief
                    was unable to sell it and then abandoned it.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Dead Body Found</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An old man named Aux was found dead on the tracks of the Franklin Railroad
                    north of Greencastle.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maclay</ln>
                        <fn>J. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Esq.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rhone</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on November 20th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Steck</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keagy</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moore</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on December 7th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Steck</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hepfer</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shoner</ln>
                        <fn>Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on December 6th at the Lutheran Parsonage.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harden</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cowan</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McElroy</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on November 20th at the White Swan Hotel.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Eliza</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Died on November 17th, aged 53 years old. Left behind a husband and four
                    children.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.12.12.06">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.12.12.07">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.12.12.08">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
