<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1866/va.au.ss.1866.06.05">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>John Riedl</taggerName>
            <tagDate>05/22/00</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1866-06-05">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="06">June</month>
            <day>05</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1866.06.05.01">
            <div type="l">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>For the County Court</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Mr. Editor:--As the county levy will be laid at the next term of the June
                        Court. I think it an appropriate occasion to call the attention of the Court
                        by a subject which calls loudly for reform. The county is heavily taxed for
                        county purposes; yet the poor, being the more numerous class, bear the heavy
                        proportion of the tax. Should not those who have large material interests in
                        the county bear a tax proportionate to that interest? In looking over the
                        assessment books of this county, I find Mr. F--'s property is valued at
                        fifty thousand dollars, and Mr. D--'s property is valued a fifty dollars.
                        Yet strange to say, while Mr. F-- paid nine dollars. Is there any justice or
                        reason in such discrimination against the poor, and in favor of the rich?
                        This unequal and unjust tax is now driven many of the industrious, honest
                        laboring men from the country, while the idle and vicious, who never pay
                        their taxes by assessing a property tax, as well as a Capitulation tax.</p>
                    <p>In these times of high taxes, to bear the oft repeated adage, "Blessed is he
                        that hath nothing." But the County Court (by their assessments) would seem
                        to say "Cursed is he that hath many children."</p>
                    <p>REFORM</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Reform</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Denounces "discrimination against the poor, and in favor of the rich" and
                    calls for reform in the system of taxation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1866.06.05.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that 10,498 immigrants, mostly German and Irish, arrived in New
                    York last week.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Decorating Soldiers' Graves in Richmond</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On Monday of last week about 8000 persons turned out at Richmond with the
                        proper implements to decorate the graves of the 6,000 soldiers buried in
                        Hollywood Cemetery. On the next Thursday, about 20,000 persons turned out to
                        dress the graves and to strew them with flowers. The <emph rend="italics"
                            >Examiner</emph> of Friday last says that agreeably to the
                        pre-arrangements of the Hollywood Memorial Association, the sacred touching
                        ceremonies incident to the dressing and floral adornment of the graves of
                        the Confederate dead that lie buried in Hollywood Cemetery, were carried
                        into effect. Business was suspended, the city was deserted, and the feet of
                        the people who revere the brave bore them forth to the quiet city of the
                        dead, where the hand of youth and of age, of both sexes, were busied in the
                        work of flowery decoration. The occasion was such an one as has never before
                        been witnessed in Richmond; and it is not probable that the eyes that looked
                        in admiration upon the deep, patriotic, heartfelt demonstration will ever
                        look upon a like scene again -- the Mourning Festival of Flowers.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>On two occasions last week an estimated total of 28,000 people turned out
                    to decorate the graves of the Confederate dead in Richmond.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Freedmen's Bureau Bill</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Last Wednesday the House passed a bill extending the life of the Freedmen's
                    Bureau for three additional years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1866.06.05.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>E. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>E. M. Young's smokehouse was broken into last week and eight pieces of
                    bacon were stolen.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gooch</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bledsoe</ln>
                        <fn>Thos. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reid</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sarah Gooch was committed to jail last week for stealing clothing from Mrs.
                    Thomas Bledsoe.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News--Try Again, Boys</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Staunton Base Ball Club was beaten by the Monticello Club in a game at
                    the University of Virginia by a score of 42 to 5.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News--A Call Upon The Gentlemen</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kunkle</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pilson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Ladies Cemetery Committee requests all able-bodied men to assemble at
                    the cemetery on Saturday to contribute their efforts to improving the graves of
                    the Confederate dead. Ladies are requested to provide provisions.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News--Augusta Circuit Court</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The June term of the Circuit Court commenced its session in Staunton, on
                        Friday last, the 1st day of June -- Judge Hugh W. Sheffey , presiding. The
                        charge to th Grand Jury was able, and contained an eloquent eulogium upon
                        the private and official character of the late Judge Lucas P. Thompson. Wm.
                        A. Abney was selected as foreman, and the following indictments and
                        presentments were made: Indictment against Robert F. Craig, for grand
                        larceny. The Judge being interested as counsel in this case, it was
                        postponed until the July Special Term, (over which Judge Watson, of
                        Albemarle, will preside,) and the prisoner admitted to bail in the sum of
                        $7,000 for his appearance there. Indictment against Alexander W. Greaver,
                        (No. 1) for grand larceny; indictment against same, for grand larceny;
                        indictment against the same, for grand larceny, (No. 2). These cases not
                        being ready for trial, they were postponed. Indictment against George
                        Greaver, for petit larceny, indictment against Henry Woodson, (colored) for
                        house-breaking, &amp;c.; indictment against Peter Ransom, (colored) for
                        house-breaking, &amp;c; cases tried, and prisoners found guilty --
                        verdict of Jury for three years in the penitentiary; Robert Lewis, (colored)
                        for grand larceny -- case tried, prisoner found guilty, and verdict of Jury
                        for three years in the penitentiary. Mover for new trial. Several other
                        presentments for minor offences.--The docket of civil causes is unusually
                        large.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>Lucas P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Abney</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craig</ln>
                        <fn>Robert F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greaver</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greaver</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greaver</ln>
                        <fn>Franklin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woodson</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ransom</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lewis</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>An account of proceedings at the first session of the June term of the
                    Circuit Court.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Local News--Interesting Ceremonies</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bixio</ln>
                        <fn>Father</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McMahon</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Collins</ln>
                        <fn>N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Murray</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>O'Brien</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hurley</ln>
                        <fn>K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLaughlin</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sullivan</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crowley</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nelligan</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crowe</ln>
                        <fn>B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scherer</ln>
                        <fn>L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kelley</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLaughlin</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Connors</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crimmons</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hurley</ln>
                        <fn>N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>An account of the ceremonies at St. Francis Church last Thursday, where
                    forty or fifty girls participated in a floral procession accompanied by song.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dickerson</ln>
                        <fn>H. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Julia A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>H. B. Dickerson, of Charlotte county, and Julia Crawford, of Augusta, were
                    married on May 20 by Rev. J. C. Baker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1866.06.05.04">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
