<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1866/va.au.ss.1866.05.08">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>John Riedl</taggerName>
            <tagDate>05/22/00</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1866-05-08">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day>08</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1866.05.08.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>The Radicals</head>
                <origin>New York News</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Assesses the current political climate and the conflicts between "the
                    Democracy and the Radicals," concluding that the Presidential election of 1868
                    will be "brimful of danger to the public repose."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1866.05.08.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Honor Fallen Heroes</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The local Ladies Cemetery Committee will join in a statewide day dedicated
                    to honoring the Confederate dead.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>A Suggestion to Our Farmers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Recommends that farmers plant buckwheat to supplement the wheat crop, which
                    has been greatly reduced due to excessively cold temperatures.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>"That Petition"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It will be remembered that, shortly after the Federal troops were withdrawn
                        from this place we announced that we had been informed that W. J. Dews was
                        engaged in getting signers to a secret petition praying that the troops be
                        sent back to this place, and charging that "Union men were, otherwise , not
                        safe. When asked by us if it were true, Dews denied it, and asserted that it
                        was a petition to Congress for an entirely different purpose. The citizens
                        of Staunton were justly indignant, and though they were anxious to see the
                        petition, it was never made public, and they heard nothing more of it till
                        Wednesday evening last, when the papers, containing the telegraphic notice
                        of the proceedings of Congress of the day before, were received, when they
                        found that Senator Trumbull had presented to the Senate of the United States
                        a petition purporting to be a petition of "146 loyal citizens of Staunton"
                        never signed it.--Clarity compels us to believe that the large majority of
                        those who were inveigled into signing it were ignorant, simple-minded
                        denizens of the brush who did not know the purport of the paper they were
                        signing. We can forgive them for they knew not what they were doing. They
                        were too ignorant to know that they were disgracing themselves, whilst
                        slandering the citizens of Staunton, and the people of the county generally.
                        We warned unsuspecting Union men at the same time against the nefarious
                        designs of the author of the petition, and told them that he would make a
                        catspaw of them to subserve his own selfish purposes. We stated that he
                        wished to gain notoriety that he might be the recipient of a better office
                        than the one he then held and disgraced. He has since been appointed Notary
                        Public, and is now an applicant for still more important one, to wit:
                        --Commissioner under the Civil Rights Bill.</p>
                    <p>Those who perpetrate such an abominable slander against any people as that
                        contained in this petition against the citizens of Staunton, have an object
                        to attain. Othello would say:</p>
                    <lb/>
                    <p>"I will be hanged if some eternal villain,</p>
                    <p>Some busy and insinuating rogue,</p>
                    <p>Some cogging, cozening slave, <emph rend="italics">to get some office,</emph></p>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italics">Have not devised this slander."</emph>
                    </p>
                    <lb/>
                    <p>No greater evidence of the patience, forbearance an long suffering of the
                        citizens of this community could be furnished than the fact that they have
                        allowed a man to remain unmolested in their midst who has been engaged in
                        secretly slandering them to the authorities who only need a pretext to
                        increase the burden of oppression now unjustly heaped upon them. The last
                        ounce of weight broke the camel's back.</p>
                    <p>There is a point beyond which forbearance ceases to be a virtue. that point
                        has been nearly reached, and it is time for some to heed the admonition.
                        Justice will finally be done, old scores will be settled, and the "<emph
                            rend="italics">devil will get his Dews</emph>."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dews</ln>
                        <fn>W. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A petition from "146 loyal citizens of Staunton" was recently presented in
                    Congress. It is suspected to be the work of W. J. Dews, who has been rumored to
                    be circulating petitions of a suspicious character. The petition claims that
                    "loyal" citizens of Staunton have been "persecuted by rebels" and calls for the
                    return of federal troops. The editor expresses outrage at this "slandering of
                    the citizens of Augusta."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Representation in Congress</head>
                <origin>Richmond Whig</origin>
                <commentary>"The South should not surrender a single Constitutional right for the
                    sake of securing representation in Congress. We concur in the sentiment
                    expressed by the Richmond Whig, that:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that "it is just as well for the Southern States to be kept out of
                    the Union forever" as to "be governed by a bitter, malignant, despotical party,
                    maintained in power by the aid of negro votes."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1866.05.08.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News--Reprieved</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chaney</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Isaac Chaney, who had been held in jail in Staunton before being
                    transported to Richmond to be executed, was reprieved by order of the War
                    Department.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Local News--Police Court</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trayer</ln>
                        <fn>Jas.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robinson</ln>
                        <fn>Jas.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parent</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kurtz</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Evans</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strother</ln>
                        <fn>Elijah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Horring</ln>
                        <fn>W.T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGuffin</ln>
                        <fn>D. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lewis</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hawkins</ln>
                        <fn>Fanny</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Floyd</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sketches recent arrests and proceedings at the Mayor's Court.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Local News--Sketch of the Proceedings of the Council for the Town of Staunton</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hope</ln>
                        <fn>R. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickle</ln>
                        <fn>R. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bagby</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Price</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kurtz</ln>
                        <fn>J. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doom</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Collins</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kayser</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Outlines the recent proceedings of the Town Council.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Graham</ln>
                        <fn>J. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fauntleroy</ln>
                        <fn>A. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Conrad</ln>
                        <fn>Sallie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Conrad</ln>
                        <fn>R. Y.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sallie Conrad and Dr. A. M. Fauntleroy were married on April 26 by Rev. J.
                    R. Graham.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1866.05.08.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Lovers and Husbands</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Asks husbands why many of them do not "pay the same little attentions to
                    your wives as before" marriage, noting that praise "goes a great way with
                    women."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
