<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1866/va.au.ss.1866.05.22">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>John Riedl</taggerName>
            <tagDate>05/23/00</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1866-05-22">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day>22</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1866.05.22.01">
            <div type="l">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Lorenzo Sibert</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sibert</ln>
                        <fn>Lorenzo</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>An account of a geological survey of Rockbridge, Amherst, and Augusta
                    counties.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Old Mortality</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>"Old Mortality" calls for the erection of a monument to Augusta's
                    Confederate dead in the Court House square.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>"How-E"</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Referring to a months-old controversy involving local Bishop Glossbrenner,
                    "How-E" questions whether the church still desires to "place the negro over and
                    above us."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>06</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Bremo</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Referring to the recent petition from loyal citizens of Augusta to
                    Congress, "Bremo" calls on members of the community to "expose all those who
                    signed this petition," arguing that "forbearance is no longer a virtue with this
                    class."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1866.05.22.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Filching Money From Negroes</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The report of Gens. Steedman and Fullerton shows that a number of men
                        connected with the Freedmen's Bureau are using their positions to make money
                        out of the negroes whom they are pretending to protect. In the South, it has
                        always been considered the very meanest of acts to take advantage of a
                        negro. A man who will cheat or in any way take advantage of a negro to "put
                        money into his own pocket" is worse than a chicken thief, and if he occupies
                        an office the duty of which makes him the guardian of the negro's interest,
                        and uses it to filch money from the negro, he is worse than a highway
                        robber. That some who are connected with the Freedmen's Bureau are making
                        money out of the negroes, whilst they hypocritically pretend to be acting
                        the part of their best friends, there can be no doubt. That we would not
                        have to go far to find a case of this kind will appear from the following:</p>
                    <p>A negro has $30 stolen from him. A member of the Freedmen's Court proposes,
                            <emph rend="italics">for a consideration</emph>, to recover it. The
                        negro does not agree to employ him. The judge of the Freedmen's court
                        proposes a second time, and importunes the negro till he consents to employ
                        him, the negro agreeing to give him $8 on the condition that he recover a
                        single cent of the money, but makes the negro pay him $3 any way.</p>
                    <p>In another case, a negro wishes to have some State Bank notes exchanged for
                        Greenbacks.--He went to the same Judge in the Freedmen's Court and requested
                        him to have the exchange made for him. The Judge took his money, walked to
                        the Bank, but a short distance off, and received $17 in Greenbacks in
                        exchange for the negro's State bank money, and for this service required the
                        negro to pay him $3.00.--These facts have been reported to us by a
                        respectable gentleman. The place where these nice operations were effected
                        is the town of Staunton, and the individual who performed them is W. J.
                        Dews, Judge of the Freedmen's Court, Notary Public, author of the slanderous
                        petition to Congress, and applicant for the office of Commissioner under the
                        Civil Rights Bill.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dews</ln>
                        <fn>W. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Argues that W. J. Dews, who apparently initiated the controversial recent
                    petition sent to Congress, used his position as a member of the Freedmen's Court
                    to "filch money from the negro," making him "worse than a chicken thief."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Denials of the Signers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The last <emph rend="italics">Vindicator</emph> contains the cards of Messrs.
                        John A. Harris, Jno. A. Harris, Jno. K. Keiser, Benj. M. Lines, Thos. K.
                        Durboraw, Samuel Driver and Samuel H. Weaver, who say that they did <emph
                            rend="italics">not</emph> sign the petition to which their names were
                        attached, and also the cards of Messrs. R. B. Moore, A. B. Roadcap and
                        Samuel L. Wampler, who say that they signed it under misapprehensions of its
                        characters.</p>
                    <p>W. J. Dews and Jas. Todd have sworn that these names were signed and that
                        they were signed in their presence. These men, whose names are upon the
                        petition, swear that they did <emph rend="italics">not</emph> sign it. Both
                        parties cannot be telling the truth. "North to put too fine a point upon
                        it," but to express it in the plain vernacular, "there is a <emph
                            rend="italics">lie</emph> out." Who are the liars? We will not pretend
                        at this time to determine. As these parties deny signing whilst Dews and
                        Todd swear away they did sign, it devolves upon Dews and Todd to prove the
                        affirmative. The <emph rend="italics">onus probandi</emph> rests upon Dews
                        and Todd.--There is a very general belief in this community that Dews and
                        Todd have sworn to two falsehoods. 1st. That the signers to the petition
                        were citizens of Augusta, as it is known that a number of them -- twelve, we
                        believe -- were citizens of Rockbridge. 2nd That they signed their names in
                        their (Dews' and Todd's) presence, whilst it is believed that a number of
                        them never saw Dews and Todd.</p>
                    <p>Under the circumstances, the simple denials of any man, whose character has
                        the least claim to credibility, will outweigh the affidavits of Dews and
                        Todd. It is the opinion of this community that Dews and Todd have sworn
                        falsely, knowingly and wilfully, and that it is the duty of the Grand Jury
                        to indict them for perjury. It is the duty of those who have been wronged to
                        bring the wrong-doers to justice. It will not do for them to say, with
                        Othello,</p>
                    <lb/>
                    <p>"You told a lie: an odious, damned lie;"</p>
                    <p>Upon my soul a lie; a wicked lie."</p>
                    <lb/>
                    <p>whilst they nothing to establish the charge.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keiser</ln>
                        <fn>Jno. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lines</ln>
                        <fn>Benj. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Durboraw</ln>
                        <fn>Thos. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Driver</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weaver</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moore</ln>
                        <fn>R. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roadcap</ln>
                        <fn>A. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wampler</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dews</ln>
                        <fn>W. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Todd</ln>
                        <fn>Jas.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Some of the men who apparently signed the recent petition to Congress now
                    claim that they never signed it, while others claim they signed it "under
                    misapprehensions of its character." The article also argues that Dews and Todd,
                    the men who circulated the petition, should be indicted for perjury by the Grand
                    Jury.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Staunton Vindicator</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keiser</ln>
                        <fn>Geo. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>C. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pelter</ln>
                        <fn>Sampson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A two month old infant was recently left at the residence of George Keiser
                    near Waynesboro with a note asking he and his wife to please care for the
                    infant.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1866.05.22.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News--The Lee Club</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>R. Skip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Junior Base Ball Club has organized as the Lee Club.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the "colored people" of the town began a Fair at Town Hall on
                    Monday for the purpose of raising funds to pay for their Church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An English nobleman traveling through America recently stayed at the
                    Virginia Hotel in Staunton and stated that he had not stayed at a better hotel
                    in all America.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News--Freedmen's Court Suspended</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tukey</ln>
                        <fn>F. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Risk</ln>
                        <fn>Harvey</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dews</ln>
                        <fn>W. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The local Freedmen's Court has been suspended. No new cases will be tried
                    pending further orders.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News--Police Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ellis</ln>
                        <fn>Thos.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snapp</ln>
                        <fn>Jno. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shean</ln>
                        <fn>Bob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parent</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sergeant</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hardy</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Justice</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Evans</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Justice</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>An account of recent police activities, including the arrest of a group of
                    white boys apprehended for swimming in a local creek.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Message From The President--Veto of the Bill Admitting Colorado as a State</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Transcript of President Johnson's most recent veto, refusing Colorado
                    admission as a state.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italics">Editor of the Spectator:</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>Sir:--I observe in your issue of the 15th inst., my name attached to a
                        petition praying for a return of U. S. troops to this section on a plea that
                        loyal citizens could not get justice done them in civil court, and that
                        threats were made against their lives and property. I was not aware that
                        justice could be obtained or that threats had been made, and, therefore, had
                        no reason for signing that petition, and most emphatically deny signing or
                        authorizing any one to sign what I understood was a petition. I did sign my
                        name to such a petition for Mr. W. J. Dews to be appointed Notary Public,
                        but none other. I never saw Mr. Todd but twice in my life, and never signed
                        any paper or petition for him. I want it distinctly understood, however,
                        that if I had signed that petition, or in any way laid myself liable to
                        manipulation of Messrs. Todd and Dews I would not be afraid to own it; and
                        when I am satisfied that the presence of troops is needed in this county to
                        preserve the lives and property of loyal citizens and that no other force
                        can accomplish that end, then, and not until then, will I allow my name to
                        be put to such a petition.--Be kind enough to give this a place in your next
                        issue, and request the "Virginian" to copy, and oblige.</p>
                    <p>Very respectfully,</p>
                    <p>Your obt. servt.,</p>
                    <p>Thomas K. Durboraw</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Thomas K. Durboraw</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Durboraw</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dews</ln>
                        <fn>W. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Todd</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Thomas Durboraw denies signing the recent petition sent to Congress, though
                    he says he did sign a petition for Dews to be made Notary Public.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>A Card</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The undersigned acknowledges that he signed the petition praying for the
                        return of Federal soldiers to Staunton for the protection of the lives and
                        property of Union men, and that he took one of the petitions and got some
                        signatures to it. He was doing business at the time near Goshen, in
                        Rockbridge, and, about the time the soldiers were withdrawn, W. J. Dews
                        represented to him that the lives and property of Union men had been
                        threatened and would not be safe unless troops were kept in the county for
                        their protection, and under the impressions made upon his mind by the
                        representations of Wm. J. Dews, he signed the petition in Dews' presence --
                        no Todd's -- and interested himself in getting others to sign it. All the
                        signatures he got were the names of citizens of Rockbridge. He relied upon
                        the representation of Dews because Dews occupied a position which would
                        enable him to know, and he did not suspect, at the time, that Dews was
                        misrepresenting the state of feeling of the citizens towards Union men. He
                        is satisfied now that Dews did misrepresent, and does not believe there is
                        any necessity for the presence of Federal troops for the protection of the
                        lives or property of Union men.</p>
                    <p>Jas. F. Davis.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Jas. F. Davis</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>Jas. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dews</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Todd</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jas. F. Davis admits signing the recent petition, but claims that Dews
                    misrepresented the sentiment toward Union men and now does not believe Federal
                    troops are needed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheets</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Todd</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dews</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James Sheets denies signing the petition, and claims he would sign a
                    petition for the opposite purpose.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spitler</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bishop</ln>
                        <fn>Virginia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kiracofe</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Virginia Bishop and Thomas Spitler were married on May 17 by Rev. J. W.
                    Kiracofe.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1866.05.22.04">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
