<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1866/va.au.ss.1866.03.06">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>John Riedl</taggerName>
            <tagDate>05/08/00</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1866-03-06">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day>06</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1866.03.06.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The President's Speech</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An account of a speech given by President Johnson in Washington, in which
                    he calls on his audience to stand with him in defense of the Constitution.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>06</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Signal</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>"Signal" invites the editor of the Spectator to West View, where he can be
                    entertained by "'shows,' skating, fine views, natural scenery and pretty women."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1866.03.06.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The President and the Radicals</head>
                <origin>Lynchburg News</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Replete with allusions to the French Revolution, the article argues that
                    the Radicals are now on the run in the wake of Johnson's veto.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Proclamation of Peace</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The President, says the Richmond <emph rend="italics">Times</emph>, no longer
                        makes a State secret of the fact that he will in a very short time issue an
                        official proclamation that the late civil war is ended.--When he does this
                        he will have accomplished the last and highest act which the Executive
                        Department of the Government can perform towards the restoration of peace.</p>
                    <p>He cannot compel Congress to admit Representatives from the Southern States,
                        but his proclamation will subordinate military to civil authority, and place
                        all the States composing the Union upon a footing of equality in that
                        respect.</p>
                    <p>The privileges of the writ of <emph rend="italics">habeas corpus</emph> will
                        then be within reach of the humblest citizen of the South,and our State
                        government will become supreme within the limits of the States for the
                        protection of whose citizens they were organized.</p>
                    <p>Martial law, which now reigns supreme in eleven States, will then only be
                        potent for the control and punishment of those who are connected with the
                        army, in the manner defined by the Articles of War. Every great right
                        guaranteed by that grand and famous Virginia Bill of Rights, which looks
                        very sadly out of place in front of the "Alexandria Constitution," will then
                        be enjoyed by our citizens. Particularly dear to every honest, fearless,
                        patriotic journalist will be that Article which declares that "the freedom
                        of the press is one of the great bulwarks of Liberty, and can never be
                        restrained but by despotic Governments."</p>
                    <p>The Southern people, after a probation of nearly twelve months, will hail the
                        proclamation of peace with great joy. And yet, as far as our resistance to
                        the authority of the Constitution and laws of the United States is
                        concerned, there has been peace the most profound and undisturbed since the
                        1st of May last. The history of civil wars, ancient and modern, furnish no
                        more remarkable and striking instance of the speedy and honest acquiescence
                        in the result of a contest than the people of the South have done since
                        their armies capitulated. The sun of the Confederacy sunk, leaving no margin
                        of gradually darkening twilight. The blackness of darkness fell upon the
                        "lost cause" as rapidly as night follows, the setting of the sun in Eastern
                        countries.</p>
                    <p>The inexorable logic of the war convinced the people of eleven States with a
                        rapidity without precedent in the history of the world. No thought of
                        resistance of the Federal Government kept a single guerilla in the field an
                        hour after the capitulation of LEE and JOHNSTON.-- The utter futility of
                        further resistance was universally admitted, and in the heart of Virginia
                        and North Carolina, a sergeant's guard made arrests as easily as they would
                        have done under the guns of Fortress Monroe.</p>
                    <p>The good faith of the people of the South has been, during the last ten
                        months, manifested in many different ways. A labor system, which the habits,
                        customs and usages of many generations had rendered part and parcel of the
                        South, was annihilated in a day, but despite the terrible temporary
                        annoyances which its destruction visited upon our people, they bore the
                        change with wonderful fortitude and equanimity.</p>
                    <p>Indeed, in a infinite variety of ways we have demonstrated to all impartial,
                        unprejudiced persons, our fitness for the judicious exercise of those great
                        civil rights which are so soon to be restored to us by the President. His
                        forthcoming proclamation of peace will be recognized by all conservative
                        Northern men, and by all christendom, as a most wise and statesmanlike
                        exercise of the most important functions of his high office.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Praises President Johnson's upcoming proclamation of peace as "a most wise
                    and statesmanlike exercise of the most important functions of his high office."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Treatment of Negroes</head>
                <origin>Richmond Whig</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We are forced, says the Rich. Whig, to the conclusion that these Radical
                        fanatics desire to compel us to treat the negroes harshly, and that to this
                        end they are endeavoring by law to establish unpleasant relations between
                        the two races. They want the negroes to look up to them, and they propose to
                        confer upon them the elective franchise in order that they may exercise it
                        in their interest. They make so much fuss over them that their heads are
                        completely turned. Their poor intellects are bewildered, and they really do
                        not know what to do or which way turn. So many promises are made them, so
                        much time devoted to measure relating to them, and so many expectations
                        excited in their minds, that they are kept in a state of feverish anxiety.
                        They are cajoled out of the larger portion of the little money they get, by
                        hook or crook, by school marms, or preachers, or pedlars, or -- worse than
                        all -- politicians, who get up meetings among them and induce them to
                        contribute money to various projects, chief among which is the appointment
                        of delegations to go to Washington to act upon Congress and pay unwelcome
                        visits to the President. Where there is one honest man and sincere friend of
                        the negro thus engaged, there are a thousand rogues and wretches who are
                        using them to promote their own selfish ends. they make more out the negro
                        than the negro will ever make out of them. Leaving out of consideration the
                        bounties of the Government distributed through the officers of the
                        Freedmen's Bureau, where is the negro who has received any help from these
                        pretended friends. They have had advise --volumes of it; and oaths --
                        volleys of them; but when, where, and from whom have they received private
                        benefits and charities? When the negro wants to be flattered or fleeced, he
                        may go to these people -- nay, they will go to him. But when he wants a
                        scuttle of coal or a stick of wood to keep him from freezing, or, to use his
                        own language, "a meal of victuals" to keep him from starving, or clothing to
                        cover his nakedness, he neither goes to there people, nor do they go to him.
                        He goes to "his natural enemies -- the Southern whites" -- and gets what he
                        wants. His pretended friends are ready to give him suffrage to spite the
                        South , and to vote him lands, and food and clothing, when it costs them
                        nothing, or to get up subscriptions to relieve his wants, when the money is
                        to pass through their hands, and they can keep back a large share of it as
                        "the recompense of their reward" -- but when it comes to giving of their own
                        substance, they would see him in Jericho first.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that the "Radical fanatics" are attempting to force white
                    Southerners to "treat the negroes harshly" by legislating "unpleasant relations
                    between the two races."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1866.03.06.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harper</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paul</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A vacant house was burned on March 1st, suspected to be the work of "an
                    incendiary."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News--Horse Thief Arrested</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duggan</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A horse thief who swindled a number of local residents has been captured in
                    Amherst county.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News--Stealing Boots</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Darden</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A local freedman stole two left-foot boots from a local store and is
                    awaiting trial in the Freedmen's Court.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News--Delegates to R. R. Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn>H. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>Bolivar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>A. H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>W. J. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bruce</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shelton</ln>
                        <fn>T. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McChesney</ln>
                        <fn>Adam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henry</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>Jas.</fn>
                        <sf>Sr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tate</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sterrett</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wislon</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>Absalom</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>J. Marshall</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fulton</ln>
                        <fn>J. Givens</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gamble</ln>
                        <fn>Theopilus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harper</ln>
                        <fn>Keaton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf>Sr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Finley</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craig</ln>
                        <fn>J. Davis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Montgomery</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A list of Augusta county delegates to an upcoming convention, which will
                    address the construction of the Valley Railroad.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flory</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thomas</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Flory and Sarah Wright were married on February 22nd by Rev. Daniel
                    Thomas.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wine</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Evy</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Evy</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thomas</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel Wine and Mary Evy were married on February 25th by Rev. Daniel
                    Thomas.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palmer</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gaver</ln>
                        <fn>H. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. John Myers and Maggie Palmer were married on March 1st by Rev. H. A.
                    Gaver.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craun</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hale</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Craun and E. Hale were married on March 1st by Rev. O. Beard.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bear</ln>
                        <fn>Louisa</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bear</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bear</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Louisa M. Bear died of a "complicated disease" on February 24.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Significant Order</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The citizens of this place and county are disposed to co-operate with the
                        Freedmen's Bureau in the discharge of their duties. those who maintain that
                        there is any necessity for troops here to enable the Freedmen's Bureau to
                        discharge its duties, slander our people. The following order of Court needs
                        no comment:</p>
                    <p>Virginia:--Augusta County Court, February 26th, 1866.</p>
                    <p>It having been suggested to the Court, that the officers of the Freedmen's
                        Bureau have found some difficulty, in having their processes executed,
                        within the limits of this County,and this Court, feeling a strong desire to
                        co-operate with the officers of the Bureau in the preservation of order, the
                        enforcement of the laws, and the protections of freedmen and refugees in all
                        their rights:</p>
                    <p>It is thereby ordered to be entered on the records of this Court, that the
                        Court, the Magistrates in their respective districts, and the Sheriff and
                        other officers of the Court, are ready and willing, at all times, to render
                        every necessary assistance to the officers of the Bureau in the discharge of
                        their duties, and the at the Sheriff and Constables be and they are hereby
                        instructed to serve promptly, all processes which may be placed in their
                        hands by the officers of the Bureau and to enjoin on the people the
                        necessity of a ready obedience thereto, and in other respects to render all
                        the aid in their power in the execution of the laws of the United States.</p>
                    <p>Copy teste.</p>
                    <p>WM. A. BURNETT, Clerk.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burnett</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Includes an order pledging support from the local courts and constabulary
                    for the Freedmen's Court, maintaining that federal troops are not required in
                    the area.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1866.03.06.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Constitution of the Churchville Farmers' Club at Churchville, Augusta County,
                    Va.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A copy of the constitution of the newly formed farmers' club in
                    Churchville.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Farmer</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>This letter from "Farmer" praises the formation of the farmers' club in
                    Churchville as an example worthy of emulation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
