<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1866/va.au.ss.1866.11.20">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>John Riedl</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/27/00</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1866-11-20">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="11">November</month>
            <day>20</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1866.11.20.01">
            <div type="l">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>The Difference</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>H.</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>"H." relates a tale of a Swiss woman who had formed an erroneous opinion of
                    the nature of Southerners because of the influence of the "abolition
                    population," many of whom had come from the Valley. Her opinions were changed
                    during a near shipwreck, when Northerners were "wild, frantic and terrified"
                    while Southerners were "calm, composed and resigned."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1866.11.20.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>What's the Use of It?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Some of the papers announce that members of Congress are to be elected next
                        Spring in this State. Why elect them? There is no earthly probability that
                        they will be admitted to seats, and it is a useless, not to say foolish,
                        consumption of time, to go through the forms of an election. No members of
                        Congress will be admitted until after the next Presidential election, and we
                        are therefore decidedly opposed to an election for such officers, until we
                        have some assurance that we are not doing "<emph rend="italics">a vain
                        thing</emph>." We went through the farce once. Let us not enact it
                            again.--<emph rend="italics">Lexington Gazette and Banner</emph>.</p>
                    <p>We do not concur with the <emph rend="italics">Gazette and Banner</emph> in
                        its decided opposition to the election of Representatives to Congress, and
                        do not consider that such an election would the enactment of a "<emph
                            rend="italics">farce</emph>," or the perpetration of "<emph
                            rend="italics">a vain thing</emph>," and think that the <emph
                            rend="italics">Gazette and Banner</emph> has expressed such sentiment
                        without due reflection. To refuse to elect Representatives to Congress would
                        be to yield seeming assent to the theory of Thad. Stevens and other extreme
                        Radicals that the Southern States have forfeited the rights and lost the
                        character of States -- that they are <emph rend="italics">outside</emph> the
                        pale of the Union, and have not the rights of States in the Union.</p>
                    <p>President Lincoln apprehended that the great difficulty to a restoration of
                        the Union consisted in the fact that the Constitution did not provide for
                        requiring the States to elect Representatives to Congress, and he supposed
                        the citizens of the Southern States might refuse contumaciously to elect
                        Representatives, and thus practically prevent a restoration of the Union.</p>
                    <p>He favored an amendment of the constitution to remedy this difficulty. Had
                        the citizens of the South acted as he apprehended, they would been to blame.
                        As it is, the want of restoration is due to the Radicals in Congress who
                        refuse to admit the Representatives chose by the South. The whole blame now
                        rests with them -- none attaches to the people of the South. The South is
                        anxious, and has been since the surrender of its armies, for an immediate
                        and thorough restoration of the Union on the basis of equal constitutional
                        rights, and should do nothing which could, by any possibility, be construed
                        as being inconsistent with this position. If the conservatives of the South
                        should fail to elect Representatives, all may rest assured that the Southern
                        Radicals would not fail to elect <emph rend="italics"
                        >mis</emph>-representatives. On the 4th Thursday in May elections for
                        members of Congress will be held, and if the Conservatives or true Union men
                        will not vote, the Radical disunionists will, and the result will be that
                        Radicals -- Southern Radicals worse than Wendell Phillips -- will be
                        elected. Shall this burning shame be inflicted upon Virginia? No. Virginia,
                        God bless her, Virginia will do <emph rend="italics">her</emph> duty. She
                        will elect good, sound, pure <emph rend="italics">representative</emph> men.
                        She will not enact a "farce," but will perform a solemn duty.</p>
                    <p>The past session of Congress, with the Representatives from the South
                        excluded, was not, in the meaning and intent of the Constitution, a Congress
                        at all. Congress is composed of the Senate and House of Representatives, and
                        the Constitution says that, "The Senate of the United States shall be
                        composed of two Senators from <emph rend="italics">each</emph> State," and
                        that "no State shall be deprived of its equal suffrage in the Senate," and
                        that, "The House of Representatives shall be composed of members chosen
                        every second year by the people of the <emph rend="italics">several</emph>
                        States."</p>
                    <p>The President would be justified, (indeed, it would seem, acting in
                        compliance with his duty, under his sworn official obligations of fidelity
                        to the Constitution) in refusing to acknowledge that body, with the
                        Representatives from a portion of the States excluded, as a <emph
                            rend="italics">Constitutional Congress</emph>. He may, in the
                        circumstances surrounding, feel it his duty to do so, and, to make it a
                        Congress in the Constitutional sense, may call together the Representatives
                        elect of <emph rend="italics">all</emph> the States. What would then be the
                        sad predicament of the South, if she had failed to elect Representatives, or
                        worse, if she had allowed the few Radicals in the South to elect such as
                        would represent <emph rend="italics">them</emph>! It is important not only
                        to have an election, but to elect the <emph rend="italics">right</emph> kind
                        of men. It is no time for the people of the South to be sleeping upon their
                        posts when the enemy are at her gates. "Eternal vigilance is the price of
                        liberty."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Responding to an article in the Lexington Gazette and Banner that argued
                    there was no reason to elect representatives to the next session of Congress
                    since they would not be seated, the editor of the Spectator instead encourages
                    people not only to vote, but "to elect the right kind of men." The article
                    argues that taking the course proposed by the Gazette would play in to the
                    Radicals' hands.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Signs of War</head>
                <origin>Richmond Whig</origin>
                <commentary>"We publish on the fourth page the address of the committee of the
                    Radical 'Soldiers' and Sailors'' Union under the caption--"Revolutionary
                    Plot"--calling upon the Radical soldiers to assemble en masse in Washington city
                    on the 1st of December to greet the Radical members of Congress, and, in the
                    language of the call, to 'assure protection to the loyal majority in Congress,'
                    accompanied with the comments of the National Intelligencer and the Richmond
                    Dispatch. In an article in reference to this matter the Richmond Whig says
                    that:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We publish on the fourth page the address of the committee of the Radical
                        "Soldiers' and Sailors' Union" under the caption -- "Revolutionary Plot" --
                        calling upon the Radical soldiers to assemble [unclear] in Washington city
                        on the 1st of December to great the Radical members of Congress, and, in the
                        language of the call, to "assure protection to the loyal majority in
                        Congress," accompanied with the comments of the National <emph
                            rend="italics">Intelligencer</emph> and the Richmond <emph
                            rend="italics">Dispatch</emph>.</p>
                    <p>In an article in reference to this matter the Richmond Whig says that "where
                        there is so much smoke there must be some fire. When we hear hostile threats
                        from so many quarters, and see preparations for a conflict in so many
                        Northern localities, and then read their solemn appeals to all the disbanded
                        soldiers and sailors of the North, black and whites, to assemble at the
                        national capitol, when Congress meets, to protect the Radical majority, we
                        scent brimstone and villainous saltpetre.</p>
                    <p>If the signs of the times are not meaningless, one of tow things will be
                        likely to happen before six months shall roll by: The Radicals will either
                        butt their brains out against the Government, or they will seize upon it
                        with violence, and administer it in their own interest.--We have ceased to
                        shudder at any contemplated contingency. for our part, we are tired of being
                        suspended between heaven and earth. We want our status fixed and destiny
                        determined, and if the battle of 'Armageddon' is to be fought, we would
                        rather, Massachusetts consenting, see it fought at Washington at the opening
                        of Congress than have it in the South at some more distant period. If this
                        battle is to be fought, we want to have no part or lot in it. We beg to be
                        counted out.</p>
                    <p>We shall not speculate as to the probable arrangements that the President and
                        General Grant will make in view of this formidable demonstration against the
                        Government and the regular army. We take it for granted that they will be
                        prepared for any and every contingency that may arise. There is but little
                        doubt that General Butler is at the bottom of this revolutionary project.
                        Should it succeed, he would stand a good chance for the Presidency."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The author claims to "scent brimstone and saltpetre" in the plans of the
                    Soldiers' and Sailors' Union and anticipates "Armageddon" soon. The article also
                    suggests that General Butler is "at the bottom of this revolutionary project."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Constitutional Amendment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The legislature of Georgia overwhelmingly rejected the proposed
                    Constitutional Amendment, 36 to 0 in the Senate and 131 to 2 in the House.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Valuable Lessons</head>
                <origin>Baltimore Gazette</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that "the war has taught the people of the South some valuable
                    lessons," among them that "an agricultural people must always remain more or
                    less a dependent people" and urges Southerners to cultivate industry to make
                    themselves "more self-reliant and more powerful."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>The Effects of a Financial Crash</head>
                <origin>Richmond Times</origin>
                <commentary>"As the Richmond Times believes that it will require war, foreign or
                    domestic, or a terrible financial crash, which will inflict keen suffering upon
                    them, to mollify the indurated hearts of the Northern people and make them have
                    some feeling of sympathy for the Southern people, it prays, in preference, for
                    the financial crash. It says:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that the "signs of commercial and financial ruin" in the North are
                    "ominous" and that if the signs become a reality then "the political tempest
                    will no longer rage."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1866.11.20.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spitler</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carson</ln>
                        <fn>James E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carson</ln>
                        <fn>Robert N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James Carson was fined $250 for assault and battery against John Spitler.
                    The judgment against his brother, Robert Carson, set aside because of
                    insufficient evidence.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News--Fireman's Fair</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hardy</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The "ladies of this place" will hold a fair tomorrow to fund equipment for
                    the Augusta Fire Association.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News--Federal Cemetery</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Byers</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that federal soldiers are in the county seeking to establish a
                    cemetery for the federal soldiers in the area.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>"Peter Puff" Puffing</head>
                <origin>Lexington Gazette and Banner</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A satiric letter from a correspondent of the Lexington Gazette and Banner
                    that suggests the Staunton newspapers have been engaging in extravagant
                    boosterism.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flournoy</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tribbet</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGuffin</ln>
                        <fn>Sue</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Tribbet, of Rockbridge, and Sue McGuffin, of Greenville, were married
                    on November 8 by Rev. Flournoy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whisner</ln>
                        <fn>P. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reagan</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sandford</ln>
                        <fn>Mollie A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Hugh Reagan, of Staunton, and Mollie Sandford, of Rockbridge, were married
                    at the Lexington Hotel on November 8 by Rev. P. H. Whisner.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Tabitha G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Reed, of Frederick, and Tabitha Myers, of Augusta, were married on
                    November 8 by Rev. C. Beard.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnston</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCutchen</ln>
                        <fn>Sue R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sue McCutchen and J. M. Johnston were married on November 15 by Rev. Wm. E.
                    Baker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fry</ln>
                        <fn>C. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woodfin</ln>
                        <fn>A. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Little</ln>
                        <fn>J. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parrish</ln>
                        <fn>Mary M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary Parrish, of Augusta, and J. T. Little, of Alabama, were married at the
                    residence of Rev. C. F. Fry on November 13 by Rev. A. B. Woodfin.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>W. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Creigh</ln>
                        <fn>Cyrus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tate</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tate</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Margaret Tate, of Augusta, and Cyrus Creigh, of Greenbrier, were married at
                    the home of the bride's father on November 14 by Rev. W. E. Baker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1866.11.20.04">
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Revolutionary Plot--The Radicals Convoke a Force to Back Congress</head>
                <origin>Dispatch</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Includes the proclamation of the Soldiers' and Sailors' Union calling on
                    the "loyal majority" to assemble in Washington and support the Radical Congress
                    as well as commentary which casts the document as "the most hideous phase of the
                    worst passions and designs of Radicalism."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
