<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1866/va.au.ss.1866.10.02">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>John Riedl</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/20/00</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1866-10-02">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="10">October</month>
            <day>02</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1866.10.02.01">
            <div type="l">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Letter from Hon. J. B. Baldwin</head>
                <origin>Richmond Enquirer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>John B. Baldwin</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Staunton resident John Baldwin responds to an editorial in the Richmond
                    Enquirer that criticized Baldwin's position on secession and his comments before
                    the Reconstruction Committee.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1866.10.02.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The patriotic labors of he late "national Convention," which met in
                        Philadelphia, have, we fear, says the Richmond <emph rend="italics"
                        >Times</emph>, been attended with no good results. A truce was patched up
                        between the Northern Democracy and moderate Republicans, but it was
                        temporary, hollow and insecure, and has been followed by open hostilities
                        between the late allies. The pledges to support the Presidents's policy of
                        reconstruction which were given by Raymond and Weed, as the accredited
                        representatives of the Conservative Republicans, have already been broken.</p>
                    <p>The Maine and Vermont elections utterly demoralized the author of the address
                        of the Philadelphia Convention, and, in imitation of Saturn, he is devouring
                        his own offspring. Indeed, the coalition of Northern parties, from which
                        such happy results were anticipated, has fallen to pieces, and those who
                        were six weeks ago most vociferous in advocating the policy of the President
                        are now deserting it, and advocating the adoption of the Congressional
                        amendment. The New York <emph rend="italics">Herald, Times</emph> and <emph
                            rend="italics">Post</emph> have already gone over bag and baggage to the
                        enemy, and thousands of time-serving demagogues are in motion, or busily
                        packing up and preparing to go over. A defeat to the Conservatives in
                        Pennsylvania would give the finishing blow to the Conservative party. The
                            <emph rend="italics">Herald</emph> and the <emph rend="italics"
                        >Times</emph> now boldly affirm that the President will very soon succumb to
                        the teachings of the late Northern elections, and issue a proclamation
                        advising the Southern States to adopt the Constitutional amendment which he
                        has devoted so much time to opposing.</p>
                    <p>These demonstrations have greatly alarmed the Radicals, who fear that the
                        adoption of the "Amendment" will strip them of all pretext for further
                        sectional agitation. As they are ill-omened birds that delight only in
                        stormy weather, may of them have already boldly proclaimed that even if the
                        Southern States shall abase themselves to the earth and adopt the
                        "Amendment," they shall not profit by their humility and dirt-eating. The
                        leading organ of that party now declares that "no leading Republican in
                        Congress means to admit the ten waiting States simply on the adoption of the
                        Constitutional amendment until the rebel States consent to come back upon
                        the basis of equal political rights to all loyal citizens." If, therefore,
                        there is any Southern man who believes that the adoption of the "Amendment"
                        will bring peace and restoration, he is very much mistaken.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Laments that the fragile coalition forged at the National Convention in
                    Philadelphia is now fracturing and warns Southerners against adopting the
                    Constitutional Amendment in the hopes that it will bring "peace and
                    restoration."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Praises "the extent to which the noble women of our country have aided the
                    soldier's family, the soldier himself" and "the cause for which he fought."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>The Great Issue of the Times</head>
                <origin>Richmond Whig</origin>
                <commentary>"The signs of the times indicate that the people of the North are on the
                    verge of civil war. The excitement is even now intense, and is destined to
                    increase in fervor. The issue is of such moment as to stir the hearts of the
                    people. The Richmond Whig very properly describes it as follows:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that President Johnson should not recognize the "fractional and
                    sectional Congress" and that when the Radicals respond with violence it will be
                    up to Johnson to "meet force with force."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Richmond Times</origin>
                <commentary>"The Richmond Times says:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that despotism may be the only answer "if revolutionary excesses be
                    not arrested."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Origin of Staunton</head>
                <origin>Rockingham Register</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Responding to a recent series of articles in the Spectator, the Rockingham
                    Register claims that Staunton "owes its name to a calf and a dutch butcher" and
                    not to Lady Staunton of England.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1866.10.02.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Last Friday in Craigsville "a negro woman" was "caught between the train of
                    cars and the platform at that depot and seriously, if not mortally injured."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the Federal Tax Collector collected $12,500 in Augusta county
                    last week.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News--Hair Tonic</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>W. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yeakle</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that local doctor W. B. Young has manufactured a hair tonic that
                    cleanses the scalp while restoring grey hairs to their original color.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News--Tournament at Staunton</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>A. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>Alex.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>E. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>O'Ferrall</ln>
                        <fn>J. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>E. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>W. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn>E. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carson</ln>
                        <fn>C. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parker</ln>
                        <fn>Ed.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mason</ln>
                        <fn>Claiborne</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn>J. Bernard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Covell</ln>
                        <fn>Avery</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woodward</ln>
                        <fn>Alice</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chapman</ln>
                        <fn>Rosa</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn>Emma</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woodward</ln>
                        <fn>Kate</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn>Jennette</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A tournament was recently held in the meadow in front of the Institute for
                    the Deaf, Dumb, and Blind. A. W. Harman was victorious and crowned Avery Covell
                    Queen of Love and Beauty.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Farmer</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>"Farmer" questions the propriety of a proposed tax to finance the
                    construction of the Valley Railroad, a measure advocated by the editor of the
                    Spectator last week.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1866.10.02.04">
            <div type="l">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Bessie Bell and Mary Gray</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Oldest Inhabitant</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>"Oldest Inhabitant" explains the origins of the names of Bessie Bell and
                    Mary Gray, two of the most prominent of the Staunton hills. He contends that the
                    names originated in Scotland and Ireland and "by our Scotch-Irish ancestors they
                    were brought to the Valley of Virginia."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
