<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1866/va.au.ss.1866.01.09">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>John Riedl</taggerName>
            <tagDate>04/13/00</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1866-01-09">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day>09</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1866.01.09.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Resolutions of Respect</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>At a meeting of the Ladies of Mt. S----- in Virginia, Mrs. Peggy was called
                        to preside, and Miss Kit requested to act as Secretary. On motion, a
                        committee consisting of Mrs. Jamsha, Miss Tobitha, and Miss Kit, was
                        appointed to draft resolutions. The committee submitted the following, which
                        were unanimously adopted:</p>
                    <p>Whereas, the Rev. Henry Ward Beecher, has kindly volunteered to act as
                        Advocate and Champion for "Women's Rights," and whereas, the merits of his
                        efforts demand a passing tribute, therefore.</p>
                    <p>Resolved, That we the ladies of Mt. S-----, tender the Rev. Henry Ward
                        Beecher our most appreciative thanks for his eloquent appeal, in behalf of
                        women's rights of suffrage, made in his "address delivered in the Hall of
                        Representatives at Washington City, before an immense audience."</p>
                    <p>Resolved, That if he intends the right of suffrage for the black man, and
                        black woman only, that we blot his name from our remembrance.</p>
                    <p>Resolved, That our wrath, and indignation be appeased for his bit of
                        glittering and overpowering flattery in calling, "woman the great
                        civilizer."</p>
                    <p>Resolved, That if his original idea becomes a fixed law, he shall be
                        immortalized as the "Savior" of "Women's Rights."</p>
                    <p>Resolved, That he shall have all the glory, as Gen'l Washington, and our
                        ancestors, never thought of woman's worth.</p>
                    <p>Resolved, To believe that "Time and the genius man create wonders."</p>
                    <p>Resolved, To confess that we are rather green in politics.</p>
                    <p>Resolved, That if Mr. Beecher pushes his bill of woman's right of suffrage
                        through Congress, that we unitedly [unclear] purchase his new, and
                        celebrated Pamphlets, on Political Instructions for Females.</p>
                    <p>Resolved, That we cheerfully give his price one cent apiece, for his
                        "Political Instructions."</p>
                    <p>Resolved, That a striking characteristic of our nature is obstinacy.</p>
                    <p>Resolved, That we do not vote for candidates whom male friends appoint for
                        office.</p>
                    <p>Resolved, That we nominate only the rich men.</p>
                    <p>Resolved, That we shall have no regard for intelligence, or capability.</p>
                    <p>Resolved, To bury in the graves of our ancestors all delicacy of feeling, and
                        love of horse empire.</p>
                    <p>Resolved, To fight the men, and buy their votes with brandy on election days.</p>
                    <p>Resolved, That we attend to national affairs, leave the gentlemen at home to
                        wash, and iron their linen, cook their meals, and take charge of the
                        children.</p>
                    <p>Resolved, If our esteemed advocate sill continues to plead for our right of
                        suffrage, that we will forsake our homes, husbands, and children for the
                        prosperity and harmony of our country.</p>
                    <p>Resolved, That we nominate the richest black man in the State for our next
                        President.</p>
                    <p>Resolved, That the photograph of Rev. Henry Ward Beecher be sent to Africa.</p>
                    <p>Resolved, That after his decease an Anatomist prepare his body for Barnum's
                        Museum.</p>
                    <p>Resolved, That these resolutions be published in all the papers in the United
                        States, and copies be sent to the family of our revered friend.</p>
                    <p>Peggy, Chairman</p>
                    <p>Kit, Secretary</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Peggy, Kit</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>A series of mock resolutions from an imaginary committee, designed to
                    disparage the ideas of women's rights, especially suffrage.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Women "On the Rampage"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Stanton, Anthony and other "ardent advocates of women's
                    rights" have submitted a petition to Congress, claiming that "white women have
                    quite as much right to be invested with the suffrage as four millions of
                    blacks."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1866.01.09.02">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1866.01.09.03">
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seawright</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cupp</ln>
                        <fn>Fannie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Veitch</ln>
                        <fn>E. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Fannie Cupp and John Seawright were married on Dec. 28 by Rev. E. R.
                    Veitch.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Points</ln>
                        <fn>W. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Points</ln>
                        <fn>Adele</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nelson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Adele Points and W. J. Points were married last Wednesday by Rev. Nelson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1866.01.09.04">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
