<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1869/va.au.rv.1869.08.20">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>01/20/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1869-08-20">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="08">August</month>
            <day norm="">20</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1869.08.20.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1869.08.20.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The test oath question is that which agitates the public mind of Virginia
                        to-day.--Will General Canby exact it of the lately elected members of the
                        Legislature or not? That is the question. Some of our exchanges have
                        indulged in able arguments to show that Gen Canby would not exact it. But of
                        what avail if he determines to do so? He has required it of Commissioners of
                        Chancery and we conclude he will require it of Legislatures, unless higher
                        authority forbids it. Will this higher authority forbid it? We have
                        conflicting telegrams and correspondence from Washington, the one declaring
                        it will be required and the other denying it. As our readers are all
                        interested in this question, we publish elsewhere the opinion of President
                        Grant, as published by a heretofore unknown fellow, calling himself Tarbell,
                        who has been interviewing him. If this be a true representation of Grant's
                        views, he is as inconsistent as we supposed he would be when we read his
                        inaugural--a perfect puppet in the hands of those who hold the wires. He
                        will back up Canby on the test-oath question and thus over-ride the will of
                        the whole people of Virginia, as expressed by an immense majority in the
                        last election.</p>
                    <p> The best comment, perhaps, we have seen on the sentiments of a President, as
                        to political parties in a State, we give below from the <emph rend="italic"
                            >Alexandria Gazette</emph></p>
                    <p> "To what a lamentable condition is our country reduced, when the <emph
                            rend="italic">fiat</emph> of the President, as to <emph rend="italic"
                            >his</emph> choice of political parties in the States--and <emph
                            rend="italic">his</emph> decision--as to which section of a party is to
                        be considered the "proper" one--are regarded as all important for the
                        regulations of the opinions and votes of the people? Without shame, the
                        politicians now go to Washington to elicit the Presidential edict for the
                        regulation of party movement in the States or Provinces! Can there be a
                        lower degradation in the administration of government? Principles are
                        entirely disregarded! It is coming, to be the Imperial regime, under the
                        forms of Republicanism. It is now, what does the President think? Think so,
                        too. What does the President <emph rend="italic">propose?</emph> That
                        do!--Alas, for our country!" </p>
                    <p>Gen. Sherman, it is also reported, is in favor of exacting the test-oath of
                        our Legislators. The Commander in Chief of the Army is, by act of Congress,
                        given almost absolute power on this subject. If it really be true that he
                        favors this course, we should like to know what has become of his vaunted
                        Democracy, or what constitutes a Democrat in these degenerated times?</p>
                    <p>It is also reported that Attorney General Hoar has decided that the test-oath
                        must be required by general Canby. At any rate, it looks very much like our
                        Legislators elect, who can't take the test-oath, will have to give way to
                        their opponents, whom they generally defeated by large majorities.</p>
                    <p>In that case the only consolation we can offer is, that at the next election
                        the military and test-oaths will be out of the way, and the defeat the
                        Radicals will experience will convince them that Virginians can and will
                        rule Virginia.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article questions whether or not General Canby will demand the
                    test-oath of the recently elected Legislators. While evidence is conflicting,
                    many suggest that the test-oath will indeed be demanded. If this be the case,
                    newly elected Legislators will have to yield their seats to their opponents.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Petersburg Index facetiously suggests that Gen. Canby will soon "issue
                    an order requiring Notaries Public, Editors, Bar-keepers, Ministers who perform
                    the marriage service, Blacksmiths who shoe Government horses, and pedestrians
                    who pass by military headquarters in Richmond, to take the iron-clad oath."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Tribute of Respect</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Winfield</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph F.</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Points</ln>
                        <fn>A. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>Sandie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>S. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Forsyth</ln>
                        <fn>H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hageman</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A committee representing Staunton Lodge No. 45, I. O. O. F., issued a
                    tribute of respect upon the death of fellow-member Joseph F. Winfield, Jr.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1869.08.20.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Long Needed</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Workmen are busy making much-needed improvements to the pavement and
                    curbing on New Street.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turner</ln>
                        <fn>Job</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A new pavement is being laid from the residence of Job Turner to the Deaf,
                    Dumb, and Blind Institute. Though it is one of the most popular promenades in
                    town, it had been in such poor condition that it had become almost impassable
                    for ladies during bad weather.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that the drought continues. The corn crop is in bad
                    shape.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schultz</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. Schultz, the "popular chirpodist," leaves town today. He will stop in
                    Waynesboro for a few days where he will be at the Dettor House treating corns,
                    bunions, bad nails, and warts. He is known for "skillful and painless"
                    operations.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Sad Accident</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Winfield</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>George A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Joseph Winfield died while superintending the digging of a well for George
                    A. Smith of Staunton. He fell after a draft of foul air caused him to faint.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Finley</ln>
                        <fn>Sam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Witts</ln>
                        <fn>Walker</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sam Finley and Walker Witts, two black men, died while digging a well near
                    Greenville for J. Milton Brooks. Foul air was the cause.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>Walter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Walter Davis died near Barterbrook, Augusta County, on August 4th. He was
                    77 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1869.08.20.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
