<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1869/va.au.rv.1869.05.07">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>10/12/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1869-05-07">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day norm="">7</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1869.05.07.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1869.05.07.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Conservative Convention met in Richmond on the 28th ult, the proceedings
                        of which, in substance, will be found in another column.</p>
                    <p>It was composed of gentlemen, who in 1867 were earnest advocates of the then
                        policy of the Conservatives, who had since gone off after the nine, or in
                        advocacy of the policy of those who nominated Walker, Lewis &amp; Co,
                        and a few who remained true to the declared principles of the party. As a
                        consequence, the majority report of the Committee was adopted, which
                        virtually yields the field to the Republicans.</p>
                    <p>It accepted the resignations of the Conservative Candidates, without
                        nominating a new ticket, and renounced the principles of 1867, in the fear
                        of some dire Radical calamity they know not what. It advises voting against
                        such clauses of the Constitution as many be presented separately without
                        knowing what clauses will be submitted to a separate vote, and not a word of
                        advice does it give as to voting for or against the remainder of the
                        Constitution. Had they given any further advice it would evidently have been
                        to vote for the expurgated Constitution and for Walker.</p>
                    <p>It has disorganized the Conservative party, by withdrawing its candidates and
                        destroying its platform and now calls upon them to do wonderful execution as
                        guerrillas.</p>
                    <p>Under this action each man is forced to determine for himself what is best.
                        Whether to vote for or against the expurgated Constitution. Whether he will
                        vote for Walker or Wells, or neither.</p>
                    <p>As to ourselves we remain just where we were. We are opposed to the Underwood
                        Constitution, out and out. Each and every portion of it is
                        objectionable--oppressive. It is a bundle of abominations, and, as we have
                        all along advised, we again advise all to vote against each and every
                        portion of it. Vote the whole thing down. This done, it will matter little
                        whether Walker or Wells receives the greater number of votes.</p>
                    <p>We can not make a choice between the candidates in the field, and do not
                        advise any. They are both Republicans and opposed to us in principles. If
                        any can make a choice, we will not urge an objection. In each and every such
                        case it will be deemed a choice between evils forced upon them by the action
                        or rather in-action of the Conservative Convention.</p>
                    <p>Each man, by this in-action, is forced to be a captain unto himself and must
                        pursue the course he deems best. We trust that each may prove a Mosby and
                        rout the enemy at every point, that not a vestige of the Underwood
                        abomination may be palmed upon us.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Disgusted with the Conservative convention, which dissolved its ticket and
                    left conservatives to fend for themselves. Editor still urges voters to vote
                    down the constitution and take matters into their own hands.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1869.05.07.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carroll</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Price</ln>
                        <fn>George E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper reports that the hay scales have been repaired. The weigh-master,
                    John M. Carroll, can always be found at George E. Price's store.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>C. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. C. R. Harris will repeat his lecture delivered before the Harrisonburg
                    Literary Society entitled, "The Influence of the Fine Arts on the Moral
                    Sensibilities." It will be held on May 7th in the Methodist Church. Admission is
                    25 cents.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hefelfinger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Augusta and White Sulphur and Alum Springs will open on June 1st under
                    the direction of the expert proprietor, Mr. Hefelfinger. "These Springs are in
                    easy reach of the business portion of our community, to whom we commend them,
                    should their families need a respite from town life."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houser</ln>
                        <fn>S. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hess</ln>
                        <fn>Hattie G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hess</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dameron</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>S. F. Houser and Miss Hattie G. Hess, daughter of William Hess, were
                    married on April 29th at the residence of the bride's father near Midway by the
                    Rev. C. Dameron.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brooks</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fauber</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Engle</ln>
                        <fn>J. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James W. Brooks and Miss Sarah A. Fauber, both of Augusta, were married at
                    Churchville on April 29th by the Rev. J. J. Engle.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houser</ln>
                        <fn>David S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Golliday</ln>
                        <fn>Eliza Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donald</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whithers</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>David S. Houser of Augusta and Miss Eliza Jane Golliday of Nelson were
                    married in Buckingham County at the residence of Capt. John Donald on April 15th
                    by the Rev. Mr. Whithers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cleveland</ln>
                        <fn>George Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cleveland</ln>
                        <fn>O. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cleveland</ln>
                        <fn>S. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George Thomas Cleveland, son of O. E. and S. E. Cleveland, died on May 1st.
                    He was 2 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1869.05.07.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
