<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1869/va.au.rv.1869.11.05">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>01/24/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1869-11-05">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="11">November</month>
            <day norm="">5</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1869.11.05.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1869.11.05.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The present low price of the great staples of this section, wheat and flour,
                        has a depressing effect upon all classes. Farmers, who can, hold back for
                        better prices, and consequently but little money is returned here for our
                        productions, and hard times and scarcity of money is the cry. The Wheat crop
                        of the country the past season was a large one, and the demand seemingly not
                        so great as that of the past year, and hence the decline. In this case, it
                        is a problem for our farmers to solve, "whether to sell at present prices or
                        continue to hold for a rise." Farmers differ much on this question. Some
                        contend that altho' the prices are low, the use of ready money is far
                        preferable to holding for a rise, and <emph rend="italic">vice versa</emph>.
                        It depends very much, after all, on a man's circumstances as to which
                        opinion he entertains.</p>
                    <p>It is not to solve this question that we write, but for another purpose--to
                        urge upon all not to forget, in fulfilling the large demands upon them,
                        their small demands, which also claim their attention. The mechanic and
                        laboring man and others to whom small debts are due, need their dues to meet
                        their obligations. We, ourselves, saw an account of $15 paid a few days
                        since to a mechanic, which satisfied, in the same day, four editors, and
                        heard of a note of $100 being paid, which, in the space of an hour, paid
                        three claims of $100 each and made the debtors easy. This much to exemplify
                        that the payment of even small dues enables many others to pay small debts,
                        and makes them easy, and, in the aggregate, puts in circulation a large sum,
                        and thus, even in hard times, liquidates a large amount of indebtedness and
                        makes money comparatively easy.</p>
                    <p>Many debts were paid immediately after the war, with the small amount of
                        money then in circulation, and it is universally acknowledged that money was
                        easier then than since.</p>
                    <p>This much can call the attention of those having money in hand--and who are
                        indebted in even small amounts to the easy mode of dispelling "hard times."
                        Pay the small debts, at least, and money enough will be put in circulation
                        to pay the large debts--continue this system and<lb/> "Hard times will come
                        again no more."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that low staple prices have been having a negative effect
                    on the economy. The paper urges the importance of paying off small debts to help
                    alleviate the "hard times."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1869.11.05.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stanley</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scherer</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>George M.</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn>H. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Circuit Court is in session. The most important case to be tried is
                    that of John M. Stanley for the murder of Jacob Scherer. James Bumgardner, Jr.,
                    opened arguments on behalf of the commonwealth. George M. Cochran, Jr., and Col.
                    J. B. Baldwin will speak on behalf of the prisoner. Judge H. W. Sheffey will
                    conclude the commonwealth's case.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Runnels</ln>
                        <fn>William D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Terrell</ln>
                        <fn>Virginia A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Terrell</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William D. Runnels and Virginia A. Terrell, daughter of Robert Terrell of
                    Waynesboro, were married on October 2nd at the home of the bride's father by the
                    Rev. C. Beard.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCune</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ramsey</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Col. Samuel McCune and Miss Mary E. Ramsey, both of Augusta, were married
                    on October 28th at the Lutheran Parsonage near Waynesboro by the Rev. C. Beard.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allen</ln>
                        <fn>S. Brown</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamilton</ln>
                        <fn>Mary S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamilton</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fletcher</ln>
                        <fn>P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. S. Brown Allen and Miss Mary S. Hamilton, daughter of John Hamilton of
                    Augusta, were married on September 26th at the residence of the bride's father
                    by the Rev. P. Fletcher.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>George E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>English</ln>
                        <fn>Inez Josephine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>English</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Haynes</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. George E. Eyster and Miss Inez Josephine English, daughter of the Rev.
                    John English, were married in Staunton on November 2nd at the residence of the
                    bride's father by the Rev. Dr. Haynes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1869.11.05.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
