<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1869/va.au.rv.1869.04.16">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>10/11/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1869-04-16">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day norm="">16</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1869.04.16.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1869.04.16.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>From the bill published elsewhere it will be seen that an early election in
                        Virginia is probable.</p>
                    <p>The bill provides that the President may order an election, at such a time as
                        he may deem best, on the ratification or rejection of the Underwood
                        Constitution and may submit to a separate vote such provisions as he may
                        deem best. It also provides that the constitution, and separate clauses,
                        shall be submitted to the registered voters of the State, registered at the
                        time of said submission and empowers the commanding General to re-open the
                        registered lists to be revised, enlarged and corrected, prior to such
                        election, according to law.</p>
                    <p>What clauses President Grant may deem best to submit to a separate vote is
                        yet unknown and it were useless at present to discuss the merits, or rather
                        demerits, of these clauses, or the result of the adoption of the remainder
                        on the future welfare and prosperity of the State and its citizens. There is
                        one point, however, which can be and should be mentioned at this time. There
                        is but little doubt that the disqualification provisions will be submitted
                        to a separate vote. No man, be he white or black, can plead inability to
                        vote against such clauses because of a desire to vote for the adoption of
                        the constitution. Then, any one, for purposes of self aggrandizement, or
                        fiendishness, who votes for disqualification, writes himself down as an
                        enemy to the mass our of our people. He can not, having thrown the first
                        stone, expect to be tolerated by proper thinking people and he will not be.
                        Such individuals had as well calculate upon emigrating, for they can expect
                        no support or employment form those they have attempted to stab in a vital
                        part. We have no idea that such individuals would be driven away or be in
                        jeopardy of their lives if they remained, but, if in business would be
                        forced <emph rend="italic">by sheer necessity</emph>, to shut up shop, or if
                        employed could only expect to find their places supplied by those less
                        inimical to employers, and would fail to find employment from others. This
                        is but natural and to be expected and we therefore warn all inclined that
                        way of the dangers of that course.</p>
                    <p>Tacked on to this bill is a proviso for the ratification of the fifteenth
                        amendment, as a necessary precedent to restoration. There is great fear
                        among Radicals that this amendment will fail to be ratified and hence the
                        proviso coercing its ratification by Virginia, Texas and Mississippi. If
                        enough States ratify it, not counting Virginia, Texas and Mississippi,
                        Congress will take its time about admitting these, no matter what we do, but
                        if the ratification by these States is needed to engraft the 15th amendment
                        on the Constitution then they will admit them. We know not what others may
                        think or desire but for ourselves, we never like to play the part of a
                        cat's-paw to pull hot chestnuts out of the fire for any one, and in this
                        instance we would leave them to pull them out as best they may. We have no
                        very strong predilections for restoration, on the terms proposed from time
                        to time, and with this last proviso we would have none of it. We would
                        prefer a military governor for all time to come, rather than take a hand in
                        sowing the seed of an irrevocable mongrelism in this country. We are not of
                        those who belive that the mogrelism forced on the South now is irrevocable
                        and hence, in regard to restoration, with the ratification of the 15th
                        amendment as an act precedent, we would advise all, in the classic language
                        of Beast Butler, "to let it slide."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Gives a negative opinion of the conditions Virginia must meet in order to
                    end reconstruction in the state. Especially dislikes the disqualifications of
                    classes of voters and the requirement to pass the 15th amendment. Calls on
                    Virginians to never submit to these conditions even if they must endure military
                    rule forever after.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The clause in the new reconstruction act, which empowers the military
                        commandant of District No. 1, to open the lists of registration previous to
                        the election on the ratification or rejection of the proposed Constitution,
                        is a most important one. Many of our people failed to register heretofore,
                        from disgust at the course pursued towards the Southern people, from
                        disinclination to engage in political affairs in any shape, or by home
                        interests and duties preventing them from attending at the proper times and
                        places. This must not be the case when the lists are again re-opened. They
                        must forget that home has claims, when the best interests of the State, the
                        prosperity and happiness of the people and the welfare of posterity calls so
                        loudly upon every man to perform his whole duty. There must be no longer a
                        disinclination to register and vote. A crisis, such as Virginia has never
                        witnessed before, is near at hand, in which it is imperatively demanded that
                        all of her sons shall rally to her support. Dereliction of duty may have
                        been overlooked in the past, but it can not be in the present.</p>
                    <p>Many who were denied the privilege of registering when the lists were first
                        opened in this State were afterwards permitted to register. Some availed
                        themselves of it others did not. These must come forward and register when
                        the lists are again opened, and not only these, but all who were denied the
                        privilege must again make the effort to register.</p>
                    <p>The duty of each and every one is plain. Let them fail not to perform it.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes how many people have failed to register to vote, which could be
                    disastrous in upcoming elections on the proposed constitution. Declares it the
                    duty of all Virginians to register and vote for the best interests of the state.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Conservative State Committee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>At a meeting of the State Executive Committee of the Conservative Party of
                        Virginia, consisting of the Resident Committee and Consulting Members, held
                        in the city of Richmond on the 15th day of December, 1868, the following
                        resolution was adopted:</p>
                    <p>"Resolved, That the chairman of this committee be instructed, as soon as the
                        day is fixed for the election in Virginia, to issue a call immediately,
                        inviting the consulting members of the committee and the county and city
                        superintendents to assemble in Richmond for the purpose of perfecting the
                        organization of the Conservative Party and adopting such measures as the
                        public exigencies may seem to require."</p>
                    <p>And at a meeting of the Resident Members of the State Executive Committee
                        held this 10th day of April, 1869, the following preamble and resolution was
                        adopted:</p>
                    <p>Whereas, by act of Congress, it has been referred to the President of the
                        United States to fix the time for an election in Virginia, with power to
                        submit to a vote of the people separately, such parts of the constitution as
                        he may deem expedient:</p>
                    <p>Resolved, That in compliance with the object of the above resolution of the
                        15th of December, 1868, the meeting contemplated by the said resolution, be
                        fixed for Wednesday, the 28th day of April, 1869, at 12 o'clock M., at the
                        Exchange Hotel, in the city of Richmond, at which time and place, punctual
                        attendance is requested.</p>
                    <p>R.T. Daniel, Chairman.</p>
                    <p>RICHMOND, April 10th, 1869.</p>
                    <p>The above call speaks for itself. It has been promptly issued on the passage
                        of the bill, by Congress, authorizing an election in this State. The
                        attendance at the meeting on Saturday last which issued this call was large,
                        exhibiting the importance they attached to prompt action in this matter. It
                        is a matter of the greatest importance to future interests of the State that
                        there shall be a full attendance of Consulting Members and of County and
                        City Superintendents at the meeting in Richmond on the 28th inst.</p>
                    <p>Without this, the Conservative party can not be properly organized and will
                        go into action in a semi-demoralized condition. With a full attendance and
                        wise action on the part of the proposed meeting, the organization of the
                        Conservatives will be perfected and their vote cast as a unit, which will
                        tell, no matter what be the opposition.</p>
                    <p>Let this meeting be borne in mind and all who can attend, and above all, let
                        their action be well-considered and wise. The future welfare of Virginia
                        hangs upon and all will await, with anxiety, the action of this body.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces the call of the Conservative party for a meeting to unite all
                    conservatives in anticipation of the vote on restoration as set by Congress.
                    Praises the Conservative party's efforts and urges all Virginians to heed the
                    call.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1869.04.16.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allen</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sears</ln>
                        <fn>Edward</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ackerman</ln>
                        <fn>A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Allen, Edward Sears, and A. J. Ackerman have been appointed
                    Aldermen for the town of Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houff</ln>
                        <fn>Erasmus L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stover</ln>
                        <fn>John G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Erasmus L. Houff replaces John G. Stover as Commissioner of the Revenue for
                    the 2nd district of Augusta.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Staunton Council No. 47, Friends of Temperance, will hold a procession
                    and public speaking on May 1st. The Institution Band will perform.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper anticipates the "novelty" of a velocipede race at the next county
                    fair.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper touts the health benefits of cleaning Staunton's cellars,
                    streets, and yards.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ide</ln>
                        <fn>E. Louis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ide</ln>
                        <fn>August</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Staunton Musical Association will give the first concert of the season
                    tonight at the Deaf, Dumb, and Blind Institution. Dr. J. L. Brown is directing
                    the vocal department, Prof. E. Louis Ide is directing the orchestra, and Prof.
                    August Ide will play a piano solo.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dudley</ln>
                        <fn>Robert H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parent</ln>
                        <fn>J. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A man named Robert H. Dudley was arrested by Chief of Police J. F. Parent
                    on charges of stealing a mule from Judge Page of Hanover.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spitler</ln>
                        <fn>Jared W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eakle</ln>
                        <fn>Sallie F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Engle</ln>
                        <fn>J. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jared W. Spitler and Miss Sallie F. Eakle, both of Augusta, were married at
                    Mt. Sidney at the residence of the bride's parents on March 25th by the Rev. J.
                    J. Engle.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roberts</ln>
                        <fn>Robert L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shreckhise</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shreckhise</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pinkerton</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Robert L. Roberts of West Virginia and Miss Margaret E. Shreckhise,
                    daughter of Jacob Shreckhise, were married at the house of the bride's father on
                    April 6th by the Rev. John Pinkerton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crockwell</ln>
                        <fn>Katie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crockwell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crockwell</ln>
                        <fn>J. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Katie Crockwell, daughter of Dr. and Mrs. J. R. Crockwell, died in Staunton
                    on April 12th. She was 14 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craun</ln>
                        <fn>Minnie O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craun</ln>
                        <fn>George A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craun</ln>
                        <fn>Amanda A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Minnie O. Craun, infant daughter of George A. and Amanda E. Craun, died
                    near Centerville, Augusta County, on March 27th. She was 3 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Props</ln>
                        <fn>J. William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. William Props died near Moscow, Va, on April 5th of chronic rheumatism.
                    He was 29 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1869.04.16.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
