<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1869/va.au.rv.1869.05.28">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>10/13/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1869-05-28">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day norm="">28</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1869.05.28.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1869.05.28.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>If there is one duty more imperative than another, at this time, it is that
                        of Registration.</p>
                    <p>In a short time the revision and correction of Registration lists in this
                        State will take place. Many failed to register heretofore, others have
                        changed their localities, some are voters now who were not before, and all
                        the old voting precincts are re-established. It is therefore absolutely
                        necessary for each and every man to see that he is properly registered at
                        his voting precinct, in order that his right as a voter can not be
                        questioned.</p>
                    <p>It is vitally important to the interests of the State that every voter should
                        be registered properly. Those who failed to register before from
                            <sic>lurkewarmness</sic> or other causes must not longer fail to
                        register.</p>
                    <p>The issue is one of life or death to the State and their votes may turn the
                        scale.--A constitution is to be presented to the people of the State, which,
                        if adopted, is likely to impoverish her people by the immensely increased
                        burden of taxation. There can, therefore, be no reasonable excuse given by
                        any for further lukewarmness. If that constitution be adopted and the votes
                        of those who fail to register would have turned the scale the responsibility
                        will rest upon them. We are satisfied that none would like to bear the
                        onerous responsibility of the adoption of a proscriptive Constitution and
                        one which will sap the prosperity, if it does not impoverish every
                        individual in the State. As an evidence that we do not exaggerate the case,
                        we quote the following from the Richmond <emph rend="italic">Examiner</emph>
                        &amp; <emph rend="italic">Enquirer</emph>:</p>
                    <p>"We beg leave to invite the attention of the voters of the Commonwealth to
                        the consideration of the enormous field for taxation which the Underwood
                        constitution opens up. The State poll tax as fixed by the constitution
                        cannot exceed one dollar on every male citizen, twenty-one years of age; and
                        the county poll tax cannot exceed fifty cents--In 1867, by an examination of
                        the returns in the Auditor's office, it appeared that only about one negro
                        in four had paid his poll tax, and the entire poll tax, State and county,
                        that will be paid by the negroes has been estimated at about $40,000. All
                        the rest of the taxes will come out of the property of the State, and out of
                        the whites. It will be at least four times what it was under our old State
                        government. They have been estimated as high as $9,000,000. The free schools
                        to be established will alone require double the taxes which we formerly
                        paid. Then the swarm of county officers are to be paid by taxes wrung from
                        the whites--magistrates, supervisors, assessors, collectors constables,
                        township clerks, school trustees, road commissioners &amp;c.
                        &amp;c."</p>
                    <p>There is no escape from this if the "expurgated constitution" with the County
                        organization and Free School clauses contained in it be adopted. It will
                        fall heavily on the owner of property and the burden will not be a light one
                        on the poor man who rents. He must pay the rent, increased greatly by the
                        increase of taxation, consequent upon the adoption of the "expurgated
                        Constitution." This matter looks you in the face and is sufficient to
                            <sic>appal</sic>. It calls upon each and every one to do his duty and
                        his whole duty--<emph rend="italic">to register and vote down the Underwood
                            Constitution</emph>. Better a military ruler for all time than the
                        expurgated Constitution, with Wells, or Walker, or Withers, or any one else
                        for Governor. The cry of making the best of the situation, in the hope of
                        modifying objectionable features hereafter is most fallacious. We will not
                        be permitted to do so having adopted it.--The Lynchburg <emph rend="italic"
                            >News</emph> thus pointedly shows up this fallacy:</p>
                    <p>"No one who reflects a moment on the avowed causes which prevented the
                        submission of the county organization to a separate vote can agree with the
                        views enunciated in our city by Col Walker on the occasion of his recent
                        address. It will be remembered that he then advised the acceptance of the
                        residue of the constitution on the ground that the Legislature having the
                        power to propose amendments to the constitution could originate such a
                        movement, and postponing all legislation looking to the consummation of the
                        county organization and school system until the result of such proposed
                        amendment could be ascertained, could thus avert the threatened evil. To our
                        vision this only looks like an effort to cheat the Radical party out of the
                        substantial rewards of their scheming, and we need not say how utterly
                        futile and vain are hopes founded on such a basis. Why the very cause
                        assigned for retaining this feature of the constitution is the fear lest the
                        educational interest of the negro might be endangered if their plan embodied
                        in the constitution should be defeated. How, then, can it be expected that
                        Congress will ever <emph rend="italic">permit</emph> reconstruction to be
                        accomplished unaccompanied by the <emph rend="italic">fullest
                        guarantees</emph> of negro equality and free mixed schools. Should the
                        Conservatives succeed in obtaining control of the Legislature, and attempt
                        to play any such game as was indicated by Col. Walker in his speech at
                        Martin's warehouse, who so blind as not to see at once that Congress would
                        refuse its consent to the admission of Virginia until these interests should
                        have received <emph rend="italic">ample protection</emph>."</p>
                    <p>This is pretty bad picture thus far but we are compelled to add to it,
                        however unpleasant it be. The school question is not to be ignored. It
                        particularly concerns every poor man in the State and we request one and all
                        to consider the following from the <emph rend="italic">Examiner &amp;
                            Enquirer</emph> on this subject:</p>
                    <p>By the Bayne-Underwood constitution, the question whether the public free
                        schools shall or shall not be mixed schools, where white and black children
                        are to be taught under the same roof, and in the same room, is remitted to
                        the Legislature. The convention rejected the proposition to provide separate
                        schools. The subject will come up in the Legislature. If the negroes control
                        that body, (and who doubts they will if the expurgated Constitution be
                        adopted? <emph rend="italic">Ed Vin</emph>) we may have the Louisiana law
                        which requires the children, without regard to color, to attend the same
                        schools. But perhaps you flatter yourself that you can keep your children at
                        home, or send them to some private school. You may if you are rich and are
                        willing to pay for two sets of schools.--But what will you do if you are a
                        poor man? The constitution provides for forcing the poor man's children, in
                        the contingency contemplated, to attend the public schools--The 4th section
                        of the xviiith article of the constitution is as follows. The General
                        Assembly shall have power, after a full introduction, of a public free
                        school system, to make such laws <emph rend="italic">as shall not permit
                            parents and guardians to allow their children to grow up in ignorance
                            and vagrancy</emph>.</p>
                    <p>Thus have we endeavored to lay before you, as concisely as we can, some of
                        the serious objections to the "expurgated Constitution." Consider the
                        subject well, one and all, and we are satisfied, you will not only register
                        but vote to save your people and State from the horrors of reconstruction
                        under the expurgated but not purified Constitution.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Issues another plea for Virginians to register to vote so they can defeat
                    the Underwood constitution. Also emphasizes the sections dealing with taxation
                    and mixed public schooling, which the editor particularly abhors.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In the election to be held on the 6th of July a very important item is the
                        selecting of good men as members of the Legislature. Should the expurgated
                        Constitution be adopted an important duty will devolve on the Legislature.
                        With it will remain the last hope of a once Free People.</p>
                    <p>The XVth Amendment will come before that body for ratification, and should be
                        defeated. Many desire its ratification that they may enjoy the sweet morsel
                        of revenge. Negro suffrage was forced upon us in our adversity by the
                        exultant North and now they desire to see it forced on the North and by the
                        oppressed South. There is some satisfaction in the thought only. It would
                        fasten it irrevocably on the whole Country.--The North cares little but for
                        the principle, having comparatively few negroes, but the South would be
                        affected by it for all time.</p>
                    <p>We have never regarded colored suffrage, as at present forced upon us, as a
                        fixture.--we look for a time and not very distant, when the rights of the
                        States will be religiously defended as the mainstay of Republican
                        Institutions (In fact the Republic must cease if this be a great while
                        denied.) In that event the old order of things will return, if we do not fix
                        universal suffrage on ourselves. Let us then vote for such Legislators only
                        as declare their determination to labor and vote against the ratification of
                        the XVth Amendment. If that be defeated in the Legislature, we remain just
                        where we are and the odious county organization will fail just there. This
                        is a second chance to defeat the "expurgated Constitution" which should be
                        borne in mind. Put no man in the Legislature who favors the ratification of
                        the XVth Amendment.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Calls on all voters to only vote for legislators who will vote against the
                    15th Amendment. Sees it as a huge threat to the future of the South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>General Canby has issued an order for correction of the Registration lists.
                    The Boards of Registration will meet for ten days beginning June 14th to revise
                    and add to the registration lists. All must see to it that they are properly
                    registered.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1869.05.28.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Col. Gilbert C. Walker will address the people of Staunton on June 28th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Bishop McGill of the Catholic Church will be in Staunton next Saturday to
                    administer the sacrament of confirmation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huffman</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George Huffman has been appointed Magistrate of the 8th District of
                    Augusta.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wells</ln>
                        <fn>H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gov.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chandler</ln>
                        <fn>L. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Governor H. H. Wells and L. H. Chandler will address the people of Staunton
                    on June 11th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Bishop Whittle preached in Staunton on Wednesday and received 35 applicants
                    into the holy communion of the church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Ladies of the Presbyterian Church will hold their annual fair and
                    dinner in the Town Hall on June 1st.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maupin</ln>
                        <fn>A. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A. T. Maupin has been appointed agent of the Republican Executive
                    Committee. He will solicit funds in the North and canvass Virginia on behalf of
                    the Wells party.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Col. J. B. Baldwin addressed the people of Augusta in the Court House on
                    Monday. He advised them to vote for the expurgated constitution and Gilbert C.
                    Walker for governor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Landes</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A daughter of Daniel Landes drowned last Friday in the race of Dice's Saw
                    Mill near Burke's mill. She had been playing on a board across the race and fell
                    from it.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Gen. Canby has re-established all the old voting precincts in Augusta
                    county and appointed boards of registration for each. "This will be a great
                    convenience to all parties in the revision of registration lists and in casting
                    their ballots at future elections. It will add greatly in bringing out a full
                    vote at elections."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoover</ln>
                        <fn>H. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A Council of the Friends of Temperance was organized at Churchville, H. L.
                    Hoover president. It will be called Churchville Council No. 60.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Confederate Memorial Ceremonies will be held on June 5th. Participants will
                    gather at the Cemetery Gate at 8:00am and a procession will depart from their to
                    decorate the graves of the soldiers. "Appropriate and interesting ceremonies
                    will take place and all who revere our fallen heroes--our loved and lost, should
                    be present and engage in scattering tributes of affection and respect on their
                    last resting places."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Staunton Council No. 47, Friends of Temperance, and Charity Council No. 6
                    held a procession on Saturday. They adjourned to the Methodist Church to hear
                    the State Lecturer, Rev. James Young. He also delivered an address at the Town
                    Hall and a Temperance Sermon. 108 people signed a pledge.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Proceedings of the County Court</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Fifteen Magistrates were in attendance and an election for Presiding Justice
                        was held, resulting in the election of Junius F. Maupin.</p>
                    <p>Jno. B. Fauver, Jno. Siler and Jas. F. Davis qualified as Overseers of the
                        Poor.</p>
                    <p>David Myers, Geo. Huffman and William Gibson qualified as Justices of the
                        Peace.</p>
                    <p>The resignation of David Alexander as a Justice was accepted.</p>
                    <p>Alex. S. Turk and David A. Cooke qualified as Notaries Public.</p>
                    <p>Levi Plecker, Jno. R. Syrele, Isaac Coffman, Jno. Crum and Elijah Coiner were
                        appointed Surveyors of Roads.</p>
                    <p>License was granted Thos Jefferson, colored, to keep an Ordinary in the town
                        of Waynesboro.</p>
                    <p>License was granted Jno. Detter of Waynesboro', to sell liquors not to be
                        drank at the place of sale.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maupin</ln>
                        <fn>Junius F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fauver</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Siler</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>James F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huffman</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gibson</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Alexander</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turk</ln>
                        <fn>Alex S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cooke</ln>
                        <fn>David A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Plecker</ln>
                        <fn>Levi</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Syrele</ln>
                        <fn>John R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coffman</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crum</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coiner</ln>
                        <fn>Elijah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jefferson</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dettor</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Covers business done at the County Court, mainly appointments of
                    Magistrates, notary publics, and licenses issued.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spitzer</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jackson</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>William J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John A. Spitzer and Miss Mary Jackson, both of Augusta, were married on May
                    13th by the Rev. William J. Miller.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Driver</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCall</ln>
                        <fn>Sallie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thomas</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jacob Driver and Miss Sallie McCall, both of Augusta, were married on May
                    11th by the Rev. Jacob Thomas.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doom</ln>
                        <fn>Kenton H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brady</ln>
                        <fn>Arminta</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kramer</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Kenton H. Doom and Miss Arminta Brady, both of Augusta, were married on May
                    18th by the Rev. George Kramer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hughart</ln>
                        <fn>James P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCutchen</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCutchen</ln>
                        <fn>Chapman</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilmore</ln>
                        <fn>Harvey</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James P. Hughart of Bath and Miss Mary E. McCutchen, daughter of Chapman
                    McCutchen of Augusta, were married on May 18th by the Rev. Harvey Gilmore.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Haines</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John H. Haines, formerly of West Virginia, died suddenly in Waynesboro of
                    disease of the heart. He was 60 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Supple</ln>
                        <fn>Susan J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Supple</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Supple</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Susan J. Supple, daughter of Robert and Mary Supple, died in Greenville on
                    May 18th of heart disease. She was 22 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Michie</ln>
                        <fn>Henry Bedinger</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Michie</ln>
                        <fn>Henry B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Michie</ln>
                        <fn>Virginia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Henry Bedinger Michie, infant son of Henry B. and Mrs. Virginia Michie,
                    died in Staunton on May 24th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1869.05.28.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
