<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1869/va.au.rv.1869.03.12">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>10/10/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1869-03-12">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day norm="">12</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1869.03.12.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1869.03.12.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We lay before our readers in this issue, the inaugural address of President
                        Grant. As all anticipated, it is brief and has also but few salient points.
                        Its silence must speak louder than its words or we can draw but little
                        comfort therefrom for our oppressed South.</p>
                    <p>From the announcement, that he had taken the oath of office without mental
                        reservation and would commence the duties incumbent upon him as President
                        untrammeled, as the office has come to him unsought, we expected like bold
                        and independent expressions to characterize the address throughout and a
                        bold line of policy, so much needed now to convert the political chaos of
                        the present into light, and bring method out of confusion. In this we were
                        mistaken. Although he threatens with a veto, yet he becomes suppliant in the
                        next sentence, and expresses his willingness to execute all laws whether he
                        approves them or not, constitutional or unconstitutional, his oath to the
                        contrary notwithstanding. His plan for getting rid of obnoxious laws is
                        faulty in the extreme. The obnoxious laws of the last administration have
                        been and of the present, in all probability, will be passed simply because
                        they are onerous upon a section of the country which has, in reality, no
                        voice in their enactment and which the dominant section desires to keep in
                        its present powerless condition. How his plan will relieve from such
                        obnoxious laws Gen. Grant may have an idea, but we venture the assertion
                        that no one else has.</p>
                    <p>As to the public debt he seems to have no very clear conviction. That it must
                        be paid he asserts, but how and when he fails to give an opinion. He
                        declares for economy in expenditures, the faithful collection of the revenue
                        and a strict accountability for every dollar collected. We hazard the
                        assertion that the carrying out of this proposition will be the biggest job
                        he or any other man, or set of men ever undertook. He has thousands of wily
                            <sic>partizans</sic>, and their aiders and abetters in Congress, to
                        contend with single handed. If he opens a fight on this line it will consume
                        his entire administration and with no better result than the contest he once
                        waged on a certain line which took all summer: In the fall he was almost as
                        near the goal as he was in the early spring. We shall however wish him
                        better luck in this than in his famous summer campaign.</p>
                    <p>His counsel, to consider the questions to arise without prejudice, hate or
                        sectional pride, sounds oddly enough, and especially when taken in
                        connection with his recommendation of the ratification of the fifteenth
                        amendment, which is but the offspring of prejudice and sectional hate. As a
                        means of securing "the greatest good to the greatest number," we think the
                        recommendation concerning the XV Amendment, the only recommendation he
                        makes, is sadly deficient.</p>
                    <p>As a whole the inaugural must be unsatisfactory to thinking men of all
                        parties.--We confess that we arise from its perusal with little hope of the
                        restoration of peace and prosperity to the country from the administration
                        of President Grant, and reluctantly inclined to the opinion that Congress
                        will continue to be President for the next four years.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Expresses a low opinion of Grant's inaugural address, and feels there is no
                    hope for the South in any of its passages. Especially dislikes Grant's plans on
                    the public debt and his endorsement of the 15th amendment. Believes Grant will
                    just be the pawn of a Radical Congress.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper denounces bills designed to strengthen the public credit. The
                    editors assert that greenbacks are now the strongest currency and should not be
                    "tinkered" with. The best way to improve public credit is to re-admit the
                    southern states to the Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1869.03.12.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Rev. C. Beard has held a meeting in his Salem congregation, Augusta
                    County. It resulted in 55 professions of religion. Participants ranged in age
                    from 10 to 75.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On the sight of the 4th inst, about twenty of our colored Republicans,
                        including the big and the little, essayed to celebrate the inaugural of
                        Grant. They burned several tar-barrels in the streets and shot off half a
                        dozen rockets and yelled. It failed to be the big thing those who subscribed
                        expected. In fact, as a colored looker-on said, "it was a fizzle."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Ridicules the attempts of blacks to celebrate Grant's inaugural by burning
                    tar barrels.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Virginia Annual Conference of the M. E. Church has been meeting in
                    Richmond. Charles King has been appointed for Augusta.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fox</ln>
                        <fn>George H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>Mary M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shreckhise</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George H. Fox and Miss Mary M. Hanger, both of Augusta, were married on
                    February 25th by the Rev. J. M. Shreckhise.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wynn</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heizer</ln>
                        <fn>Susan M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>George B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Charles Wynn and Miss Susan M. Heizer were married on March 1st by the Rev.
                    George B. Taylor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beach</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Day</ln>
                        <fn>Emma J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>George B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William H. Beach and Miss Emma J. Day were married on March 4th by the Rev.
                    George B. Taylor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deter</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hill</ln>
                        <fn>Julia A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pinkerton</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John B. Deter and Miss Julia A. Hill were married near Mossy Creek Iron
                    Works on February 25th by the Rev. John Pinkerton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Graham</ln>
                        <fn>J. W. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>Lizzie J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pearson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. W. T. Graham of Greenville, Augusta County, and Miss Lizzie J. Thompson
                    of Missouri were married in Missouri on March 4th by the Rev. Mr. Pearson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bush</ln>
                        <fn>Rachel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bush</ln>
                        <fn>James S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Rachel Bush, wife of James S. Bush, died on March 5th at the residence
                    of her husband near Waynesboro. She was 78 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fry</ln>
                        <fn>Peamelia F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Peamelia F. Fry died at the residence of her mother in Waynesboro on
                    March 2nd after a lingering illness. She was 30 years old. A mournful poem
                    accompanies the announcement.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1869.03.12.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
