<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1869/va.au.rv.1869.07.16">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>01/19/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1869-07-16">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day norm="">16</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1869.07.16.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1870.07.16.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The course of the colored men in the late election may be regarded with a
                        prejudiced eye by some. To avert any injustices to any we desire to call the
                        attention of our readers to the following facts:</p>
                    <p> The colored and white voters in this section, as a whole, voted side by side
                            <emph rend="italic">for</emph> the Constitution. </p>
                    <p> They voted side by side <emph rend="italic">against</emph> the
                        Disfranchising and Disability Clauses. </p>
                    <p>These were the main issues of the contest and colored and white stood
                        together, as one man, on them.</p>
                    <p> The only point of difference was in a choice for the gubernatorial ticket.
                        That the colored man should vote for Wells, appealed to, by those they have
                        been taught to believe, to vote for him as the only means of their political
                        salvation, and warned by their <emph rend="italic">professed</emph> friends
                        that Walker's election would ensure their reversion to slavery--ignorant as
                        the majority of them are, creates no surprise in our mind. With a colored
                        man on the ticket it is even less surprising to any. </p>
                    <p> A number of more enlightened colored men knowing that they could not be
                        damaged politically or <sic>pecuniarily,</sic> preferred and voted for
                        Walker and thus more nearly allied themselves with the native
                        whites.--Numbers, who voted for Wells, seeing that they were misled as to
                        the difference between Walker and Wells, and that their political fate was
                        not at all in the scale, would, if the election were to be gone over, vote
                        for Walker. </p>
                    <p>In view of the fact then that they, in the main, voted to relieve Virginia
                        White men of their Disfranchisement and Disabilities, and only differed with
                        the Whites in the choice of Governor, and that they, from the light thrown
                        on the subject by the result of the election, are less liable to be in
                        conflict with the Whites of Virginia hereafter than heretofore, we counsel a
                        great degree of leniency to them on account of their ignorance and bad
                        teaching. We believe that the vast majority of our people look at this
                        matter in the right light, but for fear a few may act from prejudice rather
                        than reason, we call their attention to the above facts.</p>
                    <p>The contest between the white and colored men of this State ended most
                        happily and peacefully for all parties in the late election. The colored men
                        understand it and are rapidly realizing that the white people of the South
                        are their best friends. They will hereafter stand with them on all important
                        issues, for their interest are our interests. --Then let us, as one man,
                        convince them by our acts that we are their best friends and that they have
                        been most egregiously misled by men who desired only to use them against us,
                        for the offices which they believe in their power to confer.</p>
                    <p>"Unfair election" say some malcontents. "Fraud, intimidation" &amp;c say
                        others. This is not at all singular. In every election there must be a
                        defeated party. There must be a scape-goat and hence the cries above noted.
                        Gen. Canby asserts that it was as fair an election as could be held in any
                        State. It stands to reason that he is correct. Among the vast majority of
                        the White and the Colored voters in the State there turns out not to be a
                        great difference. The Constitution is carried by an immense majority, while
                        the Disfranchising and Disability clauses are defeated by an equally large
                        majority. This must have been done by the White and Colored voters combined.
                        We know a number of White and Colored Wells men, who openly electioneered
                        against the clauses. It was their preference without fear or intimidation of
                        any. This we judge to have been the case every where in the State. With this
                        the case, as far as the Constitution and clauses are concerned, the cry of
                        intimidation and unfairness falls to the ground.</p>
                    <p>These charges are only then be alleged in reference to the votes for Walker
                        as against Wells. That intimidation would be used to secure votes for a man
                        as against another, when it was not used in regard to the Disfranchising and
                        Disability clauses, which were a thousand fold more important to the people
                        of Virginia than the choice between any man could be, is simply so absurd,
                        ridiculous and childish that sensible men can only entertain it in fits of
                        desperation or passion. Hence the cry has quieted if not died out. To carry
                        the cry into requiring a new election, would result in the defeat of any
                        extreme Radical Candidate by twice the majority that Walker has obtained.
                        Radicals of sense can see this and hence we argue that they will drop this
                        childish cry rather than suffer a more ignominious defeat.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article illustrates the supposed political allegiance between the
                    majority of black and white voters in the recent gubernatorial election. White
                    Virginias, claiming they are the "best friends" of blacks, suggest that if the
                    few blacks that voted the radical ticket had a chance, they would realize that
                    they had been misled and would change their votes. All radical "cries" of
                    intimidation and election fraud are flatly rejected.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Congressional Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Augusta delivered a 2,507 vote majority for Milnes in the congressional
                    election. Milnes defeated Harris with a 4,727 vote majority in the district as a
                    whole.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Intimidation</head>
                <origin>Dispatch</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article asserts that black voters in favor of Wells prevented black
                    voters in favor of Walker from voting. "This is no doubt much nearer the truth
                    than the statement that they were intimidated by their employers."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1869.07.16.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Circus Coming</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Old John Robinson's Big Show, Circus, and Menagerie is coming to Staunton.
                    Jimmy Robinson, "the greatest bare-back rider in the world," will perform. Miss
                    Cordelia, the famous female writer, will also be in the show. Clowns and a
                    menagerie will also be highlights.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCutchen</ln>
                        <fn>James R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>L. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilmore</ln>
                        <fn>Harvey</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James R. McCutchen and Miss L. E. Baylor, daughter of David Baylor, were
                    married on June 24th near Summerdean by the Rev. Harvey Gilmore.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>Eugene</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>W. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>M. V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Eugene Anderson, infant son of Col. W. D. and M. V. Anderson, died on July
                    8th. He was 23 days old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pritchard</ln>
                        <fn>Cora Temple</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pritchard</ln>
                        <fn>Mary A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pritchard</ln>
                        <fn>J. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Cora Temple Pritchard, infant daughter of J. T. and Mary A. Pritchard, died
                    in Staunton on Friday. She was 1 year old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kramer</ln>
                        <fn>Pearce</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kramer</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kramer</ln>
                        <fn>Jennie V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Pearce Kramer, infant son of Rev. George and Jennie V. Kramer, died in
                    Staunton on Friday. He was 9 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ide</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ide</ln>
                        <fn>E. Louis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. William Ide, father of Prof. E. Louis Ide of Staunton, died in
                    Richmond on Thursday. He was 60 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Showalter</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jacob Showalter died at his residence near Mt. Solon on July 2nd.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henkel</ln>
                        <fn>Charles Hanger</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henkel</ln>
                        <fn>Jewett</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henkel</ln>
                        <fn>Virginia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Charles Hanger Henkel, infant son of Jewett and Virginia Henkel, died near
                    Mt. Crawford on July 6th. He was 10 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1869.07.16.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
