<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1867/pa.fr.fr.1867.03.06">
    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>10/08</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1867-03-06">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day>06</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1867.03.06.01">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1867.03.06.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An appeal from the editors urging the legislature to approve a bill calling
                    for a constitutional convention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The XXXIXth Congress</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The 39th Congress belongs to history. Of all it has been the most important,
                        and will be most memorable. The 37th and 38th Congresses had to struggle to
                        save a Republic from open, armed, manly foes. Treason came with its banners
                        streaming, its bayonets bristling, and its deadly purpose was declared in
                        the hoarse thunders of its artillery. It drew a marked dividing line between
                        the people. All were either loyalists or traitors, and the common, patent
                        peril appealed to every consideration of patriotism and every instinct of
                        self-preservation to grapple with the enemies of law and government. The
                        path was clear; the duty plain; and how freely the appalling sacrifice was
                        given, let the ridged graves of our countless martyrs tell. The banner of
                        crime was stricken in hopeless disaster, and there came from the leaders of
                        desolation the promise of submission for peace. The nation had just
                        re-inaugurated its trusted Ruler to complete the great work of restoration
                        prepared by the sword. With him had been called to the second position in
                        the government, one who claimed to have most zeal among the zealous, most
                        fidelity among the faithful, and most devotion among the devoted for the
                        principles of unconditional loyal rule in the land just redeemed by loyal
                        blood. The assassin's arm, nerved by the teaching of treason, bereft the
                        Republic of its President just in the noon-tide of his triumph for Humanity
                        and Freedom, and Andrew Johnson became his successor, and thenceforth he has
                        been the friend only of his country's foes, and the enemy only of its
                        faithful friends.</p>
                    <p>With the colossal perfidy of Andrew Johnson the 39th Congress had to deal. He
                        stood not upon the order of his treachery, but made it course its way alike
                        in boisterous currents and in still but steady streams throughout the land
                        to poison the popular mind, and paralyze the people in the consummation of
                        their great work. Treason was invited to insolence; the conquered dictated
                        terms to the conqueror; and over the graves of our thousands of slain
                        heroes, the cause of their murderers was defended and their work clothed
                        with honor. Steadily, slowly, but surely the 39th Congress approached its
                        mighty task. It met no flaunting banners of crime; no armed battalions
                        arrayed against the government; no Lees, or Beauregards, or Johnsons, or
                        Forrests waved their plumes amidst the hail of death; no Andersonvilles, or
                        Belle Islands, or Salisburys, remained to shame mankind by their thousand
                        deaths refined for each defender of his flag; but in the very inner
                        sanctuary of power the spoiler sat enthroned, and around him there were
                        millions to greet his effort to deny a nation's deliverance--fairly won in
                        deeply crimsoned triumph--by falsehood and fraud. The foes of Freedom came
                        with gifts to their apostate leader, and the very altar of liberty, still
                        fragrant with the increase of incalculable sacrifices, was blotted by their
                        proffered devotion which was but a lie, and their proposed submission which
                        was a falsehood and fraud as well.</p>
                    <p>It was no common task for a Congress thus to rescue a distracted nation, and
                        no common men could have performed it. Many faltered, some staggered and a
                        few fell before the temptations of power and plunder; but the feeble were
                        reclaimed, the hesitating were admonished by a faithful people to duty, and
                        the fallen rose no more. For nearly two years there was one ceaseless,
                        desperate struggle between Right and Wrong--Power and Patriotism. Defiantly
                        the perfidious President entered the struggle, and when the bending lines of
                        Congress rallied in stern, unbroken column to resist the shock of the new
                        foes of Freedom, he bowed the Republic that had honored him in consuming
                        shame by his ribald harangues and insolent proclamation of his treachery.
                        But it rallied a mighty and noble people to the new perils which
                        overshadowed them, and they spoke as never men spake before, in behalf of
                        the full fruition of their triumph. There were dark days, and doubtful
                        struggles for a time; but it made names immortal and principles as sacred as
                        religion itself. The Freedman's Bureau bill and the Civil Rights bill were
                        made laws over the impotent veto of the President, and in the hour of
                        victory, the generous terms of reconstruction known as the constitutional
                        amendments, were proposed to the rebellious people with which to
                        rehabilitate themselves in the folds of a common Union. But treason was not
                        content with the struggle. It had gained much--it would have more. The
                        humble Freedman was left destitute of the great element of manhood, and
                        forthwith his practical re-enslavement became the work of traitors. Wherein
                        victorious loyalty had forgotten justice, discomfited treason supplied the
                        crowning boon. The same men who rejected rebel suffrage because it was not
                        universal, now must accept universal suffrage from the disenthralled slave,
                        and henceforth the leaders of the rebellion shall be strangers to
                        citizenship and aliens to our common nationality.</p>
                    <p>The reconstruction bill, (published in full in our last) was vetoed by the
                        President on Saturday, and on the same day passed over his veto by the
                        overwhelming vote of 38 to 10 in the Senate, and 135 to 48 in the House. On
                        the same day he returned a bill limiting the power of the President in
                        removals from office, and before either branch adjourned, the bill was
                        passed over the veto by nearly the same vote given for the reconstruction
                        bill. Notwithstanding Gen. Grant twice called upon the President to urge his
                        approval of the reconstruction bill, and leading Democratic statesmen like
                        Reverdy Johnson, Caleb Cushing, and Gov. Brown of Georgia, and such journals
                        as the New York <emph rend="italic">World</emph>, the Boston <emph
                            rend="italic">Post</emph>, the Chicago <emph rend="italic">Times</emph>,
                        the Richmond <emph rend="italic">Whig</emph>, the Buffalo <emph
                            rend="italic">Courier</emph> and many lesser lights of the Democratic
                        faith, demanded the acceptance of the bill by the President and the Southern
                        people, the President, unshaken in his devotion to treachery and wrong,
                        returned it with his veto only to see it enacted before the setting of the
                        sun.</p>
                    <p>Thus did the 39th Congress close and crown its labors, and whatever may have
                        been its shortcomings and errors, a rescued nation and a grateful people
                        will tell the proud story of its undaunted patriotism and its triumphs for
                        Mankind, while Freedom has votaries among the living!</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Labeling it the most "important" and "memorable" session ever, the editors
                    note the end of the passing of the 39th Congress. Although the body faced the
                    immense task of countering the "colossal perfidy of Andrew Johnson," they note,
                    it persevered, rescuing the nation from hands of treachery.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>THE defeat of the Tariff bill by the 39th Congress was a most serious
                        blunder, and must have been well nigh fatal to our industrial interests as
                        well as to our credit ultimately, but for the fact that the 40th Congress is
                        now in session and will certainly pass a Tariff bill before it adjourns. It
                        is not pretended that anything like a majority of Congress was opposed to
                        the Tariff, but it was delayed and badgered by the appeals of delegations
                        representing various interests, until the waste of precious time and the
                        multiplicity of amendments ended its overthrow. When it is considered that
                        many of our manufactured articles now pay in direct taxes more than the
                        Tariff on the same articles from abroad, the necessity for a Tariff must be
                        comprehended by all. We are actually, by our taxes, discriminating against
                        our home manufactures, and making them cost much more than the foreign
                        article, with duties added. We charitably infer that the Tariff was
                        purposely referred to the 40th Congress to mature and enact, and it is to be
                        hoped that its fate with the new body will not be doubtful. If we would
                        maintain our credit, we must employ a Tariff for the two-fold purposes of
                        securing revenue, and sustaining our manufactures which will contribute
                        vastly to the public treasury.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article characterizes the 39th Congress' failure to pass the Tariff
                    Bill as its "most serious blunder," and expresses the hope that the next
                    Congress will remedy the situation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The piece calls on the legislature to pass a Registry law to deal with the
                    "earnest and frequent" complaints of election fraud in the mining counties of
                    the state. "Any party that resists a fair registry of the voters does not desire
                    honest elections," it asserts.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In an opinion delivered by Judge Agnew, the Supreme Court of Pennsylvania
                    has ruled that the shares in the National Bank are subject to state taxation in
                    the hands of shareholders.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Legislative Reform</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">To the Editors of the Franklin Repository:</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>I regret to mark that in your last two issues you almost neglected to refer
                        to the plan you propose for a change in the number of our legislators. I
                        hope that in the future you will not cease to urge upon the people of the
                        State the importance and feasibility of reforming the legislature, by a
                        large increase of its proportions. There are so many plausible pretexts for
                        travelling on in the little narrow path our fathers trod before us, and so
                        much sophistry has been employed in past years, in regard to determining how
                        many members best conduce to the united wisdom and integrity of a
                        deliberative assembly, that unless men are pressed to think carefully on the
                        subject, they are liable to lazily conclude we had best be governed in
                        coming years as in those gone by. I believe some of the strongest
                        authorities which might be misconstrued into a vindication of the present
                        constitution of the legislature, are to be found in parts of the
                        contributions of Madison to the almost oracular <emph rend="italic"
                            >Federalist</emph>. If the conclusions of those productions are closely
                        scrutinized, they can only weigh in favor of an increase of numbers, as we
                        ask. That talented author had before him the difficult task of reconciling
                        the citizens of the different States to a constitution which limited the
                        House of Representatives of the whole country, for the space of three years,
                        to only sixty-five members, and we must remember that one of the reasons
                        Madison gave that the nation should acquiesce in enduring so small a number
                        in the beginning, was that it would rapidly become larger, and that in fifty
                        years, by the arrangement he counselled, the House of Representatives alone
                        would be increased to four hundred members. It had been objected that "so
                        small a number (sixty-five) cannot be safely trusted with so much power,"
                        and Madison, in reply, said: "I take for granted here, what I shall in
                        answering the fourth objection, hereafter show, that the number of
                        representatives will be augmented, from time to time, in the manner provided
                        by the constitution," and then adds these emphatic words, "On a contrary
                        supposition, I should admit the objection to have very great weight indeed."
                        He seemed anxious to be clearly understood as proposing the small number for
                        only a limited time. Thus further on he writes: "The true question to be
                        decided then is, whether the smallness of the number, as a temporary
                        regulation, be dangerous to the public liberty. Whether sixty-five members
                        for a few years, and a hundred, or two hundred for a few more, be a safe
                        depository for a limited and well guarded power of legislating for the
                        United States." Again the same statesman argued--"Sixty or seventy men may
                        be more properly trusted with a given degree of power, than six or seven.
                        But it does not follow, that six or seven hundred would be proportionably a
                        better depository. And if we carry on the supposition to six or seven
                        thousand, the whole reasoning ought to be reversed." Observe how guardedly
                        the great writer proceeded in the discussion, and how careful he was to
                        insert the word "proportionably" into his statement, so as to impliedly
                        admit that six or seven hundred were <emph rend="italic">better</emph> than
                        sixty or seventy, though it did follow from his preceding axiom, that they
                        afforded so high a degree of security as to insure <emph rend="italic">ten
                            times</emph> the safety of sixty or seventy.</p>
                    <p>We must remember that in framing the constitution of a great government
                        extending over many States, a desideratum was to form as small a House of
                        Representatives at first as prudence would permit in order to prevent the
                        inevitable rapid proportionate increase of members, from swelling the
                        legislature to a number too large for practicable deliberation and thus
                        changing it into a mob. But the number to which we now propose to augment
                        our law-making body has been proved by years of experience in many of the
                        States to be within the limits necessary for candid and successful debate
                        and cool decision, and if our commonwealth grow to rival China in population
                        we need not on that account increase our legislature one man. It is our
                        misfortune that we cannot form our legislatures of men equal in purity and
                        wisdom to the tried patriots who composed the first Congress under the new
                        constitution. As to the material of those past national councils Madison
                        said: "I am equally unable to conceive, that there are at this time, or can
                        be in any short time in the United States, any sixty-five or an hundred men,
                        capable of recommending themselves to the choice of the people at large, who
                        would either desire or dare within the short space of two years to betray
                        the solemn trust committed to them." And he wisely continues, "What change
                        of circumstances, time and a fuller population of our country, may produce,
                        requires a prophetic spirit to declare, which makes no part of my
                        pretensions."</p>
                    <p>It is painful to be compelled to admit that "change of circumstances" has so
                        metamorphosed the members of our legislatures in States where those bodies
                        are made up of comparatively few members, that in Pennsylvania it is almost
                        as much as a man's character for honesty is worth to be sent to the
                        legislature, while in New York the integrity of that branch of the
                        government in the esteem of the people has been illustrated by the convict,
                        travelling on the Hudson River railroad, just before the legislature met,
                        who when asked by a fellow passenger if he were "going to the legislature,"
                        replied, "No, thank God not so bad as <emph rend="italic">that</emph>, I'm
                        going to the penitentiary." If we could form our legislatures of such men as
                        those who were sent to the early Congresses, perhaps we might rest at ease
                        with a few members, and feel safe in trusting them. But when, without
                        reflecting upon any particular individual or even any particular
                        legislature, we are forced to acknowledge that if a man should wish a bill
                        put through the House and Senate, the most potent arguments he could use,
                        have become wonderfully light and lustre lacking since greenbacks have
                        superseded gold, and yet strange to say, they are as powerful now as before,
                        and when Senator Chandler would say "it is alleged, I know not whether it be
                        true or false, but it is alleged" that in our legislature an honest member
                        is looked upon with contempt by his fellow lawgivers, as one so weak and
                        foolish as to be an object for the most heartfelt pity. When these
                        statements have become as familiar throughout all Pennsylvania as is the
                        name of William Penn, it behooves us to exert ourselves to remedy the evil.
                        It may be urged that however large a legislature, it will be controlled by
                        the arguments of a few leading spirits. The statement is true when
                        interpreted in one way, and false when interpreted in another. "Enough for
                        two is enough for eight," is said to be correct, with reference to gas
                        lights, but not with reference to oysters. So the arguments which would
                        command the votes of one hundred legislators, might command the votes of
                        five hundred if those arguments were constituted of reason and philosophy,
                        but if they were offered in the shape of bank notes, at least five times the
                        amount would be required to produce the same result, and it would be
                        necessary to possess five times the trickery to conceal the corruption.</p>
                    <p>It may be argued that having a whole county from which to choose one
                        legislator, we can select a better class of men than we could if we elected
                        five or ten within the same limits. This supposition is very reasonable as a
                        mere theory, but it is not of much importance in practice. We all know what
                        kind of men are sent to our legislature now, and without meaning to cast
                        reproach on the present or even on any past legislature, I am certain all
                        sensible men will agree that we can readily find five or ten men in each
                        county, according to its size, every one of whom will be as good and useful
                        a member of the legislature, as those who have composed the great body of
                        that assemblage, during any session for twenty years. When a legislator
                        sells himself to support a measure in violation of the will of the majority
                        of the people of his county, he loses the respect and support of those
                        people, and he must be paid a price sufficiently large to remunerate him for
                        the sacrifice of popularity he makes. If we send five men in his stead, each
                        of whom at least upon his election establishes a character throughout the
                        whole county, it will require five times as much money to bribe the five
                        that it would to bribe the one. The wisest rule by which to determine how
                        many members should compose a legislature, is to fix on the largest number
                        capable of so controlling themselves as not to degenerate into the
                        turbulence and passion of a mob. As I have already said, a number equal to
                        that we advocate have so governed themselves in several State legislatures
                        for many years. Let us avail ourselves of the wisdom contained in the
                        proverb, "In the multitude of counsellors there is safety."<lb/>
                    JUSTIFICUS.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Justificus</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>In his letter, "Justificus" expresses the belief that a constitutional
                    convention should be convened to increase the size of the legislature.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>To Pennsylvania Soldiers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An appeal from the State Historian, Samuel Bates, asking soldiers to
                    furnish details of their personal history to be included in the History of the
                    Pennsylvania Volunteer and Militia Organizations.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1867.03.06.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Grand Army of the Republic</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elder</ln>
                        <fn>James G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilmore</ln>
                        <fn>James R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>F. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fletcher</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harmony</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilbert</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reynolds</ln>
                        <fn>R. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>It is reported that Franklin county has been constituted a "District of the
                    Grand Army of the Republic," and that Col. James G. Elder, late of the 126th
                    Regiment Penna Vols., has been elected District Commander.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Promotion</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>George O. Seilhamer, formerly editor of the Repository, has been promoted
                    to Assistant City Editor of the New York Tribune.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Odd Fellows' Anniversary</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Columbus Lodge, No. 75, of the I. O. O. F. will celebrate their
                    twenty-fifth anniversary on April 5th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Revival</head>
                <origin>Mercersburg Journal</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The revival that had been in progress at the M. E. Church for the past
                    eight weeks in Mercersburg has come to end, according to a report in the
                    Mercersburg Journal. Over the course of the event, over one hundred persons
                    "expressed a change of heart, nearly all of whom were admitted as members of
                    that church."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Confirmed</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>C. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes that C. S. Eyster, former resident of Chambersburg, has been
                    confirmed by the U. S. Senate as U. S. Judge of Colorado.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stull</ln>
                        <fn>C. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Oller</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Price</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Feb. 21st, C. C. Stull and Rebecca Oller were married by Rev. Jacob
                    Price.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilmore</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Feb. 28th, Mary Gilmore, 61, died in Upper Strasburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hill</ln>
                        <fn>Susannah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Feb. 25th, Susannah Hill, 60, died in St. Thomas.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zeigler</ln>
                        <fn>Agnes C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zeigler</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zeigler</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Feb. 17th, Agnes C., daughter of Thomas and Margaret Zeigler, died near
                    Dry Run. She was 4 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Piles</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Piles</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Piles</ln>
                        <fn>Calvin S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Feb. 18th, Calvin S., infant son of William and Mary Ann Piles, died at
                    Dry Run. He was 3 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coulter</ln>
                        <fn>Matthew E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Feb. 26th, Matthew E. Coulter died near Doylesburg. He was 90 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zeigler</ln>
                        <fn>Elmer E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zeigler</ln>
                        <fn>Brice B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zeigler</ln>
                        <fn>Jane M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Feb. 27th, Elmer E., son of Brice B. and Jane M. Zeigler, died near Dry
                    Run. He was 5 weeks old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1867.03.06.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
