<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1867/pa.fr.fr.1867.09.25">
    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>01/09</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1867-09-25">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day>25</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1867.09.25.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Recollections fo General John F. Reynolds</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The piece eulogizes Gen. Reynolds as a fallen hero of the Commonwealth, and
                    describes his battle field heroics.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1867.09.25.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A reminder to voters that they must be assessed at least ten days before
                    the election if they hope to cast a ballot.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Informs readers that the manner of voting has changed; in this election,
                    voters will have to fill out one slip for the "Judiciary" and a second for the
                    "County."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Mr. Wallace Redivivus</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors criticize the Chairman of the Democratic State Central
                    Committee for his attacks on Judge Williams's character, particularly his New
                    England roots. His efforts, they say, represent a new political low.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>In Earnest</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Anger at the President and his advisors is mounting throughout the nation,
                    contend the editors. And the Amnesty Proclamation may push the people to action.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Poking fun at their new rivals, the editors question the likelihood that
                    the owners of the Valley Spirit will achieve their goal of making the journal "a
                    fountain from which all may drink pure, unadulterated wholesome truth."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article notes that Col. Wingert, the Democrats' nominee for the
                    Assembly, was, until a year ago, a Republican.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A reminder to readers: in 1864, the Democratic party "opposed the
                    restoration of the Union by war."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Far Off Chats With Friends</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In his article this week, McClure describes life in the valleys of Montana.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Facts for the People--No. II</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Dr. W. B. Brown</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article informs readers about "Scrofula," a "disease of the blood"
                    though long-held to be incurable.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Laughing</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Obidiah Snodgrass</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Another installment from Obidiah, who this time discusses the sin of
                    laughing.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>8</column>
                <head>Political Preaching</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">To the Editors of the Franklin Repository.</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>In the <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> of the 18th inst., a certain "what
                        say you?" seems to be stirred in spirit by an intolerable grievance he has
                        "observed in many churches," to wit, "A disposition in Pastors to indulge in
                        politics." As a cure for this soul-cramping practice, this pious worshipper
                        suggests "that the true friends of the Christian faith should at once rise
                        from their seats and leave the church to those who favor such proceedings."
                        What particular item of politics is thus made to infringe on the sanctified
                        taste of the complainant, does not appear, but we presume some "high minded"
                        or perhaps humble minded minister has attempted to palm off for <emph
                            rend="italic">bona fide</emph> scripture, such passages as "God has made
                        of one blood all nations of men for to dwell on <emph rend="italic"
                        >all</emph> the face of the earth, and hath determined the <emph
                            rend="italic">times</emph> before appointed, and the bounds of their
                        habitation." "If ye fulfill the royal law according to the <emph
                            rend="italic">scripture</emph>, Thou shalt love thy neighbor as thyself,
                        ye do well; but if ye have respect to persons, <emph rend="italic">ye commit
                            sin</emph>, and are convinced of the laws as transgressors." "As ye
                        would that men should do to you, do ye even so to them, for this is the law
                        and the prophets." In response, we present to the suggestion of this devotee
                        of the true faith once delivered to the Saints by those who preached the
                        "divine origin of slavery," there will be a terrible exodus from the church
                        some of these days. We beg to suggest to this afflicted brother the
                        propriety of getting Andy Johnson or Frank Winger to issue a proclamation to
                        the faithful. Not to dictate, it might be couched in something like the
                        following terms:</p>
                    <p>WHEREAS, Slavery and Democracy after having harmoniously walked together in
                        regulating church and State in the days of our fathers, and under the
                        circumstances then existing, it was altogether fitting that the christians
                        should be regularly edified with the scriptural teaching that the <emph
                            rend="italic">nigger</emph> descended from and bore the curse of Canaan;
                        that Slavery was a divine institution, and that "servants should obey their
                        masters in all things;" but</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Whereas</emph>, Caesar has given to the nigger his
                        freedom, and claims to regulate his <emph rend="italic">status</emph> as a
                        freeman, it has become necessary that the Democracy should find a new ally,
                        and as infidelity has long contended that God did not "make of one blood,
                        all nations of men," it has been deemed right and proper by the Democracy to
                        seek its aid, and therefore, we have discarded the idea that the nigger
                        descended from either Ham, Noah or Adam, but is a distinct creation, has
                        been sent into the world to torment the Democracy; and</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Whereas</emph>, Having given up the use of all scriptural
                        passages which we once relied on, and having, in defence to our new ally,
                        desired the unity of the human race, it is deemed highly offensive in
                        ministers to remind us of any relationship we sustain toward <emph
                            rend="italic">all men</emph>.</p>
                    <p>Therefore, I, A. J., or F. W., (as the case may be) do proclaim it to be the
                        duty of conscientious Democrats to leave and withdraw from any church in
                        which by word or deed any such relationship to "<emph rend="italic">all
                        men</emph>" is acknowledged, or is sought to be sustained by any scriptures
                        as aforesaid.</p>
                    <p>W.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>W.</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>With a sardonic tone, "W." decries the use of the pulpit to push political
                    messages, particularly by the Democrats who legitimize their support of slavery
                    by invoking the myth of Ham.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1867.09.25.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Railroad Movements</head>
                <origin>Hagerstown Mail</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is reported that three executives of the Cumberland Railroad Company
                    were in Franklin "to make a reconnaissance of the route between Hagerstown and
                    Williamsport," and that their "visit proved entirely satisfactory."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--The Ballon Ascension</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that John A. Light's balloon flight last Thursday was the "most
                    successful and beautiful of the six he has made from our town." After hovering
                    over the town for some time, the balloon sailed in a southeasterly direction
                    before landing in the vicinity of Funkstown, a distance of ten miles.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Death of a Horse</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates that one of J. McD. Sharp's horses died while en route from
                    Chambersburg to McConnellsburg. The animal died shortly after it was discovered
                    to be "swollen, and lagging in an unusual way." The cause of the animal's death
                    is believed to be a "sudden attack of colic."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Prof. Dalton's Lecture</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that Prof. Dalton has agreed to deliver a lecture, "Oxygenized
                    Air as a Remedial Agent," in Repository Hall next Friday. Dalton is a professor
                    of Physiology at the Philadelphia Medical University.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scribba</ln>
                        <fn>Victor</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes that Victor Scriba, a former resident of Chambersburg, died in
                    Allegheny county last Thursday. He was 65 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Appointment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamman</ln>
                        <fn>P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Applauds the appointment of P. Hamman to a constabulary position by the
                    Court.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--An Old Woman</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bostic</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Relates that a black woman named Mrs. Bostic died near Waynesboro on August
                    26th at the age of 105.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Logan</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cover</ln>
                        <fn>Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bishop</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Sept. 18th, John Logan and Ann Cover were married by Rev. J. M. Bishop.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brotherton</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Sept. 12th, Dr. James Brotherton died in Waynesboro. He was 73 years
                    old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keefer</ln>
                        <fn>John Geary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keefer</ln>
                        <fn>William S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keefer</ln>
                        <fn>Eliza</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Spet. 4th, John Geary, infant son of William S. and Eliza Keefer, died.
                    He was 8 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harmon</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Sept. 3rd, James Harmon died near Spring Run. He was 61 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ehrhart</ln>
                        <fn>Adam Rush</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ehrhart</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ehrhart</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Sept. 13th, Adam Rush, infant son of William Mary E. Ehrhart, died in
                    St. Thomas. He was 2 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nill</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Sept. 19th, John Nill died in Chambersburg. He was 64 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clark</ln>
                        <fn>Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On August 28th, Ann Clark died in Chambersburg after suffering a lingering
                    illness. She was 70 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1867.09.25.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
