<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1867/pa.fr.fr.1867.12.18">
    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>01/30</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1867-12-18">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="12">December</month>
            <day>18</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1867.12.18.01">
            <pageNote>Page includes advertisements and variety of anecdotes and short
            stories.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1867.12.18.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Southern Convention vs. Mr. Johnson</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>When disgusted by Johnson's impudence, or wearied or chafed by Democratic
                        harping on the wornout strings of passion and prejudice, we often turn for
                        relief to the daily reports of the saying and doings in the Conventions now
                        in session in most of the rebel States, which are met for the uniform
                        purpose of drafting loyal constitutions for their respective communities. We
                        are invariably cheered by the reading. It is apparent, as one watches and
                        notes the daily progress, that the members mean business; that they have
                        either brought up with them from their country homes correct notions of the
                        popular needs, and of the best forms of government to supply them, or that
                        they have speedily learned to profit by the lessons of others success in
                        discerning and supplying; that they are neither too indolent to labor, too
                        captious or pragmaticul to agree, nor too proud to imitate and learn. The
                        natural result is that which, by being daily apparent, cheers our eyes when
                        we turn them from Democratic balderdash or stupidity, namely, the steady
                        growth of free constitutions, under and by and because of which the late
                        slave States will, we trust, soon become, so far as their governments can
                        make them, the freest, purest, happiest and best of commonwealths.</p>
                    <p>When Andrew Johnson, daring to say at last what the hypocrite always
                        cherished as a conviction, that certain men exist who ought simply to be
                        governed, without any show of authority in the community they inhabit, we
                        turn to read in their well considered declaration of rights, that a share in
                        the government in some degree, is an inalienable right conferred by the God
                        who made us all; when rural Copperhead writers denounce the negro's race as
                        an inferior one, doomed never to produce a thinker or an actor who may rank
                        with a Democrat in cognitive or executive ability, we laugh as we see that
                        negro thinkers and talkers and voters are largely helping to shape an
                        excellent form the constitutions of States, and casting aside the
                        workmanship of their arrogant predecessors are surpassing them on their own
                        ground; and when Johnson and the Copperheads in unison are vociferating that
                        the Congress and the loyal nation have failed and are failing to solve the
                        problems of reconstruction, and will eventually be compelled to adopt the
                        plan they offer of healing wounds and retrieving losses, by letting all
                        things run their own sweet way, we laugh again as we see, the swift coming
                        day, when these labors will be happily concluded, and when a grateful people
                        having applauded their work by their votes of adoption, a gratified nation,
                        by the mouths of their Congress, will welcome their return to the halls of
                        their fathers, clothed and of right mind. When that day comes even
                        Democrats, in the retrospect, will see the magnitude and the excellence of
                        their work, and it will go hard with the Democracy, if with even more than
                        Catholic zeal they do not at once seek, with the honied words of admiration
                        and sympathy, to proselyte the voters they to-day so foully abuse. We are
                        content to wait for this day ourselves, for we see it fast coming. The
                        Democrats feel that it is coming, but they hope by slander and
                        misrepresentation to delay it. It is useless--this great globe of ours,
                        spins round and round with irresistible force, but with noiseless motion,
                        and the vulgar who feel no jar and see no milestones, often deny their
                        transit from constellation to constellation, yet they do not deny, winter
                        and summer to be facts, nor fail to enjoy the delights of the one or escape
                        the hardships of the other. The sphere of our polity moves at the bidding of
                        forces, which emanate from the center of all justice as of all power, but
                        the heedless or purblind partisan may deny that it bears him in the pathway
                        of the stars, even though he may revel in the sunshine of humanity and
                        benevolence, or be scourged by the blasts of injustice and inequality. The
                        world does move, however, and some school-master will one day prove it to
                        even Democratic satisfaction.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In contrast to the impudence articulated by President Johnson and the
                    Democrats, say the editors, it is refreshing to hear what is taking place in the
                    various constitutional convention now meeting in the South. There, they relate,
                    "capable and trustworthy men" are drafting legislation to make the southern
                    states "the freest, purest, happiest, and best form of commonwealths."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Congress and Christmas</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>While we write, Congress is hesitating as to whether they will adjourn over
                        the holidays, or remain at their post to counteract the wilful wickedness of
                        the President. The recent elections have elevated his excellency to a high
                        pitch of self-complacency and arrogance; and, relieved from the apprehension
                        of impeachment, he bullies and defies the National Legislature with the
                        spirit of the whilom overseers. Backed up and urged on by such reckless
                        characters as Black, Foorhess, Morrissey and their associates, he will leave
                        no effort unassayed to destroy the good work of the loyalists, and to
                        restore to their former supremacy the rebel democracy. If Congress can
                        prevent any evil from these sources, it is their duty to continue their
                        session uninterrupted to its end. The hopes of the true people of the nation
                        rest upon the wisdom and courage of their legislators. Never had a
                        legislative body more solemn duties imposed upon it. The restoration of the
                        Union to peace and harmony, the securing of justice and equality to its
                        citizens, and the establishing upon a firm and honest basis the financial
                        policy of the government, will tax the sagacity of the wisest. The issue of
                        elections next fall will measurably depend upon the actions of Congress this
                        session. If they prove unequal to the just demands of the people, no name,
                        however great, will save our party from final ruin. We hope and trust that a
                        perception of this truth will control our friends at Washington; that they
                        will lay aside all unnecessary issues that may beget discord, and will unite
                        in support of the great principles recognised by all as just, right, and
                        imperative. We do not fear that they will abandon any of the high ground
                        they have taken. To do so, is to accept defeat. It is itself defeat. There
                        could be no more fitting observation of the hallowed season dear to the
                        christian heart and home, than the fulfillment of the duties which we owe to
                        our country and to our fellow men. The lowly and down trodden, the poor and
                        oppressed were the special care of the blessed One, whose advent consecrates
                        the approaching holidays; and their influence should soften the hearts of
                        our people so that they may go out in sympathy with the despised and humble
                        children of a common Father, in whose sight they are as precious as the most
                        distinguished and powerful of the earth. The unchristian, unphilosophic and
                        ungenerous, not to say vulgar, mean, and brutal, theories which hold that
                        men are made to be the abject slaves of favored fellow-mortals; to be denied
                        the rights which are inherent to humanity; to have all innate aspirations
                        after a higher grade of life, which of themselves establish the kinship of
                        the races, crushed out by rude violence; to be condemned to humility and
                        degradation by scoffs and ribaldry and bitter jeers; to be classified by
                        ignorant pretenders to technological science with the most loathsome orders
                        of the brutes, and to be hooted at, and cuffed, and stigmatised with obscene
                        epithets by the coarse minions of partisan naturalists "falsely so called."
                        Such theories, we aver, are not in harmony with the loving, all-embracing,
                        refining, influences of the sacred Christmas-tide. This is a humanizing
                        season, when christian people, of whatever sect, or race, in whatever land
                        or clime, of whatever rank or condition, unite in one common faith, and
                        bring their tributes of reverence to one common shrine, their "hearts
                        adoration" to one common Redeemer, in whom "all the kindreds of the earth
                        are blessed."</p>
                    <p>We trust that Congress will take new inspiration from the occasion. That it
                        will be strengthened in its resolves to discharge its duties, for the duties
                        sake, and we are resigned that the approval of the country will follow
                    them.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors call on Congress to continue its work so that it may finish the
                    present session "uninterrupted to its end." This, they say, is necessary to
                    insure that Congress's plans for reconstruction are implemented, and to counter
                    any attempt by President Johnson to "destroy the good work of the loyalists."
                    "Never had a legislative body more solemn duties imposed upon it."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article castigates Gen. Hancock for his behavior since the end of the
                    war, particularly his "official conduct in command of the Gulf Department."
                    During his command over the military district, Hancock has overseen the virtual
                    restoration of "the Louisiana Slaveocracy." His justification for these actions
                    "grossly insults the loyal people his order outrages, presumes upon the
                    ignorance of the people whose servant he is."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"Mr. McClure's views of the Indian question meet with more favor among
                    the Western people than the Tribune's comments. The Rocky Mountain News,
                    refering to the letter which originally appeared in the Tribune, and which was
                    afterwards copied into these columns, says:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>A. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Extracts from the western journal repudiate the Tribune editor's negative
                    assessment of McClure's views of the Indians and the "'blundering and
                    inefficient policy of the government'" toward them. Having no first-hand
                    experience with such matters, it is "'impertinent'" for the Tribune editor to
                    "'slur'" McClure's reliability.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The National Republican Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the National Union Republican Convention was held in
                    Washington on Dec. 11th. At the meeting, it was determined that Chicago will
                    host the following convention where the candidates for President and
                    Vice-President will be nominated.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>How They Voted</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koontz</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The article lists the members of Pennsylvania's congressional delegation,
                    and their votes on the impeachment resolution.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Far Off Chats With Friends</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In his article, McClure discusses a few of Montana's "heroes," and relates
                    some of their exploits.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Our National Finances</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The piece examines the various monetary policies promulgated by politicians
                    as a means to stimulate trade and repay government loans.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1867.12.18.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brotherton</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brotherton</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brotherton</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brotherton</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brotheron</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf>Sr.</sf>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The article offers a detailed sketch of John Brotherton's life; Brotherton,
                    formerly of Chambersburg, recently died in Springfield, Ill., where he had lived
                    for the past few years. In the days since John's death, his brother William
                    passed away in Lock Haven, Pa. In fact, the family has suffered a number of
                    tragedies in the past couple of years, losing one son in the war and another
                    shortly after.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Local Items--Constitutional Amendments</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that a meeting will take place this Wednesday at the Court House
                    to discuss the "movement now in progress so to amend our constitution, State and
                    National, as to incorporate therein a reverent recognition of the Almighty."
                    Rev. T. P. Stevenson, of Philadelphia, will preside over the gathering.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Local Items--Fraternal Visit</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that seventy members of the George Washington Lodge, No. 143, A. Y.
                    M., of Chambersburg, visited their brethren at the Friendship Lodge in
                    Hagerstown, Md. The group was accompanied by the Silver Cornet Band.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Local Items--Dedication</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that the United Brethren in Christ congregation will dedicate their
                    new church in Mowersville on December 29th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Local Items--No Relief</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>When it met last Wednesday, relates the article, the Congressional
                    Committee on Claims "reported aversely" on the petitions lodged by the citizens
                    of Chambersburg for indemnification for damages suffered as a result of the
                    burning of the town.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Washabaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Upton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes that Upton Washabaugh, "one of the most highly respected and esteemed
                    citizens," died last Friday from the effects of a "long and painful" illness.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>Franklin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Galbrain</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Galbrain</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woodburn</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Dec. 3rd, Franklin Skinner and Sarah Jane, daughter of Joseph Galbrain,
                    of Cumberland county, were married by Rev. Woodburn.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Humbert</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Dec. 9th, David Humbert died in Loudon. He was 80 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1867.12.18.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
