<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1867/pa.fr.fr.1867.11.13">
    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>01/21</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1867-11-13">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="11"/>
            <day>13</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1867.11.13.01">
            <pageNote>Page contains advertisements and a variety of anecdotes.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1867.11.13.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Sympathies of the Age</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors lambaste their counterparts at the Philadelphia Age, a
                    Democratic journal, for asserting the Democrats played a role in achieving the
                    present state of peace in the Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Foreboding</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We must acknowledge that the aggregate result of the fall elections is
                        against us. It is useless to seek the cause of our defeat. It is worse than
                        idle for leaders, who differ slightly as to the means of attaining the same
                        end, to criminate and recriminate. It matters little now whether our defeat
                        in New York was caused by the lukewarmness of professed party organs, or
                        wholesale corruption. Whether in Pennsylvania by apathy or the negro, or by
                        other causes equally as plausible. We are rather concerned about the effect
                        the success of those, who during the late war, were so closely connected
                        with the enemies of the Republic, will have upon the decision of the great
                        questions which now agitate the nation. Those who voted against us in
                        October and November opposed the war at every stage; fought every measure
                        taken for its preservation. They pronounced the making of the national
                        currency a legal tender unconstitutional; the draft was unconstitutional;
                        emancipation was unconstitutional and a great infringement of the rights of
                        their Southern allies. Many of them fought against us with arms in their
                        hands, and, according to their confederates, it would be a monstrous wrong
                        to disfranchise them. What will a party composed of such elements do when it
                        comes into power? is a question which every true friend of the nation should
                        ponder well. It is natural to suppose that they will endeavor to remedy,
                        according to their notions, what they deem to have been done amiss, and how
                        they will reconstruct the States lately in rebellion is not left to
                        conjecture. All they want yet to give them complete control of the
                        government is the restoration of the rebels to all the rights and privileges
                        which they enjoyed before their rebellion, without any guarantees as to
                        their future behavior. But--thanks to the better mind which prevailed in the
                        past--there yet remains a loyal Congress, and thanks to fleeting time a
                        disloyal President's term of office draws near its close. Unless they
                        succeed in the great contest next fall, their present success will do them
                        little good and will do their unreconstructed friends much harm. The latter,
                        taking time by the forelock, anticipating the action of the Democratic party
                        if entirely successful, have begun already to set at defiance the laws of
                        the land. As far as it lies in their power they are preparing the way for
                        the abrogation of the enactments which gave freedom to four millions of
                        slaves. They exult at the partial success of this despicable party, because
                        they hope to secure through it what they failed to secure by their appeal to
                        arms. They know that when that party holds the reins of government their
                        cause is no longer the "lost cause." The anti-progression party, grows upon
                        its denunciation of the radical party and not from any intrinsic merit. It
                        has offered no plan of reconstruction while it denounces that of the party
                        in power. It rants about the corruption in State and national affairs, but
                        wherever they hold the reins--in New York City for example--their rottenness
                        is without precedent. In fact the aim of their tactics is to get control of
                        the government. There is no evidence anywhere of an intention on their part
                        to deal fairly with the great questions at issue. They have changed no
                        opinion held and advocated by them during the war, and every one knows that
                        those opinions were radically antagonistic to the principles in defense of
                        which the war was waged. The most bitter exponents of these opinions,
                        Vallandingham, Vorhees, Pendleton, &amp;c.--are to-day the headers and
                        the candidates for the prospective honors of the party. These men croak of a
                        war of races through the action of the radical party, and with the same
                        breath stir the worst prejudices of their ignorant followers against an
                        inoffensive and weak race. Once in power the march of progress stops, nay
                        worse than that, from that moment we go backward. The questions which we
                        fondly thought were forever settled will then be re-opened and the result
                        may be another appeal to arms. We will not however borrow trouble. We have
                        got a loyal Congress, loyal governors and we believe a great majority of the
                        people are with us upon the great questions of the day. Let us only be
                        vigilant and active, and all will be well.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Despite the Republicans' recent electoral setbacks, explain the editors,
                    the Democrats will not be able to reverse the current course of the nation.
                    Though the "partial success of this despicable party" has emboldened southerners
                    and given them new hope that they might achieve what they "failed to secure by
                    their appeal to arms," the vigilance of Congress and the people will prevail.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The November Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article supplies the results from the elections held last week: in New
                    York, New Jersey, and Maryland the Democrats won by sound majorities; in
                    Massachusetts and Minnesota the Republicans triumphed; and in Kansas, voters
                    defeated Constitutional Amendments to allow "female and colored suffrage."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>At the recent election in Virginia the negroes voted almost to a man in favor
                        of a constitutional convention, and for just such delegates to the
                        convention as the majority of Whites did not want.</p>
                    <p>There was nothing surprising in this, at least to any one who had credited
                        the Negro with sufficient judgment to discriminate between friend and foe.
                        That he should want to exercise the rights of citizenship, since he is
                        compelled to bear its burdens, it is natural, just as natural as it was for
                        him when a slave to covet his freedom. That he should use his ballot so as
                        to secure the former, might be expected just as naturally as that he should
                        use his legs in days gone by to secure the latter. Any other course on his
                        part would have indicated a stupid ignorance or sottish indifference that
                        would have satisfied all minds of his utter unfitness for the endowment. But
                        just because he did what he ought to have done, and what would have degraded
                        him in the estimation of the rebels themselves if he had not done, they turn
                        upon him with a ferocity that would disgrace even the negroes were the
                        situation of the parties reversed. They propose to drive him from
                        employment, to deny him the common right of all God's creatures, that of
                        toil, and to bring upon him all the horrors of absolute and hopeless want.
                        Such madness and stupidity combined, have seldom been equalled in the same
                        people. Even supposing that there existed a necessity for some vindicatory
                        measure, the thing proposed is the very refinement of nonsense itself. The
                        community that would attempt it would soon find that its own was the greater
                        punishment, and we know of no people who would be likely to discover the
                        unpleasant truth sooner than the Virginians themselves. They, least of all,
                        can afford to do this thing; yet they have commenced in downright earnest,
                        and to-day there are thousands of Negroes in Virginia in enforced idleness
                        and perhaps want. Idleness is the Devil's work shop; want is his
                        opportunity. Whatever of crime or violence results from this mad course, let
                        the responsibility of it be correctly fixed. That considerable of both will
                        come if the present purpose of the white people of Virginia is persisted in,
                        who can doubt?</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>That blacks "voted almost to a man in favor of a constitutional convention"
                    in the recent election in Virginia should come as no surprise, relates the
                    article. After all, they can differentiate friend from foe. If whites continue
                    to abuse blacks and deny them employment opportunities for expressing their
                    political independence, future acts of "crime or violence" committed by the
                    freedpeople will be the sole responsibility of the white people of Virginia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Mi Experiens in Kourtin</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Obidiah Snodgrass</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>In this installment from the fictitious character, Snodgrass discusses his
                    youthful attempts at wooing the hearts of young maidens.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Italian Question Settled</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports from Italy indicate that Garibaldi's attempt at revolution has
                    ended "in total failure."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1867.11.13.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>A. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The article relates that A. K. McClure's letters from Montana to the New
                    York Tribune and Repository have been judged a huge success by the "entire press
                    of Montana."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Court Proceedings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDowell</ln>
                        <fn>James B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deitrich</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLanahan</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Youse</ln>
                        <fn>Levi</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Iser</ln>
                        <fn>Basil</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Groff</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Inley</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cessna</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Speelman</ln>
                        <fn>Rudolph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The following cases were disposed since this journal's last issue. Common
                    Pleas: James B. McDowell vs. Lewis Deitrich. Summons Case. Verdict for plaintiff
                    for $68.42. Motion for a new trial. Court made reduction of $10 verdict, and
                    refused new trial. John B. McLanahan vs. Cumb. Valley Railroad
                    Company--Ejectment. Verdict for one-half of land in dispute. Levi Youse and wife
                    vs. Basil Iser and wife--Summons case in slander. Verdict for plaintiffs for one
                    dollar damages and defendants to pay costs. John Groff vs. Martin Inley and
                    wife--Replevin. Verdict for defendant for $500. Motion for a new trial. John
                    Cessna vs. Rudolph Speelman and Daniel Myers--Ejectment. Verdict for plaintiff
                    for the land in dispute, to be realized upon the payment of the sum of $1,061.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>.</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Sabbath School Institute</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that the Cumberland and Franklin County Sabbath School Teachers'
                    Institute will be held in Shippensburg on November 19th and 20th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Teachers' Institute</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shoemaker</ln>
                        <fn>P. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Superintendent</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes that the Franklin Teachers' Institute, which began on Monday last,
                    will continue its session until Thursday evening.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--An Accident</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Waynesboro Record</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tharp</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that Jacob Tharp suffered serious injuries in an accident that
                    occurred while he was driving his father's team on the turnpike near Antietam.
                    Tharp was thrown from the wagon after the horses took fright and suddenly ran
                    off. Though he is "suffering considerably," his injuries are not judged to be
                    life-threatening.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Gen. Tom Thumb</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that Gen. Tom Thumb and his troupe will perform at Repository
                    Hall next Monday and Tuesday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--The Meat Market</head>
                <origin>Williamsport Gazette</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors call on the Town Council to repeal its ban on allowing farmers
                    to sell small quantities of meat on the streets; at present, they note, the
                    prices for meat in town stores are too high, thus the community would benefit
                    from the increased competition.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Tannery Sold</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Middour</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Oyler</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes that George Middour, of Waynesboro, purchased the Quincy tannery of
                    M. Oyler for $3,200.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--I. O. G. T.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>J. Burns</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shively</ln>
                        <fn>Helen</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolf</ln>
                        <fn>fL. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGowan</ln>
                        <fn>Stuart</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greenawalt</ln>
                        <fn>D. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bittinger</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McElroy</ln>
                        <fn>Robert F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Renfrew</ln>
                        <fn>Harris J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richards</ln>
                        <fn>Kate</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snively</ln>
                        <fn>A. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Black</ln>
                        <fn>Sadie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McElroy</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilders</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Deputy Charles W. Lego, of the Gilmore Lodge, No. 358, I. O. G. T., of
                    Fayetteville, appointed officers for the following quarter at the meeting held
                    Thursday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Local Items--New Director</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillan</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Criswell</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clayton</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heintzelman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Piper</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gelwicks</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bard</ln>
                        <fn>Cephas L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bonebrake</ln>
                        <fn>E. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes that John Gillan, Jr., assumed his duties as the Director of the Poor
                    on Nov. 4th, replacing John H. Criswell, whose performance was "acceptable." The
                    board now consists of Messrs. Clayton, Heintzelman, and Gillan. Board members
                    made the following appointments: Steward, David Piper; Treasurer, Charles
                    Gelwicks; Physician, Dr. Cephas L. Bard; Attorney and Clerk, E. J. Bonebrake.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Local Items--Tearing Down Bills</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reminds readers that it is crime punishable by a $5 to $20 fine for tearing
                    down handbills.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Local Items--Railroad Accident</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stepler</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Andrew Stepler suffered internal injuries while working at the Cumberland
                    Valley Railroad last Saturday morning. Stepler was coupling railroad cars when
                    he was sandwiched between two of them.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Local Items--Steam Fire Engine</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Town Council authorized the purchase of a steam fire engine at a
                    special meeting last Monday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Local Items--Temperance Lecture</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that the "great advocate of temperance" Dr. Charles J. Jewett
                    will deliver at lecture in Chambersburg next Saturday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Local Items--Snow</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The first snow of the season fell yesterday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shaffer</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoke</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hummelbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>H. Y.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Oct. 31st, Charles Shaffer, of Adams county, and Sarah A. Stoke were
                    married by Rev. H. Y. Hummelbaugh.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Conner</ln>
                        <fn>James H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rots</ln>
                        <fn>Fannie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hummelbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>H. Y.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Oct. 31st, James H. Conner and Fannie Rots were married by Rev. H. Y.
                    Hummelbaugh.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoover</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rhorer</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoover</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Nov. 7th, Samuel Hoover and Mary Rhorer, daughter of A. Rhorer,
                    Letterkenny township, were married by Rev. H. Hoover.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Funk</ln>
                        <fn>John S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Morgal</ln>
                        <fn>Clara S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Krebs</ln>
                        <fn>W. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Oct. 31st, John S. Funk and Clara S. Morgal were married by Rev. W. E.
                    Krebs.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Diel</ln>
                        <fn>Enoch</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bare</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>I. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Oct. 31st, Enoch Diel and Margaret J. Bare were married by Rev. I. N.
                    Hays.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foltz</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel Powell</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foltz</ln>
                        <fn>Franklin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foltz</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Nov. 5th, Daniel Powell, son of Franklin and Mary Foltz, died in
                    Chambersburg. He was 18 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duncan</ln>
                        <fn>Eleaner</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Nov. 1st, Eleaner Duncan died in Guilford township. She was 76 years
                    old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1867.11.13.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
