<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1867/pa.fr.fr.1867.03.27">
    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>10/11</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1867-03-27">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day>27</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1867.03.27.01">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1867.03.27.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn>A. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A correction to the story that appeared in the last issue of the Repository
                    stating that A. D. Gordon is the acting Assessor of the district. In fact, the
                    position is held by Frederick Wiemer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Schuyler Colfax will deliver his address, "Across the Continent," in
                    Chambersburg on April 20th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"To persist in treachery is bad enough at best, but to persist in it
                    without even the hope of making it effectual, is a refinement of stupidity that
                    none but a debauched apostate could be guilty of."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article notes that Congress passed the supplementary Reconstruction
                    Bill, overriding President Johnson's veto. The vote in the Senate was 40 to 7,
                    and in the House 114 to 25.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The World Moves!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Like the Bourbons of France, the Democracy of the North learn nothing and
                        forget nothing. They triumphed for years by blind devotion to Slavery, and
                        schooled themselves and their children to hatred of the African, and fears
                        of his successful competition with them in the race for social and political
                        honors. They even bowed down to the demands of the slave power when it
                        pronounced the Union a mere loose association that could be broken at will,
                        and when traitors denied to the government the inherent power to preserve
                        itself, every Northern Democrat echoed the same sentiment, and declared
                        coercion to be a crime. Nor did its awkward folly stop there. It staggered
                        through the war, ever afraid to avow its sympathy and belief, and too false
                        to learn how dear to all were the blessings of our beneficient system of
                        free government. When, in order to save the Republic, Slavery was stricken
                        down, there was a protest as broad and as deep as Democracy could make it,
                        and when the emancipated slave entered the Union ranks to defend our common
                        flag, he was declared a dolt and a coward, and his presence in the army was
                        pronounced an insult to the white soldier, and a needless wound to our
                        "erring brethren" of the South. But step by step the world moved on, and
                        Progress with Justice and Humanity emblazoned on its banner, until the still
                        unrepentant traitor made negro enfranchisement an imperative necessity.
                        Again the unlearned and unlearning Democracy revolted, and the doleful
                        appeals for protection against the social and political equality of the
                        negro resounded from every stump, as frightened Democratic orators plead
                        their own cause against the advancement of the African. At last manhood
                        suffrage dawned upon the National capital, and after the returned rebel
                        soldiers and their congenial sympathizers had exhausted their indignation,
                        they marched up to the polls, side by side with the negro, and the negro
                        triumphed. The peace was unbroken; no violent convulsion in either nature or
                        politics followed his voting, and his right and his power are now, and
                        forever henceforth, accepted facts in the capital of the country. There may
                        be political changes in Congress in time. Other parties than the Republicans
                        may wield the power of the government, but none will abridge suffrage on the
                        ground of color or caste.</p>
                    <p>Throughout the whole Union, and especially in the States lately in rebellion,
                        the progress of public sentiment toward manhood suffrage is sweeping
                        opposition from its course. In South Carolina, and in its very capital, the
                        whites and blacks met and mingled by thousands last week, to consider the
                        State of the country. The whites were not adventurers or those who are
                        classed as traitors to the South. On the contrary, such lordly Democratic
                        leaders and rebel warriors as Gen. Wade Hampton, and ex-U. S. Senator
                        Desasseure, and others equally eminent, spoke from the same stand with sable
                        orators, to an audience dotted with an equality of pale and dusky faces. The
                        proud Hampton pronounced in favor of political equality, and his liberality
                        was responded to by Nash and Picket, who with unlearned but eloquent tongues
                        proposed for their white friends universal amnesty. On the same day some
                        3,000 negroes met in Savannah, Georgia, and were addressed by both blacks
                        and whites, all uniting in proposing peace, brotherhood and impartial
                        rights. Even in proud Virginia, the wet-nurse of treason and the boasted
                        mother of statesmen, the voices which were defiant until now, begin to
                        advocate the supremacy of the laws, and the acceptance of the principles of
                        universal justice. Soon the negro, long the abject slave, will peacefully
                        deposit his vote side by side with his old oppressor, and before another
                        autumn shall tint Virginia's mountains, manhood suffrage will be the
                        accepted and fixed policy of the Old Dominion. Nor is it looked upon as a
                        temporary expedient. It is as immutable as the eternal laws of truth, and it
                        will abide perpetually, while the blind passions which protested will fade
                        into forgetfulness. Truly, the world moves!</p>
                    <p>In Pennsylvania our political Bourbons are still stumbling and snarling about
                        the negro. While Wade Hampton was speaking with and to his ex-slaves in
                        South Carolina, recognizing them as citizens and cordially conceding all
                        their rights, the Democracy of the Pennsylvania legislature were resorting
                        to revolutionary measures to defeat a bill forbidding railroads to
                        discriminate against negroes, and they fitly represented their party. Here
                        in Pennsylvania last of all will the Democracy learn that the negro is a
                        citizen, and may progress in social and political rights in defiance of the
                        prejudices which belong to other days. Nevertheless the world does move and
                        will move, and those who move not with it, will be forgotten in the
                        advancement of the age.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Across the country, and even in the states lately in rebellion, assert the
                    editors, there is growing public sentiment in favor of granting blacks the right
                    to vote. The lone exception to this shift in sentiment is among Northern
                    Democrats whose blind devotion to slavery and fear of economic competition with
                    blacks in postbellum society has stifled their ability to move on and join the
                    rest of the world in welcoming the dawn of a new era in American history.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article criticizes a suggestion made by the Pittsburg Gazette to form a
                    mixed ticket of Republicans and Democrats to represent Allegheny in the next
                    election for the state assembly. The Gazette proposed the idea because "the
                    present legislature has lost the Republican party its prestige and power," a
                    notion that the Repository editors do not challenge, though the editors do
                    question whether the election of Democrats will solve the problem.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The piece welcomes the return of the Mercersburg Review after a six year
                    hiatus. The journal will be published with "renewed life and energy" under the
                    direction of Rev. H. Harbaugh.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Harrisburg</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Horace</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>In the state capital, explains Horace, the Repository's Harrisburg
                    correspondent, there were "lively times" during the past week. Of particular
                    note, he says, was the controversy over the bill to increase funding for the
                    Pennsylvania Railroad Company, which Gov. Geary vetoed much to the delight of
                    the "Western enthusiasts in the anti-monopoly line."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Washington</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Spectacles</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Repository's Washington correspondent reports that Congress easily
                    passed the supplemental Reconstruction bill, only forty minutes after the
                    President had vetoed the same measure. Manhood suffrage, "Spectacles" declares,
                    is now the fixed policy of the government," and "it will never be overthrown."
                    Among the other events of note during the past week was the "scramble for the
                    spoils of the administration," which was the "most disgusting exhibition of
                    place-hunting ever witnessed in the history of this government."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Impeachments</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article provides a brief summary of some of the impeachment proceedings
                    conducted against members of Congress and the Judiciary since the establishment
                    of the United States.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>A Case of Woman Whipping</head>
                <origin>Evanston Courier</origin>
                <commentary>"A Gibson county correspondent of the Evansvill (Ind.) Courier gives the
                    following account of a recent case of woman whipping:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The piece relates the story of B. F. Mead, an "old man" who beat his
                    daughter with "a large black-jack switch four or five feet long" because he
                    disapproved of the style she had cut her hair. The beating left her with "a
                    great number of stripes extending from shoulder to shoulder," one of which cut
                    through the skin. Attempts to bring the man to trial were thwarted by his
                    ability to keep his daughter from testifying.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>The Schuylkill County Murders</head>
                <origin>Pittsburg Gazette</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>According to Gov. Geary, in the last four years, nearly fifty murders have
                    been committed in Schuylkill county, a coal mining region where there are
                    numerous "secret affiliations" among "disorderly" miners. To deal with the
                    lawlessness, says the article, a committee of citizens from the county visited
                    the legislature and urged it to institute a program to halt the violence which
                    continues to threaten their community.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Serious Riot in New York</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is reported that a riot broke out in New York as a procession of Irish
                    societies made their way through the city's streets. The violence began after a
                    truckman was attacked for taking too long to remove his team from the route.
                    Numerous rioters and policemen were seriously injured in the ensuing melee.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1867.03.27.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--The Spring Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilhelm</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Loose</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kuhn</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lesher</ln>
                        <fn>Christian D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lechrone</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snively</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Witmer</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Frantz</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillen</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shank</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snively</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brendle</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Detrich</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mowen</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Morehead</ln>
                        <fn>James C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davidson</ln>
                        <fn>George H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weir</ln>
                        <fn>A. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deardorff</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hawbecker</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Contains the election results from Antrim township and the Borough of
                    Greencastle to complete the list of officers elected in Franklin county. In the
                    Spring Election, Republicans elected judges of the election in ten districts and
                    Democrats in twelve, with a tie in Warren. In Washington, which usually goes
                    Republican, a Democrat was elected, and in Guilford, where Democrats generally
                    win, a Republican emerged victorious; elections in the other areas went largely
                    as predicted.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Appointments</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carroll</ln>
                        <fn>D. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>S. H. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>At the 10th Annual Session of the East Baltimore M. E. Conference, which
                    was held Frederick, Md., on March 19th, appointments were made for the Carlisle
                    and Frederick districts.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--The Road Law</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Contains a supplement to the recently enacted Road Law for Franklin county
                    stipulating that roads shall be sold or contracted for no longer than a year,
                    and that no drains or ditches shall be required on the road when the bed of the
                    road is solid.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Arrest of W. R. Kreps</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Krebs</ln>
                        <fn>W. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>It is reported that W. R. Kreps, formerly of Franklin county, was arrested
                    for his involvement in the murder of an infant in Harrisburg, where he was the
                    proprietor of the States Union Hotel. Evidently, a woman staying at the hotel
                    gave birth to the child, then left with another woman and Kreps. Shortly after,
                    the baby's body was found buried in the hotel garden. The three were arrested in
                    New York and brought to Harrisburg to face charges of murder.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Telegraph Office Opened</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kurtz</ln>
                        <fn>J. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Informs readers that a telegraph office opened in Waynesboro at the drug
                    store owned by J. F. Kurtz.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Highway Robbery</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ely</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Williams</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that John Ely was attacked and knocked down by "a colored man named
                    Williams" while crossing the bridge near Lemnos Edgetool factory on Wednesday
                    night. The thief absconded with one hundred dollars in greenbacks and another
                    hundred in promisory notes. Williams was arrested the following day, though only
                    half the money was recovered. He is currently being held in Fort Doebler.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Heavy Snow</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKnight</ln>
                        <fn>C. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heysinger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The storm that passed through the area on Thursday and Friday, leaving 15
                    inches of snow, caused three barns to collapse.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Assault with Intent to Kill</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rock</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>In a fight that took place in Quincy on Monday evening, George Rock stabbed
                    Jacob Fisher eleven times in his abdomen. Rock attacked his victim shortly after
                    the two men got into an altercation. Fisher is expected to recover.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Gettysburg and Chambersburg Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that the legislature has extended the time for the payment of the
                    enrollment tax on the Act to Incorporate the Gettysburg and Chambersburg
                    Railroad company, which was initially approved on April 17, 1866.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shull</ln>
                        <fn>D. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shaffer</ln>
                        <fn>Mary J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>P. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On March 19th, D. J. Shull and Mary J. Shaffer were married by Rev. P. S.
                    Davis.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foust</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christmas</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crider</ln>
                        <fn>T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On March 14th, Andrew Foust and Mary Christmas were married by Rev. T.
                    Crider.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stouffer</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bixler</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hummelbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>H. Y.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On March 21st, David Stouffer and Mary Bixler, of Carroll county, Md., were
                    married by Rev. H. Y. Hummelbaugh.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maloy</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingert</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>P. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On March 19th, Joseph S. Maloy and Sarah E. Wingert were married by Rev. P.
                    S. Davis.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kelley</ln>
                        <fn>Cyrus F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Forney</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>P. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On March 19th, Cyrus F. Kelley and Sarah Forney were married by Rev. P. S.
                    Davis.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lochbaum</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reasner</ln>
                        <fn>Annie M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hummelbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>H. Y.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On March 21st, William Lochbaum and Annie M. Reasner were married by Rev.
                    H. Y. Hummelbaugh.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Norris</ln>
                        <fn>Joshua J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cramer</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kunkleman</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On March 19th, Joshua J. Norris and Sarah J. Cramer were married by Rev. J.
                    A. Kunkleman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blood</ln>
                        <fn>Cyrus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On March 17th, Cyrus Blood, 71, died in Chamberburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roof</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roof</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Dec. 23rd, 1866, Elizabeth, wife of Joseph Roof, formerly of
                    Chambersburg, died in Urbana, Ohio. She was 60 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Warden</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Feb. 27th, Sarah Warden, 84, died in Urbana, Ohio. She was the mother of
                    Elizabeth Roof.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1867.03.27.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
