<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1867/pa.fr.fr.1867.03.13">
    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>10/11</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1867-03-13">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day>13</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1867.03.13.01">
            <pageNote>The page includes a number of short stories and unrelated
            anecdotes.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1867.03.13.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Edward McPherson has been selected Clerk of the House by unanimous vote.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn>A. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>It is reported that B. F. Myers, of the Bedford Gazette, has been nominated
                    as the new Collector of Revenue for the district that includes Franklin county,
                    though the Senate has not yet approved the appointment. No nomination has been
                    made for Assessor. Until the two positions are officially filled, Jeremiah
                    Bowles and A. D. Gordon will continue to carry out their respective duties as
                    Collector and Assessor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article informs readers that Mr. Ashley, in a speech characterized "by
                    exceedingly bad temper and as bad taste," has renewed his efforts in Congress to
                    impeach the President. Such actions, it contends, can only damage "the
                    impeachment programme."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>How To Attain Reform</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Obstacles to legislative reform, say the editors, come from two sources:
                    those Republicans who disregard the will of their constituents and Democrats who
                    "could not elect their just proportion of Delegates under the legislative
                    apportionment." To overcome these impediments, the editors offer a solution that
                    calls for the election of thirty men--fifteen from each party--to oversee the
                    reform efforts at a constitutional convention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is reported that Gen. Grant named Generals Schofield, Sickles, Sheridan,
                    Thomas, and McDowell as the commanders of the five military districts in the
                    South, as called for by Military Reconstruction Act.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The War Department has released a report indicating that 32,662 whites and
                    24,238 blacks in the South "will need food from some source before the next crop
                    can relieve them." To accomplish this task, the study estimates that 170,700
                    rations per month will be required.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Franklin County Road Law</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The piece includes a copy of the road law recently passed by the
                    legislature. The new act gives supervisors the power to determine how new roads
                    should be divided and contracts awarded for the work.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Work Done By Congress</head>
                <origin>North American</origin>
                <commentary>"The 39th Congress did not adjourn without having accomplished a great
                    deal of good work. Notswithstanding the check upon the legislation that the
                    President's opposition would naturally create, the members generally have
                    proceded in the path of duty indicated so unmistakeably by the determined and
                    over-powering sentiment of the country. The North American sums up the leading
                    measures of the session as follows:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The 39th Congress did not adjourn without having accomplished a great deal of
                        good work. Notwithstanding the check upon legislation that the President's
                        opposition would naturally create, the members generally have proceeded in
                        that path of duty indicated so unmistakably by the determined and
                        over-powering sentiment of the country. The <emph rend="italic">North
                            American</emph> sums up the leading measures of the session as follows:</p>
                    <p>1. The bill establishing universal and impartial suffrage in the District of
                        Columbia without distinction of race or color has become a law over the
                        President's veto, and the first election has been held under it, and has
                        resulted in a Republican triumph.</p>
                    <p>2. In like manner the bill establishing universal and impartial suffrage in
                        all the territories of the republic has been enacted into a law over the
                        veto, and thus terminates the validity of all territorial laws that
                        disfranchise a man on account of race or color. By the operation of this
                        bill the colored man will have a right to vote in Colorado despite the
                        unfriendly statutes of the territorial Legislature, and all efforts to
                        disfranchise the colored citizen in territories like New Mexico, Montana,
                        Arizona and Idaho are rendered useless. This act will not enfranchise the
                        Chinamen in California and Nevada, but it will have the effect of attracting
                        them from those States to the gold mining territories, where they will be
                        voters.</p>
                    <p>3. The Military Reconstruction bill, of which we have heretofore spoken at
                        length, has become a law over the veto. It establishes military protection
                        for freedmen and Union men in the South, fixes terms of readmission for the
                        rebel States, declares the existing governments of those States provisional,
                        and secures the right of suffrage forthwith to every adult colored man in
                        all the elections therein.</p>
                    <p>4. A bill to regulate the tenure of national civil offices has become a law
                        over the veto. It puts an end to the capricious removals for political
                        reasons that have disgraced the present Administration, and renders the
                        official no longer a mere dependent on the Executive pleasure. It deprives
                        the President of much of the power he has wielded for corrupt purposes.</p>
                    <p>5. The amendatory Tax bill has become a law, with the President's signature.
                        It reduces the income tax, the manufacturers tax, and many other imposts, to
                        the extent of at least seventy millions per annum.</p>
                    <p>6. An amendatory Tariff bill has been passed relating mainly to the duties on
                        wool and woolen goods, and intended to benefit chiefly the west.</p>
                    <p>7. Nebraska has been formerly admitted as a State, despite a Presidential
                        veto.</p>
                    <p>8. A bill has been passed authorizing an issue of loan certificates at a
                        little over three per cent. interest, to the extent of fifty millions of
                        dollars, to provide for the redemption of the accruing compound interest
                        notes.</p>
                    <p>9. An act has been passed providing for the suppression of the abominable
                        institution of peonage in New Mexico and other territories.</p>
                    <p>10. Payments to slaveholders for slaves enlisted as soldiers have been
                        directed to stop.</p>
                    <p>11. A national bankrupt law has been enacted.</p>
                    <p>12. All future danger of a legislative interregnum, such as happened in 1861,
                        at the outset of the rebellion, has been obviated by the passage of an act
                        providing for the meeting of every new Congress on the first day of its
                        term, March 4.</p>
                    <p>13. An act has been passed providing for the acceptance of League Island as a
                        site for the iron-clad naval station.</p>
                    <p>14. An act has been passed establishing a department of education as a part
                        of the national government.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article provides a brief summary of 14 bills passed by the 39th
                    Congress, ranging from the new regulations for suffrage rights to new
                    educational initiatives.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1867.03.13.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Davis Panorama of the Rebellion</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Harry H. Davis, "whose panorama of the Southern Republic has
                    won distinction both in the U. S. and Europe," will exhibit his show in
                    Chambersburg next Saturday and Monday evenings.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>Local Items--Church Dedication</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Forney</ln>
                        <fn>C. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Elder</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Church of God's new temple was dedicated last Sunday in a service that
                    included a sermon by Elder C. H. Forney, former pastor of the Congregation. The
                    new building was erected on the site of the old church, which was destroyed
                    during the July 30, 1864 raid on Chambersburg, and cost over $6,000 to
                    construct.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Handsome Presents</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kunkelman</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Relates that the Lutheran Congregation presented their pastor, Rev. J. A.
                    Kunkelman, with a "handsome and complete stone china dinner and tea set,
                    together with nearly one hundred dollars in greenbacks."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Bold Robberies</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Leisher</ln>
                        <fn>David F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reisner</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A thief broke into David F. Leisher's residence on West Market street last
                    Tuesday evening while he and his wife were asleep. The thief absconded with
                    Leisher's pocket-book, which, fortunately for Leisher, was empty. The same
                    night, John Reisner's home was entered illegally, but in this instance the
                    thief, who is thought to be the same person, made off with a silver watch and
                    two suits of clothing.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Borough Nominations</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Everett</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGrath</ln>
                        <fn>Allen C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maurer</ln>
                        <fn>B. Latrobe</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henninger</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilbert</ln>
                        <fn>Calvin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pearse</ln>
                        <fn>Nathan P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flack</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>J. Boyd</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houser</ln>
                        <fn>Michael W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davison</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCauley</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Leisher</ln>
                        <fn>David M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamman</ln>
                        <fn>Philip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pearse</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reges</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snider</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houser</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lists the men nominated to represent the Republican party in the upcoming
                    borough elections.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Washington Township</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walter</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Potter</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Summers</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bonebrake</ln>
                        <fn>Nicholas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Funk</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kriner</ln>
                        <fn>Valentine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kugler</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henicle</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Summers</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barr</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Resh</ln>
                        <fn>D. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>H. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lists the men from Washington township nominated for the Republican ticket.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Local Items--Personal</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>A. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>While en route to the state capital, Louis W. Hall, Speaker of the Senate,
                    and Morrow B. Lowry, Senator from Erie, visited Chambersburg last Friday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Pardoned</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bernthisel</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Gov. Geary has pardoned Mrs. Bernthisel, of Greencastle, for her adultery
                    conviction.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>John C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McFerren</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneck</ln>
                        <fn>B. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Feb. 18th, John C. Brown and Elizabeth McFerren were married by Rev. B.
                    S. Schneck.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Oyer</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneck</ln>
                        <fn>B. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On March 7th, Daniel Oyer and Elizabeth Brown were married by Rev. B. S.
                    Schneck.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carl</ln>
                        <fn>J. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pfoutz</ln>
                        <fn>Martha A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hassler</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On March 7th, J. F. Carl and Martha A. Pfoutz were married by Rev. J.
                    Hassler.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moor</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coons</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Feb. 14th, William Moor and Elizabeth Coons were married by Rev. J. B.
                    Jones.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>George</ln>
                        <fn>William C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKenzie</ln>
                        <fn>Nannie J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>S. H. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.'</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On William C. George and Nannie J. McKenzie were married by Rev. S. H. C.
                    Smith.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gipe</ln>
                        <fn>Susanna</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gipe</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On March 2nd, Susanna, consort of David Gipe, died in St. Thomas. She was
                    37 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snively</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Feb. 18th, John Snively died in Green township. He was 85 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1867.03.13.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
