<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1867/pa.fr.fr.1867.05.22">
    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>10/25</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1867-05-22">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day>22</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1867.05.22.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>8</column>
                <head>Anecdote of Stephen Girard</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An anecdote stressing the importance of learning a trade, which, if all
                    else fails, will provide a good living "to fall back upon."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>8</column>
                <head>Beauty of Irish Women</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The piece celebrates the beauty of the Irish women, and proclaims the Irish
                    race is as "strong as it is handsome, as vigorous as it is charming."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1867.05.22.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Tragedy And Farce</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>By an unfortunate combination of circumstances treason and rebellion have to
                        all appearances gained an important triumph. Open hostilities ceased two
                        years ago, but treason and rebellion are still actual realities
                        nevertheless, and still capable of receiving and inflicting injury. It may
                        be impossible for treason now to win a triumph that will restore to it its
                        lost power and give to rebellion the horrid front it once presented, yet it
                        can be revived and encouraged to such a degree that it may again boldly
                        assert itself and bring new trouble and disgrace to the Republic. For this
                        reason we deplore, in common with a vast majority of the loyal people of the
                        country, the summary release of Jefferson Davis.</p>
                    <p>No event has occurred since the disaster of Appomatox exploded the
                        Confederacy, that has so encouraged and emboldened those who gave themselves
                        to treason's work to seek someway out of its wreck to rise in. The huzzahs,
                        and jubilations, and general congratulations that followed Mr. Davis's
                        release were not unmeaning, but on the contrary illustrate beyond all
                        question the lingering devotion to treason, the enduring hostility to the
                        Republic and the cordial sympathy with its implacable foes that yet
                        characterize the people we have conquered. To them it was a triumph, not of
                        civil law over military force, as some of our own people have professed to
                        regard it, but of the Rebellion over the Republic--of treason over loyalty.
                        They gave to their joy the widest manifestation, not because of a
                        restoration of civil law, but because of this tacit acknowledgement that
                        treason is not a crime and that Rebellion can protect its own supporters.
                        Who can say that they deceive themselves in this when the Chief Conspirator
                        to-day travels through the land as free and undisturbed as the most trusted
                        loyalist?</p>
                    <p>There may be those whose natures are so fine and whose hearts are so full of
                        benevolence and human sympathy that they can see in this only a noble
                        magnanimity, and a commendable clemency on the part of an outraged
                        government. They may be right, but they are certainly not appreciated. The
                        people look upon the release of Davis as an outrage upon them; a mockery of
                        justice and law, and a triumph of treason. They know Davis as the head of a
                        great rebellion, the individual in whose name and by whose authority that
                        rebellion was conducted, and the one above all others responsible for the
                        unparalleled atrocities and barbarities that were perpetrated in its
                        interests. They have no legal knowledge of these facts it is true, but no
                        one will question that they are plain, open and palpable facts, at least
                        sufficiently evident to warrant his arrest and trial as an offender against
                        law and justice. They do not ask his punishment in advance of a fair and
                        impartial trial, but they do ask that the man to whom suspicion of such
                        horrible guilt attaches be held to answer, and if guilty, then punished
                        according to his deserts. Jefferson Davis was arrested two years ago,
                        charged with complicity in the assassination of President Lincoln. The
                        public prosecutor was President Johnson, who had him arrested and confined.
                        He preferred the charge, and by his orders he was detained in custody two
                        whole years. Why he was so long imprisoned without a trial, no one knows but
                        Mr. Johnson, who is solely responsible for whatever departure there has been
                        in this case from the usual and constitutional methods of procedure. We do
                        not justify this denial of rights, nor indeed can it be justified. The
                        prisoner has been within the power of the President ever since his arrest,
                        and a proper regard for the laws demanded his discharge, so far as this
                        particular offence was concerned, whenever it became evident that the charge
                        was unfounded. Others were tried and punished for participation in that
                        crime, why was not Jefferson Davis? We have all the Surratt tragedies; why
                        the Davis farce? But be this as it may, we have the fact that he was held as
                        prisoner of State beyond the reach of civil process, until the beginning of
                        the present month. He was then surrendered by Mr. Johnson, immediately to be
                        arrested on an indictment found, charging him with treason, the highest
                        crime known to the law. The prisoner's counsel were ready to proceed to
                        trial; the counsel for the government was likewise ready, but the private
                        counsel of Mr. Johnson asked for a continuance. It is not strange that the
                        prisoner asked for a release on bail, but that such a request should be
                        joined in, at least not resisted by, the opposing counsel, and be finally
                        granted by the Court, stamps the whole proceeding as a farce, amusing to
                        some no doubt, but an indignity and outrage upon the loyal people of the
                        country.</p>
                    <p>The fact of Davis's long imprisonment does not in the least relieve it of
                        this character. He was confined not upon a charge of treason, but for
                        suspected complicity in President Lincoln's assassination. He had never been
                        imprisoned a single day on suspicion of having committed any other offense.
                        Must the law deal more leniently with such a suspected criminal because he
                        has been suspected of other offences, heinous enough in all conscience, and
                        confined therefor? Ought not the officers of the law to be rather the more
                        vigilant and strict when dealing with such a man? Instead of this we see an
                        eagerness on the part of those concerned to aid the prisoner to his freedom
                        and to make the farce as disgusting to loyalty as possible. This eagerness
                        ill became the Judge who presided, the council who should have prosecuted
                        and several of the bondsmen who should have been about their own business.</p>
                    <p>We fail to see one single reason why Jefferson Davis should be set at
                        liberty, and can detect not even one circumstance in his case that could
                        appeal to the generous, magnanimous or the philanthropic for interference.
                        As it is, immunity is granted to treason and the law cheated of its victim.
                        A disgusting farce has followed close upon a painful tragedy, and while
                        thousand of brave spirits sleep in the dust and thousands of others linger
                        out a painful existence for the crimes which this one man perpetrated, he
                        walks up and down unrestrained, protected in his life, his person and his
                        property.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In no unclear terms, the editors condemn the decision to release Jeff
                    Davis, which they construe as a signal to southerners who continue to reject the
                    authority of the federal government that "treason is not a crime."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Demagogsim</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Assailing the Presidential aspirants for their attempts to solicit votes,
                    the editorial lambastes the men for their ambitions.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Far Off Chats With Old Friends</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In this installment in his series of correspondence, McClure details the
                    segment of his journey between Omaha and Denver, during which time the specter
                    of possible Indian attacks kept the Repository owner and his entourage
                    continuously on guard.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Harrisburg</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Horace</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>"Horace" welcomes the apparent willingness of Republicans throughout the
                    state to re-evaluate the character of their representatives in the wake of the
                    previous legislative session. If the representatives are not "made to feel that
                    there is such a thing as personal accountability to their constituents for all
                    their official acts," he notes, "we can but expect a repetition of the
                    recklessness which characterized our last legislature."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1867.05.22.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Good Templars' Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brownson</ln>
                        <fn>R. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turner</ln>
                        <fn>John R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Creigh</ln>
                        <fn>Ella D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rockafellow</ln>
                        <fn>C. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coyle</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tolbert</ln>
                        <fn>William E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thrush</ln>
                        <fn>E. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schlosser</ln>
                        <fn>N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gorley</ln>
                        <fn>H. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Murray</ln>
                        <fn>Ada</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wanamaker</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heck</ln>
                        <fn>Hennie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn>G. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dorn</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Relates that the Cumberland Valley Quarterly Convention, which includes
                    delegates from the local chapters in Cumberland, Franklin, and Fulton counties,
                    met in the Hall of McMurray Lodge on last Wednesday and elected officers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Sheep Disease</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that at the meeting of the Philadelphia Society for Promoting
                    Agriculture held on May 1st, Dr. McClure advised the organization the "Cachesia
                    Agusea, or Rot," an illness reportedly caused "by the sheep feeding on low, wet
                    marshy lands which generate the common fluke worm in ducts of the liver."
                    According to McClure's estimates, in 1829 or 1830, the disease infected two
                    million sheep in France, and now it has broken out in West Chester.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Laying on of Hands</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heller</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dessam</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eckert</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Etter</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keyler</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Goldsmith</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bushman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shank</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The article reports that several local residents have been cured of their
                    ailments after visiting a healer currently staying at the National Hotel.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Horse Thief Arrested</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houser</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Officer</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Officer Houser arrested a horse thief named Isaac Shaffer last Sunday after
                    receiving a hand bill sent out by the animal's owner, James Menown, of Allegheny
                    county, Pa. Houser caught Shaffer at Gordon's Hotel when he noticed that the
                    horse he was riding fit the description of the bill. Shaffer was brought before
                    Justice McElwain and committed to jail while awaiting transfer to Allegheny.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Be Prepared For The Cholera</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Warns readers that the "cholera season" is approaching, and urges them to
                    take the necessary precautions to avert an outbreak of the disease in Franklin
                    county.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Gypsies</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article reports that gypsies arrived in Chambersburg last week, and
                    notes that the gang of "roving malcontents" engaged in their "usual a avocations
                    of fortune-telling," "horse-trading," and "pilfering."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Child Lost</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Considerable excitement was generated last Saturday when a child went
                    missing and was presumed carried off by the Gypsies who were in town. The child
                    was found later that afternoon "quietly sleeping under a bed in a neighbor's
                    house."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Pennsylvania Reserves</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that the Pennsylvania Reserves Association will meet in
                    Harrisburg on May 30th where "a grand time is anticipated."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Not Sold</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The sale of the Old Market was postponed, says the article, after residents
                    in South Wared objected. Equally important is the fact that subscriptions to the
                    new market house are not "very encouraging."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--I. O. G. T.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brownson</ln>
                        <fn>R. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Atherton</ln>
                        <fn>I. Y.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Creigh</ln>
                        <fn>Ella D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stick</ln>
                        <fn>M. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shirts</ln>
                        <fn>Junie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Long</ln>
                        <fn>A. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stine</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fauss</ln>
                        <fn>F. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Murray</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whetstone</ln>
                        <fn>A. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bradley</ln>
                        <fn>Eliza</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burkholder</ln>
                        <fn>Eliza</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKinistry</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Agnew</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>At the last meeting of the I. O. G. T. Mercersburg Lodge, No. 285, John
                    Gilmore installed a number of officers for the quarter commencing May 1st.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Street Sprinkler</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKinly</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The businessmen whose shops are on Main Street between Washington and King
                    have made arrangements with William H. McKinly to sprinkle the street in front
                    of their shops.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Immersion</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunter</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Ten people converted last Sunday during the revival at the Church of God,
                    reports the article. The newly blessed were immersed in Conococheague Creek by
                    Rev. Hunter.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Attack On Judge Kelly</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>MOBILE, ALA., May 14, midnight.--A murderous and bloody affair occurred here
                        this evening. A desperate attack was made upon Judge Kelley and the body of
                        gentlemen who surrounded him, on the steps of the Old Court-house, at the
                        corner of Government and Royal streets, during the meeting held this
                        evening.</p>
                    <p>The Judge had been speaking about a quarter of an hour in a frank and
                        temperate manner, when there appeared to be a disposition to create a
                        disturbance on the outskirts of the meeting. Cries of "put him down" were
                        heard, to which Mr. Kelley replied: "I tell you that you cannot put me down.
                        The 15th infantry are at my back, and if they cannot keep the peace in
                        Mobile, the United States army can."</p>
                    <p>The tumult suddenly broke out at this point by a sudden rush toward the
                        platform, and a general scattering of the crowd. About 100 people were on
                        the platform, including many eminent citizens, reporters of the local press,
                        and the correspondent of the New York <emph rend="italic">Herald</emph>, who
                        sat beside Judge Kelley, and the correspondent of the Philadelphia <emph
                            rend="italic">Inquirer</emph>. This rush seemed to be the signal for the
                        melee to commence. The Chief of Police attempted to arrest a ringleader on
                        the borders of the crowd, and he drew a pistol on him. The cry of "fire" was
                        then raised at the corner of Royal street, and instantly a perfect fusillade
                        of pistols was opened on the crowd who occupied the platform. In a moment a
                        colored man who stood beside your correspondent fell, being struck in the
                        head. Again the cry of "Oh, God!" and a heavy fall announced that an other
                        had been laid low. Some friends dragged Judge Kelley from out of the range
                        of fire, and finally succeeded in getting him away unharmed.</p>
                    <p>For several minutes the fire continued to be directed to the platform, the
                        occupants of which were hastily making their escape, while others endeavored
                        to protect themselves by getting behind the table, which afforded little
                        protection, and those nearest the platform were evidently firing under it.
                        One man was badly wounded by a shot thus aimed, and a ball glanced off a
                        water bucket which fortunately stood between your correspondent's head and
                        the assassin's benevolent intentions.</p>
                    <p>The firing, by this time, was directed right and left among the crowd in the
                        street, who were flying in all directions. There seemed to be no attempt on
                        the part of the police to arrest the violence, or if there was it was
                        ineffectual, for the rebels had it all their own way.</p>
                    <p>It is impossible to tell, at this hour, how many were shot. I saw three fall
                        in my immediate vicinity, but I occupied the place of a target. I saw one
                        poor boy carried off the ground, moaning piteously.</p>
                    <p>It was evidently a preconcerted affair, and was probably stimulated by
                        incendiary articles in the rebel press for the past few days.</p>
                    <p>Col. Shepperd, who commands the military here, at once dispatched a body of
                        troops to the Battle House, where Judge Kelley is stopping. There are now on
                        the ground in front of the hotel, where Col. Shepperd has taken up quarters
                        for the night.</p>
                    <p>The city at present is quiet. The Republican party is not as strong here as
                        New Orleans. All the municipal offices are filled by secessionists, whose
                        hostility to the government has not abated a jot.</p>
                    <p>Judge Kelley very coolly descended from the platform, amid the fire, pushed
                        his way through the crowd, reached his hotel in safety, his only disguise
                        being your correspondent's hat, who subsequently got off with the only hat
                        left on the table, which fortunately proved to be Mr. Kelley's, and,
                        therefore, there was no loss of property in hats.</p>
                    <p>MOBILE, May 15--During the melee last night the following were killed and
                        wounded:</p>
                    <p>Killed--Tabril Alsen, white, and Samuel Britton, colored.</p>
                    <p>Wounded--Whites--Thomas Taylor, D. H. Hord; David Parsons, of the police; two
                        boys; James Barnes, and Colonel D. S. Sedbury, a goldsmith. I. Gough is
                        reported having since died.</p>
                    <p>Dr. Nicholson, colored; Pierce Mitchell, and a number of men, both whites and
                        colored, were slightly injured, whose names could not be ascertained.</p>
                    <p>Judge Kelley was invited by Mayor Withers to remain and speak, offering the
                        protection of all good citizens. Col. Shepperd also offered protection. The
                        Judge declined, and left for Montgomery to-day.</p>
                    <p>A call will appear in to-morrow morning's papers, signed by many of the best
                        citizens of Mobile, for a meeting, to express unqualified condemnation of
                        the parties engaged in the disturbance of the Republican meeting last
                    night.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>While on tour of the South, relates the piece, Judge Kelly was attacked by
                    a mob in Mobile, Alabama. The "tumult" started during a speech delivered by the
                    judge when a group of onlookers rushed the stage. Soon after the outbreak of
                    violence, guns shots were fired sending the crowd off in a panic. Scores of
                    people were killed or seriously injured in the mayhem, though Kelly escaped
                    unharmed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mowers</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn>Jennett B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>S. H. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On May 16th, Samuel A. Mowers ands Jennett B. King were married by Rev. S.
                    H. C. Smith.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1867.05.22.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
