<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1865/pa.fr.vs.1865.02.08">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Amy Murrell</taggerName>
            <tagDate>1/18/98</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1865-02-08">
            <year>1865</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day norm="08">8</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1865.02.08.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Adaptation to the Land</head>
                <origin>Agriculturalist</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reminds farmers that different breeds of cattle require different types of
                    soil and climates. Care should be taken to ensure that their cattle can adapt to
                    their land.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Household Notes for February</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lists tasks that should be accomplished in February, such as preparing
                    spring and summer clothing and making sure children receive schooling.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Report of Franklin county expenditures and receipts for 1864, columns 1-3,
                classified ads, columns 3-5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1865.02.08.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Gen. A. H. Coffroth</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"By this vote he has severed his connection with the party that elected him
                    to his present position. . . . The Democracy never again trust where they have
                    once been betrayed."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>This gentleman has recently added another name to the already somewhat
                        extended list of those, who, on obtaining positions of trust and prominence
                        through the Democratic party, have abandoned its principles and betrayed
                        those who have elevated them to such positions. It would appear in these
                        latter days to require stern virtue in a Representative of the people to
                        withstand the allurements of the party in power. The scent of the fleshpots,
                        it seems, overpowers many of the weaker brethren, and principle, honor,
                        honesty, and all those virtues, which to many, are above all price, are
                        sacrificed with an ease that is astonishing to honest men. The Democracy of
                        Pennsylvania, during the past several years, have sent their full share of
                        men of easy virtue to represent them in the councils of the nation and in
                        the present Congress, three districts of the State have been betrayed. We
                        were not much surprised at the defection of Bailey at the last session, as
                        his Democracy was more than questionable at the time of his election; nor
                        could we be very much astonished at any vote Archibald McAllister might
                        cast, inasmuch as it is notorious that ever since his advent at Washington
                        his principal business has been to secure a contract for himself, and that
                        he was disposed to vote almost any way to secure his object; but that Gen.
                        Coffroth could prove faithless to a confiding constituency, was to us, until
                        quite recently, almost past belief.</p>
                    <p>It will be seen by the vote on the Amendment to the Constitution of the
                        United States abolishing slavery, published in another column, that Gen.
                        Coffroth's name is recorded among those of the Abolitionists in favor of the
                        Amendment. By this vote he has severed his connection with the party that
                        elected him to his present position, and although in the reasons given by
                        him for his vote he claims to have given it "for the good of [the]
                        Democratic party," we incline to the belief that but few Democrats in the
                        16th Congressional District can be convinced that the good of the party will
                        be advanced by a vote in favor of its enemies and in direct opposition tot
                        he position of the party ever since its organization. The position of the
                        Democratic party on the slavery question, has ever been--and at no time more
                        so that [sic] the present--the true one, and Gen. Coffroth can no more
                        remain a Democrat and vote with the enemies of his party and his country,
                        than a man can remain a Christian, and yet yield a willing support to the
                        Devil whenever he may require his help. The Democratic party has ever held
                        that Congress had neither the power nor the right to interfere with slavery.
                        It was established by the local laws of States in which it existed, and was
                        left by the framers of the Constitution to the States themselves. It could
                        therefore only be controlled by the States. This policy of letting slavery
                        alone was the true policy, and it was part of the mission of the Democratic
                        party to prevent if possible, the occurrence of such a series of disasters,
                        as have been precipitated upon us by the fanatical crew now in power. The
                        Democratic party merely insisted upon the observance of the provisions of
                        the fundamental law of the land. It was, as it still prides itself on being,
                        the constitutional party of the country. The Constitution was the Bible of
                        its political creed, to which it conscientiously squared every act of its
                        political life. It knew no North and no South, but legislated and labored
                        diligently for the good of a common country. It never denounced the
                        Constitution because slavery was recognized and protected by it; but obeyed
                        its every behest, claiming for the General Government only such powers as
                        were conferred upon it, and leaving to the States the regulation of their
                        domestic affairs, slavery included.</p>
                    <p>In opposition to this we have had a party in the country laboring unceasingly
                        for the abolition of slavery in violation of the letter and spirit of the
                        Constitution. It is to the efforts of this party and its accession to power
                        in consequence of unfortunate division among the Democracy in 1860, that the
                        present deplorable condition of our country is, to a considerable extent,
                        attributable. And now that these fanatics have obtained power and have
                        originated the scheme of altering the Constitution, when the Southern States
                        can have no voice in a matter which they consider of vital importance, and
                        which must have the effect of retarding their return to their allegiance, we
                        find men in Congress, claiming to be Democrats, voting with these people,
                        and assisting in the consummation of an act which will be the greatest
                        obstacle the seceded States will have to overcome, in returning to the
                        Union.</p>
                    <p>We may have more to say on this subject hereafter, one thing the
                        representative of the 16th District can rely on, his political grave is open
                        for his reception, and the sooner he gets into it the better. The Democracy
                        Never Again Trust Where They Have Once Been Betrayed.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coffroth</ln>
                        <fn>A. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lambastes Gen. A. H. Coffroth, member of the US House of Representatives
                    representing Franklin county, for betraying the Democratic party by voting for
                    an amendment to abolish slavery.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Rev. Daniel Steck</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We challenge the annals of history to produce a worse case of bigoted
                    intolerance, and persecution for opinion's sake, taking into consideration that
                    we live in the nineteenth century of the Christian era, and in the free Republic
                    of North America."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Steck</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Steck</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Expresses outrage at the vote of the Lutheran Church Council to expel Rev.
                    Daniel Steck from the church for voting for General George McClellan. Steck, the
                    brother of Rev. Jacob Steck, once was the pastor of the Lutheran congregation in
                    Chambersburg before he left for Dayton, Ohio.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Louisville Democrat</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"One of the charges against the party shows its merits. It would not use
                    the power of the Federal Government to the credit of one class of States and the
                    discredit of another. It would not make war on the institutions of one class of
                    States to gratify the other."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Defends the Democratic party from ongoing criticism from the Republicans.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Vote to Amend the Constitution</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prints the results from the vote of the US House of Representatives on
                    January 31 that approved an amendment to abolish slavery by a 119-56 vote. Rep.
                    A. H. Coffroth, who represents Chambersburg, voted for the amendment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Congressional</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reviews recent proceedings of the US Congress, including consideration of
                    proposals to reconsider the draft quota of Rhode Island and to build a ship
                    canal around Niagara Falls.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Dispatches reporting on peace talks, column 7, report of skirmishing in South
                Carolina, column 71</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1865.02.08.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Draft</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The quotas we think can be filled with volunteers if the proper measures
                    are taken."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lists draft quotas for each of the townships in Franklin county as
                    established by Lincoln's latest call for troops: Antrim, 79; Greencastle, 28;
                    Chambersburg, NW, 77; Chambersburg, SW, 73; Fannet, 20; Green, 70; Guilford, 75;
                    Hamilton, 28; Letterkenny, 52; Lurgan, 17; Metal, 12; Montgomery, 75;
                    Mercersburg, 19; Peters, 50; Quincy, 69; St. Thomas, 46; Southampton, 40;
                    Warren, 4; Washington, 56; Waynesboro, 25. Total draft quota for Franklin
                    county, 915.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>United Brethren Conference</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dixon</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burd</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf>P.E.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Colestock</ln>
                        <fn>Z. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bishop</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>T. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hummelbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>H. Y.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bingham</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Slichter</ln>
                        <fn>H. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shoaff</ln>
                        <fn>J. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clem</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces the appointments made by the Pennsylvania Conference of the
                    Church of the United Brethren in Christ at its annual session on January 19. For
                    the Chambersburg district, the conference appointed J. W. Burd, P.E., and the
                    following: J. Dixon, Chambersburg Station; Z. A. Colestock, Big Spring; J. M.
                    Bishop, Rocky Spring; J. C. Smith, Greencastle Circuit; T. F. Smith, St. Thomas;
                    H. Y. Hummelbaugh, Newburg; S. Bingham, Carlisle; H. A. Slichter, Shippensburg;
                    J. G. Shoaff, Littlestown; J. B. Jones, Path Valley; J. A. Clem, Bendersville
                    Mission. Appointments for Alto Dale and Carlisle Mission Station have yet to be
                    made.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Militia Law</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges anyone who can claim an exemption under the "Act for the
                    organization, discipline, and regulation of the militia of the Commonwealth of
                    Pennsylvania" to act soon. Describes procedures for obtaining these exemptions,
                    which are available to men with a "physical defect," "bodily infirmity," or who
                    are otherwise exempted under Pennsylvania or US law.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Defeated</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the Pennsylvania legislature defeated a resolution requesting
                    the US Congress to pass a law requiring that each township fill its draft quota
                    with bona fide residents.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Southern Determination</head>
                <origin>New York Times</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We may as well open our eyes to the fact that the Southern leaders hate us
                    as the Turk hates the Gisour, as the Crusader used to hate the Jew, and that it
                    is only natural that a feeling of this sort, instead of being abated by reverse,
                    should be intensified, and should animate those who are under its influence to
                    greater efforts for its gratification than ever."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Tries to explain why it is that southerners have not given up despite their
                    huge losses on the battlefield.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mahon</ln>
                        <fn>Hattie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mahon</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Howe</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maclay</ln>
                        <fn>C. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On January 26, Rev. W. Howe married Hattie Mahon, daughter of Robert Mahon,
                    Esq., and Dr. C. T. Maclay.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>P. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seilhamer</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clugston</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Agnes</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. P. S. Davis married John Seilhamer and Mary Agnes Clugston on February
                    2.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>P. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maltby</ln>
                        <fn>William J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hendricks</ln>
                        <fn>Aletha J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. P. S. Davis married William J. Maltby and Aletha J. Hendricks on
                    January 18.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dyson</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Oliver</ln>
                        <fn>William M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rinehart</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William M. Oliver and Susan Rinehart, of Shippensburg, were married on
                    February 2 by Rev. F. Dyson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dyson</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deran</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fletcher</ln>
                        <fn>Sadie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. F. Dyson married Charles Deran, of Reading, to Sadie Fletcher on
                    February 6.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnhart</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ridgley</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. Thomas Barnhart married Charles Ridgley and Catharine Snyder on
                    February 2.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnhart</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zein</ln>
                        <fn>Jeremiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henry</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. Thomas Barnhart married Jeremiah Zein and Elizabeth Henry on February
                    5.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bishop</ln>
                        <fn>James M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thrush</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel Webster</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bollinger</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. James M. Bishop married Daniel Webster Thrust, Esq., Editor and
                    Proprietor of the Shippensburg News, to Mary Ann Bollinger on February 2.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Krebs</ln>
                        <fn>W. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moser</ln>
                        <fn>Josiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClain</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. W. E. Krebs married Josiah Moser and Sarah Jane McClain on February 2.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brotherton</ln>
                        <fn>James H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allen</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allen</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James H. Brotherton, son of Henry and Mary Allen, died on January 25 at age
                    1 year and 23 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burkholder</ln>
                        <fn>William W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William W. Burkholder died on January 22 at age 37.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 3-7</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1865.02.08.04">
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 1-7</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
