<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1865/pa.fr.vs.1865.08.02">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/03/99</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1865-08-02">
            <year>1865</year>
            <month norm="08">August</month>
            <day norm="00">02</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1865.08.02.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>President Johnson's Inherited Cabinet</head>
                <origin>New York World</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p> The country has practiced toward Mr. Johnson a more generous forbearance
                        than has been accorded to any other President since Washington. This is less
                        a attribute to the man, than a patriotic impulse set in action by the
                        appalling circumstances of his accession. Under that sudden shock the
                        country, for the first time, was alarmed for the existence of the
                        government. The instant unanimity with which all parties stood by the new
                        President was a protest against assassination, against anarchy, against
                        attempts to change the <emph rend="italic">personnel</emph> of the
                        government or the politics of the country except by the republican methods
                        of free discussion and regular elections. Nothing more creditable has ever
                        occurred in our history. But the danger which struck us all with sudden
                        dismay is past; and henceforward President Johnson, like every ruler of a
                        free people, must encounter the criticism by which responsibility is
                        enforced upon public officers. </p>
                    <p>There has been, thus far, a disposition to discriminate between President
                        Johnson and his official advisers. These advisers were not of his
                        appointment, and it was presumed that their stay in the cabinet was a
                        temporary convenience. If he had intented to keep them, it was assumed he
                        would control them; and it was impossible to believe that the outrageous
                        acts of Secretary Stanton were approved by any honest statesman sworn to
                        defend the Consitution. It was easy to se how, in closing a great war and
                        settling a great mass of unfinished business, the services of an officer
                        familiar with its details might be valuable, especially as the President had
                        no personal connection with the administration of the war. With the great
                        mass of new business emerging, he could not afford to master the unwieldly
                        details of a system that had served its day and was falling into disuse.
                        Shockingly as Stanton had violated the Constitution, it was not difficult to
                        discover possible reasons for his temporary retention. But Mr. Johnson is in
                        his fourth month; and, for aught that appears, the Cabinet is as firmly
                        seated under him as under his predecessor who appointed it. An indulgent
                        country cannot much much longer consent to distinguish between acts of the
                        administration and acts of the responsible chief. If the most conspicuious
                        and offensive heads of the departments are to go with Mr. Johson through his
                        term, or through any large and considerable part of it, the country is
                        justified in concluding that he keeps them because he approves of their
                        conduct; that their acts are his acts; and that he ought to be help
                        responsible for their usurpations.</p>
                    <p>The country will come reluctantly to this conclusion. Even after its
                        confidence is shaken, it will, for a long while, hope against hope. But
                        certain it is, that this people, cradled in liberty, will stand by no man
                        who abandons the principles of the Constitution. The subordintation of the
                        military to to the civil power, goverment by law insted of goverment by
                        arbitrary will, the [unclear] a free press, and free elections, will be
                        resolutely claimed; and no man or party can stand who are faithless to these
                        guarantees. Great allowance was made, during the war, for the difficulties
                        of the situation; but the plea of an over-ruling public necessity will no
                        longer avail. The people now demand that the officers sworn to support the
                        Constitution shall keep their oaths. They they will give their confidence to
                        no public officer who is deliberately recreant to republican principles of
                        government.</p>
                    <p>On one great subject President Johnson satisifies the just expectations of
                        the country. If he stands by his recognition of State governments, the
                        people will support him till that battle is won. But the other great
                        question of the supremacy of the law is too urgent to be much longer
                        adjourned; and considering how the law had been trampled under foot, defied,
                        and spit upon, even since Mr.Johnson's accession, we can see no other
                        suitable atonement than a removal of the offending members of the Cabinet,
                        and filling their places with honest, law-abiding citizens.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Having assumed the country's helm in the midst of a terrible crisis,
                    President Johnson benefitted from the people's reluctance to criticize a new
                    president. Four months have passed, however, and now, the article contends, it
                    is time for the honeymoon to end. Johnson's decision to keep the cabinet he
                    inherited from his predecessor made sense under the circumstances, but if he
                    chooses to retain those officials, many of whom have brought disrepute to the
                    administration--namely Secretary Stanton--then the president must account for
                    the actions of these individuals as though they were his own selections.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Georgia and Reconstruction</head>
                <origin>Atlanta Intelligencer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lauds the appointment of Herschel V. Johnson as Georgia's Provisional
                    Governor, and declares that, with a few solitary exceptions, most of the state's
                    whites are prepared to accept the terms prescribed by President Johnson's
                    Reconstruction policy in order to return to the Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Reorganization of the Democratic Party</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The restoration of the Union is political death and burial to the
                    Republican party. By no possibility can it survive that event."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Now that the rebellion has been put down, the political life of the
                    Republican Party is nearly extinguished. In its place, the article insists, the
                    Democratic Party, the only true national party, will soon resume its pre-war
                    position of dominance. Though some commentators claim that the Democrats will
                    have to be reconstructed with a new, post-bellum image, the writer disputes all
                    such assertions.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>President Johnson's Provisional Governors</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The general testimony which reaches us from the South is to the effect
                    that the 'provisional governors' whom [President Johnson] has appointed really
                    possess the confidence of the people over whose return to the Union they are to
                    preside."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Castigates those individuals and groups who have criticized President
                    Johnson's selections for provisional governors, and suggests that it is not
                    important whether the nominees are acceptable to the residents of Massachusetts
                    or Iowa. Rather, it is the views of the Southerners that are most relevant.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Progress of the Two Great Improvements</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on the progress of the Atlantic Cable and the Pacific Railroad,
                    both of which will have an enormous impact on the country when complete.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1865.08.02.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>President Johnson and Reconstruction</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In contrast to the war, the problems posed by Reconstruction will be more
                    difficult to solve because they cannot be corrected simply by marshalling armies
                    and equipment. The article supports President Johnson's efforts to reunite the
                    country and chastises Radical Republicans for erecting a variety of obstacles to
                    impede the achievement of his goal.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>"Micawber Democracy"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Objects to a piece printed in the Repository that mocks President Johnson
                    and his Democratic sympathies.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In response to an article that appeared in the Repository some weeks
                    earlier, in which Democrats were castigated for their belief that the
                    declaration that all men are created equal pertained only to whites, the Spirit
                    admonishes their Republican rivals for their ignorance. Not until "the advent of
                    Abolitionism as political power but a few years ago," the Democratic organ
                    states, did the notion that blacks have any sort of rights exist.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Radical Programme--A New Source of Revolution</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The radicals should beware, for the moment they start the disunion
                    programme, based on negro suffrage, that moment will seal their fate as the
                    originators of disunion, war, and all the ills under which the nation has so
                    long suffered."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Denounces the Radicals and their efforts to force black suffrage upon white
                    America. The article casts the Reconstruction program, as advocated by the
                    "radical element" in Congress, as a plot contrived by extremists bent on
                    punishing white southerners. The Spirit alleges that the growing conflict
                    between those who support President Johnson and those who endorse the Radicals
                    threatens to return the country to war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Gen. Sherman and Negro Suffrage</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Applauds General Sherman for his stand regarding the question of black
                    suffrage. The "most brilliant soldier of modern times" discussed his views in a
                    speech delivered in Indianapolis, where he confirmed his opposition to granting
                    freedmen the vote. Additionally, the general stated his support for a plan to
                    colonize blacks in Florida.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>A Black Ram</head>
                <origin>Louisville Democrat</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article gives a scathing physical description of a black soldier
                    court-martialed for falling asleep at his post.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>How The Shoddy Broth Is Mixed</head>
                <origin>New York Tribune; Patriot and Union</origin>
                <commentary>"The New York Tribune discourses, as follows, about the incongruous
                    admixture of radicalism, shoddy, and all the other odds and ends of the "loyal"
                    party in Pennsylvania."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The intra-party conflict among the various Republican factions is coming to
                    a head in Philadelphia where three competing interest groups--the Radicals, the
                    city's Congressmen, and the Cameron-Forney camp--are battling to appoint their
                    supporters to important patronage positions.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"This is the blackest kind of black mailing by the blacks."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Provides the details of a law passed the winter before in Massachusetts
                    that levies a fine of fifty dollars on every landlord who refuses to allow his
                    black boarders to sit at the table with him and his white guests. The article
                    maintains that several blacks have made a "small fortune" by taking advantage of
                    the law.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Republicans in Pennsylvania have settled on a platform that includes a
                    demand for black suffrage throughout the South, and a change in Pennsylvania's
                    constitution granting equal political rights to blacks and whites.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1865.08.02.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Franklin and Marshall College</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wickersham</ln>
                        <fn>M. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyer</ln>
                        <fn>Cyrus</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cole</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Van Bokkelen</ln>
                        <fn>Libertus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stenger</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mays</ln>
                        <fn>Cyrus V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Steiner</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cessna</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Buchanan</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Ex-President</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On July 26th, the twenty-ninth commencement for Franklin and Marshall
                    College was held in Lancaster. Eighteen students received the Degree of A. M. in
                    course, while Capt. M. D. Wickersham was presented with an honorary title of
                    this degree. The honorary Degree of A.B. was awarded to Cyrus Boyer, Esq., and
                    the title of D.D. was bestowed upon Rev. David Cole, a professor of Greek at
                    Rutgers College. Rev. Libertus Van Bokkelen was conferred the L.L.D.. W. S.
                    Stenger delivered the biennial address before the Literary Societies; Cyrus V.
                    Mays provided the Master's oration; and Dr. Lewis H. Steiner presented the
                    Alumni address. Ex-President Buchanan resigned his Presidency of the Board of
                    Trustees. The position was assumed by John Cessna.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Pennsylvania College</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The catalogue for Pennsylvania College has come out for 1864-65, listing 16
                    Seniors, 15 Juniors, 18 Sophomore, 15 Freshmen, and 51 Preparations. The
                    commencement will be held in the second week of August, beginning with the
                    Baccalaureates Discourse on August 6th, given by Rev. Dr. Baugher. The Junior
                    Exhibition is scheduled for the morning of the 9th and the Biennial Address
                    before the Philomethean Society, presented by Prof. R. W. Hitchcock, on the same
                    day. That afternoon, the Biennial Address of the Phrenakosmian Society will be
                    performed by William B. Sprague, D. D. Rev. M. Valentine will deliver the Annual
                    Address before the Alumni of the College in the evening. The Commencement
                    exercises will take place on the morning of the 10th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Death of Wm. M. Beetem</head>
                <origin>Carlisle Volunteer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beetem</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hassler</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Underwood</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Wm. M. Beetem, a cashier at the Carlisle Deposit Bank, committed suicide by
                    hanging himself in the garret of his dwelling. Mr. Beetem's lifeless body was
                    discovered by two of his co-workers, Mr. Hassler and Mr. Underwood.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Struck by Lightning</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolfe</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On July 28th, lightning struck the barn on the farm of the Misses Beatty,
                    severely shocking Jacob Wolfe, who was inside the structure. Mr.Wolfe suffered
                    no serious injuries, but the barn and its contents were destroyed, incurring
                    $2,500 worth of damage.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Negro Camp Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>On August 19th, blacks intend on holding a camp meeting near Shippensburg.
                    The brief piece warns its readers that several "riots may confidently be
                    expected."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McHenry</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fox</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>Charlotte E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On July 26th, Charles Fox, of Conshohocken, Montgomery county, married
                    Charlotte Eyster at the bride's parents' house. The service was presided over by
                    Rev. S. McHenry.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McHenry</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Haulman</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rupert</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George Haulman, of St. Thomas, and Mary E. Rupert, of Hamilton township,
                    were married on July 27th, by Rev. S. McHenry.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dosh</ln>
                        <fn>Cyrus W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McHenry</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gelwicks</ln>
                        <fn>Louisa M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On July 27th, Rev. S. McHenry served as the minister in the marriage
                    ceremony that united Cyrus W. Dosh to Louisa M. Gelwicks, both of Guilford
                    township.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dyson</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Downy</ln>
                        <fn>Patrick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duke</ln>
                        <fn>Jane M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>At a ceremony presided over by Rev. F. Dyson on July 27th, Patrick Downy,
                    of Middleton, New York, wed Jane M. Duke.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henneberger</ln>
                        <fn>Julia Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henneberger</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Julia Ann Henneberger, 57, died in Newville, on July 16th. Henneberger is
                    survived by her husband Peter.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parks</ln>
                        <fn>Nancy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On July 9th, Mrs. Nancy Parks, 63, died in St. Thomas.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1866.08.02.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
