<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1865/pa.fr.vs.1865.01.25">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Amy Murrell</taggerName>
            <tagDate>1/15/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1865-01-25">
            <year>1865</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day norm="00">25</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1865.01.25.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>How Cavalry Cover a Retreat</head>
                <origin>Correspondence Cincinnati Commercial</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Essay explains strategies undertaken by successful cavalrymen.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Now is the Time to Pay Debts</head>
                <origin>Prairie Farmer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"It will be a glorious epoch when the people of these prairies own their
                    farms, and this we believe may at once be, if proper advantage be taken of the
                    times in which we now live."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Suggests that these inflationary times are ideal for the farmer trying to
                    get out of debt.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 1-3, poetry, column 4, reports from New York,
                Tennessee, and Massachusetts, column 6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1865.01.25.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>To Our Patrons -- Special Notice</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Explains that the high price of paper will make it necessary to raise the
                    Valley Spirit's subscription prices. Asks anyone indebted to the paper to please
                    pay up as soon as possible.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Convention of Publishers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that a convention of newspaper publishers will take place in
                    Harrisburg on February 9. Notes that discussing how to urge Congress to help
                    printers and publishers will be the main item of business.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Costs of War</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"If the same energy and expenditure had been used in developing the
                    resources of the country, increasing the facilities of intercommunication and
                    adding to all the various means of moral, intellectual and physical improvement,
                    as has been in the civil war which has been consuming our accumulated wealth, it
                    would have made us not only the strongest nation upon the face of the earth, but
                    added vastly to the individual well being of the people."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Ponders what progress could be made if the million men now fighting the war
                    focused their energy instead on developing the nation's resources.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Peace Rumors Again</head>
                <origin>Age</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"If they assume that the whole negotiation must necessarily rest upon the
                    slavery issue, they will take a short, narrow and unstatesmanlike view of the
                    matter."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Acknowledges reports of Confederate President Davis calling for peace
                    negotiations and encourages the US government to consider more issues than
                    slavery in any attempt at reconciliation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Taxing Labor</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"It goes out of its way searching after a few cents revenue from some poor
                    and needy man, and leaves the income of the rich untouched."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Calls the new law taxing incomes "wholly unjust."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The war has brought many sufferings, trials, and burdens to the people of
                    the North in the past, but severe as have been its lessons, we are daily the
                    more strongly confirmed in our belief that its hardships have only commenced."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that rumors are circulating about Republican support for
                    discontinuing bounties for US soldiers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Pennsylvania</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lists the valuation of real and personal estate, the assessment of tax on
                    that property, and the number of taxable inhabitants in each of Pennsylvania's
                    counties. Franklin county is listed with $12, 674,963 in real and personal
                    estate, $32,723.47 in assessed taxes, and 9,459 taxable inhabitants.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Reports on troop movements in South Carolina and Georgia, columns
            6-7</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1865.01.25.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Draft</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Outlines the rules surrounding exemptions from the draft, including the
                    exclusion of men under age 20 and over age 45.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Cheap Ice House</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Explains how anyone living near a water course can build an ice house to
                    hold a cube of ten feet square for only ten dollars.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Court Proceedings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Creasler</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bitner</ln>
                        <fn>Simon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stenger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharpe</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stewart</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garner</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sollenberger</ln>
                        <fn>Israel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gehr</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dowhower</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnston</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowen</ln>
                        <fn>Frances</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kimmell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cessna</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewer</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Norris</ln>
                        <fn>Cain</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fahnestock</ln>
                        <fn>A. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gsell</ln>
                        <fn>Obed</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reisher</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pennock</ln>
                        <fn>S. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reber</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peterman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peterman</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Etter</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rodgers</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keyser</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports on last week's court proceedings. In Commonwealth vs. Michael
                    Creasler, prosecuted by Simon Bitner, the defendant was found not guilty of
                    assault. Stenger and Sharpe found for the Commonwealth, while Stumbaugh and
                    Stewart found for the defendant. In Commonwealth vs. Jacob Garner, prosecuted by
                    Israel Sollenberger, the defendant was found guilty of horse stealing and was
                    sentenced to 3 months in the Eastern Penitentiary. Stenger, Stumbaugh and Gehr
                    found for the Commonwealth, Sharpe for the defendant. In Commonwealth vs. James
                    Dowhower, prosecuted by Israel Sollenberger, the defendant was found guilty of
                    horse stealing and was sentenced to 2 years and 6 months in the Eastern
                    Penitentiary. Stenger, Stumbaugh and Gehr found for the Commonwealth, and Sharpe
                    for the defendant. In Commonwealth vs. James Johnston, prosecuted by Frances
                    Bowen, the defendant was found guilty of seduction. A motion for a new trial was
                    agreed to for Wednesday January 25. Kimmell, Sharpe, Stewart and Stenger found
                    for the Commonwealth, Cessna and Brewer for the defendant. In Commonwealth vs.
                    Cain Norris, the defendant was found guilty of larceny of 95 cents from the
                    money drawer of A. H. Fahnestock and was sent to the house of refuge. Stenger
                    found for the Commonwealth, and Stewart for the defendant. In Commonwealth vs.
                    Obed Gsell, prosecuted by Samuel Reisher, the defendant was found not guilty of
                    larceny of logs worth $3.00. Stenger found for the Commonwealth, Stumbaugh and
                    Gehr for the defendant. In the Court of Common Pleas: in S. M. Pennock &amp;
                    Co. vs. William Reber, a action in assumpsit brought for the price of a reaping
                    machine, the verdict was in favor of the defendant. In John Peterman, Adm'r of
                    William Peterman, dec'd vs. Lewis Etter, an action to recover the balance due
                    William Peterman as the substitute for Etter, the verdict was in favor of the
                    plaintiff. In William Rodgers vs. William Keyser, trover and conversion, the
                    plaintiff's claim was accepted and the defendant ordered to pay the claim plus
                    $55 in damages.</summary>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Franklin County Taxes</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The above is a very snug sum for one small county to pay."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lists the total amount of taxes paid by Franklin County residents into the
                    state treasury during the past year: $3,338.89 in taxes on bank dividends;
                    $3,527.60 on corporation stocks; $30,760.06 on real and personal property;
                    $5,907.57 on half-mills; $25.86 on net earnings or income; $400.00 on enrollment
                    of laws; $333.08 on tonnage; $713.39 on writs; $9,402.58 on collateral
                    inheritance; $1,034.15 on tavern licenses; $4,217.18 on retailers' licenses;
                    $38.00 on billiard room licenses; $7.60 on peddlers' licenses; $266.00 on
                    restaurant licenses; $166.25 on distillery and brewery licenses. The total paid
                    by Franklin county was $59,138.15.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Bank Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Amberson</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamilton</ln>
                        <fn>Alex.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Besore</ln>
                        <fn>Geo.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jacobs</ln>
                        <fn>Geo.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Price</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Frantz</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mickley</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Good</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clayton</ln>
                        <fn>Jas. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On January 10, the following men were elected to be directors of the First
                    National Bank of Waynesboro: W. S. Amberson, Alex. Hamilton, Geo. Besore, Geo.
                    Jacobs, John Price, Samuel Frantz, Daniel Mickley, Henry Good, Jas. H. Clayton.
                    On January 11, that board chose Amberson to serve as President and Clayton to
                    serve as Secretary.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Tavern Licenses</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robison</ln>
                        <fn>Childerson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seibert</ln>
                        <fn>A. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kitzmiller</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bratten</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hartle</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The following men were licensed at the present session of the court to
                    "keep tavern": John Miller, Chambersburg; A. B. Seibert, Concord; Childerson
                    Robison, Concord; David Kitzmiller, Roxbury; J. B. Brumbaugh, Middleburg;
                    Alexander Martin, St. Thomas; William Bratten, St. Thomas; and John H. Hartle,
                    to sell liquor wholesale in Greencastle.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Congressional</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reviews proceedings of the US Congress, including the consideration of a
                    petition asking that rebel prisoners in Northern prisons be released and placed
                    under the care of discharged Union prisoners.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deal</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dyson</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kester</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dyson</ln>
                        <fn>Ada</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On January 11, Ada Dyson and Rev. A. Kester, of East Baltimore, were
                    married by Rev. S. Dyson. The ceremony took place in the home of the bride's
                    brother-in-law, J. W. Deal, Esq.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Holsinger</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Unger</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Holsinger</ln>
                        <fn>Susie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. Daniel Holsinger married George Unger and Susie Holsinger on January 5
                    near Waynesboro.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keller</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGrath</ln>
                        <fn>William P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keefer</ln>
                        <fn>Mary A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. Mr. Keller married William P. McGrath and Mary A. Keefer, of
                    Cumberland County, on January 12.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hostetter</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Black</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hostetter</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hostetter</ln>
                        <fn>Georgiana</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary Black Hostetter, daughter of Jacob and Georgiana Hostetter, died on
                    January 10 at age 1 year and 3 months.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fletcher</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas L.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Thomas L. Fletcher, Esq., died on January 19.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 5-7</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1865.01.25.04">
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 1-7</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
