<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1865/pa.fr.vs.1865.12.13">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/25/99</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1865-12-13">
            <year>1865</year>
            <month norm="12">December</month>
            <day norm="00">13</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1865.12.13.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Message of the President of the United States</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Contains a transcript of President Johnson's speech at the opening of the
                    39th Congress.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1865.12.13.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>"John Brown's Soul Is Marching On!"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Proceedings of the 39th Congress--Important Bills Introduced.</p>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">A Bill to allow the Negroes of District of Columbia to
                            "Wote"--A Bill to allow Negroes to Sit as Jurors in the Courts of the
                            District of Columbia."</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>For the benefit of negro-sympathizers we give space to the following, taken
                        from the Senate proceedings of its first day's session:</p>
                    <p>Mr. Wade presented a bill to regulate the elective franchise in the District
                        of Columbia. It provides that from and after its passage every male person
                        twenty-one years of age, a citizen of the United States, and resident of the
                        District of Columbia six months, and has never been convicted of infamous
                        crime, shall be entitled to the right of suffrage in the district. Any
                        person who shall disturb or interfere with such voter in the exercise of his
                        right shall, on conviction, suffer the penalty of a fine not exceeding
                        $1,000 or imprisonment in the dungeon or the city jail and fed on bread and
                        water for a period not exceeding thirty days or both. It imposes the duty
                        upon the criminal courts of the District of giving this act in special
                        charge to the grand jury at the commencement of each term. Ordered to be
                        printed.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Sumner introduced various bills as follows, which were severally ordered
                        to be printed:</p>
                    <p>"A bill to carry out the principles of a republican form of government in the
                        District of Columbia." It provides that no person in other respects
                        qualified to vote shall be excluded from that right by reason of his race or
                        color. Any one whose duty it is to receive votes, who shall refuse the vote
                        of such person is to be liable to indictment and fined not exceeding $5,000,
                        or imprisonment not exceeding one year, or both, and where the rejected
                        party of is African descent, the jury to try the case shall be composed of
                        one-half of COLORED MEN. Any person molesting a party entitled to vote is to
                        be fined, on conviction, a sum not exceeding $3,000, or imprisonment not
                        exceeding six months, or both, the jury to be composed as above where the
                        party is of African descent.</p>
                    <p>"A bill to preserve the right of trial by jury by securing impartial jurors
                        in the courts of the United States." It provides that where, according to
                        the census of 1860, one-sixth or more of the population was of African
                        descent, grand juries shall consist one-half of African descent, and petit
                        juries in the same proportion where the matter tried relates to any injury
                        inflicted by a person of African descent upon a person not of such descent,
                        or <emph rend="italic">vice versa</emph>. And prejudice against such race is
                        made ground of challenge and exclusion.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on a bill introduced in Congress that would grant blacks in the
                    District of Columbia the right to vote, sit on juries, and give testimony in
                    court.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The President's Message</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editorial lauds Johnson's message and his view of the country's current
                    state of affairs, including his prescription for future peace and prosperity.
                    The editorial contends that Johnson will have to bend to the wishes of the
                    Democrats if he hopes to achieve any of his goals because the alternative,
                    seeking support from the "congressional mob of infuriated radicals," will fail
                    horribly.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Patriot and Union</origin>
                <commentary>"Notwithstanding the Repository may find fault yet we venture to
                    "reproduce" the following from the Patriot and Union:"</commentary>
                <excerpt>"In many localities in the South, the fiends in black skins, urged on by
                    cowards in white skins, are about to kill, burn, ravish, and destroy white
                    mothers, sisters and daughters, and infants, and to "occupy the land till the
                    Black Republicans come."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Highlighting the recent turmoil in Jamaica as a possible scenario for what
                    may come if blacks are allowed to vote in the South, the article calls attention
                    to the white men at the vanguard of the black suffrage movement.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Andrew Johnson's Consistency</head>
                <origin>New York World</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The piece applauds Johnson's performance thus far, but concedes that he has
                    had to walk a fine line in dealing with the demands of the most extreme members
                    of his party.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Currency and High Prices</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The development of the vast resources of the country is being seriously
                    retarded by the effects of an inflated currency."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The impression is gaining ground that Secretary McCulloch, in his forthcoming
                        message, will recommend a steady funding of the floating debt, and a regular
                        withdrawal of greenbacks, with a view of contracting the National Bank
                        currency. This is a result generally desired, as it is conceded that the
                        present high prices of all articles is owing to the inflated currency.
                        During the war the opinion was expressed that when the contest ceased prices
                        would be reduced. But the war has terminated, and there is no reduction. Few
                        expected that at the end of a season unusually productive, and in the midst
                        of a peace, they would be compelled to pay higher prices for all articles
                        used in the family than they paid during the war, when gold was at two
                        hundred and fifty, and rising. But they are compelled to pay higher for
                        everything, and, as a matter of course, will sustain any movement calculated
                        to bring figures to a legitimate standard.</p>
                    <p>The Detroit <emph rend="italic">Free Press</emph>, in appealing to the
                        business and working men of the nation to join in compelling Congress to
                        strike at the root of the evil, and remove the principal cause of the high
                        prices, the inflation of the currency, says: </p>
                    <p>If the people who are affected by these prices will but united in saying the
                        word, Congress will not dare to refuse, early in the session, to remove this
                        inflation, which is the heaviest of all our taxes. Not only does it keep up
                        prices, but by its uncertainty and fluctuations in the price of gold, it
                        renders it impossible to do business with certainty--the margin of
                        uncertainty must always be against the consumer, and the superabundance of
                        currency stimulates speculation and compels every man to charge an
                        exorbitant profit in self-defense. Congress can cure this. Congress can
                        contract currency till it and gold assimilate in value. Congress can restore
                        specie payments, and when Congress does this it will accomplish all that we
                        can ever again hope to see done, and that is not to get back to old prices,
                        but to restore the equilibrium between wages and living. Therefore what we
                        really want is a return to a specie standard, with a reduction of
                        circulation to the of business--when we will again realize the comfort, so
                        well known of aid, called "good times," and mankind can judge at the
                        commencement of the year how he will come out if he pursues a certain
                        course.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Commends the changes pursued by the Secretary of the Treasury, which
                    reportedly includes a proposal to fund a floating debt and a "regular withdrawl"
                    of the greenbacks in circulation in an attempt to reign in the spiraling rate of
                    inflation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column/>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes the departure of Gen. "Bottle" Butler from Johnson's Cabinet. The
                    Secretary of War resigned his post, but his war-time legacy continues to haunt
                    him as he faces an number of suits alleging gross incidents of misconduct.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>News Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Ex-confederate General William Mahone has been elected President of the
                    Southside (Va.) Railroad.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>News Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Georgia has become the 28th state, and 4th Southern state, to ratify the
                    anti-slavery amendment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>News Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Virginia Legislature has amended the state's constitution to allow
                    former ex-Confederates to hold office.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1865.12.13.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal</head>
                <origin>Greencastle Pilot</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Criticizes the coverage of the Greencastle Pilot, which reported on a fire
                    that destroyed a stable a week earlier in Chambersburg. The son of the widow who
                    owns the building was charged with arson, an accusation the Pilot confirmed as
                    true despite the fact that a trial has not yet taken place. The Spirit maintains
                    that the trend toward judging the guilt of alleged criminals prior to due
                    process has become widespread, a tendency it deplores.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>News Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that a County Convention of the district's School Boards will be
                    held on Dec. 29th, to discuss finances for the upcoming year. Delegates from
                    Franklin will be selected at the Dec. 14th meeting.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>P. S.&gt;</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Proctor</ln>
                        <fn>Edward</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lewis</ln>
                        <fn>Rosanna</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Dec. 7th, Edward Proctor and Rosanna Lewis were married in the African
                    M. E. Church., by Rev. P. S. Davis.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>West</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kirkpatrick</ln>
                        <fn>William G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burk</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burk</ln>
                        <fn>Nannie J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William G. Burk and Nannie J. Burk, daughter of William Burk, were wed on
                    Dec. 3rd, by Rev. William A. West.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>S. H. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shatler</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gramm</ln>
                        <fn>Lavita</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Dec.7th, David Shatler and Lavita Gramm were wed in a ceremony performed
                    by Rev. S. H. C. Smith.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>S. H. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wagman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kaufman</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Dec. 7th, John Wagman and Margaret Kaufman were married by Rev. S. H. C.
                    Smith.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>S. H. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dull</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mentzor</ln>
                        <fn>Mollie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mollie Mentzore and William Dull were wed on Dec. 7th, by Rev. S. H. C.
                    Smith.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>P. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gruber</ln>
                        <fn>Adam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Emrich</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Dec. 7th, Rev. P. S. Davis presided over the marriage ceremony uniting
                    Adam Gruber and Sarah E. Emrich.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dyson</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>David W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donithen</ln>
                        <fn>Hannah C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>David W. Jones and Hannah C. Donithen were married on Dec. 6th, by Rev. F.
                    Dyson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type=" s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whetstone</ln>
                        <fn>A. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCalvy</ln>
                        <fn>Franklin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lego</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Dec. 7th, Franklin McCalvy and Mary Lego were wed in a ceremony
                    performed by Rev. A. M. Whetstone.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roth</ln>
                        <fn>G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bestwich</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burcket</ln>
                        <fn>Kate</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jacob Bestwich, of Pittsburgh, and Kate Burcket were married on Dec. 7th,
                    by Rev. G Roth.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sarah Orr, 79, died on Dec. 3rd.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koontz</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koontz</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Elizabeth Koontz, wife of William Koontz, died in Antrim township on Dec.
                    3rd. Mrs. Koontz was 29 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wassen</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wassen</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James Wassen, son of Jacob Wassen, died on Nov. 30th, at age 8.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1865.12.13.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
