<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1866/va.au.vv.1866.01.31">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>5/26/04</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1866-01-31">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day norm="">31</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1866.01.31.01" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Scraps From My Haversack</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper continues its series of a veteran's account of campaigning with
                    Stonewall Jackson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1866.01.31.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>"What's the Times?"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>This question is often asked now by our people and it is a serious one, so
                        serious to us that it is painful to attempt an answer to it. If President
                        Johnson's policy had been carried out by Congress, our Country, the South,
                        would have now been on the high road to prosperity and some hope of
                        repairing the devastation of war could be entertained. It has not been
                        carried out, but, has been opposed by the Radicals with consummate ability
                        and spite. When the armies of the Confederacy surrendered and our people
                        accepted the pledges of Andrew Johnson and Gen. Grant, they expected to be
                        restored to all rights and privileges of citizens of the United States, to
                        which they renewed their allegiance. They accepted, in good faith, the
                        results of the war; gave up slavery and were prepared to work out the
                        problem of free negro labor, as best they could.</p>
                    <p>And now after doing all that was asked of us by the President of the United
                        States and Gen. Grant, and more than was ever claimed by the "so-called"
                        Union party North, "what's the times?" We elect representatives to the
                        Congress of the U. S. and they are refused admittance, and we are told that
                        our oaths to support the Constitution are false and we are not to be
                        trusted. A new interpretation of the Constitution, for them, is given by the
                        Radicals in Congress, and they practically assume the position held by the
                        States rights men during the war, <emph rend="italic">i. e.</emph> that we
                        had a right to secede. They declare us out of the United States and demand
                        new guarantees before the "Territories of the South" can be admitted to full
                        representation, as States of the United States. At first we hoped that the
                        Conservative element in the North was strong enough to check the Radicals in
                        Congress in their mad career, but since they have been home and come back to
                        Washington, more bitter than ever we can see no hope for the South, except
                        in the nerve and firmly expressed purpose of Andrew Johnson to oppose their
                        ruinous measures.</p>
                    <p>It is a very simple question with our people. They were promised certain
                        things, by the only power of the U. S. Government authorized to grant them.
                        The Congress of the U. S. refuse to approve the contract and, in fact,
                        repudiate it. We have honestly done our part, and it remains for the people
                            <emph rend="italic">in</emph> the United States to force their
                        representatives to aid Andrew Johnson in doing theirs. If they do not we can
                        see very little in the future of this continent to look forward to
                        hopefully--but a people who have gone through four years of such a war as
                        ours can certainly look the future bravely in the face.</p>
                    <p>The Jacobin Radicals, in Congress, are doing their utmost to make a war of
                        races; their speeches and their votes show it. Negro suffrage is to be
                        enforced and the negro placed not only on an equality, but made superior to
                        the white man. When the contest opens, as we hope it never may, the "times"
                        in the South will indicate the extermination of the negro race. All this and
                        the confiscation laws make the times look very black, and we can see but one
                        hopeful sign that is in the old saying, that "the man who killed a dog for
                        spite never saw him buried."</p>
                    <p>But still there is something to live for in this desolated land of ours. It
                        is something to feel that you did your duty in the past four years; that
                        your people made a name that can never perish; that the glory and the heroes
                        of war are acknowledged to be yours by the world. It is something to feel
                        proud of, when you can say you were with Stonewall Jackson at Kernstown and
                        Lee at Appomattox. Hecatombs of martyred dead tell you you did no wrong, and
                        a world forever applauds your glorious deeds. The wives, the mothers and the
                        orphans of our dead, demand of us that we make a brave effort to secure
                        "better times," such an effort as they made on the battle field to secure
                        independence. They lost all. We still have life and a duty to perform to
                        those they left a "sacred heritage" to us. So let the Radicals in Congress
                        do their worst, if we but do our duty, no more harm can come to us than has
                        already. To develope our resources; to raise this country from poverty and
                        weakness to wealth and strength; to feed the widows and the orphans of our
                        dead is the only duty, of "the times," for us to attend to. And if President
                        Johnson's nerve, and his kindness to the people of the South, and General
                        Grant's pledges avail us nothing, then, we can say we have done our duty, in
                        war and peace, and looking the world honestly in the face be prepared for
                        all that comes.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This editorial denounces Congress's decision to prevent the seating of
                    Southern representatives. The radicals, the article asserts, are intent on
                    starting a race war. The South, the editors argue, have kept their half of the
                    bargain by accepting the results of the war, including the end of slavery, but
                    now the North is going back on its promises of speedy reunion. If only Johnson's
                    policy had been adhered to, the South would have been able to quickly regain
                    peace and prosperity. Proud Confederate veterans, the paper asserts, have a duty
                    to resist radical policy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The President on the 28th stated to a distinguished Senator that the
                        agitation of the negro franchise question in the District of Columbia at
                        this time, was a mere entering wedge to the agitation of the question
                        throughout the States; that it was ill-timed, uncalled for and calculated to
                        do great harm. He believed it would engender enmity and strife between the
                        two races which would result in great injury to both, and the certain
                        extermination of the negro population. Precedence, he thought, should be
                        given to more important and urgent matters of legislation, which were
                        essential for the restoration of the Union, the peace of the country and the
                        prosperity of the people. The above is strictly true.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper endorses President Andrew Johnson's position opposing suffrage
                    for African Americans.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paul</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>J. Wayt</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Francisco</ln>
                        <fn>C. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>W. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Finley</ln>
                        <fn>S. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>T. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gambell</ln>
                        <fn>Theo</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kenney</ln>
                        <fn>Chesley</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper prints the results of recent local elections. Capt. James
                    Bumgardner Jr. was elected Attorney for the Commonwealth. Samuel Paul was
                    elected Sheriff of Augusta. The following Magistrates were elected: Staunton
                    district (No. 1), J. Wayt Bell and C. C. Francisco; Greenville (No. 4), W. F.
                    Smith; New Hope (No. 6), S. B. Finley; Mt. Sidney (No. 7), T. J. Burke and Theo
                    Gambell; Mt. Solon (No. 8), J. M. McCue and Chesley Kenney.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper announces that General Terry, commanding the Department of
                    Virginia, "has issued an order declaring the vagrant law of Va., recently
                    passed, of no effect, as far as regards negroes. White men can take care of
                    themselves. So we go."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Scraps From My Haversack</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper continues its series on the history of Jackson's command.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Our Honored Dead</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Below we continue the list of Confederate Soldiers buried in Thornrose
                        Cemetery.</p>
                    <p>North Carolina</p>
                    <p>B. Skinner, 2; J. A. Long, 14; H. Potter, 30; W. R. Phillips, 33; A. Sigman,
                        18; Geo. Bridgit, 23; A. Poore, 2; C. T. Taylor, 48; L. A. Caswell, 3; J. A.
                        Stallings, 30; P. B. Tlanger, 30; G. F. Jones, 2; S. Henderson, 38; J. S.
                        Barker, 4; E. Ritchie, 28.</p>
                    <p>South Carolina</p>
                    <p>T. Shayler, 13; A. R. Hurley, Phillips Legion; D. Errand, 3; W. A. McDowell,
                        12; R. M. Gills, 17; J. M. Chissley, 3.</p>
                    <p>Georgia</p>
                    <p>B. A. Stonaker, 21; S. Fields, 35; J. W. Baker, 13; J. Aultman, 6; J. W.
                        Harris, 51; W. F. Watly, 45; W. W. Burges, 38; W. W. Keen, 31; H. Grimes,
                        49; B. S. Green, 38; C. R. Stevens, 44.</p>
                    <p>Alabama</p>
                    <p>W. C. Atkins, 12; W. M. Hunsucker, 11; W. Radon, 17.</p>
                    <p>Virginia</p>
                    <p>S. Kalam, 9; J. Clary, 21; J. F. Heperis, --; H. H. Amos, 47; J. Hults, 42;
                        J. W. Willson, 1st Va. Art.; M. A. Bodgers, 5th Va. Cavalry.</p>
                    <p>Mississippi</p>
                    <p>W. M. Tate, 2.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Long</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Potter</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phillips</ln>
                        <fn>W. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sigman</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bridgit</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Poore</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>C. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Caswell</ln>
                        <fn>L. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stallings</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tlanger</ln>
                        <fn>P. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>G. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henderson</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barker</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ritchie</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shayler</ln>
                        <fn>T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hurley</ln>
                        <fn>A. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Errand</ln>
                        <fn>D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDowell</ln>
                        <fn>W. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gills</ln>
                        <fn>R. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chissley</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stonaker</ln>
                        <fn>B. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fields</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Aultman</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Watly</ln>
                        <fn>W. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burges</ln>
                        <fn>W. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keen</ln>
                        <fn>W. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grimes</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Green</ln>
                        <fn>B. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stevens</ln>
                        <fn>C. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Atkins</ln>
                        <fn>W. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunsucker</ln>
                        <fn>W. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Radon</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kalam</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clary</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heperis</ln>
                        <fn>J. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Amos</ln>
                        <fn>H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hults</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Willson</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bodgers</ln>
                        <fn>M. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tate</ln>
                        <fn>W. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper publishes names of Confederate soldiers buried in Staunton's
                    Thornrose Cemetery. The list includes regimental identification.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>An old gentleman remarked the other day that in 1776 we went to war on
                        account of the stamp act, and got the nigger; while in 1861 we went to war
                        about the nigger and got the stamp act.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports the comments of a man regarding the results of the
                    Revolution and of the Civil War.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crum</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thuma</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hammack</ln>
                        <fn>C. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Crum and Mrs. Catharine Thuma, both of Augusta, were married on
                    January 21 by the Rev. C. B. Hammack.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whisner</ln>
                        <fn>P. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Arey</ln>
                        <fn>Lou</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paird</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. P. H. Whisner and Miss Lou Arey, of Augusta, were married in January
                    24 by Rev. W. S. Paird.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Andrews</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCall</ln>
                        <fn>Josephine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dunlap</ln>
                        <fn>M. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John H. Andrews, of Augusta, and Miss Josephine McCall, of Rockingham, were
                    married on January 7 by Rev. M. D. Dunlap.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1866.01.31.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>A Skirmish</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that a skirmish between "two parties of Freedmen" took
                    place on the outskirts of Staunton. "It seems one party were having a dance, and
                    the other, jealous of their sport, attempted to break up the 'hop.' The
                    Superintendent of the Freedmen's Bureau is energetically investigating the
                    matter and the guilty will be brought to trial."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Bacon Stolen</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper reports that 2,50 lbs of bacon were stolen from the smokehouse of
                    James Bumgardner, near Greenville. The thieves were tracked to the vicinity of
                    Staunton and the bacon was found hidden in the woods near Cochran's Mill. No
                    arrests were made.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>S. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper reports that Rev. S. D. Stuart of Staunton received $10,000 as
                    the first subscription to the Lee Endowment in N. Y.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>That Petition</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dewes</ln>
                        <fn>W. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tukey</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper reports that Mr. W. J. Dewes "assumes all the responsibility for
                    getting up the mysterious petition that has been circulating in the County, for
                    the supposed purpose of bringing the troops back" to Staunton. The paper asserts
                    that Mr. Tukey had nothing to do with it. Dewes declined to show the petition to
                    the editors of the Valley Virginian, but planned to make it public after
                    consultation with other Union men. The editors "protest against the secret
                    circulation of any petition," but forbear further comment until the draft
                    becomes public.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1866.01.31.04" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Confederate Note</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The following lines were written upon the back of a Five Hundred Dollar
                        Confederate Note, by Major S. A. Jonas, subsequent to the surrender:</p>
                    <p>Representing nothing on God's earth now,<lb/> And naught in the water below
                        it;<lb/> As a pledge of a nation that's dead and gone,<lb/> Keep it, dear
                        Captain, and show it.<lb/> Show it to those that will lend an ear<lb/> To
                        the tale this this paper can tell<lb/> Of Liberty born, of the patriot's
                        dream,<lb/> Of a storm-cradled nation that fell.</p>
                    <p>Too poor to possess the precious ore,<lb/> And too much a stranger to
                        borrow,<lb/> We issue to-day, our "Promise to Pay,<lb/> And hope to redeem
                        on the morrow."<lb/> Days rolled by, and weeks became years,<lb/> But our
                        coffers were empty still;<lb/> Coin was so rare that the Treasury'd
                        quake<lb/> If a dollar should drop in the till.</p>
                    <p>But the faith that was in us was strong indeed,<lb/> And our poverty well
                        discerned,<lb/> And these little checks represented the pay<lb/> That our
                        suffering veterans earned.<lb/> We know it had hardly a value in gold;<lb/>
                        Yet as gold the soldiers received it;<lb/> It gazed in our eyes with a
                        promise to Pay,<lb/> And each patriot soldier believed it.</p>
                    <p>But our boys thought little of price or pay,<lb/> Or of bills that were over
                        due;<lb/> We knew if it bought our bread today,<lb/> 'Twas the best our poor
                        country could do.<lb/> Keep it! it tolls all our history over,<lb/> From the
                        birth of the dream to its last;<lb/> Modest, and born of Angel, Hope,<lb/>
                        Like our hope of success it passed.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper prints a poem honoring the Confederacy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
