<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1866/va.au.vv.1866.08.29">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/28/04</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1866-08-29">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="08">August</month>
            <day norm="">29</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1866.08.29.01" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Richmond Correspondence</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Richmond Correspondent for the Virginian reports that residents of the
                    city are engaged in cleaning up and repairing Oakwood and Hollywood Cemeteries.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1866.08.29.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Situation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Every one has had their say about the Philadelphia Convention, pro and con.,
                        and the world still moves along in the same old way, much to the surprise of
                        some people. It is gratifying to notice how cooly the people of the South
                        take the whole matter, and the good sense shown by the press generally, in
                        "accepting the situation." In the North, where the battle is to be fought,
                        there are cheering indications of the triumph of Conservatism over the
                        Radicals, and we can only bid our people--be of good heart, work, and trust
                        to God for the ultimate triumph of those principles of free government, for
                        which they have sacrificed, and are still enduring, so much.</p>
                    <p>From Europe, by the Cable, comes news of peace between the great Powers, and
                        with it a marked improvement in commercial and financial circles. They have
                        butchered thousands over there, and a heap of stuff is sent over the wires
                        about "rectifying boundaries," and all that; but our only interest in the
                        matter is that it will enable the capitalists who have undertaken to build
                        our great canal and railroad to the Ohio, to raise the funds necessary. We
                        have a great admiration for the wonderful things done in the short war in
                        Europe, but we will feel much better when the Covington and Ohio railroad is
                        built.</p>
                    <p>In our columns will be found the proceedings of the Valley Rail Road Meeting,
                        Monday, and the order of the Court, for a vote to be taken on the
                        proposition for the county to subscribe $200,000 to this great work. The
                        meeting was large and respectable, and how our people will vote upon the
                        subscription is of more importance to us than all the politics and all the
                        wars in the world.</p>
                    <p>The people of Augusta now have a chance to show again, as they have often
                        done, their public spirit, their liberality, and their devotion to all the
                        interests of the great Valley. Two hundred thousand dollars, to be
                        subscribed by the Court, looks like an awful sum, but the same was said
                        about the subscription to the Central railroad years ago--and who felt it?
                        Augusta must set an example to her daughters by voting for this
                        subscription, and every friend of the road should work to accomplish that
                        object. This is a matter of such vital importance; a matter upon which hangs
                        so many present and future benefits to us and our children, that before it
                        all other questions sink into nothingness. The destiny of our loved Valley
                        and our people depend upon our building this road. Vote for the
                        subscription, and it will be built. Then we will be rich and
                        independent--not before.</p>
                    <p>Our people should recollect that in the changed position of the colored
                        people we have duties to perform of equal importance to those imposed upon
                        the freedmen. Little things go a great way in this world, and, in our
                        present situation, good sense and sound judgement are required more than
                        ever. One little thing, the word "nigger," is too often used, and it wounds
                        the feelings of the colored people. "Nigger," to them, means everything mean
                        and low in their race, just as "Yankee" expresses everything low and mean in
                        the white. Remember this, and it will do a world of good.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors apprise readers of developments upon several topics. They argue
                    that the Philadelphia Convention, while not changing much, could be a harbinger
                    of Conservative triumph in the North. The Valley Railroad is still in need of
                    subscribers, and the editors urge citizens to contribute. In the area of race
                    relations, the editors admonish people to address the freedmen with more
                    respect.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The President's Speech</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On the 18th August, Andrew Johnson made a speech in Washington about the
                        Philadelphia platform. In it he bravely defends himself, and shows up the
                        destructive course of the mob, called Congress. Here is the gist of the
                        whole speech, and it will do. He said:</p>
                    <p>"But as the work progressed, as reconciliation seemed to be taking place, and
                        the country becoming united, we found a disturbing and warring element in
                        opposition. In alluding to that element, I shall go further than did your
                        convention and the distinguished gentleman who has delivered to me the
                        report of you proceedings. I shall make no reference to it. That I do not
                        believe the time and occasion justify. We have witnessed in one department
                        of the government every effort, as it were, to prevent the restoration of
                        peace, or harmony, and of the Union. We have seen hanging upon the verge of
                        the government, as it were, a body called, or which assumed to be, the
                        Congress of the United States, but in fact a Congress of only part of the
                        States. We have seen this Congress assume and pretend to be for the Union,
                        when its every step and act tended to perpetuate disunion, and make a
                        disruption permanent.</p>
                    <p>Instead of promoting reconciliation and harmony, its legislation has partaken
                        of the character of penalties, retaliation and revenge. This has been the
                        course and the policy of one department of your government. The humble
                        individual who is now addressing you stands the representative of another
                        department of the government. The manner in which he was called upon to
                        occupy that position I shall not allude to on this occasion; suffice it to
                        say that he is here under the constitution of the country; and being here by
                        virtue of its provisions, he takes his stand upon that charter of our
                        liberties as the great rampart of civil and religious liberty. [Prolonged
                        cheering.] Having been taught in my early life to hold it sacred, and having
                        practiced upon it during my public career, I shall ever continue to
                        reverence the constitution of my fathers, and to make it my guide."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper prints excerpts from a speech by Andrew Johnson taking
                    Congressional Republicans to task, and pledging to uphold the Constitution.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A Staunton correspondent of the Abingdon Virginian, in speaking of Staunton,
                        says:</p>
                    <p>"In regard to Staunton, I can tell you nothing with which you are not
                        familiar. The characteristic of Staunton is that it is emphatically a
                        "business place." It is the central point of the trade in this great Valley.
                        Farmers, traders and producers of all kinds, from this and adjacent
                        counties, empty their products here. The main street is often crowded with
                        wagons small and great, in which may be seen everything common among the
                        producers of the country. Merchants chiefly are the buyers, and the citizens
                        here and in Richmond are the consumers."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This excerpt from a correspondent of the Abingdon Virginian describes
                    business activity in Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>The Staunton Artillery in the Battles of Spotsylvania Ct. House and Around
                    Richmond</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In Camp, Cold Harbor,<lb/> June 10, 1864.</p>
                    <p>This battery entered the service at Harper's Ferry, under the command of
                        Captain (now General) John D. Imboden, and has been in all the engagements
                        with the A. N. Va. since--distinguishing itself in each. On Tuesday, May the
                        10th, at Spotsylvania, it was in position near the head-quarters of the
                        Commanding General, when a company of artillery was forced, fighting
                        gallantly, to leave their guns. Capt. Garber was then called on by Gen. Lee
                        to take his men and work the guns, when they were retaken, which order was
                        complied with and the guns kept vomiting out their deadly contents, under a
                        most terrific fire of the enemy's infantry, until the close of the
                        contest--the officers and men receiving, for their gallantry and
                        extraordinary heroism, the compliments of Generals Lee, Gordon, and Long.
                        During the night the guns of the Staunton Artillery were brought up to the
                        position, and held it on the terrible "12th of May."</p>
                    <p>When the enemy broke through our lines on the morning of the 12th, the guns
                        of this battery were turned to the right upon him, and, firing over the
                        heads of our own men, checked his advance until relief came from other parts
                        of our line, when the lost works were retaken and our lines reformed.
                        Captain Garber then advanced a part of his men and worked three of our
                        re-captured guns of another battalion, with a spirit and success which again
                        elicited the praises of general officers.</p>
                    <p>A simple statement of these facts is sufficient to show the character of both
                        officers and men, and the importance of the work accomplished is evident.</p>
                    <p>The battery was also engaged on the 18th of May, when the enemy were repulsed
                        by artillery fire alone. On the 2d of June a section of the battery repulsed
                        a column of the enemy, when our infantry had been flanked and left it
                        exposed to capture.</p>
                    <p>The casualties show how the company has suffered, and this statement of its
                        conduct is but a simple act of justice to its officers and men.</p>
                    <p>Major Cutshaw, commanding the battalion of which the Staunton battery is a
                        part is one of the most gallant officers in the service, and on the
                        occasions above referred to, acted with distinguished valor and intrepidity,
                        and though his brave command has been sadly reduced in numbers, it is still
                        able to hold its own in the front ranks.</p>
                    <p>In making this statement, it is not intended to detract from other batteries,
                        nearly all of which have received favorable mention in the papers, but
                        simply to let the "old folks at home," in old Augusta, know that <emph
                            rend="italic">their battery</emph> still retains its well earned
                        reputation, and has added fresh laurels to those previously obtained.</p>
                    <p>Augusta</p>
                    <p>Casualties In Staunton Artillery In Battles in Spotsylvania &amp;c.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Killed</emph>.--Private James S. Burns and Corporal B.
                        Phor.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Wounded</emph>.--Sergeant John B. Ryan, severe flesh
                        wound in the leg; sergeant J. W. Butler, severe flesh wound in the thigh;
                        corporal Geo. W. Long, flesh wound in the shoulder; bugler Peter Good,
                        severely in the hip; private Peter H. Proctor, flesh wound in the leg; C.
                        Hoffman, flesh wound, leg; C. N. Styrewalt, severely, hip; A. Karanaugh,
                        severely, arm, since amputated; W. C. Smith, severely, hip; Henry Trice,
                        badly, shoulder; A. L. Marshall, flesh wound, leg; private Henry Wood, arm,
                        since dead. Total--2 killed, 12 wounded.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burns</ln>
                        <fn>James S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phor</ln>
                        <fn>B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ryan</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Butler</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Long</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Good</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Proctor</ln>
                        <fn>Peter H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoffman</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Styrewalt</ln>
                        <fn>C. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Karanaugh</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>W. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trice</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Marshall</ln>
                        <fn>A. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wood</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn>John D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garber</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper publishes an account of the Staunton Artillery's role in the
                    battles of Spotsylvania and around Richmond. A list of casualties is included.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>The Valley of Virginia</head>
                <origin>Weldon N. C. State</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>What North Carolina soldier, of General Lee's army is there, who has not
                        kindly and pleasant recollections of the Shenandoah Valley? Where did they
                        meet with readier sympathy, where, when suffering, did they get more
                        affectionate nursing, or who furnished them with <emph rend="italic">bigger
                            loaves of bread</emph>, when hungry, than the good people of this goodly
                        valley, from Staunton to the Potomac. Our soldiers have not forgotten these
                        things, and we know they will hear with pleasure that this beautiful valley
                        is fast recovering from the sad effects of Hunter's ruthless and wicked
                        invasion and desolation.</p>
                    <p>On their behalf and our own, we wish the Valley a full and speedy return of
                        its former prosperity.--<emph rend="italic">Weldon N. C. State</emph>.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This excerpt from a North Carolina newspaper describes the affection of
                    many Confederate veterans for the people of the Shenandoah Valley.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A telegram from Washington, says Gen. Howard, grand Head Centre of the
                        Freedman's Bureau, "intends to stop issuing rations to the destitute of the
                        South, thus throwing the support of the indigent of both races on the local
                        authorities." Very good, so far as it goes, but why not carry the idea to
                        its logical conclusion and relieve us of the Bureau too? All most of them
                        have to do is to eat, issue rations, and make mischief.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors welcome a rumor that the Freedmen's Bureau will stop issuing
                    rations in the South, and suggest the complete dismantling of the bureau.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Several bodies of Confederate soldiers, killed in the Valley, passed through
                        Staunton last week. It was touching to notice that every coffin had a wreath
                        of flowers on it, the tribute of the fair and gentle women of the Valley to
                        the brave and honored dead.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports on the passage of coffins of Confederate soldiers through
                    Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1866.08.29.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that cold weather has driven many visitors from the
                    mountains, and the hotels in Staunton are full as a result.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pierce</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Ladies' Cemetery Committee acknowledge the receipt of $1,200 from a
                    gentleman of Georgetown, D. C. through Mrs. Pierce, of Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. David Taylor, "a man of energy, a working man," has given "general
                    satisfaction" as the head of the Staunton Water works.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A special reporter estimates that there are 84 widows and 21 widowers in
                    Staunton, rather than the reverse. He will later count all the "old maids and
                    bachelors."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors correct the misperception that the newspaper is named the
                    "Staunton" Virginian rather then the "Valley" Virginian. "No pent up Utica
                    contracts our powers,/The boundless Valley is ours."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Camp Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that though camp meetings in the Valley are numerous, the
                    most important is occurring near Mountain Top. About 2,000 persons from Augusta
                    and Albemarle were present. "Penitents were numerous--about six or seven."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Our Valley</head>
                <origin>Richmond Times</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This excerpt from the Richmond Times asserts that the Shenandoah Valley is
                    recovering more rapidly from the war than any area in the South. The paper
                    attributes that to "ready adaptation of its soil to any system of labor," the
                    "small number of freedmen," and the spirit and energy of the population.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Our Generals</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that Staunton hosted Confederate Generals Johnson, Ewell,
                    Heath, Imboden, Echols, and Manning in the past week. They all stayed at the
                    American Hotel and were serenaded by the Stonewall Band.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>About Dogs</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors complain about dogs creating disturbances in the street, and
                    urges passage of an ordinance to solve the problem. "If a man gets drunk and
                    'disturbs the peace and good order' of Staunton, by yelling on the streets, he
                    is arrested and lodged in jail, but something less than a thousand worthless
                    dogs are allowed to 'make the nights hideous,' with their barking."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>A Specimen Brick</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCarthy</ln>
                        <fn>Florence</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Virginian agrees with the Richmond papers in condemning the speeches
                    made by Rev. Florence McCarthy at the Colored Baptist Convention in Richmond.
                    McCarthy declared himself "the only loyal preacher in the South." "A few weeks
                    ago we saw this man in the mountains of Virginia and he boldly proclaimed the
                    most extreme Southern doctrines and boasted of his services at the first battle
                    of Manassas." Both papers agree that he is crazy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Police Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greaver</ln>
                        <fn>Harry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilmer</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kurtz</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Deputy Sergeant</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mayor</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ware</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carter</ln>
                        <fn>Pink</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thornton</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kayser</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kenney</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bruce</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Justice</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Isaac Brown, Harry Greaver, and Charles Gilmer, "colored boys," were
                    arrested by Deputy Sergeant Kurtz for breaking into the Lutheran Church Sunday
                    School. Mayor Trout had them bound over for good behavior after trial. John
                    Ware, Pink Carter, and Henry Thornton were arrested for fighting. They were
                    tried before Recorder Kayser. Ware and Thornton were discharged but Carter was
                    held to bail awaiting indictment before the Hustings Court. Daniel Walker and
                    John Kenney, "colored, were arrested for 'rock battle,' on the streets. Not
                    being resident and ignorant of the law, Justice Bruce discharged them on promise
                    of good behavior."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>County Court</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickle</ln>
                        <fn>R. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>J. Wayt</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pierce</ln>
                        <fn>A. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hailman</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huff</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Todd</ln>
                        <fn>Preston</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wallace</ln>
                        <fn>Joel S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chapman</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paul</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Engleman</ln>
                        <fn>Francis M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Engleman</ln>
                        <fn>George Washington</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Livick</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Livick</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Livick</ln>
                        <fn>Harriett</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parkins</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grady</ln>
                        <fn>Robert Taylor</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McAller</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lilly</ln>
                        <fn>J. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Augusta County Court met on August 27. The following Justices were
                    present: R. G. Bickle, James Wilson, J. Wayt Bell, A. E. Pierce, and Benjamin
                    Hailman. James Huff was appointed Surveyor of the Public Road, precinct 124;
                    Preston Todd for precinct 156. Joel S. Wallace and William Chapman qualified as
                    Notaries Public for Augusta. Samuel Paul qualified as Sheriff, giving bond for
                    $90,000. Francis M. Engleman qualified as guardian of George Washington
                    Engleman, who is under age 14. Andrew J. Livick qualified as guardian of
                    Margaret and Harriett Livick. John H. Parkins qualified as guardian of Robert
                    Taylor Grady, under age 14. Michael McAller was appointed surveyor of road
                    precinct 30 and J. D. Lilly of 67. Rev. Joseph A. Miller, of German Baptist
                    Church was authorized to celebrate marriages. "Several colored children were
                    ordered to be bound out." A special election will be held on the 4th Thursday of
                    October asking the voters of Augusta if the Court, on behalf of the County,
                    should subscribe $200,000 to the stock of the Valley Railroad.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>A. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crosby</ln>
                        <fn>C. V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>R. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A. P. Anderson and Miss C. V. Crosby, both of Augusta, were married on
                    August 16 by the Rev. R. C. Walker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armentrout</ln>
                        <fn>C. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Layne</ln>
                        <fn>C. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>G. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>C. E. Armentrout and Mrs. C. A. Layne, both of Augusta, were married on
                    August 2nd by the Rev. G. B. Taylor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Horn</ln>
                        <fn>O. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Major</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Geltmacher</ln>
                        <fn>Hettie M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Major O. P. Horn, C. S. A., of Virginia, married Miss Hettie M. Geltmacher,
                    of Michigan, on August 11th. The Rev. W. M. Moffett presided.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>W. T. Armstrong, aged 17 months, died in Staunton on August 15th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1866.08.29.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
