<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1866/va.au.vv.1866.08.15">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/24/04</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1866-08-15">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="08">August</month>
            <day norm="">15</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1866.08.15.01" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>07</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Rockingham Register</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article from the Rockingham Register asserts that "our want of a
                    Railroad will be sadly felt by our people this Fall, when the immense corn crop
                    which now covers the face of the county all over, begins to mature. The crop
                    will be so immense that our people will hardly know what to do with it.
                    Thousands of dollars will be lost because there are no adequate means for its
                    transportation beyond the limits of the county. How long we are to suffer and to
                    lose on this account, we wish scheming, bargaining Railroad Presidents would
                    tell us."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1866.08.15.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that "a riot occurred in Washington on Wednesday between
                    the white and negro troops stationed there."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper claims that a report by Generals Steadman and Fullerton decided
                    conclusively that the Freedman's Bureau should be removed from the South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that "a negro man is to be hung at Grayson Court House,
                    Va., on the 24th inst., for outraging the person of a white girl, only 12 years
                    of age."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that a woman in Philadelphia hired two black men to kill
                    her husband. The plot failed when the police arrived after hearing the husband's
                    cries. The three are in jail. "It is noticeable that the Radical papers don't
                    make much fuss about 'outrages' of this kind when they occur North," the paper
                    asserts.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Secretary of the Treasury rescinded the "restrictive regulations" for
                    the "removal, under bond, without prepayment of taxes, of taxable products or
                    manufactures within the limits of the late Confederate states." That way "the
                    manufacturers and producers of those States will be allowed to ship their goods,
                    under bond without prepayment of taxes."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The National Intelligencer, speaking of the present condition of the country,
                        says:</p>
                    <p>The South is to have no peace; every incentive is to be used to create and
                        intensify the antagonism of races at the South, and every outbreak will be
                        so much clear gain to Radicalism. We have fallen upon the unhappy times,
                        when selfish partizans find that the best way to attain power is to unchain
                        the furies. What will liberty, what will property, what will life ultimately
                        be worth in this country if this horrible diabolism is sanctioned by the
                        endorsement of the people.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This excerpt from the National Intelligencer asserts that the Radical
                    Republicans will not allow the South any peace.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Truth of History</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bixio</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Father</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The editors discuss some criticisms they have of Dabney's Life of Jackson.
                    They assert that Catholic clergy served the brigade well, and, along with the
                    Sisters of Charity, exerted themselves in efforts to aid the wounded. Father
                    Bixio served the Maryland line as well as hospitals in Staunton,
                    Charlottesville, and Gordonsville.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Virginia Hotel, Staunton</head>
                <origin>Richmong Whig</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Staunton is fast resuming the energy and industry which were leading
                        characteristics of its business population before general adversity fell
                        upon all parts of the country. In no department is this more discernible
                        than in its fine and capacious hotels. Travelers, once partaking of the
                        excellent fare and delightful quarters they receive here, go on their
                        journey more than pleased. The old and well known Virginia Hotel is one of
                        the most complete establishments in the country. The Messrs. PEYTON, in
                        reopening its ample accommodations, have spared no expense in giving
                        convenience, style and elegance to the apartments and the outfit in every
                        particular. With their own is given the polite attention of the
                        superintendent, Mr. B. F. WEBB and Mr. BERNARD PEYTON.</p>
                    <p>The guest, on his entrance, is made to feel that he has around him not only
                        the ease and freedom of "Old Virginia" hospitality and courtesy, but that he
                        is invited to all the comforts and luxuries of a first class city
                            establishment.--<emph rend="italic">Richmond Whig.</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn>Bernard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Webb</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>This article from the Richmond Whig reviews favorably Staunton's Virginia
                    Hotel.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Notes By the Way</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It is certainly very gratifying to a dweller in our lovely Valley, to note
                        the rapid progress our people are making in restoring our war-stricken
                        country to its former thrifty appearance. The changes are apparent to the
                        eye of a stranger, but to one that, with a sad heart, saw Sheridan's
                        ruthless devastation and witnessed the destruction, as it went on, of four
                        years of vandalism, and can tell when each scar was made that so marred the
                        features of this loveliest of lands, these changes for the better are
                        eloquent in speaking of the past and cheering for the present and the
                        future.</p>
                    <p>It is needless to speak of the improvements in Staunton, they are "not done
                        in a corner," the town is <emph rend="italic">filling up</emph> and <emph
                            rend="italic">spreading out</emph>, as far as the water pipes will let
                        it, especially is the town creeping down the Valley Turnpike, where the
                        houses, some very good ones, have already topped the hill, the fences have
                        resumed their old places and near the little chopping mill on Fanny's Run,
                        Col. Harman's fine new Merchant mill, running like clock-work, first
                        attracts attention after getting into the country--and it is well worth a
                        visit, if for no other purpose, to see how well everything has been done
                        there. I am sure a <emph rend="italic">good</emph> roll would taste all the
                        better if the eater knew the flour had been ground in so neat a mill. The
                        fine crops, the fences, the improvements that have been made to houses and
                        barns, speak well for the industry of the farmers, as we go towards the
                        Augusta Church, and there the fine new building that is nearly completed for
                        the school of the Messrs. Bowman and the New Cemetery that is nearly
                        enclosed and is to be neatly and tastefully laid out and ornamented, speak
                        well for the public spirit that is still alive in the old land. Mt. Sidney
                        gives few signs of life we are sorry to say: the hotel has a new sign and
                        the smoke rises from the oven of the pottery, but the end has fallen out of
                        the school house and the weeds grow in the streets, even the toll gatherer
                        was "<emph rend="italic">non est</emph>." As we near Burke's Mill two steam
                        saw mills give an active look to the little Valley of the West Branch of
                        Naked Creek, and Capt. Burke's new mill looks as though Sheridan's crow
                        might replenish his haversack there, provided--well, we're
                        reconstructed--The whole place is alive from the steam mill to the stage
                        stables. Pleasant Grove Academy is sadly in need of a tenant, but the huge
                        new barn of Mr. Roller near by proclaims that that fine region has not been
                        sold for taxes yet. Mt. Crawford looks very well, except the church, which
                        always had a <emph rend="italic">forward</emph> look, the reservoir in front
                        is more than ever a scar on the body politic, or the corporation, (for all
                        the towns in Rockingham, such as Mt. Crawford, Bridgewater, Dayton,
                        &amp;c., are incorporated.) It speaks well for the place that they are
                        fixing to use the fine water power of Cook's Creek at one end of the town,
                        and are making crocks from the marsh at the other end. The hand of steady
                        industry is apparent all the way from Mt. Crawford to Harrisonburg, this
                        portion of the country was made very desolate, but one could hardly tell
                        that anything had ever happened to it, surely no one ever saw finer crops of
                        corn, or such fields of grass, so many new fences, to say nothing of the new
                        houses and new finger boards. The big spring even had a new look, as though
                        it had recuperated after resting from the many calls of <emph rend="italic"
                            >the many</emph>.</p>
                    <p>Harrisonburg does not give many <emph rend="italic">external</emph> proofs of
                        prosperity, but the town appears, upon closer acquaintance, to be getting
                        along very well. The Female Seminary is said to be very flourishing, but the
                        outside of it looks as though it were in a state of siege: it needs a little
                        paint and some trees. The new bank will be a very nice building, but the
                        head gear of it looks too much like an old fashioned lady's high-topped
                        comb. General Jones has improved the outside of the old stone church, and
                        the lots of tools he has stowed away inside when they get into the hands of
                        the farmers will do much to improve the country. The Collector of the U. S.
                        taxes goes into the old bank, where he will, no doubt, have more deposits
                        than the new one. The Register office looks much the same as of yore, but it
                        has a fine power press that beats all our Staunton new mills, but the
                        establishment reminded us of Imboden's big mule and little cannon that came
                        down to help us fight the battle of Port Republic. The "boys" all thought
                        the mule was too big for the gun, and we thought the press was too big for
                        the room it had, we don't mean anything more, for we venture that in a short
                        time they will have "the thing" going by steam. The Register is "an
                        institution" still in Rockingham, and its Senior evidently enjoys, (and who
                        would not?) the crowd of the old and young, male and female, that at an
                        early hour on the day of publication crowds his Sanctum eager for the
                        appearance of the paper. It always does us good to see people enjoy
                        themselves as the editor and his subscribers seemed to enjoy themselves. We
                        can't say much for the hotels, and, as for merchants the "Mammoth Store"
                        seems to have swallowed all the others, and surely a store that <emph
                            rend="italic">took in</emph> ninety thousand pounds of butter in one
                        year ought to swallow well. The lawyers appear to have taken Harrisonburg as
                        the Doctors have Staunton--and lest you should weary and say we have taken
                        too many notes we will stop.</p>
                    <p>Yours, &amp;c.<lb/> Z.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roller</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>This letter describes a trip through Augusta and Rockingham counties, and
                    highlights the recuperation of the Valley from the devastations of war. The
                    towns, businesses and buildings of the area are described in detail.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Staunton Male Academy</head>
                <origin>Richmond Whig</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Powers</ln>
                        <fn>Pike</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>This excerpt from the Richmond Whig praises the excellence of the Staunton
                    Male Academy, its Principal Mr. Pike Powers, and his associate Mr. Young. The
                    article notes that Staunton "has long been famous for its schools," and has a
                    "highly refined and attractive society" as well.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper prints the following report from New Orleans on the aftermath of
                    the riot: "The negroes are very docile now, very polite, and anxious to
                    cultivate the friendship of the Southern whites. They declare that the riot was
                    the fault of men whom they do not intend to have any further connection with."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper asserts that "the public will be gratified to know that General
                    Schofield has relieved Gen. Terry in command of this Department."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1866.08.15.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"Successful religious revivals are reported in Rockingham, Augusta and
                    Rockbridge counties."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shuey</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper reports that "four freedmen" were put in jail and charged with
                    stealing from George Shuey below Summerdean in Augusta County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Arrivals</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper estimates that there are over 2,000 tourists in the mountains.
                    629 people arrived in Staunton in the previous week; 356 at the American and 273
                    at the Virginia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>True Reconstruction</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that Col. C. A. Wells, late of the first New York Veteran
                    Volunteers, wrote a letter thanking the Ladies' Cemetery Committee for the work
                    they did on the graves of U. S. soldiers. "The brave honor the brave."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Base Ball</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richards</ln>
                        <fn>H. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>This article declares that "Staunton started Base Ball in Virginia." H. F.
                    Richards, a Baltimore native living in Staunton, introduced the sport, and "may
                    properly be called the father of the game in this State." Staunton's pioneering
                    efforts have led to the formation of clubs in Harrisonburg, Charlottesville, and
                    Richmond as well.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Our Town</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper is gratified to report that workmen have returned from the town
                    outskirts and are now engaged in repairing pavement on Main Street. The gas lamp
                    posts are also being put up. "Now if the Council would order the removal of all
                    obstructions; cellar doors, porches, &amp;c., we will be all right. Who is
                    the man in the Council bold enough to take this matter in hand?"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that "the colored people of Harrisonburg" raised over
                    $100 at a dinner heavily attended by whites. "The ministers of the various
                    denominations addressed them and the best of feeling prevailed among all
                    parties. We are always glad to chronicle such pleasant facts about our colored
                    population in the Valley, which we believe is the best in the South."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>W. A. Sterrett</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sterrett</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper confirms a "painful rumor" that W. A. Sterrett, "Little Will," is
                    dead. He passed away in Santa Fee, Missouri. "Staunton will mourn the loss of
                    one of her favorites."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Richmond Whig reports that the "public spirit and enterprise of
                    Staunton are generally up to, if not ahead of our large cities."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is announced that the Augusta Female Seminary will open on September
                    17th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that a federal soldier who had been wounded and held
                    prisoner in Staunton sent a $1 contribution to assist the ladies' efforts to
                    decorate the graves of the Confederate dead. "This fact speaks volumes to some
                    of our people."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>A Way to Sleep</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A reporter who had trouble sleeping occupied himself by counting all the
                    widows and widowers in Staunton. The result: 21 widows and 82 widowers. "He then
                    started to count the pretty girls, counted 627 and went to sleep, dreaming of
                    Mahomet's Heaven."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Crops</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A trip through Augusta, Rockbridge, and Allegheny counties results in
                    information on the crops. "The corn has improved wonderfully lately, and in some
                    portions farmers will not be able to house their crop. The splendid crops have
                    greatly encouraged the people, and everything is looking up. Now for the Valley
                    Railroad--we can afford it, and it must be built."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>Robert H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>Ellie H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Latane</ln>
                        <fn>J. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lieut. Robert H. Fisher, of Richmond, and Miss Ellie H. Taylor, of
                    Staunton, were married on August 9th by the Rev. J. N. Latane.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickle</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lockridge</ln>
                        <fn>Bettie N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Preston</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John A. Bickle, of Staunton, and Miss Bettie N. Lockridge, of Rockbridge,
                    were married by the Rev. Mr. Preston on July 25th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gochenour</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Elizabeth Gochenour died in August 7th near Hermitage. She was 18
                    years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennady</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Sarah A. Kennady died on August 10th near Hermitage. She was 34 years
                    old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1866.08.15.04" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that at a fair for the benefit of soldiers' and sailors'
                    orphans held in Washington, D. C., and "conducted almost exclusively under New
                    England auspices, orders were issued not to admit colored persons."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
