<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1866/va.au.vv.1866.05.09">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/16/04</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1866-05-09">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day norm="">9</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1866.05.09.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1866.05.09.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that the alleged riot at Falmouth turned out to be a
                    hoax.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports "great excitement" in Memphis surrounding a "negro riot"
                    which was suppressed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that "some fool in Congress has been talking about
                    admitting negro cadets to West Point, but it was voted down."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Honor the Fallen Brave</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>To-morrow is the sad anniversary of the death of Virginia's bravest and best
                        loved son. To-morrow three years ago, Stonewall Jackson, the Christian, the
                        Soldier and the greatest military genius of the age, passed from earth to
                        Heaven. And it is but meet that the people of his loved Valley should
                        consecrate the day and hold it sacred--devoting their minds, hearts and
                        hands to the work of decorating the graves of his soldiers and paying proper
                        respect to his memory. The Ladies Cemetery Committee call upon the people of
                        Augusta to join them in this "labor of love," and we feel confident that,
                        though the notice is short, the demonstration will be worthy of old Augusta.
                        Let our farmers aid the ladies, and let evergreens and flowers be brought in
                        by wagon loads. Over two thousand "dead heroes," from every State in the
                        South, lie uncared for and unnoticed in Thornrose Cemetery. Brave hearts and
                        true, they lost all, even life, for us, and it will gladden the hearts of
                        many widows and orphans in the far distant South, to know that the remains
                        of their loved ones are not neglected by the fair women of the Valley.</p>
                    <p>In the more Southern States, the 23rd of April, was devoted to this holy
                        purpose, but by common consent the 10th of May has been set apart in
                        Virginia to preserve and perpetuate the memory of our martyred dead; to
                        freshen their graves and to renew, from year to year, these offices of love
                        and attention that make green the memory of those who once "trod the path of
                        glory." Our Merchants and business men will observe the day by closing their
                        places of business, and it is hoped that all will unite to pay that respect
                        due those who gave all for their country and their principle.</p>
                    <p>It is but little that is left to us of the South, but surely we can devote
                        one day to the honored memory of those that sleep in soldiers' graves. Then
                        cover their graves with flowers; make the barren hill that disgraces our
                        Cemetery, for one day at least, "blossom as the rose," and give an earnest
                        of what you intend to do, to beautify and adorn the last resting place of
                        our best and bravest. Come, if only to shed a tear over the graves of those,
                        who for you, now lie in that neglected spot; come, they have "crossed over
                        the river," but do not "rest under the shade of the trees;" come and see</p>
                    <p>"How deep the brave who sink to rest<lb/> By all their country's wishes
                        blest!<lb/> When spring with dewy fingers cold<lb/> Returns to deck their
                        hallowed mould,<lb/> She there shall dress a sweeter sod<lb/> Than fancy's
                        feet have ever trod!</p>
                    <p>By fairy's hands is their knell rung;<lb/> By forms unseen their dirge is
                        sung;<lb/> There honor comes--a pilgrim gray<lb/> To bless the turf that
                        wraps their clay,<lb/> And freedom shall awhile repair<lb/> To dwell a
                        weeping hermit there!"</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper urges everyone to honor the anniversary of Stonewall Jackson's
                    death by decorating the graves of the Confederate dead. The editors report that
                    places of business will be closed for the occasion.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>That Petition</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Last week our citizens were astonished by seeing a telegraphic dispatch,
                        stating that Mr. Trumbull had presented a petition to the U.S. Senate, from
                        145 citizens of Staunton, praying for the return of troops to protect Union
                        men. That 146 citizens of Staunton, or even ten, ever signed such a petition
                        is false, and we suppose it is the same petition that was secretly
                        circulated over the county some time ago. Never has this town and county
                        been so orderly and quiet as it has been since the troops left, and even the
                        negroes rejoice at the change. No Union man has been molested and all have
                        received justice from the civil authorities. The friends of the originator
                        of this petition, apologize for his conduct on the ground that he is crazy,
                        but the fact that he has been tolerated in our midst so long, is the best
                        answer to the statements made in the petition. There is an old saying "that
                        if a man can't do any good in a country he should leave it," or at least try
                        to do no harm, and there is a point, where "forbearance ceases to be a
                        virtue."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper expresses outrage and disbelief that a petition asking for the
                    return of Federal troops to Augusta and signed by citizens of Staunton was
                    presented in Congress. The paper denounces it as a fraud and claims that "never
                    has this town and county been so orderly and quiet as it has been since the
                    troops left, and even the negroes rejoice at the change."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1866.05.09.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The remains of that noble hearted boy and gallant soldier, Thomas M. Garber,
                        color bearer of the 12th Virginia Cavalry, were brought to Staunton from
                        Upperville yesterday week and re-interred in Thornrose Cemetery. He was
                        mortally wounded in the Cavalry fight near Upperville, in 1863, and died
                        soon after. He was universally beloved by his Regiment, and though not of
                        military age, he volunteered at the call of his State. Peace to his
                    ashes.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garber</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper reports on the return to Staunton of the remains of Thomas M.
                    Garber, color-bearer of the 12th Virginia Cavalry.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Floyd</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hawkins</ln>
                        <fn>Fanny</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper reports that "John Clarke (white) and Floyd Smith (colored) were
                    arraigned before the Mayor and bound over to be of good behavior for six
                    months." The men were arrested "on complaint of Fanny Hawkins (free woman)."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Liberal</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>O'Ferrall</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper reports that Col. O'Ferrall, of the American Hotel, has placed
                    two wagons and teams at the disposal of the Ladies' Soldier's Cemetery
                    Committee, to prepare for decorating the Soldiers' graves."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Firemen's Parade</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that the Augusta Fire Company "turned out, 80 strong,
                    with engine, reel, transparances and torches and, headed by the Stonewall Band,
                    paraded through the principal Streets of the City. At Bickle's corner they gave
                    an exhibition of their skill, in the management of their engine, and right well
                    did they do their work. The band discoursed some of its sweetest music and the
                    whole affair was a great success."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Horse Thieves Arrested</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clauss</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Watson</ln>
                        <fn>Richard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Watson</ln>
                        <fn>D. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilderman</ln>
                        <fn>R. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mayor</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parrent</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Chief of Police</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper reports that "some stir was created in town by the arrest of two
                    men, Lewis Clauss and Richard, or D. A. Watson." The two men were charged with
                    stealing horses from R. M. Wilderman of Alleghany County, Maryland. Mr.
                    Wilderman tracked the men through the mountains, enlisting the help of a
                    Confederate veteran as a guide. They were found under false names at the
                    Virginia Hotel, and had sold two horses and were about to sell a third when
                    Chief of Police Parrent arrested them. Mayor Trout had the men held awaiting the
                    wishes of the Governor of Maryland. "The men had been working for Mr. Wilderman
                    and he supposed they had struck South, thinking he would be afraid to follow
                    them, as the Radical press has made the people out there think it unsafe for a
                    Union man to travel here. They counted without their host, for Mr. Wilderman
                    followed them and bears strong testimony to the kindness shown him by all
                    classes, and the assistance given."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fauntleroy</ln>
                        <fn>A. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Conrad</ln>
                        <fn>Sallie H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Conrad</ln>
                        <fn>R. Y.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Graham</ln>
                        <fn>J. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. A. M. Fauntleroy, of Staunton, and Miss Sallie H. Conrad, daughter of
                    the Hon. R. Y. Conrad of Winchester, were married on April 26th by the Rev. J.
                    R. Graham.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1866.05.09.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
