<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1866/va.au.vv.1866.03.07">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>5/27/04</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1866-03-07">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day norm="">7</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1866.03.07.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1866.03.07.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Baltimore and Richmond</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We said in our last, that we would undertake to show that the Valley Railroad
                        and Covington and Ohio Road, will move on harmoniously together, and, that
                        Richmond would be benefitted by every effort of Baltimore to advance either
                        of these improvements; and we proceed very briefly to give our views on
                        these points. <emph rend="italic">First</emph> then, in a great measure, the
                        two improvements are dependent on each other; and they must in our opinion
                        work in harmony. Intrinsically the through Valley Road from the Potomac to
                        Salem will be self sustaining; and its future abounds with promises of
                        prosperity. It will pass through the center of the richest Valley,
                        considering its width and length, on the Continent. It will force its way
                        through no barren wastes, inhospitable wilds or rugged Mountains. From one
                        terminus to the other, it will be in the midst of productive lands and
                        mineral deposits--water-power and facilities for manufactures, unsurpassed
                        in the world. As it advances, wealth, enterprize and eager crowds of earnest
                        men will follow in its wake and occupy the lands, develope their hidden
                        resources, and build up factories, workshops and manufactories. So that, by
                        the time the road is extended to Salem, the Valley itself will yield trade
                        enough to render the investment in it fairly remunerative. At Staunton it
                        will cross the Central; at Buchanan the Canal, and at Salem it will receive
                        blessings from and confer them on the Virginia and Tennessee.</p>
                    <p>Suppose in view of these intrinsic advantages and incidental connections, the
                        men of Baltimore should resolve to build the Valley Road, as they doubtless
                        will--how will this determination affect the Covington and Ohio enterprize?
                        This is to be a grand trunk line, connecting the Valley of the Ohio with the
                        Atlantic frontier. It is now locked up in the fastnesses of the Mountains;
                        it moves not--it is almost dead. How shall it be started forward, and made
                        alive with energy and power? By the reviving touch of Capital. How can
                        Capital be enlisted in this great Virginia work? By the hope of reward--the
                        prospect of gain. And we must remember that the Capital in this improvement
                        will make profits out of operations <emph rend="italic">only</emph> between
                        Covington and the Ohio River. It is a trunk line from the River through the
                        Mountains. To make <emph rend="italic">it</emph> pay, it must have as many
                        arteries and channels of trade and travel converging upon it at both ends as
                        possible. And we verily believe that Capital cannot be invested in this
                        work, without a fair prospect of liberal branches to attract traffic and
                        travel over it; and that, if the Legislature were to declare, that the
                        operations over the line should be in connection with Richmond alone, the
                        Road would never be made, except by direct and oppressive taxation on the
                        two Virginias.</p>
                    <p>Hence we argue that a reasonable prospect of a first class road down the
                        Valley from Staunton, will stimulate the investment of Capital in the
                        Covington &amp; Ohio Road; and on the other hand, the assurance that the
                        Covington and Ohio Road will be advanced in its prospects of success, by the
                        construction of the Valley Road, will quicken the earnest determination of
                        the friends of the Valley improvement, to have it ready to receive its share
                        of the full flow of wealth, which will burst through the Mountains when the
                        trunk line West is opened. Hence we say the two enterprizes must contribute
                        to the advancement, each of the other, and move on harmoniously to final
                        success.</p>
                    <p>And what of Richmond the while? Is she to sit mourning in ashes and ruin?
                        Heaven forbid a doom so sad. We have more cheerful views of her future. We
                        take it for granted she will try to get ready for the Spring tide of
                        fortune--that her store-houses will be fitted up--her shops and factories
                        busily at work--her communications with City Point and Newport News opened
                        and in full operation--her manufacturers skillful--her merchants
                        enterprizing--her offers to trade tempting--and her strong arms stretched
                        forth to grasp the rich prizes of trade as they are thrust to the Mountains,
                        Eastward, in search of a market. All these things we expect of her; and we
                        have no doubt our expectations will not be disappointed.</p>
                    <p>"The Gods aid those who help themselves," and so it will be with Richmond, if
                        she enacts the part neither of Niobe nor of Rachel. Tears won't help her.
                        She must work--"begin, be bold and venture to be wise." She must arm herself
                        "with the unconquerable will, the courage never to submit or yield." She
                        must invite Capital to her, and not force it away by exorbitant
                        exactions--and, with new means and energy and courage, make use of the
                        prodigious advantages nature has bestowed on her for the supremacy in
                        manufactures; and in ten years the eddying currents of wealth-giving traffic
                        will move up and down the Valley, through the Tunnel and "on to Richmond,"
                        and the gushing volume of her through trade with Cincinnati, Louisville and
                        other cities of the Great West will task her utmost capacity to accommodate
                        and dispose of it.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In this editorial, the paper advocates construction of both the North-South
                    Valley Railroad and the East-West Covington Railroad despite the objections of
                    Richmond. The editors assure Richmond that their city will not be hurt,
                    celebrate the resources of the Valley, and paint a glowing picture of the area's
                    economic future.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>The Cholera</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper calls the attention of the street commissioners to tips for the
                    prevention of cholera "which threatens to attack us next summer." Householders
                    should scrupulously clean their property, the streets must be cleaned, and all
                    must be done in February and March because "if put off until warm weather, the
                    very effort necessary for the removal of filth will only tend, in the essential
                    nature of things, to hasten the appearance of the disease, to increase its
                    malignity, and to extend the time of its devastation; because the suns of Spring
                    and Summer the sooner warm it into life and intensify the viperic and malignant
                    influence, which in its remorseless tread, wrecks so much of human happiness and
                    desolates so many hearthstones."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1866.03.07.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper warns that counterfeit money is circulating in the area.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper announces that Captain James Bumgardner qualified as Attorney for
                    the Commonwealth at the last court.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper announces that the County Court has ordered the civil officers of
                    Augusta to enforce all summons of the Freedmen's Court.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper notes that "the colored people turned out in a body last Sunday,
                    to attend the funeral of a child of one of their number. Their Church is
                    flourishing."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Corporation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kayser</ln>
                        <fn>William B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>R. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper announces that the town council passed an ordinance creating the
                    offices of "Commissioner of Streets" (appointing Mr. William B. Kayser) and
                    "Superintendent of Water Works" (appointing R. W. Smith).</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper announces that the Staunton Fire company "are ready for action,
                    having greased up their hose." "The run with the reel last Friday was a splendid
                    sight."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Decker</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Biby</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kurtz</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Deputy Sergt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper reports that Catharine Decker and Margaret Biby, "street walkers
                    from the country" were arrested and put in jail by Deputy Sergt. Kurtz. "The
                    authorities are determined to keep such cattle out of town."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Odd</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tukey</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn>Bob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shelton</ln>
                        <fn>Bob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper reports that Bob, "a colored boy" was arrested by Mr. Tukey for
                    stealing two odd boots, a number 7 and a number 8, from Darden and Brothers.
                    "Bob Shelton, the colored man in Darden's store, saw the other Bob with the
                    boots on and arrested him and recovered the boots."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Graduated</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phillips</ln>
                        <fn>Charley</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Berkeley</ln>
                        <fn>Carter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper announces the graduation, with honors, of "two of our Staunton
                    boys" from the Baltimore Medical College. Charley Phillips graduated first in
                    his class and Lieut. Carter Berkeley, second. "Wherever they hang their shingle,
                    they have our best wishes for the success we know they well deserve."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Robbed</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Briggs</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tukey</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper reports that John Briggs, "one of the most respectable colored
                    men of Staunton," was robbed of specie and other goods by a black man. Briggs
                    took the case and the culprit to Mr. Tukey and "was satisfied with the result."
                    "In this connection we are pleased to notice that Mr. Tukey is doing every thing
                    in his power to regulate the Freedmen, and his decisions give general
                    satisfaction. In this good work he should have the assistance of all good
                    citizens.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Augusta's Delegates to the Valley Rail Road Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn>H. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>Bolivar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>A. H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>W. J. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bruce</ln>
                        <fn>G. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shelton</ln>
                        <fn>T. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McChesney</ln>
                        <fn>Adam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henry</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf>Sr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>S. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tate</ln>
                        <fn>W. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sterrett</ln>
                        <fn>W. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>Absolom</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fulton</ln>
                        <fn>J. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gamble</ln>
                        <fn>Theopolis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harper</ln>
                        <fn>Kenton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>T.</fn>
                        <sf>Sr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Finley</ln>
                        <fn>S. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craig</ln>
                        <fn>J. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Montgomery</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper announces Augusta's delegates to the Valley Railroad Convention.
                    They were appointed by the chairman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>John S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palmer</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gaver</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. John S. Myers, of Waynesboro, married Miss Maggie J. Palmer, of Port
                    Republic, Rockingham County, on March 1st. The Rev. Mr. Gaver presided.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Airy</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George Airy passed away on February 25th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John McCue, aged 51 years, died on February 22nd.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Poole</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>General</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>General H. Poole, aged 25 years, died at Bridgewater on February 10th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sterrett</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. James Sterrett, aged 46 years, died on January 1st in Rockbridge.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>James</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Robert James, a member of the 27th Infantry, Stonewall Brigade, died of
                    consumption on March 1st. He was from Alleghany.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Although it is with mournful pleasure that our thoughts dwell on the memory
                        of this brave boy, it is yet with profound sadness we remember his early
                        death. Associated with him during his career as a soldier, it may be
                        supposed, that we intimately knew his good qualities, and loved him as only
                        a brother could.</p>
                    <p>It is seldom that we find in one so young as Captain FLETCHER such firmly
                        fixed principles. He was the soul of honor, and his gallantry in action and
                        strict attention to duty in camp, combined to raise him to the highest place
                        in the confidence of his superiors. Nor was he less beloved or less honored
                        and respected by his associates and men. They acknowledged his rare talents
                        and military virtues, and gave him their respect and obedience on all
                        occasions.</p>
                    <p>Independent of his excellent military qualities which, of necessity, tend
                        socially to separate men, he possessed a kind, humane and loving heart, and
                        his last thoughts, as shown by his words, were turned to his young comrades
                        in arms, with whom he had passed so many hours of pleasure and of trial. But
                        it was the will of a Higher Power that he should depart, and we must not
                        repine--but, although we know that--we cannot repress our grief.</p>
                    <p>At this time, although far removed from the scene, we are carried back to the
                        banks of the Chickahominy; a young and mangled body arises before our
                        eyes--the whirl and excitement of battle--and then, the end--the death-damp
                        upon his noble brow--the painful lingering of a few days--the mutterings of
                        home and friends--the release. He is gone, and a <emph rend="italic">nobler
                            boy</emph> never died. His memory and example alone remain with us. Let
                        us cherish the one and emulate the other.</p>
                    <p>The following is an extract from a letter written by the late Colonel Wm. S.
                        Baylor to a friend:</p>
                    <p>"How nobly has your city contributed in men and officers for this war; and
                        oh! how sadly has this war dealt with them. I wrote to you not long since of
                        poor young FLETCHER. How gallantly the boy--for he was not a man in years,
                        though fully one in manliness and soldierly bearing--bore himself in all the
                        battles we were in together. Wounded by a severe bruise of a shell on
                        Friday, he did not ask to be relieved of duty, but still was at the head of
                        his company, next morning, attending to its wants as he always did. And when
                        at the Battle of Malvern Hill he was struck by a shell which penetrated
                        through and through his body, leaving the most frightful wound I ever saw,
                        his brave spirit, forgetful of his own awful pain, still thought of his men
                        and his country, as he turned his eyes towards the regiment and said: 'Keep
                        in good spirits boys! This is a just cause.' He afterwards said, 'I am dying
                        a poor little refugee,' as his thoughts turned to his home and the dear ones
                        far away. The tear that I wiped from my cheek, as I turned from his side to
                        other duties, was not unmanly, nor did it unfit me for the more dangerous
                        scenes which surrounded us. His was an untimely end, and had Providence in
                        His wisdom seen fit to spare him, though a youth to fortune and fame
                        unknown. I believe he would have proven himself a man in this world and the
                        pride of his family. If you have an opportunity please let his family learn
                        what his Colonel thought of him, and you can assure them I but speak the
                        voice of the entire regiment--it may assuage their grief."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fletcher</ln>
                        <fn>Louis J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>William S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Capt. Louis J. Fletcher, of Company A., "Marion Rifles," 5th Virginia
                    Infantry, died on July 3rd, 1862, of wounds received at the battle of Malvern
                    Hill. He was 19 years old and hailed from Winchester. The paper publishes the
                    following obituary.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1866.03.07.04" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Women of the South</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>From a beautiful tribute to the women of the South, in the <emph
                            rend="italic">Courier des Etats Unis</emph>, the French paper in New
                        York, we make the following extracts. It is written in answer to the gross
                        slanders of the New York Tribune. It is all the more gratifying when we
                        answer it as the unbiased opinion of a foreigner. The <emph rend="italic"
                            >Courier</emph> says:</p>
                    <p>Let us permit the <emph rend="italic">Tribune</emph> to insist upon the
                        "gross ignorance" of the Confederate women, and to refer to this ignorance
                        their energy and constancy during the war. We attribute the great qualities
                        of which the Southern women have given noble example to a higher origin.
                        Ignorance, the <emph rend="italic">Tribune</emph> has said it a hundred
                        times, can engender only vice and meanness--and, if the Confederate women
                        have been heroic, it is because they had faith in their cause. There are
                        occasions in history when women, whose mission in ordinary times is to make
                        the good wife, the tender mother, and to polish manners by the charm and
                        grace which she brings into all social relations, may rise above herself and
                        give examples of the highest virtues. These occasions occur when the sacred
                        soil of her country and with it (or through it) the domestic hearth and the
                        family are threatened with invasion.</p>
                    <p>These high virtues of the women of the South have practiced without
                        ostentation, without theatrical parade. They have borne all privations, they
                        have defied all outrages by their proud and impassable attitude. Soldiers,
                        drunken with blood, could outrage their bodies, but their victims remained
                        as pure as those Christian virgins whose memories the embraces of the
                        executioner could not defile. All that is precious to women--dress, jewels,
                        the luxuries of home--all those the Southern women gave up--they did not
                        even recoil before sacrifices still more painful--they did not fear to break
                        their hearts by sending forth their sons to do battle for a cause, sacred in
                        their eyes, like that Lacedomonian mother who showed a shield to her son and
                        said simply--return with it--or upon it--do thy duty, or die. Do not expect
                        such traits from ignorant women, from souls without elevation!</p>
                    <p>And while desolation over all the hearths of the South, while mothers had
                        each day fresh tears to wipe away, yet bravely bore their grief, how, were
                        the women of the North employed? In developing a costly luxury against which
                        the <emph rend="italic">Tribune</emph> itself cried out, calling attention
                        to its scandalous extent, feminine prodigality became more and more
                        unrestrained. We know to what disastrous result this state of affairs had
                        led. Some ladies, it is true, like Miss Anna Dickenson, gave it tiresome
                        lectures to promiscuous audiences; other clamored for pretended woman's
                        rights, and exposed themselves to the derision of the public; and others
                        still enrolled themselves under the banner of miscegenation. It is among
                        these classes of women, who defy good sense and modesty in public
                        exhibitions, that the <emph rend="italic">Tribune</emph> finds its ideal?</p>
                    <p>Let this journal then cease to insult these conquered women, of whom the
                        defeat has not diminished the greatness; let it cease to embitter and
                        dishonor its pen in sustaining an indefensible paradox. The North, like the
                        South, has its continent of good, graceful, educated and elegant bred women;
                        it has, perhaps, a larger number of that class who so little deserve the
                        name of women, and for whom certain announcements are made in the journals;
                        it possesses, also, a greater share of learned and pedantic ladies--but for
                        these, will New Orleans not become envious of Boston. As for good and
                        well-bred society, it is the same everywhere, and the <emph rend="italic"
                            >Tribune</emph> may be sure that a woman of the world, coming from
                        Boston, would not feel out of place in New Orleans, nor would the contrary
                        be true. In calumniating the Southern women Mr. Greeley has simply proved
                        that he does not know them, and that he knows still less the common laws of
                        propriety.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper prints extracts of an article from the Courier des Etats Unis
                    defending the honor and reputation of Southern women. The women of the South,
                    the article argues, acquitted themselves bravely during the war, and behaved
                    according to accepted gender roles. Their actions stand in stark contrast to
                    Northern women who embraced a variety of radical causes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
