<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1866/va.au.vv.1866.10.17">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>7/2/04</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1866-10-17">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="10">October</month>
            <day norm="">17</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1866.10.17.01" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Repudiation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors of the paper come out against repudiation of state debts.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1866.10.17.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Situation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We give this heading with no pleasant feelings this week, not that we feel so
                        very badly over "the situation," but because we know there are many of our
                        people; many brave men and glorious women, who do. And, in fact, "the
                        situation" is not cheering, nor does the future break upon us with paths
                        strewn with flowers, or of "pleasantness and peace."</p>
                    <p>The Radicals have carried, if not with increased majority, any how with
                        enough for all practical purposes, the great States of Pennsylvania, Ohio,
                        Indiana and Iowa. Baltimore City is still under the iron heel of radical
                        misrule, and the shouts of triumph, from the victors, over the friends of
                        law and order, are the only sounds that reach us from the North. General
                        Geary, Governor elect of Pennsylvania, speaks in no uncertain tones, when he
                        congratulates the supporters on the triumphs they have gained; he boldly
                        proclaims the President a "traitor," and stigmatizes him as a "tyrant,"
                        compared with whom "Nero, whose infancy is written in the immortal pages of
                        [unclear]," is a patriot and a gentleman. He proclaims a policy for his
                        party that looks to the elevation of the negro to an equality with the white
                        man. The lesser lights of the dominant party are jubilant, vindictive and
                        mean, and, like flee dogs, make more noises than the sturdy curs of power.</p>
                    <p>The whole North seems to be in a whirl of excitement, and foolish people
                        there talk of war as a thing not only to be expected, but to be desired.
                        They talk of "impeaching the President," for doing his duty conscientiously,
                        and men who carried them successfully through the war are glibly called
                        "traitors," "perjured scoundrels," &amp;c. Amid [unclear] storm of
                        abuse; of vilification; of run mad folly, the President backed by the
                        Conservative or Democratic party North, stand true to his principles, a
                        giant among the pigmies.</p>
                    <p>That the President will continue to stand firm, every indication leads us to
                        believe and, as foolish as we think the radicals, we can not bring ourselves
                        to believe they are fools enough to try the game of impeachment. Men, in the
                        struggle for political power, especially in a Republican Government, say
                        many things they never intend to carry out or attempt. Braggarts and
                        cowards, who never faced a Confederate line of battle, talk bravely of war
                        and of subduing unarmed "rebels," but the war proved one thing, viz: <emph
                            rend="italic">that no war can be carried on in this Country without a
                            draft or conscription</emph>, and those who talk about it <emph
                            rend="italic">would do well to count the cost</emph>.</p>
                    <p>It is a consoling thought that those who fought through the war, on both
                        sides, have had enough of it, and that those who "shirked" are not likely to
                        get up a war for their own amusement. In short, the sum and substance of the
                        result of the late election is that the radicals used every social
                        influence; excited every Northern prejudice; run Generals for office, lied
                        on us, bragged, bullied and won. And now they have secured the power, we
                        believe they will not be able to make our position any worse, even if they
                        wish to.</p>
                    <p>A Northern Radical argues this way--"you Southern people controlled this
                        Republic for sixty years, you tried to break it up, on a principle, and we
                        overcame you. Now do you think we are going to give up all this power or let
                        you share it? Never, as long as we can help it. We are not particular about
                        the means we use. We don't care about the negro, only so far as he is a good
                        party rallying cry and so far as we can use him, but of one thing be
                        assured, we will use every means, good or bad, to hold the power." In
                        private this is about the argument of leading Radicals and no matter how
                        vindictive and mean some may be, we do not think the leaders are such
                        consummate fools as to allow that party to be led further.</p>
                    <p>"And what are we to do?" still comes up from the Southern people. The answer
                        is simply, attend to your own business and <emph rend="italic">work</emph>.
                        We can do nothing to effect the results North; this radical party must run
                        its course and nothing has dum founded them so much as the utter
                        indifference displayed by the Southern people, as to what is going on North.
                        To all amendments made to the Constitution we must utter an emphatic "<emph
                            rend="italic">No</emph>" and all threats, or bullying about war we must
                        laugh to scorn. If any fighting is to be done, gentlemen, do it on "your own
                        line," we have had enough. In the words of the Cavalier Bayard of the South,
                        the gallant and gifted General Hampton, of South Carolina: "The essential
                        points then, in the policy we should pursue, are, it appears to me, these:
                        That we should fulfill all the obligations we have entered into, to the
                        letter, keeping our faith so clear that no shadow of dishonor can fall on
                        us; that we should sustain Mr. Johnson cordially in his policy, giving our
                        support to that party which rallies around him; that we should yield full
                        obedience to the laws of the land, reserving to our selves at the same time,
                        the inalienable right of freedom of speech and of opinion; and that, as to
                        the great question which so materially affected our interests, the abolition
                        of slavery, we should declare it settled forever. Pursue this course
                        steadily; bear with patience and dignity those evils which are pressing
                        heavily upon you. Commit yourselves to the guidance of God, and whatever may
                        be your fate you may be able to face the future without self-reproach."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This editorial reacts to the triumph of Republican candidates in elections
                    across the North. The article argues that Republicans are bent upon retaining
                    power by abusing the South and support the impeachment of the President even if
                    it leads to further conflict. The South, the article suggests, should support
                    the President, and trust to the fact that the Radicals are too cowardly to push
                    the issue further.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>What are our Lands worth, and our Duties?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article asserts that the value of lands in Virginia and Maryland is
                    50% higher than in the North due to climate, fertility, and access to markets.
                    Southerners should not be afraid to charge high prices for their lands, but
                    should keep them affordable enough to encourage immigration from the North and
                    elsewhere. The influx of "industrious people" will only push land values higher.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Negro</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"The negro is not to be neglected," justly and sensibly remarks the Nashville
                            <emph rend="italic">Christian Advocate</emph>, "because he is no longer
                        our slave. He must be enlightened, not left in ignorance--drawn to us, not
                        driven from us--treated kindly, not coldly--as if <emph rend="italic"
                        >he</emph> were to blame for all the evils which have come upon our land--he
                        must be encouraged to labour, and that, too, in the cultivation of the soil,
                        not trusting to a precarious and perhaps dishonest support, in towns and
                        villages. Let him see that his old master is still his best friend; and that
                        the Churches which have done so much for him will do still more, by the
                        blessing of God, if he will not refuse their aid."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This excerpt from the Nashville Christian Advocate urges southern whites
                    not to abandon the freedmen, but to tutor them and encourage them to labor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Constitutional Amendment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper concurs with the arguments of the Raleigh Sentinel that urge
                    southerners not to support the 14th amendment, since it will be forced on the
                    South anyway. "Southern votes may stand for all time, and we shall become
                    parties to measures which may result in the overthrow and destruction of the
                    Republic, and the extinction or removal of one or both races in the South."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>George D. Prentice's Interview with Jefferson Davis--Danger of Secession at
                    the North--A Most Timely Warning</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This conversation with Jefferson Davis asserts that the North refused to
                    accept southern independence because it would set a precedent for future
                    fragmentation of the Union. This, the participants argue, only reinforces the
                    hypocrisy of the Radical Republicans who are willing to sacrifice easy reunion
                    for their own ends.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>236 people arrived at the American and Virginia Hotels last week.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The price of gas is much less in Petersburg, at $5 per thousand feet, than
                    in Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Flour</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fifer</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>B. F. Fifer, Staunton flour inspector, inspected 900 barrels of flour
                    between Sept. 25th and Oct. 15.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Our Soldier's Cemetery</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>This is a burning shame upon Augusta, that while other towns are proudly
                        inaugurating their Cemeteries ours is at a stand still. A meeting will be
                        held Monday evening, to devise ways and means to aid the Ladies in making
                        the Cemetery all it should be. People of Augusta and the South do your duty
                        towards the thousands who died for you and you can face the future bravely.
                        People of Augusta go to work and take this shame from among us.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper is ashamed that Augusta has not made more progress on its
                    Cemetery, and calls a mass meeting to support the project.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1866.10.17.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper calls attention to a poem printed in column two honoring Turner
                    Ashby "whose remains are soon to be re-interred in his own loved Valley."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robinson</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Robinson is commencing work on Augusta street, which forms part of
                    the Valley Turnpike. The contractor is braking rock and distributing over the
                    street.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Gas Works</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peck</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Capt. Peck of the Gas Works is asked to look into complaints about the poor
                    quality of gas used in street lamps, failure to keep the glass clean, and the
                    fact that they go out before midnight.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper encourages the girls of Winchester to come to Staunton, since the
                    "matrimonial market is dull" in Winchester. The young men there are "a set of
                    snivelers who are afraid to take any responsibility on themselves," while the
                    Staunton boys "know how to appreciate the noble girls of Virginia."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Police Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mosby</ln>
                        <fn>Marthy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greaver</ln>
                        <fn>Caroline</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greaver</ln>
                        <fn>Jerry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kenney</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carter</ln>
                        <fn>Patrick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Givens</ln>
                        <fn>Richard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Marthy Mosby, Caroline Greaver, and Jerry Greaver, "all colored, were
                    arrested for fighting and throwing rocks in the streets." The Greavers were
                    discharged, and Mosby held to bail for good behavior. Henry Kenney, "colored,
                    was arrested on complaint of Patrick Carter: brought before Justice Balthis and
                    the case dismissed. Richard Givens was arrested for being drunk and assigned
                    quarters in Harlan's Hotel."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Inspectors</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tukey</ln>
                        <fn>F. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn>J. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fullers</ln>
                        <fn>Levi</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gentry</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roberts</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Aude</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Searing</ln>
                        <fn>L. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger's</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Osbon</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fulcher</ln>
                        <fn>E. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blum</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The following liquor inspectors have been assigned to distilleries in
                    Augusta County: F. S. Tukey, at J. R. Grove's Distillery; Levi Fullers, at
                    Gentry and Roberts' Distillery; Thomas Aude, at John Hanger's Distillery; L. H.
                    Searing, at Peter Hanger's Distillery; William Osbon, at E. A. Fulcher's
                    Distillery; Mr. Blum, at L. Bumgardner's Distillery.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>How to Avoid Repudiation?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper suggest "a more liberal and enlightened policy on the part of the
                    politicians and newspapers of Eastern Virginia towards the people of the
                    Valley," if they wish to stave off repudiation and see debts paid down.
                    Completion of the Valley Railroad, opposed in Richmond, would be the best way to
                    ensure ability to pay debts.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Gen. Early</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We find an eloquent and beautiful letter of thanks to the Ladies of
                        Winchester, from this distinguished officer, in return for their patriotic
                        attention to his fallen comrades. His letter closes thus:</p>
                    <p>"It is sad, sad indeed to be an exile from my country, and still sadder to
                        mourn the loss of the most just and sacred cause for which man ever fought;
                        but there is some comfort in knowing that the struggle which developed the
                        heroism on the part of our soldiers and so many virtues in our women has not
                        been all in vain; and wherever I may wander, I will bear with me the proud
                        consolation derived from the knowledge that my countrywomen, who were so
                        faithful and devoted during all the trials and vicissitudes of our dreadful
                        contest for independence, now that it has gone against us, remain true to
                        the memories of the dead. Power and money may procure costly monuments and
                        testimonials to communicate the names of those who fought for the successful
                        party, but all the power and wealth of the world cannot command so rich a
                        tribute as that paid to the memories of the heroic dead of the Confederate
                        armies by the tears of the women of the South."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>General Early writes thanking the Ladies of Winchester for their "patriotic
                    attention to his fallen comrades."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clements</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vines</ln>
                        <fn>Nannie E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stringer</ln>
                        <fn>W. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>B. F. Clements and Miss Nannie E. Vines, both of Augusta, were married on
                    October 4th by the Rev. W. R. Stringer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoddard</ln>
                        <fn>Sallie M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sallie M. Stoddard, aged 9 months and 2 days, died in Staunton on October
                    14th after an 8-hour illness.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1866.10.17.04" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>South Carolina Protecting Her Negroes</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that South Carolina passed a law granting rights to the
                    freedmen, including the right to make contracts, sue, testify in court, inherit,
                    purchase, lease or sell property, and enjoy personal security, liberty and
                    property. "Marriages between blacks and whites are still illegal."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
