<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1866/va.au.vv.1866.12.28">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>8/02/04</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1866-12-28">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="12">December</month>
            <day norm="">28</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1866.12.28.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1866.12.28.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We would that the <emph rend="italic">Valley Virginian</emph> could truly
                        send forth such a greeting to its [section unclear]. But, as we sit down to
                        write the usual greeting, a picture comes up before us that saddens our
                        heart and makes us feel anything but "merry."</p>
                    <p>It is useless to whine and cry over the past; in the midst of the stern and
                        solemn present, idle regrets and repinings are vain. We speak now of our own
                        loved Southern people and their situation. We could paint a word picture of
                        this season, as it was years ago, that would move the sternest heart to
                        mirth and jollity. We could tell of the good old times of the past; of
                        generous and open handed hospitality, dispensed by whole souled and generous
                        Virginia gentlemen; of the good cheer that crowned their boards; of dancing,
                        of music, of egg-nogs, &amp;c., and of how, "all went merry as a
                        marriage bell." How every boy fired his "crackers," how the boys, (alas! how
                        many 'sleep the sleep that knows no waking') courted the girls, how young
                        folks were married and how we were all rich, proud and happy.</p>
                    <p>But the Christmas of 1866 brings up no such pictures. It comes to us trooping
                        with memories of a glorious past, but the glowing thoughts and
                        recollections, of other days, are clouded over by the thought that many who
                        made it so are now no more. The bitter winds, which whistle around remind us
                        that the widow, the orphan and the maimed of a ruthless and cruel war, may
                        be unprotected from the storm; unfed, uncared for and desolate in this <emph
                            rend="italic">very</emph> "Merry Christmas." In looking back over the
                        past we see the remains of a gallant and glorious people, a people who lost
                        all but honor in defence of the right--left to the tender mercies of the
                        most brutal mob that ever claimed to exercise power, under the forms of law.
                        The bright visions of a restored Republic; the fond hopes of peace; the
                        sacred pledges of a government that boasts it is the "best the world ever
                        saw," have been dissipated by the action of the present Congress and we
                        enter upon the new year, not knowing what a day or an hour may bring forth.
                        Civil law is overrun by the strong arm of military power and Sovereign
                        States whose master minds gave form and substance to Constitutional
                        Government in its infancy, are threatened with being "territorialized." The
                        North, rioting in financial wealth and prosperity full of "pride, vain glory
                        and hypocrisy," seems bent on destroying the South and deigns not to ask a
                        "Good lord to deliver them." Theirs may be, in appearance, a "Merry
                        Christmas" but surely ours is not.</p>
                    <p>Though this is a gloomy picture, we have much to be thankful for. We can at
                        least eat our humble fare and feel conscious that honest labor has rewarded
                        us with enough to supply our daily necessities. We can greet each other as
                        men who have "suffered and grown strong" together; we can look the world
                        boldly in the face and proudly point to the results of a year's labor, under
                        circumstances such as never opposed a people before. If our fare is not so
                        rich, or our servants so plenty, still we have enough and some to spare, and
                        we can look forward with cheerful hearts to the prospect of a bountiful
                        harvest and a merrier Christmas in 1867. And while we can't say "merry
                        Christmas," the <emph rend="italic">Valley Virginian</emph> sends forth its
                        best wishes to one and all of its readers, and it bids them to be of good
                        heart, for the "darkest hour lies just before the dawn."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Valley Virginian uses its Christmas message to reflect on the current
                    political situation and the destruction wrought by the war. The editors argue
                    that Christmas cannot be "Merry" in such times, but that Virginians should be
                    thankful for what they have and look forward to the future with hope.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Exactly!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The <emph rend="italic">Gazette</emph> truly says "The Radicals at the North
                        say and do everything they can to keep up sectional strife, and to excite
                        the feelings of the Southern people, and then blame our people for the state
                        of public opinion which they themselves purposely and with malice pretense
                        create. They seek to annoy, injure, irritate, and oppress, and then cry out
                        against those who show a natural resentment against such wrongs upon
                        defenseless and unrepresented communities? This is unjust and ungenerous. If
                        they so act as to induce want of respect and confidence, can they reasonably
                        expect kind feelings in return? Ought there not, now that war is over, be
                        some reciprocity, to bring out a restoration of harmony?"</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article argues that Radical Republicans in Congress deliberately
                    foment sectional discord in order to blame the South and justify harsher
                    treatment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article argues that the American Republic is doomed, and resembles
                    Rome before its collapse. War has led to the corruption of the judiciary,
                    congress and the ballot box, as they move toward the establishment of a
                    despotism. Wealth blinds Northerners to their duty. Only the South, made poor
                    through war, retains the virtue to prevent the destruction of the Republic.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1866.12.28.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper predicts that the "vineyards of the valley will become an
                    important source of wealth to Virginia. The surrounding mountain ranges give
                    them a warm and even climate, which is peculiarly favorable to grape culture."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>A Lie</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper denounces Senator Wilson as a liar for asserting that "all
                    through the South the midnight air was lightened by the burning school houses of
                    the freedmen." The editors argue that "we have just finished printing posters
                    and tickets for the colored people's fair, held here, in the Town Hall, this
                    week. The schools are going on undisturbed and the fair is visited by our white
                    people. Now if Senator Wilson is right, how is it that these colored people come
                    to an office, known as 'rebel' to get their printing done! For the proof of this
                    we refer him to the respectable colored people of Staunton."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Christmas</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rosenberger</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>N. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bagby</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Johnny</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pemberton</ln>
                        <fn>Jimmy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper announces that it will give its "soldier-printers" a week off for
                    Christmas. "In the army they were good and true soldiers--in our office they
                    have proved themselves worthy of their record." The paper mentions in
                    particular: Lieut. J. B. Rosenberger (18th Cav), the foreman; N. H. Anderson;
                    George Bagby; Johnny Smith; and Jimmy Pemberton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>"Panic in the Valley."</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper takes offence at an article published in the Richmond Times which
                    reports that all mules belonging to the U.S. kept in private hands through theft
                    or taken in as strays will be confiscated by the authorities. The order
                    allegedly caused a "panic" in the Valley as worried owners drove the animals off
                    into the mountains. "This is the first news of this order our people have
                    received, and there is no "panic" here. Who sent the dispatch?" asks the paper.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Letter From Gen. Early</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Ladies' Memorial Association of Mt. Jackson, having elected Gen. Jubal
                        Early an honorary member of that organization, the old hero, from his exile
                        in Canada, sends the following appropriate response to a letter
                        communicating the honor conferred by Association:</p>
                    <p>Toronto, Nov. 30, 1866.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Sir</emph>--I have received your note informing me of the
                        fact that I have been elected an Honorary Member of the Ladies' Memorial
                        Association of Mount Jackson. Amid all the sad recollections connected with
                        our unfortunate struggle, it is a source of great comfort to know that the
                        ladies of our country,--who were ever so self-sacrificing, during the
                        continuance of that struggle,--bestow the tribute of their tears on the
                        memory of the dead.</p>
                    <p>Though a great battle was not fought near Mt. Jackson, yet it was a place to
                        which many of the wounded from battle-fields, at other places, were carried
                        and placed in hospitals, and there received the kind attentions of the
                        ministering angels who now honor the graves of those who died. I have many
                        cherished recollections connected with the Valley of the Shenandoah, from
                        one end to the other, and I trust that peace and prosperity may soon return
                        to bless the inhabitants of that beautiful Valley, as well as of all our now
                        desolated country.</p>
                    <p>With many thanks for the terms in which you have conveyed the information
                        contained in your note, I desire you to convey to the ladies of the Mt.
                        Jackson Memorial Association my thanks for the honor done me, and my fervent
                        wishes for their prosperity and happiness.</p>
                    <p>Very truly and respectfully,<lb/> Your ob't servant,<lb/> J. A. Early</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Jubal Early responds to the news that the Ladies' Memorial Association of
                    Mt. Jackson has appointed him as an honorary member.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Merritt</ln>
                        <fn>C. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>Lizzie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McFarland</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Capt. C. G. Merritt, C. S. A., and Miss Lizzie Wilson, both of Augusta,
                    were married on December 19th by the Rev. Dr. McFarland.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGuire</ln>
                        <fn>Hunter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Latine</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. Hunter McGuire, Medical Director 2d. Corps, A. N. V., and Miss Mary
                    Stuart, daughter of Alexander H. H. Stuart, were married in the Staunton
                    residence of the bride's father by the Rev. J. A. Latine.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGuire</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chapman</ln>
                        <fn>Anna</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chapman</ln>
                        <fn>Alfred</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Latane</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Joseph D. McGuire, formerly of Washington, but now of Howard County, Md.,
                    and Miss Anna Chapman were married on December 19th at the Staunton home of the
                    bride's father, Alfred Chapman. The Rev. Joseph A. Latane presided.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hill</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hill</ln>
                        <fn>Reuben</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Margaret Hill, wife of Reuben Hill, of Staunton, died on December 5th
                    at Lebanon, Ohio.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spitler</ln>
                        <fn>Mary V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary V. Spitler, aged 14 years, 7 months, and 14 days, died in Augusta
                    County on November 20th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kenney</ln>
                        <fn>Jefferson C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jefferson C. Kenney, aged 62 years, died in Augusta County on December
                    21st.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1866.12.28.04" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Southern Cause</head>
                <origin>New York Metropolitan Record</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Written on hearing a distant bugle echoing though the
                            mountains of Virginia, and affectionately dedicated to the gallant
                            survivors of the Stonewall Brigade.</emph> By a Friend.</p>
                    <p>Sound that sweet bugle once again,<lb/> And thru' the wild wood let it
                        thrill;<lb/> Altho' it wrings my heart with pain,<lb/> I would not bid its
                        notes be still.</p>
                    <p>Sweet memories of bygone hours,<lb/> Come thronging as its tones I hear,<lb/>
                        When life's brief path was strew'd with flowers,<lb/> And we had all man
                        holds most dear.</p>
                    <p>The [unclear] dressed them in the gray,<lb/> And with high hopes their brave
                        hearts beat,<lb/> And we were merry then and gay,<lb/> For ah! we dreamed
                        not of defeat.</p>
                    <p>Freedom had gathered thirteen stars,<lb/> Soft blue, from out of the sky she
                        rent;<lb/> Caught from the rainbow crimson bars,<lb/> That with the stars
                        and blue were blent.</p>
                    <p>Then gave the banner to our trust,<lb/> [Section unclear]<lb/> Before its
                        charge like wreaths of [unclear]<lb/> Virginia's hills with thunders
                        woke,<lb/> And echoed back the Southern cheer.</p>
                    <p>On, as we charged, o'er mountains steep,<lb/> Yet bleeding that our shoes
                        were worn,<lb/> Across the rivers, dark and deep,<lb/> Our feet are
                        bleeding, awalled and torn.</p>
                    <p>And only "rested neath the shade,"<lb/> When shouts of triumph floated
                        back,<lb/> From "Stonewall's" glorious old brigade,<lb/> That followed hard
                        upon their track.</p>
                    <p>The sound to soldiers' heart is dear,<lb/> Herald of victory bravely
                        won;<lb/> When "Jackson fell upon their rear,"<lb/> Ah! then we knew the
                        work was done.</p>
                    <p>Then from our haversacks we drew,<lb/> The rations scant, perchance a
                        crust,<lb/> An ounce or more of beef so blue,<lb/> Half raw, and covered
                        o'er with dust.</p>
                    <p>And in low tones the boys would tell,<lb/> Of how some gallant comrades
                        met,<lb/> Their fate so stern, and dying fell,<lb/> Long ere the burning sun
                        had set.</p>
                    <p>They fell, but many a glorious name,<lb/> Was there inscribed on history's
                        scroll,<lb/> Caught from oblivion's death by fame,<lb/> And registered on
                        honor's roll.</p>
                    <p>But time wore on. I may not dwell,<lb/> On the bright pages of the past;<lb/>
                        Of darker themes I now must tell--<lb/> Our day of triumph did not last.</p>
                    <p>Disease and want held revels rare,<lb/> Hunger and cold did well their
                        parts;<lb/> Thou could not last, poor comrades dear,<lb/> With wasted frames
                        and breaking hearts!</p>
                    <p>We had hurled them back for four long years,<lb/> Struggling against their
                        countless host;<lb/> Then came a change, and now in tears,<lb/> We mourn our
                        cause as <emph rend="italic">almost</emph> lost.</p>
                    <p>On Appomattox fatal plain,<lb/> From out our flag were torn the stars;<lb/>
                        The blue leapt back to heaven again,<lb/> The rainbow claimed its
                        blood-stained bars.</p>
                    <p>Oh! who can e'er forget that hour,<lb/> In the long lapse of coming
                        years?<lb/> Then tho' we were, we had no power,<lb/> To stay our sobs and
                        bitter tears.</p>
                    <p>Tho' for a time our hopes have fled,<lb/> and tho' in chains the Southland
                        weeps,<lb/> Our cause is not forever dead--<lb/> 'Twill rise again--it only
                        sleeps.</p>
                    <p>And when that glorious day shall come,<lb/> When bugles echo wild and
                        clear,<lb/> When with the long roll peals the drum,<lb/> Beneath the
                        Southern cross so dear--</p>
                    <p>Then we will gather, comrades brave,<lb/> Our trusty swords we'll then
                        unsheathe,<lb/> And make the South a mighty grave,<lb/> Or crown her with a
                        laurel wreath.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Poem honoring the southern cause.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
