<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1866/va.au.vv.1866.03.21">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/10/04</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1866-03-21">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day norm="">21</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1866.03.21.01" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>07</column>
                <head>Emigration to Mexico</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper publishes information for those wishing to emigrate to Mexico.
                    Lieutenant M. F. Maury, Imperial Commissioner of Colonization for the Empire of
                    Mexico, is authorized to make land grants to interested settlers, the paper
                    reports. The report states that the "Empire is continually gaining ground" and
                    that "perfect freedom of religious worship is guaranteed by the organic law of
                    the Empire, and sanctioned by the Pope."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1866.03.21.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article reports that "Mississippi has all her 'negroes' at work, and a
                    big cotton crop will be the consequence."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Institution for the Deaf, Dumb and the Blind, at Staunton</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The last report of the Board of Visitors is before us. The Virginia
                        Institution for the Deaf, Dumb and the Blind was established by act of
                        Assembly, March 31, 1838; the town of Staunton being the point chosen for
                        its location. Hon. A. H. H. Stuart, was appointed President, and Nicholas C.
                        Kinney, Esq., Secretary of the Board of Visitors. As soon thereafter, as
                        practicable, the Rev. Joseph D. Tyler was elected Principal of the Deaf and
                        Dumb Department, and Dr. J. C. M. Merillat, Principle of the Blind
                        Department. The selection of these two gentlemen, for such high and
                        responsible positions, proved to be peculiarly fortunate. Of the highest
                        moral worth, of superior intellectual culture, of firm yet gentle demeanor,
                        zealous, indefatigable and devoted to their work, they were peculiarly
                        qualified to take charge of that Institution.</p>
                    <p>[section unclear]. early in the Spring of 1839, pupils of both classes of
                        these unfortunates began to arrive in Staunton, where buildings ample for
                        their accommodation had been procured. In the meantime each Department had
                        been supplied with a complete and efficient corps of Instructors, and
                        officers necessary for the control and management of the whole. At this
                        time, each of the two Departments, the Deaf and Dumb and the Blind, was
                        assigned to separate buildings and were kept distinct for several years. The
                        Legislature, having, at the time of the passage of the act incorporating the
                        Institution, made the appropriations necessary, steps were immediately taken
                        for the construction of buildings suitable for such an Institution. The
                        result was the rearing of that noble [unclear] directly East of Staunton,
                        which is the admiration of all beholders and known far and wide as the
                        "Institution."</p>
                    <p>These buildings were so far completed in 1816 as to be able to receive the
                        officers and pupils of both Departments, which has been stated, had hitherto
                        occupied separate buildings.</p>
                    <p>The Institution had now been in operation seven years, was firmly and
                        thoroughly established, and had already taken rank as one of the first of
                        its class in the country. Its beneficent influences were being felt, and the
                        practical success of its workings were appreciated, not only by its pupils,
                        but by the people of the State at large.</p>
                    <p>On the 16th of January, 1852, the Rev. Mr. Tyler died, cut off in the midst
                        of his usefulness, yet not without seeing the seed he had sown, spring up
                        and bear an hundred fold. This was a severe blow to the Institution, as well
                        as the community, but fortunately, so far as regarded the Institution
                        itself, his place, as an instructor of the Deaf and Dumb, was able to be
                        very happily filled by Mr. J. C. Covell, who had been engaged since 1847 as
                        instructor of Deaf-mutes in the Institution. It was now deemed advisable to
                        bring both Departments under the control of one Principal, and the Board of
                        Visitors. Dr. Francis T. Stribling, President, on the 9th of March, 1852,
                        elected Dr. Merrillatt, Principal of the Virginia Institution for the Deaf
                        and Dumb, and the Blind. The career of the Institution was still onward and
                        upward. Each year witnessed an increase in the number of pupils; the range
                        of studies was extended; new branches of trade were added. The introduction
                        of gas into the buildings; also that of complete apparatus for heating them
                        by steam, and an abundant supply of pure spring water, completed the
                        arrangements for the health, convenience and comfort of the occupants. This
                        was done by, and under the superintendence of, Wm. H. Wilson then the
                        faithful Stewart of the Institution.</p>
                    <p>It now became apparent that the multitudinous duties devolving upon the
                        Principal, and the scholastic pertaining to the Instructor, were too arduous
                        to be borne by any one man, and the Board of Visitors. James H. Skinner
                        Esq., President, elected Mr. Covell, Vice-Principal in June, 1854.</p>
                    <p>Nothing occurred to check the prosperity of the Institution, until the
                        outbreak of the war for Southern Independence in 1861, at which time the
                        number of pupils in both Departments was about one hundred and thirty, and
                        the Institution was acknowledged the first of its class in the country. On
                        the 19th of June, 1861, the buildings of the Institution were taken
                        possession of, with the consent of the Governor of the State, by the
                        Confederate authorities for Hospital purposes. The pupils numbering about
                        seventy-five, (the rest being absent at home spending their vacation,) were
                        removed to the buildings of the Virginia Female Institute, where they
                        remained until June, 1865, when, the war having closed, possession was given
                        of their own buildings. Dr. Merrillat resigned his position as Principal of
                        the institution in September, 1862, having accepted a position on the
                        Medical Staff, C. S. A., and the Vice-President, Mr. Covell, was appointed
                        to supply the vacancy.</p>
                    <p>Most of the pupils who went home during the vacation of 1861, were prevented
                        from returning in consequence of the unsettled state of the country, and the
                        uncertainty of the future. For the same reasons new pupils were not
                        admitted, and, fortunately, the number present, during that unhappy period,
                        was comparatively small. It was not to be expected that the exercises of the
                        Institution could continue uninterrupted during a war so protracted,
                        desolating and varying, yet they did not experience any serious interruption
                        until the raid of General Sheridan. He levied upon the provisions of this
                        Institution, as he did upon those of the Insane Asylum, and there was for a
                        time, consequently, a serious privation experienced. In fact, from that time
                        until the reorganization of the Institution, it is due to the energy and
                        untiring exertions of the Principal, that provisions could be procured of
                        sufficient quantity to satisfy the most frugal living. In August 1865, the
                        Institution was thoroughly reorganized under a new Board of Visitors, Thomas
                        J. Michie, Esq., President. On the 10th of that month, Mr. Covell was
                        re-elected Principal, and a full and efficient corps of instructors,
                        prominent among whom was Lieut. S. H. Coleman. Other officers necessary to
                        the complete management and operation of the Institution, in all its
                        Departments, were appointed.</p>
                    <p>The total number of Deaf mutes who have entered the Institution since it was
                        founded, is 275; total number of Blind, 151. Present number in both
                        Departments 52 and 18 applying.</p>
                    <p>There is no reason to doubt, that the close of the year 1866, will witness
                        this truly benevolent Institution occupying the same lofty pinnacle of fame
                        and usefulness that it had attained before the war. It has been the means of
                        lighting with the genial rays of happiness, many homes that would otherwise
                        have continued enshrouded in gloom. It has opened eyes that saw not,
                        unstopped ears that heard not and unloosed tongues that spoke not. It has
                        diffused joy and gladness and intelligence where all was grief, sorrow and
                        ignorance. In fine, the object for which it was founded is one that appeals
                        to all that is noble, pure, elevating and sensitive in the mind and heart of
                        man.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>A. H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>Nicholas C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tyler</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Merillat</ln>
                        <fn>J. C. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Covell</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stribling</ln>
                        <fn>Francis T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Michie</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The article gives the history of Staunton's Institute for the Deaf, Dumb
                    and Blind from its founding through the end of the war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Valley Railroad Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On the 4th of April, fourteen days from to-day, the Valley Railroad
                        Convention is to meet at Staunton. A duty more important than holding
                        meetings to endorse Andrew Johnson now devolves upon the people of the
                        Valley counties, and it is to hold meetings at once, and send earnest
                        [unclear] men to represent them in this Convention. The people in these
                        counties who have not acted in this matter should recollect that the
                        President of the United States is aware of the fact that he is endorsed by
                        the people of the Valley and can live without their endorsement; but the
                        people of this Valley cannot live and prosper without prompt action is taken
                        to organize the great Valley Railroad Company and to build the road.</p>
                    <p>What is needed now is a convention here representing the wealth and energy of
                        the Valley counties; men that will take the one hundred thousand dollars
                        worth of stock necessary to organize the Company under the charter. This, we
                        believe, can be done by Rockbridge, Augusta and Rockingham, but we want the
                        whole Valley fully represented. It is no time for holding back; every man,
                        woman and child in the Valley of Virginia is interested in this great work,
                        and if it is to be the success we hope it will be, every man must work. The
                        Covington and Ohio Railroad will soon be under contract. Will the Valley
                        people wrap themselves up in their poverty and let their great work fail for
                        want of proper exertion now?</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper urges Staunton residents to hold meetings to send representatives
                    to the Valley Railroad Convention, which is to meet in Staunton. Prompt action
                    in building the road will ensure the livelihood and prosperity of the Valley.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1866.03.21.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper announces that there will be a meeting of the Farmers of Augusta
                    county at Churchville on the 29th of March, and urges full attendance.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that "another game was played by the Base Ball Club in
                    Stuart's meadow. It is increasing rapidly and we learn that several villages
                    around think of forming clubs."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Our House</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper announces that John Christian, "proprietor of Our House," and
                    "one of the respectable colored men of Staunton," is planning to open an Ice
                    Cream Saloon for ladies. "John kept a good house during the war and always
                    conducts himself properly. We are always pleased to notice and encourage his
                    class when they act as he does."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Our Judges</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>Lucas P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper announces that Hugh W. Sheffey will replace Lucas P. Thompson,
                    who was transferred to the court of appeals, as judge of the Staunton district.
                    "Judge Thompson has been on the bench for more than thirty years--a purer and
                    better man does not live and Mr. Sheffey will make a most worthy successor."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Cleaning Up</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kayser</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper expresses its pleasure that M. Kayser, Commissioner of Streets,
                    "has commenced the work of cleaning up the town most vigorously. Cellars, yards
                    and gutters are yielding up the accumulated filth of five years and Staunton
                    will soon be as clean as a new pin. This is a fine opportunity for farmers to
                    get manure for the hauling and all are invited to do so."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Staunton Enterprise</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roberts</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nelson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lushbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper announces that after three months of work, Roberts, Nelson and
                    Co. are completing the task of tearing down Moncure's old mill to put up their
                    new foundry and machine shops. "The work is completed, notwithstanding the bad
                    weather and other difficulties they labored under and next Saturday the first
                    'blast' will be made. The energy displayed, both by Roberts, Nelson and Co. and
                    H. Lushbaugh and Brother, the builders, reflects great credit on themselves and
                    our town. The site for the works cost $10,000 and by the time everything is in
                    full operation $22,000 will not cover the whole expense."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper suggests that a cotton factory be built in Staunton. "Its fine
                    water power has been lying idle since Hunter destroyed everything in the shape
                    of a Factory near here."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blakemore</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Joseph</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Byers</ln>
                        <fn>James P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper announces appointments to Post-offices in Augusta County:
                    Elizabeth H. Blakemore, Mt. Solon; James W. Joseph, Jennings Gap; James P.
                    Byers, Parnassus.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Our Unhonored Dead</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>One patriotic lady in Winchester has raised $50 by ten cent subscriptions for
                        the "Stonewall Cemetery" there. A family, in reduced circumstances, has
                        raised $260 by giving the profits from an oyster supper each night. Two
                        thousand martyred Southern heroes lay <emph rend="italic">outside</emph> of
                        the Thornrose Cemetery near Staunton, and nothing has been done to enclose
                        their graves or mark their last resting place. The facts given above shows
                        what can be done for our "unhonored" dead, if our ladies will only try. The
                        condition of their graves is a shame and a disgrace to our people, and if
                        there is any public spirit left, we call upon the ladies of Staunton to
                        emulate the example of the noble women in Winchester.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper calls upon the ladies of Staunton to step forward and raise funds
                    for the care of the Confederate graves in town. "The condition of their graves
                    is a shame and disgrace to our people," the paper declares.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Knife and Fork Combined</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Breckenridge</ln>
                        <fn>Negus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper announces the invention of a left-handed knife and fork combined
                    by Lt. Negus Breckenridge of the Staunton Artillery, "who lost his right arm at
                    Sailor's Creek, the last fight of the war. It is so constructed that a person
                    who has lost his right arm can cut his food and feed himself without difficulty
                    and shows remarkable mechanical genius."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dunlop</ln>
                        <fn>Robert B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mish</ln>
                        <fn>Amelia M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>R. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Robert B. Dunlop and Miss Amelia M. Mish, both of Augusta, were married on
                    March 8 by the Rev. R. C. Walker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ast</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary Ast, aged 12 years and 4 days died on March 17 in Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coleman</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William H. Coleman, aged 3 years, died on March 11 in Augusta County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cowan</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Andrew B. Cowan, of Augusta County, died of consumption on March 19.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1866.03.21.04" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>An Acrostic</head>
                <origin>New York Metropolitan Record</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>[From the New York Metropolitan Record]</p>
                    <p>Acrostics do not often posses much literary merit, but the following is a
                        marked exception. The intensity of feeling which breathes through it will
                        commend it to all who sympathize with the wounded spirit of the South:</p>
                    <p>Justice, human justice! Is it dead? O, God, to Thee<lb/> Ever ascends our
                        earnest prayer, to set our martyr free!<lb/> For him we plead, for him
                        alone, our chieftain and our head<lb/> For him, our brave, true-hearted one,
                        whose every hope has fled.<lb/> Endurance with her iron grasp, would crush
                        that spirit low;<lb/> Resistance is a dream to him, poor prisoner of
                        woe!<lb/> Shut out from life and human hope, shall mercy plead in vain?<lb/>
                        On him, must all the burden fall? on him, the weight of pain?<lb/> Needless
                        the cry for human aid, for God alone is just!<lb/> Dread vengeance in the
                        human heart treads mercy in the dust,<lb/> After a weary watcher weeps in
                        bitterness alone,<lb/> Vain! vain, alas! a woman's tears to soften hearts of
                        stone.<lb/> In Thee alone, O God! we trust! for him we plead to Thee;<lb/>
                        Silent, yet heartfelt, still a prayer, "God set the martyr free."</p>
                    <p>Charleston, S. C., Nov. 1865. C. M. G.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper publishes the following acrostic honoring Jefferson Davis and his
                    name.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
