<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1866/va.au.vv.1866.09.12">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/29/04</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1866-09-12">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day norm="">12</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1866.09.12.01" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>A Speech from the Gallant Wade Hampton</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>At a meeting held recently by the soldiers of Anderson District, for the
                        purpose of forming a soldiers' association, General Wade Hampton was waited
                        upon by a committee, and in response delivered the following speech:</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Brother Soldiers of Anderson:</emph> I deem myself
                        fortunate that accident has given me the pleasure of meeting with you today,
                        and of participating in the laudable objects contemplated by your meeting;
                        and that pleasure is greatly enhanced by seeing around me many of the brave
                        men whom it was my good fortune to command during the war. These mountain
                        regions gave to the armies of the South some of our best soldiers, and it is
                        due to them that I should declare what I do here with infinite
                        gratification, that I had in my ranks none better, braver or more devoted,
                        than the men of this and the adjoining districts. In your presence I desire
                        to tender to them my heartfelt thanks for their conduct as soldiers. They
                        have the proud consciousness of having performed their duty to the State,
                        and this will be some compensation to them for the result of the war. And,
                        brother soldiers, whilst we acquiesce in the result, let us not admit that
                        the cause of it was unjustifiable or wrong. I accept the terms upon which we
                        laid down our arms, in good faith, and it is our duty to observe these terms
                        faithfully; but whilst I do this, I shall never say that we had not right on
                        our side--I shall never hold my State as guilty and her sons as traitors.
                        The cause is not to be judged by success or failure. Success does not
                        inevitably make right, or truth, or justice, nor does failure always imply
                        evil, wrong or falsehood. If the justice of a cause always insures success,
                        Poland, Hungary, and Ireland, would not now groan under the heel of the
                        oppressor, nor would the South be reduced to the sad condition in which she
                        finds herself to-day. But sad as is the condition of our beloved land, we
                        must not forsake it. She has need of all her sons. You know that in years
                        that are just passed, you regarded it as your highest duty to stand by your
                        colors. So now it is your duty to stand by your State. Her colors are nailed
                        to the mast, and let us stand or fall with her. Give her all the aid you
                        can, and if she sinks, at least let us go down with her. For these reasons I
                        have discouraged emigration. I believe it is our highest duty to assist in
                        the re-establishment of law, order, peace; to help the widows and orphans
                        made by the war, and to endeavor to raise our prostrate and bleeding
                        country. We may not be able to do much towards alleviating the suffering and
                        sorrows of our people, but we can at least take our share of them, and thus
                        lighten the general burden by distributing it amongst us all. To the
                        accomplishment of these objects--the highest that patriotism can inspire--I
                        invoke your earnest co-operation. It will require all your energy, all your
                        strength, all your endurance, to restore hope to our people or vitality to
                        our State.</p>
                    <p>We can expect nothing from the Government of the United States, whatever
                        party may be in power. The Convention at Philadelphia--where the North and
                        the South, burying the past, were to re-establish liberty, equality,
                        fraternity--has declared the platform upon which the Conservatives propose
                        to enter the next canvass. In the delusion of principles which compose that
                        platform, I see it announced that the brave soldiers and sailors who
                        suppressed the rebellion are entitled to the thanks of the nation; that the
                        debt incurred in that holy crusade is to be sacred, and that all Confederate
                        debts are null and void. We pension the men who forged our fetters; but the
                        soldiers of the South--men with empty sleeves or on crutches, such as are
                        seen around me now--are to be branded as outlaws, rebels and traitors. No
                        fostering hand of a paternal government soothes or cares for their widows
                        and orphans. The country and the government for which they fought, like
                        their hopes, are dead, and they are thrown on the cold charity of the world.
                        It is our duty to open our hearts and our hands to our brave disabled
                        soldiers, and care for the families of those who fell in our defence.
                        Whatever may have been the result of the cause in which they fell remember
                        that they died for us, fighting, and they honestly believed, to make us
                        free. They offered up their lives a willing sacrifice for their country, and
                        shame upon the man who would not help those who have lost their all in our
                        behalf. I shall never turn my back upon any brave soldier who stood by his
                        banner to the last, though that glorious banner may be forever furled;
                        though now</p>
                    <p>"There's not a man to wave it,<lb/> And there's not a soul to save it,<lb/>
                        And there's not one to lave it,<lb/> In the blood which heroes gave it."</p>
                    <p>Tis true that we have but little left us; that we are impoverished; but we
                        can at least share our pittance with those who have lost all.</p>
                    <p>To record the names of those who fought for us; to perpetuate the history of
                        the gallant troops given by our State to the common cause; to extend our aid
                        to those who are disabled, and to those whose protectors fell in the war,
                        are the noble purposes of your proposed Association. I wish you God speed in
                        this good work. I congratulate myself that I have been permitted to
                        participate in these holy objects, and I pray that God may bless them to the
                        fullest extent of your wishes. I thank you, gentlemen, for the courtesy you
                        have extended to me, and for the kindness with which you have received
                    me.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper prints a speech of Wade Hampton to the soldiers from the Blue
                    Ridge and adjoining districts. He praises their service and defends their cause.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Grand Tournament at Folley Farm</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Berkeley</ln>
                        <fn>Carter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turner</ln>
                        <fn>Charley</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilkeson</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McFarland</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Merritt</ln>
                        <fn>C. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Churchman</ln>
                        <fn>Willie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lilly</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Randolph</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilkison</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fate</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Abney</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilkison</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>Alex</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ball</ln>
                        <fn>Marcius Fire</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Forrer</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Steele</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Abney</ln>
                        <fn>Belle</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper reports that, on August 30th, "the third anniversary of one of
                    our glorious victories," a tournament was held at Folley Farm which was attended
                    by more than 200 people. "The fair daughters of Albemarle, Rockbridge, and
                    Augusta, vied with each other in loveliness, and the gallantry of the sons of
                    Augusta was only equaled by their dashing and noble daring on many a hard fought
                    battle-field." The events were followed with a dinner and dancing.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>07</column>
                <head>Valley Railroad</head>
                <origin>Rockingham Register</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickle</ln>
                        <fn>R. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lynn</ln>
                        <fn>W. H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harrison</ln>
                        <fn>Powell</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Augusta County Court put forward a proposition to the people that the
                    county subscribe $200,000 for the construction of the Valley Railroad from Salem
                    to Harrisonburg. An election will be held on the 4th Thursday in October. "Of
                    course the good people of Augusta, who have manifested so much interest in
                    organizing the Valley Railroad Company, and with the completion of which their
                    material interests are so intimately identified, will not fail to attest the
                    sincerity of their professions by a favorable return upon this tangible,
                    substantial proposition. That rich, enterprising and public spirited county
                    would hardly permit so severe a reflection as would be conveyed in the rejection
                    of this subscription, to mar their fair fame."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1866.09.12.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Influence of Railroads upon Agriculture and other Interests</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The question of prime importance before our people now, is the great Valley
                        Railroad. In the hurly-burly of the times past, our people were so intent
                        upon the achievement of one great object that the benefits of railroads to
                        the material interests of the country were necessarily over-looked. And the
                        pressing necessities of the day occupy their whole time and attention so
                        closely, even now, that few look upon the matter as they should. In fact,
                        some still cling to an old and obsolete idea that in some way or other, any
                        great improvement in machinery or locomotion, necessarily diminishes the
                        demand for labor, or for other machinery. Hence it was that the introduction
                        of printing was opposed in Europe on account of its supposed tendency to
                        diminish the employment of writers and copyists. It is now an established
                        principle that anything that diminishes the amount of labor, increases the
                        amount of labor required. This is done by cheapening the products of labor
                        so that more will be consumed and more labor be required to produce them.
                        This is illustrated by the fact that more women are employed in sewing than
                        before the sewing machine was introduced. In regard to railroads, there was
                        once an idea that the transportation of agricultural products by them would
                        decrease the [unclear] of horses, wagoners &amp;c. But from the United
                        States census of 1860, we find the result precisely the contrary. [Unclear]
                        we multiplied more rapidly than before the introduction of railroads. In
                        1850, the year railroads began to be generally introduced in the West, the
                        increase of horses, asses and mules was 12 percent. In 1860, ten years after
                        the general introduction of railroads, the [unclear] was 51 per cent. In the
                        five great States of the West, Ohio, Indiana, Illinois, Michigan, Wisconsin,
                        1,155,255 horses were employed in agriculture in 1860. In ten years 3,000
                        miles of railroad were constructed in these States, and the number of horses
                        employed in agriculture, and for other purposes, in 1860 was 2,381,671, an
                        increase of 106 percent. These facts and figures show that the more
                        railroads built in a country, the greater facilities there are for reaching
                        the great markets and hence the great number of animals required to carry on
                        the enlarged operations in agriculture, manufactures, and the general
                        business of the country.</p>
                    <p>The report before us states, that so great are the positive advantages which
                        all departments of agriculture have derived from the construction of
                        railroads, "<emph rend="italic">that if the entire cost of railroads between
                            the Atlantic and Western States had been levied on the farms of the
                            central West, their proprietors could have paid it and been immensely
                            gainers</emph>." This is evident, first because the railroads enable the
                        farmers west to do what they could not have done without them. Instead of
                        their products rotting on the ground, the railroads at once gave them the
                        prices of the great markets on the Atlantic, and this enabled them to
                        increase both the settlement and productiveness of their States. Railroads
                        carry two-thirds of the surplus products of the Northwest to the Atlantic,
                        or to foreign markets, and have caused the enormous increase of agricultural
                        products noted in this report. Where there are no railroads and no
                        competition, the cultivation of grain, beyond the immediate wants of the
                        people, must cease, or the surplus perish in the fields. Between 1850 and
                        1860, the increase, caused by railroads, in the production of animals, grain
                        and vegetables, in the five States before mentioned was, wheat 100 per
                        cent., corn 58, oats 50, potatoes 100, and cattle 59. This increase is
                        decidedly beyond the increased population, showing that agriculture in these
                        States is profitable, and in this you can read the cause of so many of our
                        best young men emigrating to these States, and leaving our richest lands
                        uncultivated--all for want of a market.</p>
                    <p>One instance of the influence of railroads on the value of lands ought to be
                        enough to convince our people of the importance of voting for the
                        subscription to the Valley Railroad. The Illinois Central Railroad received
                        from the U. S. government a large body of land, which it could not sell for
                        $1.25 per acre. That company constructed its road, and sold part of the
                        lands for $11 per acre. The wealth and population of Illinois now show the
                        benefits derived from one railroad, but the advance in the cash value of
                        farms in five States, in ten years, show it more conclusively. The aggregate
                        value of farms in Ohio, Illinois, Indiana, Michigan, and Wisconsin, in 1850,
                        was $671,678,075--in 1860, $1,738,394,188. Increase in ten years,
                        $1,066,716,113.</p>
                    <p>In giving the facts and figures from the census of 1860 in regard to these
                        States, we, of course, cannot state positively, the value to that country of
                        railroads since, but one great fact must be apparent to every man, that is
                        such results were obtained from railroads, in ten years, in a new and
                        unsettled country, that a country possessed of the resources and the
                        enterprise of our Valley, cannot be injured by a great railroad, extending
                        through its entire length and connecting it with all the great markets of
                        the continent.</p>
                    <p>People of Augusta county! this is a question of vital importance to you and
                        yours forever. Every man should talk about it to his neighbor and ignore
                        national politics; every man should work for the road, regardless of what
                        portion of the county it runs through, for by voting for this subscription,
                        you give strength and solidarity to the Valley Railroad Company, and you
                        insure the success of the enterprise. Vote against it, and the influences,
                        so hard to overcome in Eastern Virginia last year, will take it as an
                        evidence that you do not want the road, and the charter will be revoked.
                        Vote for the subscription, and you enable the company to borrow the amount
                        necessary to complete the road, and the stock necessary to build it will be
                        taken by capitalists, anxious for good investments. Everything depends on
                        this vote, and the larger it is in favor of the subscription the better. In
                        business transactions confidence is everything, and the vote for or against
                        the subscription to the Valley Railroad, by Augusta county, settles that
                        question.</p>
                    <p>We have heretofore presented the great advantages to be reaped by this county
                        and the Valley so fully, that the Virginian can say no more. Every
                        energetic, practical man, every man devoted to our glorious Valley, should
                        work for the railroad, and make the Valley in improvements, in prosperity,
                        and the happiness of its people, worthy of being called the Shenandoah--"the
                        laughing daughter of the stars."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper urges voters to support the subscription of money for the Valley
                    Railroad. The editors argue that construction of the road will increase the
                    profitability of all branches of agriculture and manufacturing.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>The Cemetery</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper corrects a mistake in reporting that the Ladies Cemetery
                    Committee received $12 from a gentleman from Georgetown, D. C. Instead he
                    contributed $15. No other contributions have been received since, and work is
                    still halted due to lack of money to pay hands. "This speaks well for Augusta
                    and those who subscribed !"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Mr. Baldwin's Evidence Before the Reconstruction Committee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Staunton, August 20, 1866.</p>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">Nat. B. Meade, Esq:</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>My Dear Sir--I have received your letter, and I thank you for calling my
                        attention to a construction of my testimony about the trial of President
                        Davis, which does injustice alike to my opinions and my feelings. My
                        testimony was taken in short hand, and was not read over to me or submitted
                        for my revision. I am surprised at its general correctness; but I find that,
                        in several instances, my meaning has been inaccurately stated, or wholly
                        misapprehended.</p>
                    <p>The point of inquiry was as to the probable result of a trial of Mr. Davis
                        before a court and jury, if one should be had, and not as to the propriety
                        of subjecting him to such an ordeal.</p>
                    <p>It was my purpose to state my belief that our unsuccessful attempt at
                        revolution must be regarded as rebellion, and if judicially considered and
                        applied to individual cases, must subject each offender to the penalties of
                        treason. Such, I presume, must be the opinion of all who do not believe in
                        what is called the "right of secession," and such must of course be the view
                        of the Government of the United States. Every pardon granted and every
                        amnesty offered is an assertion of this principle; and every pardon sought
                        or accepted admits at least a doubt of the defense to be made before a court
                        and jury.</p>
                    <p>While my opinion as a lawyer is what I have stated, I do not at all intend to
                        admit the propriety of attempting to deal by judicial trials with
                        transactions whose national proportions place them beyond the proper reach
                        of court and jury. Each individual case, if brought into court, must, in my
                        opinion, be held to constitute treason, and be dealt with accordingly, but
                        each case is so thoroughly a representative of all that a trial of any one
                        would, to all intents and purposes, be subjecting the conduct of a nation to
                        the review of twelve jurors.</p>
                    <p>If this would be true of any one Confederate, how much more must it be felt
                        to be true of President Davis, who, in his prison, is this very day more
                        emphatically the representative of our cause than he was when
                        Commander-in-Chief of the Confederate army and navy.</p>
                    <p>To subject a man occupying this position to a trial by the narrow rules which
                        limit judicial construction, and to the mockery of a jury trial, would, in
                        my opinion, be an outrage too gross to be anticipated of any government in
                        Christendom.</p>
                    <p>Every day that he is kept in prison is a peremptory adjournment of all real
                        reconciliation between the North and the South. Any attempt to subject him
                        to further humiliation must be regarded as a personal wrong done to every
                        true Southern man; and if he shall be permitted to die in captivity, his
                        name will become the watchword of Southern hate! It is to be regretted that
                        the Convention recently held at Philadelphia did not recognize the necessity
                        of amnesty for the past as a basis of good will for the future; but I trust
                        that this omission will be set right by President Johnson, and that he will
                        by the prompt discharge of Mr. Davis, give practical point and vitality to
                        his recent declaration that "unless we forget the past we can have no
                        future."</p>
                    <p>Yours truly,<lb/> John B. Baldwin.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John B. Baldwin clears up misperceptions surrounding his testimony before
                    the Reconstruction Committee. He argued that any Southerners charged with
                    treason must be afforded the right of trial by jury, including Jefferson Davis.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1866.09.12.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Badly Needed</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A new floor is needed in the Vestibule of Trinity Church, Staunton. The
                    paper urges the vestry to "see to it."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hogshead</ln>
                        <fn>M. D. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>It is announced that M. D. W. Hogshead has been appointed notary public for
                    Augusta County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Lost Cause</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Raimond</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper endorses E. A. Pollard's book, The Lost Cause. J. S. Raimond is
                    distribution agent for Augusta. "As this book relates to our side of the war all
                    should have it."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Mistakes</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doom</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doom</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Frazier</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Funkhouser</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper corrects mistakes in the spelling of the names of John Doom,
                    killed at Port Republic, and J. M. Doom, killed at the Wilderness. It also adds
                    two names to the list of casualties from the West Augusta Guard: Lieut. James
                    Frazier, "gallant Jim;" and William Funkhouser, who died of disease.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Pardoned</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greaver</ln>
                        <fn>H. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper is outraged by Governor Pierpont's pardon of H. J. Greaver,
                    convicted for larceny by the Circuit Court of Augusta, and who was serving a 1
                    year prison sentence. "Pierpont pardons every deserter, and has no respect for
                    the decisions of our Courts. And some people call this creature 'Governor of
                    Virginia!'"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harlan</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Eliza J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armstrong</ln>
                        <fn>J. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel Harlan and Miss Eliza J. Smith, both of Augusta, were married on
                    September 4th by the Rev. J. E. Armstrong.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>H. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Herndon</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armstrong</ln>
                        <fn>J. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>H. J. Davis and Miss Mary Herndon, both of Staunton, were married on
                    September 9th by the Rev. J. E. Armstrong.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1866.09.12.04" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Stonewall Jackson Borne from the Battle Field of Chancellorsville</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"Who've ye got there?"--"Only a dying brother,<lb/> Hurt in the front just
                        now."<lb/> "Good boy! He'll do. Somebody tell his mother,<lb/> Where he was
                        killed, and how."</p>
                    <p>"Whom have you there?"--"A crippled courier Major,<lb/> Shot by mistake, we
                        hear.<lb/> He was with Stonewall--"Cruel work they've here.<lb/> Quick with
                        him to the rear!"</p>
                    <p>"Well, who comes next?"--"Doctor, speak low, speak low, sir;<lb/> Don't let
                        the men find out!<lb/> It's Stonewall."--"Oh God!"--"The Brigade must not
                        know sir.<lb/> While there's a Yank about."</p>
                    <p>Whom have we here--shrouded in martial manner,<lb/> Crowned with a martyr's
                        charm?<lb/> A grand, dead hero, in a hung banner,<lb/> Born of his heart and
                        arm!</p>
                    <p>The heart whereon his cause hung--see how clingeth<lb/> That banner to his
                        bier!<lb/> The arm wherewith his cause struck--hark! how ringeth<lb/> His
                        trumpet in their ear!</p>
                    <p>What have we left?--His genius inspiration,<lb/> His prayers in council
                        [unclear].<lb/> Living, he laid the first seeds of a nation;<lb/> And dead,
                        he builds yet.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper prints a poem about the wounding of Stonewall Jackson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
