<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1866/va.au.vv.1866.11.21">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/29/04</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1866-11-21">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="11">November</month>
            <day norm="">21</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1866.11.21.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1866.11.21.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Situation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>As we have said before, we like this heading--it gives one such a full range,
                        over the world of matter that necessarily comes up every week, and enables
                        us to give our readers the benefit of our matured opinions, in a condensed
                        form. And a natural modesty; a singular diffidence, about obtruding our
                        opinions upon the public, makes it very acceptable at this time. For what
                        can we say, good, bad or indifferent? We can give an article by any heading,
                        and put plenty of the "bad, or indifferent," in it--but what single word can
                        so fully express the general idea of a modest man, and so unobtrusively show
                        the "good" things he wishes to convey to his readers? We have made diligent
                        search and have to stick to "the situation."</p>
                    <p>And, somehow or other, we can not take the same gloomy view of "the
                        situation," some of our most valued contemporaries do. The Valley Virginian
                        has not published a circular, emanating from some sneaks and cowards during
                        the war, calling on "Loyal Leagues," &amp;c., to rally in Washington for
                        the protection of Congress; for the simple reason that we thought the whole
                        thing a humbug, and felt perfectly safe, from all harm, from any such men.
                        They talk boldly about war and all that, now the fighting is over, but we
                        have a firm conviction that a "bounty jumper" could make a good pile, if a
                        flee would attack them vigorously--the signers of that call, and Forney who
                        published it, would certainly employ a "substitute" to kill him. Such being
                        our belief, we could not bore our readers with the call, and as the trouble
                        is over, we hope they are satisfied. In fact, we would take a bet that no
                        sensible man, in the South, has been excited about it any way.</p>
                    <p>Excited! alarmed! terrified! uneasy! such words can not be applied to a
                        people who have gone through the "fiery furnace" of war; who have been
                        ruthlessly devastated by a brutal soldiery, and then stripped by a more
                        heartless set of camp followers, by courtesy called "Government agents." The
                        Southern people, thanks to a "patience under affliction," only equaled by
                        their heroism in war, have still some rights left and <emph rend="italic"
                            >their land</emph>. The silly gabble of the Northern press; about
                        "Constitutional Amendments," &amp;c.; the degrading counsels of the
                        traitors among us, have had no weight. The magic power of a "passive
                        resistance," and the firm and determined <emph rend="italic">No</emph>, to
                        all encroachments on the rights of the States, has dumfounded the Radicals,
                        and given an encouragement, that will tell gloriously in the next elections,
                        to our friends North, and they are a legion. The late elections North are
                        full of encouragement, but we must profit by them and the facts they present
                        to us.</p>
                    <p>Well! what are we to do? nine out of ten readers will naturally ask. The
                        problem is simple, but its solution is hard--it is "<emph rend="italic"
                            >work! work! work!</emph>" if not with the head then with the hands and,
                        if possible with both. Never stop. As Governor Wise says, "work until you
                        are weary and still work on!" We must "fight the devil with fire;" we must
                        fight this untiring; this scheming; this practical; this infernally
                        persevering and ingenious race of yankees, with their own weapons. We must
                        bring our master intelligence down to the dull details, the monotonous every
                        day work, and with our climate and country we can beat him in the sod.</p>
                    <p>If our people will only look this material question squarely in the face; if
                        they will only bring every child, now living, up to be a master workman, and
                        educated mechanic, and a through business man, in ten years this Southern
                        people can defy the world, and they will be begged to <emph rend="italic"
                            >accept</emph> the rights the mob at Washington now scornfully refuse to
                        give them.</p>
                    <p>Rights! representation! the freedom guaranteed by the charter drawn by our
                        fathers! And are we so poor; are we so mean; are we so degraded, (tho'
                        overpowered,) that we will submit to the dictation of a yankee to get a
                        semblance of them, when by hard <emph rend="italic">work</emph>, by
                        encouraging imigration; by standing up for the <emph rend="italic"
                        >law</emph>, we can demand them in ten years? Never! two hundred thousand
                        graves say never! The solemn voice of the dead tells us to <emph
                            rend="italic">work</emph>, as they did, to suffer and endure as they
                        did; to be worthy of our past and all will be well.</p>
                    <p>In the language of our able contemporary, the Charlottesville Chronicle:</p>
                    <p>"Let us turn from politics. It is an old saying that no one can quarrel long
                        by himself. So uninviting is the field of politics to a Southerner now, that
                        we are perforce driven from it. Talking and discussing will not do us any
                        good. Nothing but one thing will help us throw off the heavy hand of the
                        North. The maxim with the North is the maxim of trade, they know no other
                        rule of life. That maxim is, that it is right to get the highest price you
                        can for your wares--that a man may legitimately make all he can out of his
                        neighbors. They regard the South as the wreckers regard a ship which has
                        gone to pieces on their coast. We shall have no pity nor mercy--and no
                        relief until we help ourselves.</p>
                    <p>The only path to salvation lies through <emph rend="italic"
                        >population</emph>. We must have <emph rend="italic">population</emph>. We
                        must shut our eyes to everything for the sake of <emph rend="italic"
                            >population</emph>. Let us turn the tide of immigration to the South,
                        and this section will stand erect once more: it may be, in the future, we
                        shall again shape the legislation of the country.</p>
                    <p>Here we have millions of acres of fertile lands lying idle, yielding nothing.
                        There is the foundation here for an empire, already occupied by six millions
                        of a hardy, brave, intelligent, Christian race. Our territory will maintain
                        several hundred millions. There are (including freedmen) one million people
                        in the State of Virginia. We want ten millions. If to-morrow one million
                        decent settlers could be put down in Virginia, the value of our lands
                        to-morrow, instead of being eight dollars per acre, would be sixteen dollars
                        per acre. The farmer with five hundred acres, held, say, at $10,000, would
                        then find the same farm worth $20,000.</p>
                    <p>When the title of immigration sets in, Congress cannot hurt us.
                        Constitutional Amendments cannot hurt us. Massachusetts will "dry up." If
                        negro suffrage comes (and it may come,) it will be harmless. In fact the
                        incoming wave will push the negro southward.</p>
                    <p>This (immigration) is <emph rend="italic">the</emph> solution of the troubles
                        which environ us. We <emph rend="italic">must</emph> have it. The
                        landholders of Virginia (confining our attention to our own State) hold the
                        key which will unlock our prison doors. Have they the skill to turn it?"</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This editorial refuses to take a pessimistic view of the political
                    situation. The "injustice" of reconstruction is nothing next to the suffering
                    and perseverance displayed by southern whites during the war years. If
                    southerners only focus on resisting the Radical agenda while developing the
                    material prosperity of their section, they will soon be readmitted to the Union
                    with rights intact.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Northern Immigrants</head>
                <origin>Richmond Times</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It is a great mistake to suppose that even after this long, bloody and cruel
                        war, in which medicine was made contraband of war and the public archives at
                        the South destroyed, that there is any prejudice against Northern men <emph
                            rend="italic">per se</emph>. Many a Northern man fell fighting bravely
                        on our side, and gave up his life in defence of the independence of the
                        South. In the ranks of the famous Washington Artillery, of New Orleans, were
                        many Northerners, and one of the best soldiers we ever saw, who was never
                        known to shirk a fight, was a Connecticut school teacher in the 12th
                        Virginia Infantry. During the war there was at the North, as in England at
                        the time of the struggle of the American Colonies for their liberty, a large
                        minority, respectable by its intelligence and social position, who opposed
                        it, and never would contribute a dollar to its support. There were others
                        who, thinking their section wrong in the matter, still resolved to support
                        it. There were others still, who, believing in the right of the South to
                        withdraw from the Union thought that it was essential to the salvation of
                        the North that the South should be kept in, and, believing self-preservation
                        would justify anything, supported the United States Government. All these
                        different classes were called by their opponents, the Black-snakers, either
                        "Copperheads" or War Democrats.</p>
                    <p>We Southerners can scarce have an idea of the way a poor Copperhead was
                        persecuted during the war by his Puritan brethren. Their sufferings almost
                        equalled those of the ancient Christians. They were tarred and feathered,
                        ridden on rails, their wives and daughters insulted when they appeared in
                        public, and all in the name of "Liberty." A distinguished Confederate
                        officer, who was in Wisconsin last winter, informs us that he met with
                        substantial farmers there who told him of the indignities and outrages
                        perpetrated on them on account of their opposition to the war. They were not
                        allowed to go to their county town, and were threatened if they did with
                        arrest and persecution for disloyalty. They had to form secret societies for
                        their own protection. Freedom of speech and freedom of the press, the two
                        boasts of the United States Constitution, were absolute myths. Many of our
                        soldiers will recollect gratefully the kindnesses shown them by Northerners
                        whilst in the United States military prisons, and many a Northern woman
                        nursed our sick and wounded kindly and tenderly in their hospitals.</p>
                    <p>So we say that there are at the North hundreds and thousands of good,
                        sensible men whom we at the South would be glad to welcome amongst us. We
                        want their industry, their thrift, their capital. They would find no
                        prejudice existing against them, and business and social relations they
                        could easily at once establish with our people. We want them to come among
                        us and ensure them a hearty welcome. For they would come to aid us in
                        building up and fostering the country, and not for purpose of creating
                        trouble and fomenting dissension amongst us. As for the canting, Puritanical
                        Yankee, with his negro affiliations, his "Plymouth Rock," his codfish, etc.,
                        we want none of that article, for we detest them almost as much as the
                        freedmen do.--<emph rend="italic">Richmond Times</emph>.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article republished from the Richmond Times asserts that southerners
                    hold little animosity toward northerners, especially since many of the latter
                    sympathized with or supported the Confederacy. Immigration of such acceptable
                    northerners should be encouraged in the South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1866.11.21.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports 506 arrivals at Staunton hotels in the last two weeks.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The cholera has disappeared from the Valley "and won't appear here again if
                    the town is thoroughly cleaned."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Mt. Sidney</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that "the colored folks are going to build a fine Church
                    in this town. Several new buildings have gone up and other are in
                    contemplation."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Burial Corps</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A burial corps from the Federal Army arrived in Staunton. They plan to move
                    their dead from the Staunton Cemetery, "where they have been cared for as our
                    own," by the citizens of Staunton. They also plan to gather bodies from the
                    battlefields of Port Republic, Piedmont, and others nearby.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Circuit Court</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lanigan</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Forrer</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Michie</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spitler</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carson</ln>
                        <fn>James E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carson</ln>
                        <fn>Robert N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The court is in session with Judge Sheffey presiding. The case of Brown,
                    Lanigan and Co., vs. Forrer began Monday. It involves $800,000 worth of
                    property. Thomas J. Michie is arguing for the plaintiffs. In the case of John
                    Spitler vs. James E. Carson for assault and battery, Carson was fined $250, and
                    his brother, Robert N. Carson, $80. The ruling against Robert Carson was later
                    set aside by the court on grounds of insufficient evidence.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>West Augusta Soldiers' Cemetery</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Ladies Cemetery Committee request 40 loads of earth to plant trees and
                    put turf grass on the graves. "It is as little as they could ask of the farmers
                    to give a day to this work."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Travel</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In the last 15 months, 11,150 people arrived at Staunton's American Hotel.
                    In the last 7 months, 5,100 people arrived at the Virginia, making a total of
                    16,250 in 15 months, over 1,000 per month.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Communicated</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Pike Powers writes the editors to call their attention to a series of
                    schoolbooks written by University of Virginia professors under the supervision
                    of George F. Holmes and published by Richardson and Co. of New York. "The prime
                    excellence of these books consists in the thoroughly Southern character of the
                    lessons and illustrations. Descriptions of southern plantations and animals;
                    sketches of southern Revolutionary worthies, Southern habits and customs,
                    adventures in Southern forests are mingled with moral and religious lessons of
                    great beauty, simplicity and truth. While there is not the slightest political
                    allusion, nor the slightest deprecation of any other region, no Southern child
                    can go through this Series of Readers without having his love of his native land
                    increased, as well as a salutary moral and religious effect produced on his
                    mind."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Alexander</ln>
                        <fn>Edgar S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cunningham</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beatty</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Edgar S. Alexander, of Moorefield, West Virginia, married Miss Rebecca L.
                    Cunningham on October 30th at Glenmoon, the home of the bride's father. The Rev.
                    James Beatty presided.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Truehart</ln>
                        <fn>Henry M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cunningham</ln>
                        <fn>Annie V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cunningham</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beatty</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Henry M. Truehart, of Galveston, Texas, married Miss Annie V. Cunningham,
                    youngest daughter of W. S. Cunningham, on October 30th at the Glenmoon, the home
                    of the bride's father. The Rev. James Beatty presided.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Creigh</ln>
                        <fn>Cyrus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tate</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tate</ln>
                        <fn>W. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>W. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Cyrus Creigh, of Greenbriar County, West Virginia, married Miss Margaret
                    Tate, daughter of Col. W. P. Tate of Staunton, on November 14th. The Rev. W. E.
                    Baker presided.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tribbet</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGuffin</ln>
                        <fn>Sue</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flournoy</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Tribbet, of Rockbridge, married Miss Sue McGuffin of Greenville,
                    Augusta County, on November 8th. The Rev. Mr. Flournoy presided.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCutchen</ln>
                        <fn>Sue R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>W. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. M. Johnson and Miss Sue R. McCutchen, both of Staunton, were married on
                    November 15th by the Rev. W. E. Baker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Little</ln>
                        <fn>J. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parish</ln>
                        <fn>Mary M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woodfin</ln>
                        <fn>A. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. T. Little, of Alabama, and Miss Mary M. Parish, of Augusta, were married
                    on November 13th by the Rev. A. B. Woodfin.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reagan</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sandford</ln>
                        <fn>Mollie A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whisner</ln>
                        <fn>P. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Hugh L. Reagan, of Staunton, and Miss Mollie A. Sandford, of Rockbridge,
                    were married on November 8th by the Rev. P. H. Whisner.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>T. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. W. Reed, of Frederick, and Miss T. G. Myers, of Augusta, were married on
                    November 8th by the Rev. C. Beard.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>Preston B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Desler</ln>
                        <fn>Mollie J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Preston B. Young, of Monroe, and Miss Mollie J. Desler, of Augusta, were
                    married on October 30th by the Rev. Mr. Jones.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1866.11.21.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
