<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1866/va.au.vv.1866.09.05">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/28/04</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1866-09-05">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day norm="">5</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1866.09.05.01" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>General Amnesty</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Washington Correspondent of the Baltimore Sun reports a rumor that a
                    general amnesty will be issued by November that includes Jefferson Davis,
                    previous exceptions notwithstanding.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>The Spirit of the Thing</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This excerpt takes issue with a New York News article that criticized the
                    Southern delegates to the Philadelphia Convention, "accusing them of a want of
                    manliness and of not upholding the Southern character." "We can assure the news
                    that our women are willing to trust the men who fought for them during the war,"
                    retorts the paper.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>07</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper sarcastically claims that Charles Sumner is "trying to get the
                    word 'white' stricken" from the White Mountains of New Hampshire.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1866.09.05.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Situation--Especially the Valley Rail Road</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Our news, local, and other columns, give our readers a very good idea of the
                        "situation," generally, in this mundane sphere. It is improving, and our
                        people may well be cheerful over the reports of the President's progress
                        through the North and the great West. Next week we will publish the gist of
                        his great speeches, and it is only necessary to say now, that he fully
                        maintains his great constitutional position, and more forcibly than ever,
                        reiterates his determination to stand by the platform of the Philadelphia
                        Convention. It is cheering to notice the dismay of the Radicals at the
                        enthusiastic reception he meets with from the people. It gives us more hope
                        for the future and the right than we have entertained for many a day.</p>
                    <p>From Europe we have news of permanent peace, and that encourages us to
                        believe the reports of the companies that have undertaken to build the
                        Virginia and Kanawha canal and the Covington and Ohio Railroad. They report
                        that with peace in Europe, they can raise the funds to complete these great
                        works, and we believe them. By peace, millions of capital will be thrown
                        into our glorious old State; and with that, willing hands and stout hearts,
                        our future need not be despaired of. A little time, patience and hard work,
                        and we will yet be a free, prosperous, and independent people.</p>
                    <p>But what has all this to do with the great Valley Railroad. Everything, for
                        "now is the accepted time" for our people to strike a blow that will secure
                        to us and our children the untold blessings to be derived from the
                        completion of this great work. How to do it is the question? Some of our
                        people have subscribed liberally, but the great desideratum is the county
                        subscriptions. Looking at the taxes we have to pay, some are scared at the
                        idea of a $200,000 subscription, and they never look at what we are worth as
                        a people. Now for a few facts--and we have always found this the only way to
                        convince a people like ours about anything requiring money.</p>
                    <p>The grand total of the value of real and personal estate in Augusta,
                        including solvent bonds not taxed, and Staunton, is $13,883,868. The
                        assessed value of land for this year is $9,573,883; of personal property, is
                        $1,554,247; value of solvent bonds, not taxed, $1,628,475; value of real and
                        personal property in Staunton, $1,127,263. Now, taking the value of land
                        alone in the county--which we take from the assessor's books--at $9,573,883,
                        the tax to be paid to meet the subscription of $200,000 to the Valley
                        Railroad, (two per cent to be paid on call--$4,000; and 13 per cent. in
                        three years--$26,000; total $30,000;) is $30,000, which is one-third of one
                        per cent for three years, and one-ninth (1-9) of one per cent, or one mill
                        and one-ninth on the dollar for each year.</p>
                    <p>Look at the facts and figures, people of Augusta, and say whether you can pay
                            <emph rend="italic">one mill and one-ninth</emph>, each year, on the
                        dollar, for this great road. And by this you realize at least 50 per cent.
                        on the increase of your property in value; you invest in good stock; you
                        raise your county to wealth and independence; you benefit all classes and
                        conditions among you, and your glorious Valley will become, in fact and in
                        truth, the garden spot of the world.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors apprise readers of the situation in several areas. They are
                    encouraged by President Johnson's speaking tour in the North, hope that peace in
                    Europe will lead to investment in Virginia, and, by pointing out the value of
                    Augusta lands, attempt to convince residents to accept a tax to pay for the
                    Valley Railroad.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>The West Augusta Guards</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Below we give the list of the killed during the war of this gallant company,
                        as furnished us by one of its members. It is suggested that the surviving
                        members have them removed to the Soldiers' Cemetery, and that a monument be
                        erected to their memory, giving the name of each, where and how wounded,
                        &amp;c. This is an admirable suggestion, and we hope action will be
                        taken in the matter at once:</p>
                    <p>Pat. O'Donnell, W. E. Woodward, Joeb Seiley, Manassas, July 21, 1861; Samuel
                        Roberts, Winchester, May 25, 1862; Jno. Donce, Port Republic, June 9, 1862;
                        Jas. Peters, Cold Harbor, 1862; Chas. Swoope, Manassas, Aug. 30 '62; Jas.
                        Reynolds, Sharpsburg, Sept. 17, '62; W. T. Martin, Chancellorsville, May 3,
                        '63; Albert Ramsey; Payne's Farm, Nov. 27, '63; Jas. M. Dorm, H. A. Hague,
                        and James W. Barnes, Wilderness, May 5, '64; T. P. Baskins and R. F. Bucher,
                        Spotsylvania May 5, '64; J. F. J. Tinsley, Lynchburg, J. H. Bryan, Monocacy,
                        July 4, '64; J. W. Bare, Winchester, Sept. 19, '64.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>O'Donnell</ln>
                        <fn>Patrick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woodward</ln>
                        <fn>W. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seiley</ln>
                        <fn>Joeb</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roberts</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donce</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peters</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swoope</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reynolds</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn>W. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ramsey</ln>
                        <fn>Albert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dorm</ln>
                        <fn>James M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hague</ln>
                        <fn>H. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnes</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baskins</ln>
                        <fn>T. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bucher</ln>
                        <fn>R. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tinsley</ln>
                        <fn>J. F. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bryan</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bare</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper lists casualties from the West Augusta Guards.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Town Council--September Session</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hardy</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peck</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Town Council met, mayor Trout presiding. The resignation of J. M.
                    Hardy, Alderman, was accepted, and H. Peck was elected to replace him. An
                    ordnance increasing stall rents for butchers to not less than $50 and all other
                    to not less than $10 per annum was passed. The street commissioner reported that
                    paving was "progressing favorably and satisfactorily."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Police Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jackson</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kurtz</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Deputy Sergeant</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carter</ln>
                        <fn>Patrick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>G. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craig</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dorson</ln>
                        <fn>Oliver</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mahaney</ln>
                        <fn>Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hyer</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary Jackson, "colored," was arrested by Deputy Sergeant Kurtz for stealing
                    $2.50 in specie from Patrick Carter, "colored," and also charged with stealing
                    silver spoons from Rev. G. B. Taylor. Sarah Craig was arrested for stealing
                    tablecloths and towels from William H. Peyton. Oliver Dorson was arrested for
                    beating and threatening to kill his wife with a washboard. "First two sent on.
                    Dorson held to bail." Ann Mahaney, "white," was arrested on complaint of Mrs.
                    Hyer. She was sent to jail after refusing to post bail.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>More Pardons</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brownlo</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dull</ln>
                        <fn>Cornelius</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kemper</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shuey</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trimble</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper prints a list of Augusta citizens who may obtain their pardon by
                    applying to the Secretary of the Commonwealth: John Brownlo, Cornelius Dull, B.
                    F. Kemper, George Shuey, J. B. Trimble, James Bumgardner.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1866.09.05.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports 75 visitors at Augusta's Stribling Springs.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports from the Register estimate that 4,000-5,000 people attended a
                    United Brethren Camp Meeting near Mt. Crawford.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>R. E. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ott</ln>
                        <fn>D. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lyle</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper reports the results of elections for officers of the 167th
                    Regiment, Va. Militia: Colonel, R. E. A. Stuart; Lieut. Colonel, D. A. Ott;
                    Major, Samuel H. Lyle.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>580 people arrived at Staunton's hotels last week.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper complains that gas costs $4 per thousand in Charlottesville, but
                    $7 in gold in Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper declares that Staunton is improving, and applauds Capt. Peck for
                    putting up the street lights.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Balsly</ln>
                        <fn>J. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Manley</ln>
                        <fn>M. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper announces that J. D. Balsly has replaced M. B. Manley as
                    postmaster at Sherando, Augusta County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Fatal Affray</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bush</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Frank Bush, "well known in Waynesboro, got into a difficulty with a negro
                    man last Thursday. Bush died from the effects of the beating the negro gave him
                    on Sunday night."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Count. Court--August Term</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gearheart</ln>
                        <fn>M. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>M. D. Gearheart was convicted of petit larceny and sentenced to 60 days in
                    jail.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper urges Valley citizens to support the Valley Railroad. Railroads,
                    the editors claim, made New England, which has some of the "poorest country in
                    the world," into one of the richest.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Accident</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dumb</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper reports that Dumb George, "the famous colored devil of this
                    office," fell from a tree, injuring his shoulder and leg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper jokingly asserts that "some people have suggested our deaf and
                    dumb servant, George Tucker, as a suitable delegate to the Radical Convention at
                    Philadelphia. He says he can't disgrace his honorable record in that way, and he
                    declines."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1866.09.05.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
