<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1866/va.au.vv.1866.08.08">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/23/04</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1866-08-08">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="08">August</month>
            <day norm="">8</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1866.08.08.01" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that Gen. Terry issued an order "prohibiting negro drills
                    and armed organizations in his District, much to the relief of the people of
                    Richmond."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Whig</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This selection takes Horace Greely and his Tribune to task for taunting
                    Raymond of the Times for supporting the Crittenden compromise in 1861. Greely
                    argued that such a course would have ruined the Republican party. "The fact that
                    it would have saved this country from the most deadly and ruinous war of modern
                    times, passes for nothing with the Tribune."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>The Morals of Washington Under Radical Auspices</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This item suggests that morals in Washington have declined under the
                    leadership of the Radical Republicans. Lawmakers are guilty of "licentiousness
                    and drunkenness" and spend much of their time in saloons, billiard halls, and
                    houses of ill fame. In the Capital "harlots and niggers occupy the galleries,
                    smile on their pet members on the floor, and throw kisses" to the
                    representatives.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>07</column>
                <head>The Coat of Faded Gray</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>By Geo. W. Harris</p>
                    <p>A low hut rests in Lookout's shade<lb/> As rots its moss-grown roof
                        away,<lb/> While sun down's glories softly fade,<lb/> Closing another weary
                        day:<lb/> The battle's din is heard no more--<lb/> No more the hunted stand
                        at bay--<lb/> The breezes through the lowly door<lb/> Swing mute a coat of
                        faded gray.<lb/> A tatter'd relic of the fray--<lb/> A thread-bare coat of
                        faded gray.</p>
                    <p>'Tis hanging on the rough log wall<lb/> Near the foot of a widow's bed,<lb/>
                        By a white plume and well-worn shawl--<lb/> His gift--the happy morn they
                        wed.<lb/> By the wee slip their dead child wore--<lb/> The one they gave the
                        name of May,<lb/> By her rag doll and pinafore--<lb/> By right it's there,
                        the coat of gray.<lb/> A red fleck'd relic of the fray--<lb/> An armless
                        coat of faded gray.</p>
                    <p>Her all of life now drapes that wall,<lb/> Poor and patient still she
                        waits<lb/> On God's good time to gently call<lb/> Her, too, within the
                        jewel'd gate<lb/> And all she craves is here to die--<lb/> To part from
                        these and pass away<lb/> To join her love eternally<lb/> That wore the
                        slip--the coat of gray.<lb/> The shell torn relic of the fray--<lb/> Her
                        soldier's coat of faded gray.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This poem celebrates an old Confederate uniform.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1866.08.08.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Richmond Correspondence</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper's Richmond Correspondent reports on happenings in the city of
                    Richmond. He denounces an incident in which two women, one black and one white,
                    were seen walking arm-in-arm down the street. "They were soon arrested by our
                    ever vigilant police and confined in the cage. Upon inquiring I found the white
                    woman was a recent importation and, consequently her selection of a companion in
                    her afternoon walk." The correspondent also reports that the city's blacks are
                    upset about the order preventing them from holding militia meetings.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>A Word to the Colored People</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In a few words we will try to state the case to the colored people. You are
                        here, a part of the great body of the Southern society and you have several
                        questions to ask yourselves. 1st. Who are you and how did you get here? 2d.
                        Who brought you here and sold you, and who has taken care of you since? 3d.
                        What is your true policy for the future? In answer to the first question,
                        you know you are black, a negro, and that your forefathers were brought by
                        force from Africa, a land of darkness and barbarism. To the 2d. we can
                        answer that the immaculate and freedom loving Yankees, of New England,
                        kidnapped you and brought you here, sold you to Southern men and then set up
                        a howl about the "brutality of Southern slavery," after these same Southern
                        States forced them to abolish the "slave trade" in 1808, sorely against
                        their will--for it was very profitable. These Southern people took your
                        forefathers, ignorant and naked, and by their kindness, patience, judgement
                        and love for you, brought you to your present state of civilization, which
                        no other portion of your race has reached. In return you gave them your
                        labor, and that you loved them was shown by your noble conduct during the
                        war. Circumstances beyond your control freed you from the restraints
                        heretofore put upon you, and an all wise Providence allowed this same
                        Yankee, who sold you into slavery, to free you--<emph rend="italic">not for
                            the love of you but to gratify his infernal hatred to the Southern
                            whites--you friends</emph>. Such is the true state of the case; you have
                        accepted the freedom forced upon you by Radical Yankee hatred of Southern
                        gentlemen and no one blamed you for it, any more than they would blame a
                        school boy for taking holiday; when the teacher is "barred out." And what
                        are you to do? Ah, there's the rub--your dispositions and education prompt
                        you to do right; prompt you to cultivate friendly feelings with your best
                        friends, our people, but foolish people among us, and designing Yankees,
                        tell you to carry out the same spite a Radical Yankee will always have. They
                        urge you to believe that we are no longer friends and they are--and the
                        promptings of vanity make you agree with these poor creatures. Now look
                        matters square in the face. You are here forever unless you die out like the
                        Indians, as the Yankees predict. How to do your part for society is the
                        question. It is to trust your white people; to be prompt and energetic; to
                        comply with all contracts; to work and study, and make up your minds that
                        only by hard work and by trusting to the kind and affectionate feelings of
                        those who raised you, can you exist on this Continent. Do this; show
                        yourselves worthy of the position you are placed in, as you heretofore
                        showed you could be trusted, and your future is clear before you--always
                        recollecting the great fact, the position of the honored and respected of
                        your class exemplifies, that "you must respect yourself to be respected."
                        Listen not to fools or worse, who tell you about "equality" and all that,
                        for that's your ruin and extermination. Be honest, be faithful; make
                        yourselves <emph rend="italic">necessary</emph> to the community and the
                        devilish schemes of the Radical Yankee to ruin the Country, though you will
                        be thwarted and your race saved.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This editorial asserts that the southern white is the best friend of the
                    African American. Northerners were responsible for the slave trade and pressed
                    for emancipation not out of concern for blacks, but out of hatred for southern
                    whites. The editorial urges southern blacks to work hard to succeed as free
                    people, and not follow the policies of the Radical Republicans.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1866.08.08.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports 500 arrivals in Staunton last week. "The watering places
                    are filling up, where people from both sections of the country mingle together
                    and the most friendly and sociable feelings predominate."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper reports that Peter Hanger, Jr., of Augusta county, was charged
                    with defrauding the US government by making false returns of distilled spirits.
                    After an examination of the case, the charges were found to be groundless.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Spotswood Hotel</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Corkery</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tinsley</ln>
                        <fn>J. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tinsley</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tinsley</ln>
                        <fn>Julius</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dupree</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper calls the attention of readers to an advertisement for the
                    Spotswood Hotel. The announcement "will take many a soldier back to the happy
                    times he spent there during the war, when he was so lucky as to have a
                    furlough." Corkery, "who made great sacrifices during the war," remains the
                    proprietor. "Our people will recognize the name of J. R. Tinsley, the
                    bookkeeper" who is the son of former townsman J. B. Tinsley and the brother of
                    Julius Tinsley "a gallant and much beloved member of the Stonewall Brigade, from
                    this place, who was killed at Lynchburg." Dr. Dupree also serves as a clerk.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va,au.vv.1866.08.08.04" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>All Over Now</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>All over now! The trumpet blast,<lb/> The hurried trampling to and fro,<lb/>
                        The sky, with battle smoke o'ercast,<lb/> The flood of death and woe!<lb/>
                        All ended now. The syren song<lb/> Of hope's ecstatic lay is hushed;<lb/>
                        And minor chords in plaintive tones,<lb/> Well out where gayer notes are
                        crushed.</p>
                    <p>'Neath feathery snow, in hallowed ground,<lb/> By far Potomac's rippling
                        stream,<lb/> Our loved ones sleep; the lulling waves<lb/> Can ne'er disturb
                        the soldier's dream.<lb/> They whisper "Peace;" the dove of peace,<lb/> Like
                        Noah's, searches for her nest;<lb/> She folds her wings among the DEAD,<lb/>
                        But with the <emph rend="italic">living</emph> finds no rest!</p>
                    <p>All over now! We gave our all--<lb/> Our loved ones, homes and prayers;<lb/>
                        God willed that we awhile shall wait<lb/> In bitterness and tears.<lb/> What
                        need of tears? Why must they flow<lb/> When all but life and breath are
                        gone?<lb/> God help us all! and help the heart<lb/> To murmur still, "Thy
                        will be done!"</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This poem meditates on the end of the war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
