<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- !DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd' -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1859/va.au.ss.1859.04.19">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Jeff McClurken</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/15/95</tagDate>
            <tagNote>2nd Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1859-04-19">
            <year>1859</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day>19</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1859.04.19.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Locofoco Extravagance</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <commentary/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Diatribe against the extravagant expenses rung up by the Congress.
                    Expresses hope that such lavish spending will inspire voters to defeat the
                    Democrats.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1859.04.19.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Candidates for the Legislature</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <commentary/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sproul</ln>
                        <fn>W.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>Jefferson</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guy</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennerly</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Massie</ln>
                        <fn>Nathaniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>J. Marshall</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>Bolivar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Van Lear</ln>
                        <fn>D.N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bruffy</ln>
                        <fn>W.O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newton</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hogshead</ln>
                        <fn>M.W.D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tate</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fulton</ln>
                        <fn>Givens</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Finley</ln>
                        <fn>S.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Berry</ln>
                        <fn>Thornton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doyle</ln>
                        <fn>R.L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>J. Marshall</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sproul</ln>
                        <fn>W.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harrison</ln>
                        <fn>Powell</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sterrett</ln>
                        <fn>F.F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guy</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craig</ln>
                        <fn>M.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moore</ln>
                        <fn>A.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robertson</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nelson</ln>
                        <fn>W.J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Complains that no Whigs have come forward to run for the legislature. Tally
                    of the balloting.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Election of Judge</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <commentary/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robertson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parker</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Vote tallies in April 14 election for Court of Appeals. Baldwin is winner
                    in Augusta County, but Robertson has a majority in other counties and is
                    probably the winner. Complains about voter apathy and low turnout.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript><p>Messrs. Editors:  One of the great objects sought to be 
                    obtained by the Reform Convention to amend the State Constitution, was 
                    to abolish the life tenure of office;  and to give to every good citizen 
                    the right to seek, or become a candidate for any office within the gift 
                    of the people.</p>
                    <p>So far as Constitution provisions were concerned, 
                        this object was attained; but it is very different to this in the 
                        practical working of the political parties of the day.  We have Cliques, 
                        Conventions, and so called meetings of the people, which nominate one of 
                        their favorites for each and every office; and then declare it to be 
                        suicidal, or a case of "self destruction" to any man who has the 
                        temerity to announce himself a candidate for any office in opposition to 
                        their selections.  As we do not believe the great mass of the people 
                        sanction or are satisfied with the action of such bodies, and believing 
                        also that a majority of them are opposed to the re-election of our old 
                        Representatives in the Legislature, we take the liberty of proposing 
                        three other Whigs as candidates to represent us, who, we think, will 
                        give entire satisfaction, and not endanger the  harmony of the Whig 
                        party.  We mean Doct. E. G. Moorman, Maj. Jas Walker and Wm. 
                        Sproul.</p>
                    <p>We are personally the friend of all the old 
                            Representatives, but think that some of  them, at least, have been in 
                            the Legislature often enough to gratify the reasonable  ambition of 
                            themselves or their friends.  We should like to have more candidates in 
                            the field for another reason; it would perhaps arouse the Whig party 
                            from the Van Winkle sleep into which they have fallen, since the great 
                            Ollapod contest, and bring to the polls every Whig voter of the county.  
                            This would certainly be advantageous to the Whig candidate for Governor, 
                            because the more votes polled in the county the larger will be his 
                            majority.  And we have no fears that the Democratic party will put 
                            candidates in the field, but will agree that if the Whigs will let them 
                            have a free fight for a Representative toCongress, the Whigs can have a 
                            fair fight for members of the House of Delegates.  We hope then the 
                            friends of the gentlemen named will prevail upon them to announce 
                            themselves as candidates on the 1st day of the April Court, and then 
                            we shall see which will triumph, King Caucus and his allies, or the 
                            people.     </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Waynesboro; April 18th, 1859</trailer>
                <commentary/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moorman</ln>
                        <fn>E.G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Major</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sproul</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letter nominating Moorman, Walker and Sproul as Whig candidates for
                    legislature. Calls for change and rejuvenation of the Whig party.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/ssapr59.html#4.19a</note>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Editors Spectator--Gentlemen:--Owing to the fact that great dissatisfaction  
                    exists among the people throughout the county that the three old 
                    candidates for the  Legislature have been renominated; and believing, as 
                    we do, that their re-nomination has been affected in a great measure by 
                    the wireworking of a clique in the town of  Staunton:  we beg leave to 
                    call upon three gentlemen to permit their names to be  presented to the 
                    voters of Augusta on the 4th Thursday in May next, as candidates for the 
                    next House of Delegates of Virginia.  Staunton has ruled the county long 
                    enough, and it remains for the people to determine whether they will 
                    throw off the yoke, or tamely submit to it forever.  The Democratic 
                    party have no candidates in the field, and will have none as they have 
                    positively declared.  Then the cry of Harmony! Harmony! raised by the 
                    clique is a mere subterfuge to appease the murmurings of an indignant 
                    Public.  We hold it to be the right of every man to vote for whom he 
                    pleases; we therefore, call upon Co. Wm. M. Sproul, Major James Walker, 
                    and Jefferson Kinney to sayat the April Court whether they will consent 
                    to become the People's Candidates for the next Legislature.  In making 
                    this call we are actuated by no unkind feelings to any of the Candidates 
                    now in the field; but having a preference for others we claim the right 
                    to express it; and we mean to express in the most unqualified manner our 
                    disapprobation of the course pursued by the Staunton Junto towards Major 
                    Walker, whom they unceremoniously thrust aside, to make room for one of 
                    the favored of the Clique.  And this they had the unblushing effrontery 
                    to do in defiance of the expressed wishes of the people for their 
                    favourite Candidate at the polls.  Let the gentlemen declare themselves 
                    at the April Court and we will see that justice be done at the polls,if 
                    not by the Staunton Caucus.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>New Hope, April 15th</trailer>
                <commentary/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sproul</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Major</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>Jefferson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letter nominating Sproul, Walker and Kinney as the "People's Candidates"
                    for the legislature. Expresses disapproval of the "Staunton Junto."</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/ssapr59.html#4.19b</note>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>For the Spectator; West View, April 16th, 1859</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <commentary/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walters</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roberts</ln>
                        <fn>F.O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Calhoun</ln>
                        <fn>Jonathon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guy</ln>
                        <fn>J.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swoope</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guy</ln>
                        <fn>J. Emmett</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guy</ln>
                        <fn>J.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eidson</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Calhoon</ln>
                        <fn>J.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guy</ln>
                        <fn>V.R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roberts</ln>
                        <fn>F.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Minutes of first meeting of West View Goggin Club.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <commentary/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamilton</ln>
                        <fn>R.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lambert</ln>
                        <fn>Jonathon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ruff</ln>
                        <fn>R.R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seig</ln>
                        <fn>H.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>P.A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guy</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>Bolivar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>S.A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Starrett</ln>
                        <fn>F.F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lambert</ln>
                        <fn>J.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Geeding</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Minutes of the meeting of the Goggin club of Churchville.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>For the Spectator; Mt. Sidney, April 11 '59</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <commentary/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bruffy</ln>
                        <fn>W.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hyde</ln>
                        <fn>C.K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harrison</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guy</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Perkins</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Minutes of Goggin club meeting.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1859.04.19.03">
            <div type="s">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <commentary/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peterson</ln>
                        <fn>E.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cross</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Franklin</ln>
                        <fn>Julia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married at Clay Street Church on April 6.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>G. B. T.</trailer>
                <commentary/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mason</ln>
                        <fn>Drusilla</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mason</ln>
                        <fn>Claiborne</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Mason died on March 29. She was a member of the Baptist
                church.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote>same political announcements, market prices</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1859.04.19.04">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
