<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- !DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd' -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1859/va.au.ss.1859.07.19">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Jeff McClurken</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/15/95</tagDate>
            <tagNote>2nd Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1859-07-19">
            <year>1859</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day>19</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1859.07.19.01">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1859.07.19.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Work for the Charleston Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <commentary/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Looks ahead to the 1860 Democratic convention in Charleston. The big issue
                    at the convention will be slavery in the Territories.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Lamp Posts</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <commentary/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The lamp posts ordered by the town council will be erected at various spots
                    around town, including Gospel Hill, the National Hotel, Court House squre, and
                    fifteen other locations.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Terrific Storm</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On Friday last, about 7 o'clock in the evening, our town was visited by the
                        most terrific thunder-storm we have ever witnessed. Indeed the oldest
                        inhabitants of Staunton say that they never have known such a storm before.
                        The rain came suddenly and in torrents from an angry looking cloud in the
                        North-west, and continued to pour down for thirty minutes, during which time
                        the heavens and the earth were illuminated by incessant flashes of the most
                        brilliant lighting, followed by stunning peals of thunder. The large drops
                        of rain descending in the twilight looked like brilliant diamonds as they
                        sparkled in the glare of the electricity. The wind blew a hurricane for a
                        short time, but we have heard of no damage being done by it. The lightning,
                        however, struck a tree near the residence of Mr. E. M. Cushing, thence
                        glancing to the dwelling-house, passing down the chimney, and shivering the
                        mantels. Mr. C. received a severe shock and Mrs. C. was slightly burned, but
                        neither of them were severely injured. We have heard of no other damage done
                        by the lightning in town. In the afternoon of Friday, however, we regret to
                        learn that a valuable negro man belonging to Mr. Washington Swoope was
                        killed by lightning.--A colt on the farm of Mr. John D. Brown, near
                        Staunton, was also killed, and one of the Messrs. Hawpe, near Greenville,
                        lost 28 sheep.</p>
                    <p> We usually contemplate a thunder-storm with admiration and delight, as one
                        of the most sublime manifestations of Omnipotence, but we confess we felt
                        some trepidation during the storm of Friday evening. Our friend Mr. S. E.
                        Clark, whose advertisement will be found in another column, thinks such
                        would not have been the case if we had permitted him to put for us a good
                        copper lightning rod, as he proposed before the storm. We have no doubt that
                        rods protect houses, and that Mr. Clarke's rods are superior to the old
                        fashioned iron rods. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <commentary/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cushing</ln>
                        <fn>E. M</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cushing</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swoope</ln>
                        <fn>Washington</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn>S. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Account of a bad thunderstorm that hit Staunton on July 15. Both houses and
                    people were struck by lightning.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/ssjuly59.html#7.19a</note>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Gas Works</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Stockholder</trailer>
                <commentary/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A stockholder and consumer of the gas works writes to thank Mr. Bowes and
                    the contractors for giving him a tour of the works and for the excellent job the
                    contractors did in building the works.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Opposition State Convention</head>
                <origin>Richmond Whig</origin>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <commentary/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Agrees with the Richmond Whig's call for an 1860 Opposition state
                    convention because it will allow Virginia the most flexibility in maneuvering
                    between the North and the South.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>For the Spectator; "Wesleyan Female Institute"</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Messrs. Editors:--The Commencement exercises of the above-named Institute
                        were brought to a close June 30th at 12 o'clock at night. The entire week
                        preceding the Commencement proper, was one of unusual interest to the
                        friends of the Institute.</p>
                    <p> On Sunday the 26th of June, a Baccalaureate Sermon was preached before the
                        Graduating Class, by the Rev. James A. McCauley, A. M., formerly a Principal
                        of the Institute, and now pastor of the Methodist Episcopal Church in the
                        town of Fredericksburg, Va. This gentleman's popularity in Staunton, where
                        he is so well known, secured a large and intelligent audience, and his
                        masterly treatment of the subject--"The relation of Christianity to
                        woman,"-- what it has done for her, what it is doing for her, and what it is
                        yet destined to do for her, as well as the bearing of Christian education
                        upon the whole subject, so captivated his hearers as to leave nothing
                        necessary to be said in this place in commendation of her merit as a chaste,
                        pure,and impressive speaker. We do most cordially commend his purity of
                        style and elegant diction to those who wish to attain to a mastery of our
                        mother tongue.</p>
                    <p> On June 27th, 28th and 29th the Examination of the several classes was
                        conducted in the presence of an intelligent Committee, and high compliments
                        were passed upon a number of the pupils for the critical and thorough
                        acquaintance with their text books which they evinced.</p>
                    <p> The graduating class, especially, acquitted themselves with great credit;
                        just at this point we may be allowed to say, high as has been from the
                        beginning of this educational enterprise, the grade of scholarship here
                        demanded, a more completely trained class of young ladies has never gone
                        forth from this classic enclosure to reflect honor upon their instructors
                        and the cause of truth.</p>
                    <p> On Wednesday night, June 29th, at 8 o'clock, a Literary Address was
                        delivered before the entire school by the Rev. B. F. Brooke, A. M., of
                        Baltimore. The accomplished lecturer gave proof not only of an enviable
                        mental culture, but a wise appreciation of what he fitly named the exelsor
                        age" in which we live, and urged the claims of solid learning strongly upon
                        his auditors.</p>
                    <p> The Commencement exercise proper, took place on Thursday night June 30th,
                        and in which all the young ladies having part therein acquitted themselves
                        with great satisfaction.</p>
                    <p>Composition has always engaged a marked attention in this school, and the
                        evidences of a very careful training in this acknowledgedly important
                        department were manifest in many of the highly [illegible] essays of the
                        evening.</p>
                    <p> The rich musical entertainment of the evening was presided over by Professor
                        Turner, and the mere mention of this gifted gentleman's name in such
                        connexion is a sufficient guarantee for elegance in the performance of
                        music.</p>
                    <p> Prof. Turner has a wide fame--a deservedly high reputation as an instructor
                        in this refining, ennobling, purifying act, and the kill of his pupils as
                        exhibited on this occasion, evinced the faithfulness and ability with which
                        they had been taught, and showed how justly he is entitled to the estimate
                        in which he is held.</p>
                    <p> During this festive week a large number of the graduates of former years,
                        nearly a score of ministers, and more than that number, perhaps, of parents
                        and other patrons from distant points, were in attendance; these, with the
                        fast friends of the Institute here resident, gave universal expression of
                        satisfaction.</p>
                    <p> The "Wesleyan Female Institute," be it known, is no longer an experiment;
                        its infancy has been passed through. It has encountered and overcome
                        difficulties potent enough to have crushed an ordinary enterprise. To the
                        indefatigable labors of a former Principal--Rev. James A. McCauley, A.
                        M.--let it be said in all justice, it owes its present well defined
                        character as a Church enterprise; others, and not a few, have given of their
                        money, labor, talent and zeal for the promotion of its welfare; and, now
                        under the management of the present scholarly and energetic Principal, Rev.
                        Benjamin Arbogast, A. M., a native Virginian, and a member of the Baltimore
                        Conference, assisted by such a board of teachers as the Catalogue sets
                        forth, much may be reasonably hoped for; already, it seems to be lifting
                        itself above difficulty, and we hazard little in predicting that its future
                        history is destined to be as bright and prosperous as its past has been full
                        of difficulty and discouragement.</p>
                    <p>Its finances are at last in a healthy condition. The Trustees, relieved from
                        embarrassment in this direction, have turned their attention to such repairs
                        and improvements as seem to be required by the increasing prosperity of the
                        school.</p>
                    <p> Nearly five hundred dollars have been this year expended for repairs,
                        Chemical and Philosophical Apparatus, new musical instruments, and
                        furnishing the entire building with gas light; so that no convenience shall
                        be wanting to make the school all that its most sanguine friends could
                        desire.</p>
                    <p> We call upon friends of this cherished Church enterprise, to rally still
                        more warmly to its support, that no proper effort may be wanting to to make
                        it the equal, if not the superior of any school of similar grade in the
                        land.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <commentary/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCauley</ln>
                        <fn>Jame</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brooke</ln>
                        <fn>B.F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turner</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Argobast</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Account of commencement week at the Wesleyan Female Institute. Praises the
                    Institute for being extremely well-run and for turning out well-trained young
                    ladies.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/ssjuly59.html#7.19b</note>
            </div>
            <pageNote>bottom left corner illegible</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1859.07.19.03">
            <div type="s">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <commentary/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCarty</ln>
                        <fn>W.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sutton</ln>
                        <fn>Joshua</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robson</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on July 17.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <commentary/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richardson</ln>
                        <fn>X.J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huxler</ln>
                        <fn>Edward</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Almarode</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on July 7.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Markets in column 1</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1859.07.19.04">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
