<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- !DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'-->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1859/va.au.ss.1859.07.05">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Jeff McClurken</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/15/95</tagDate>
            <tagNote>2nd Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1859-07-05">
            <year>1859</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day norm="05">5</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1859.07.05.01">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1859.07.05.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Celebration of the 4th</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <commentary/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Washington</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bashoug</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mallory</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCune</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Terrell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gray</ln>
                        <fn>H.J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>N.K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harper</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wertembaker</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Details of Staunton's 4th of July celebration. Several military guards
                    participated, including the Continental Morgan Guard of Winchester, Mountain
                    Guard of Spring Hill, the West Augusta Guard, officers of the Militia, and the
                    Monticello Guard of Charlottesville. The celebration included bands, speeches,
                    and picnics.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Rosin and Coal Gas</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <commentary/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newton</ln>
                        <fn>C.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>Tazewell</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stribling</ln>
                        <fn>F.T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Which gas is better--Rosin or Coal? Correspondence between Staunton and
                    Norfolk Gas Companies. Staunton used rosin gas.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>For the Spectator; Augusta Female Seminary</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript><p>Messrs. Editors:I hope you will allow me a brief 
                    space in your columns for a notice of the Augusta Female Seminary, the 
                    exercise of which for the session, closed on Thursday evening last, when 
                    a musical concert was given by the pupils, under the direction of their 
                    teachers, which for mere beginners, as they all were, in that elegant 
                    but difficult art, was in a high degree creditable, alike to the 
                    diligence of the pupils and the skill, fidelity, taste and "aptness to 
                    teach" of the accomplished ladies who preside over that department.</p><p> The 
                        examination of the other classes occupied Wednesday and Thursday, during 
                        part of which time I had the pleasure of being present.  The manner of 
                        conducting the examination could not fall to be gratifying to every 
                        friend of sound education.  It was manifest that there had been no 
                        special preparation for the occasion with a view to a striking and 
                        brilliant display, but the proceedings were so conducted as to exhibit 
                        the real progress and attainments of the pupils, and the kind of 
                        mental training and discipline to which they had been subjected. And in 
                        both these particulars the examination furnished gratifying evidence 
                        that eminent skill, patient diligence and a high conscentiousness 
                        characterize the teachers.  This school has, for two years, been under 
                        the care of J. Brown Tinsley, Esq., and although it has not been as 
                        large as its excellent character merited.  It has yet been sufficient  
                        so to satisfy the patrons and others acquainted with it, that the 
                        Trustees were very fortunate in being able to secure so competent and 
                        experienced an instructor to take charge of this institution, ultimately 
                        connected, as it is, with the educational interests of the country of 
                        Augusta.  My high opinions of the merits of this school is not derived 
                        merely from an annual attendance upon its closing examinations, but 
                        chiefly from the daily progress in their studies of several pupils 
                        connected with it for the last two sessions, and  which has fallen 
                        under my immediate and special observation.  I
                        therefore feel no  hesitation in speaking of the school as one, the great aim of which is, 
                        to impart a thorough, useful and sound education, while at the same time 
                        ample preparations are made for these branches deemed merely ornamental.</p> 
                    <p>I cannot close this communication without a passing tribute to the 
                        merits of Miss Miller, Mr. T.'s assistant in the academical department, 
                        who in addition to her accurate and thorough scholarship, combines with 
                        a firmness and decision of character, an amiable and lady-like 
                        gentleness of deportment which render her invaluable in a school for the 
                        education of girls.</p>
                    <p> This seminary is emphatically a school of the county 
                        of Augusta, it being originally established by the public spirited 
                        liberality of a portion of her citizens, when there was no other of the 
                        kind within her borders.  Since its establishment it has continued to 
                        accomplish a most excellent work in promoting as well as elevating the 
                        standard of female education in this community; and there has been no 
                        time since its origin when it was more efficiently and thoroughly 
                        organized for its appropriate functions than at present. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Amicus; July 2d, 1859</trailer>
                <commentary/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tinley</ln>
                        <fn>J. Brown</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Very complimentary report of a visit to the Augusta Female Seminary.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/ssjuly59.html#7.5a</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Elopement Extraordinary--A White Girl Runs Away with a Black Man</head>
                <origin>Philadelphia Inquirer</origin>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Phil. Inquirer</trailer>
                <commentary/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Story of a white girl in Chester County, Pennsylvania eloping with a
                    "mulatto" employed on the same farm. They eloped to save the man from being
                    lynched.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <commentary/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>J.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maupin</ln>
                        <fn>J.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Oder</ln>
                        <fn>Kara</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Oder</ln>
                        <fn>Waller</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Maupin and Oder married on June 23.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <commentary/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hutchison</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hutchison</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hutchison</ln>
                        <fn>Mildred</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary Margaret Hutchison died on May 29, age 20.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Other, not local, obits and weddings</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1859.07.05.03">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1859.07.05.04">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
