<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1868/va.au.ss.1868.09.15">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/30/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1868-09-15">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day norm="">15</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1868.09.15.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1868.09.15.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Virginia's Love for the Union</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"I could not love thee, dear, so much,</p>
                    <p>Loved I not honor more."</p>
                    <p>When Daniel Webster said that bitterer tears would be shed over the
                        destruction of the temple of American liberty, than were ever shed over the
                        ruins of Greece or of Rome, he uttered a sentiment, says the Petersburg
                            <emph rend="italic">Index</emph>, to which the heart of Virginia
                        responded.</p>
                    <p>The most solemn hour, continues that journal, which any deliberative body
                        were ever called upon to face, was that hour in which the Convention of
                        Virginia were called upon to decide whether they would adhere to the North
                        or the South, that hour in which Virginia was called upon to decide between
                        coercion and secession -- between a new Declaration of Independence and an
                        old love for the Union of our Fathers.</p>
                    <p>Right or wrong, Virginia had ever been accustomed to look upon the Union as
                        her own offspring. She felt for it all that is combined of strength and
                        constancy in parental affection, joined with parental pride. Her's was no
                        selfish love; she had demonstrated it by the free gift to the government
                        which she had founded of a domain, itself capable of becoming an empire in
                        wealth, power, and population, the most royal gift that ever yet one State
                        has bestowed upon another. The love of the Union and our common country, was
                        with her a high, a noble and exalted sentiment. She stripped herself like
                        the noble Lear of royalty, and wealth and power, to bestow them upon her
                        children. Like Lear, too, she gave up all, all, save the one reservation --
                        her independence. Alas, that the parallel should hold good in this, that
                        beggared and outcast, she sues in vain for admission into the household of
                        her ungrateful daughters, while Jubal Early, who loved her as the noble
                        loved his unhappy master, and who with others wept like a child when the
                        ordinance of secession was passed, wanders an exile in a foreign land. Tell
                        us not, wretched Radical, that you loved the Union as Virginia loved it.
                        Give not, you miserable fanatic, the name of love to your rancorous hate --
                        to love such as Virginia felt in her generous, noble, and unselfish soul.
                        You never knew -- you can never know it. Had you been capable of one
                        magnanimous sentiment, you would never have canonized the miscreant John
                        Brown, who brought fire and slaughter to her peaceful homes. Had you loved
                        your country as Virginia loved it, as Clay, and Webster, and Wright, and
                        Jackson loved it, as Horatio Seymour loves it, Virginia had never been
                        driven to the <emph rend="italic">cruel necessity</emph> of secession. It
                        was you who forced the war upon her. It was you who forced upon her the dire
                        choice between adherence to the government which she first established and
                        which she loved -- and degradation and embracing her hands in kindred blood.</p>
                    <p>With twenty thousand old muskets, with half a pound of powder and <emph
                            rend="italic">two</emph> caps to each musket, she went out in the face
                        of the cannon, and she said to the "Union," as Lovelace said to his weeping
                        wife while he armed for battle, "I could not love you, dear, so much, loved
                        I not honor more." You men of the North, if Virginia comes to you to-day a
                        beggar, it is to beg the patrimony of which she has been robbed --
                        <sic>is</sic> is to beg the <emph rend="italic">restitution</emph> of the
                        rights of which <sic>the</sic> has been deprived -- the restitution of the
                            <emph rend="italic">Old Constitution.</emph> We anticipate your answer,
                        and in November, with the tide of a great patriotism rising in your souls,
                        you will dash aside the Radical and the Fanatic who deny them, and you will
                        say, "the mother of States asks for her rights under the Constitution, and
                        SHE SHALL HAVE THEM."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Explains Virginia's secession in terms of a love for liberty and the Union.
                    Claims that Virginia will demand the restoration of her rights in the
                    Presidential election.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Expulsion of Negroes from the Georgia Legislature</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article argues that the expulsion of African-Americans from the Georgia
                    legislature was done under constitutional grounds, since blacks are not allowed
                    to hold office in that state.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper complains that although $1,600,000,000 has been raised through
                    taxes since the war, the national credit still lags behind countries such as
                    Austria, Turkey, and the South American republics.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Radical Economy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper blasts the government for increasing the national debt since the
                    end of the war. "For the purpose of forcing negro suffrage and negro equality
                    upon the Southern people at the point of the bayonet, that the Radicals may be
                    continued in power, twenty thousand troops are stationed South of the Potomac at
                    a cost of forty millions per year."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1868.09.15.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Maginley's and Carroll's circus has come to Staunton with good reviews and
                    recommendations.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Work details are now raising and recurbing the pavement near the Court
                    House under orders of the County Court.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Capt. Balthis is now engaged in thoroughly painting the interior of
                    Staunton's Baptist Church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Brian's Menagerie and Circus will be exhibiting in Staunton. The company's
                    tents can accommodate 3,000 persons. The 20 animal dens will take up a space of
                    325 feet long.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Methodist Church</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Under a military order -- for the military are now "running the churches" --
                        requiring that the Methodist churches in this county should be occupied
                        alternately by the ministers of the M. E. church and the M. E. church South,
                        Rev. E. P. Phelps of the former church held service in the Methodist church
                        of this place on Sunday afternoon.</p>
                    <p>The practical effect of this military order will be to turn out of doors one
                        half of the time a very large congregation of the M. E. Church, South, that
                        the church may be occupied by the minister of the M. E. Church which has but
                            <emph rend="italic">one</emph> member in this place.</p>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">O tempora! O mores!</emph>
                    </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Under a military order, the Methodist Church must hold services for both
                    the Methodist Episcopal church North and the Methodist Episcopal church South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Augusta Springs</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A correspondent of the <emph rend="italic">Enquirer and Examiner</emph>,
                        writing from the Augusta Springs in this county, speaks in very high terms
                        of this popular watering place. We know the correspondent to be a man of
                        character and distinction. He concludes a long and interesting letter as
                        follows:</p>
                    <p>"Having observed the effects of the remarkable curative properties of the
                        three mineral springs at this place upon a large number of invalids, and
                        received for nearly a month the polite and kind attention of the gentlemen
                        in charge of it, I should be ungrateful if I failed to warmly recommend it
                        to the people of the South. I do not know a watering place in the mountains
                        of Virginia where the visitor receives a larger return of comfort and
                        enjoyment for the very moderate expenditures which he makes than here; and
                        if its management hereafter is as liberal, excellent and well conducted as
                        at present, the "Augusta Springs, so long known to the public as
                        "Stribbling's" will become one of the most popular watering places in the
                        State. Easy of access, situated in the midst of a fertile and beautiful
                        country, nestling in the very midst of lofty mountains, and shaded by
                        magnificent forest trees, it cannot fail to become a favorite resort of
                        families from all parts of the South. During the present season it has been
                        filled by a company second to none in the mountains for refinement and
                        intelligence."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A correspondent of the Enquirer and Examiner praises Augusta Springs for
                    their curative properties, and for the quality of the service there.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Mr. W. A. Pratt</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pratt</ln>
                        <fn>W. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper welcomes W. A. Pratt, accomplished engineer and architect, to
                    Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Willie Coffman</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coffman</ln>
                        <fn>Willie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Willie Coffman, the 2 year old blind pianist, has been performing in
                    Staunton to rave reviews. The paper declares him the "most remarkable musical
                    prodigy in the world." He plays with his fingers, wrists and elbows, and his
                    performances have "excited the wonder, admiration, and astonishment of all who
                    have witnessed them."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Observations of a Philadelphia Lawyer</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Mr. "E. S.," belonging to that class proverbial for astuteness --
                        "Philadelphia lawyers" -- who was on a recent visit to this place, wrote a
                        long and well written letter to the <emph rend="italic">Philadelphia City
                            Item</emph>, under date of Staunton, August 29th. We have room for only
                        two extracts. His observations seem not to have given him a very favorable
                        opinion of negro labor. He says:</p>
                    <p>"From labor comes wealth, but that labor which bring gold into our coffers
                        and wheat into our garners, needs must be real and substantial labor, well
                        organized, well protected; and it must be <emph rend="italic">honored</emph>
                        labor. Such I find the white man's labor. The rising and setting sun mark
                        out his hours of toil, and the brown face and hard burnt hands attest the
                        severity of that toil. As an honest man I cannot so speak of negro labor. We
                        of the North do not, may be, we will not see, the inefficiency of the
                        present negro labor. You know well, Mr. Editor, that I hail from the
                        Republican side of the political house and issues, and this because I can
                        see no <emph rend="italic">safe</emph> and middle path; but this must not
                        deter me from telling the wholesome truths, palatable or impalatable to
                        extremists. I do not see any real value in negro labor -- there is no
                        certainty in it -- it is whimsical, peevish labor -- it is labor without
                        toil -- it is labor to provide food for to-day and not for the morrow. It is
                        labor which avoids husbandry, and seeks the comparative ease of town life.
                        Pardon my touching on this theme -- it is not political, it is in the order
                        of political economy. Permit me, in ending this subject, to illustrate, by a
                        single instance of the many under my observation.-- On the way to Weyer's
                        cave I saw a negro of the stalwart kind engaged in breaking limestone for
                        turnpike repair. His was easy labor. Let me picture the operation. He was
                        seated on a pile of stones chair high, in his hand a small hammer, with
                        handle about twelve inches long a little larger than a tack hammer. WIth one
                        hand he would take up a small stone about four inches square, and hold it
                        till, with slow, light, and measured blows; he would leisurely reduce it
                        into convenient size, and rest from his toil awhile, and then in like manner
                        resume his labor. Our turnpike men would little relish such labor, and would
                        not agree that the laborer was worthy of any hire. The work forcibly
                        reminded me of cracking shell-barks in my boyish days.</p>
                    <p>We do not know that he is a musician, but suppose from the manner in which he
                        thrums and tickles the ribs of the Proprietor of the Va. Hotel that he would
                        make a fine performer with bone castanets. He says:</p>
                    <p>"The Virginia Hotel, in the hands of Mr. Scheffer, is perhaps unexcelled in
                        that essential virtue which comes so near to godliness, cleanliness. The
                        pure white sheets, table cloths and other hotel linen, give evidence of the
                        tone which pervades in all departments of this hotel. The courteous host
                        spares neither time, money, nor pleasing words to give fitting welcome to
                        the coming guests, and thus makes them <sic>loth</sic> to part with such a
                        clever host. The attendance is perfect in all respects, and while gilded
                        ornament, costly mirrors, and burnished furniture may dazzle the guests of
                        the Revere, Fifth Avenue, or Continental, there is with them all that
                        absence of real home, which this Virginia house affords."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Mr. "E. S.", a Philadelphia lawyer, remarks negatively on "negro labor" and
                    positively on the excellent service at the Virginia Hotel.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Plant</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beck</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scherer</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sullivan</ln>
                        <fn>Johanna</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weed</ln>
                        <fn>J. Ambler</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Father</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Benjamin Plant and Mrs. Mary Beck, and John B. Scherer and Miss Johanna
                    Sullivan, all of Staunton, were married at St. Francis Church by Father J.
                    Ambler Weed on September 8th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tillery</ln>
                        <fn>Lewellen A. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cowger</ln>
                        <fn>Louisa A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cowger</ln>
                        <fn>Job</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pinkerton</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lewellen A. S. Tillery of City County, Missouri, and Miss Louisa A. Cowger,
                    daughter of Job Cowger, were married on September 10th at the residence of Jacob
                    Neff by the Rev. John Pinkerton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shiplet</ln>
                        <fn>Martin S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>Catherine E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thomas</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Martin S. Shiplet and Miss Catherine E. Wright, daughter of the late
                    William Wright, were married near Moscow on September 3rd by the Rev. Jacob
                    Thomas.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Robert White died at his residence near Waynesborough on September 3rd. He
                    was 72 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newton</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lambreth</ln>
                        <fn>S. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Newton died at his residence near Greenville on August 28th. He was 71
                    years old. "In all the relations of life, Mr. Newton exhibited qualities worthy
                    of praise and emulation. His prudence and firmness, his high moral character and
                    dignified deportment, won for him the respect of the entire community. For many
                    years he was a Director of the Western Lunatic Asylum and a magistrate of his
                    native county, and when he resigned the latter office, his excellent judgement
                    and wise discretion commended him to his fellow-citizens as one worthy to act
                    the part of counsellor and friend; as a citizen he was devoted to his county and
                    his state; as a neighbor, he was kind and obliging. But it was within the sacred
                    precincts of home that his character shone most brightly. There we found the
                    hospitable Virginia gentleman; the devoted husband; the tender and indulgent
                    father. Mr. Newton was a humble believer in Jesus Christ." S. S. Lambreth signed
                    the above eulogy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1868.09.15.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
