<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1868/va.au.ss.1868.07.07">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/27/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1868-07-07">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day norm="">7</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1868.07.07.01" exists="no">
            <div type="l">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Chesapeake and Ohio Rail Road</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter from "Alleghany" pointing out the advantages of constructing the
                    Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad. The new line will shorten the distance between
                    Augusta and Richmond, decrease freight costs by 25%, stimulate manufacturing,
                    and raise land values.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1868.07.07.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>National Democratic Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on the first day's proceedings of the Democratic National
                    Convention in New York.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Gen. Lee and Gen. Grant</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper quotes the New York Herald's opinion that while General Lee won
                    victories through military ability, Grant won through a "stolid strategy of
                    stupidity that accomplishes its object by mere weight." If Grant had had fewer
                    men, the article asserts, he would not have defeated Lee.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Amnesty Proclamation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper announces that President Johnson has released a proclamation of
                    amnesty for all ex-Confederates not specifically disfranchised by the 14th
                    amendment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Taxes Under the Proposed Constitution</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The <emph rend="italic">Dispatch</emph> states that "it is fairly assumed by
                        those who have examined the subject that the aggregate tax paid by the
                        oppressed and impoverished people of Virginia will not be under <emph
                            rend="italic">nine millions of dollars!</emph> or nearly three per cent.
                        on the total value of the real and personal property of the State.</p>
                    <p>With a tax such as this, how can this State recover from its prostration? How
                        can we expect strangers to come amongst us, invest their money, and cast
                        their lot in Virginia? The danger will be that our own people, unable to
                        bear the burden heaped upon them, will be compelled to fly the country.</p>
                    <p>If this abomination of a Constitution contained any fair principle by which,
                        after its adoption, the reliable and capable population, which pay the
                        taxes, could recover control of the levying of them there might be some hope
                        even should it be forced upon us. But there is no such principle in it. It
                        is a rascally and brutal instrument, which, under the assumption that the
                        great body of the whites are "rebels," secures in the hands of negroes and
                        debased white men all the offices and honors of the government, and
                        therefore the entire administration of public affairs. Moreover, by
                        gerrymandering the State, and basing the apportionment of representatives on
                        the first registration, a majority of <emph rend="italic">twenty-one</emph>
                        in the Legislature on joint ballot is given to the negroes."</p>
                    <p>Here, then, the people of Virginia see the prospect should this infamous
                        Constitution be fastened upon them. Property will be placed at the mercy of
                        paupers. Respectability, Experience, Capacity, Fidelity, and Wisdom will be
                        banished from all influence in the public councils, and the affairs of State
                        will be brought under the rule of Incompetency, Corruption, and Depravity.
                        Cursed with the most loathsome misrule, and burthened beyond their power of
                        endurance, the people must sink down in the scale until they reach an
                        unimaginable depth of poverty and misery. Against this fate the man who will
                        not struggle with all his might deserves a fate no better.</p>
                    <p>Is this an affair of property holders only? -- Deluded indeed are those who
                        think so. The poor freedmen who are led by the nose by scallawags,
                        carpet-baggers, and the Freedmen's Bureau, are fatally involved in the
                        consequences that must flow from the adoption of the monstrous Constitution
                        which they have helped to frame. If there is no prosperity, there is no work
                        -- if there is no work, there is no money -- if there is no money, there is
                        no means to buy food and clothing. Then, how are they to subsist? They
                        cannot thrive by warring upon property. Destroy the value of property --
                        break up confidence -- curtail business and occupation, and they will suffer
                        more than property holders. They will be without the means of living, and
                        will have dried up the sources of Charity in having taken from her the
                        wherewithal to be charitable. Robbery will be the last resource, in
                        resorting to which they will afflict the country indeed, but will make for
                        themselves a hell upon earth. Of all men, the negro will be most accursed by
                        that abominable Constitution which fanatics and scoundrels have induced him
                        to frame!</p>
                    <p>Let the people of Virginia look at this terrible instrument in all its
                        enormity, and if they allow to themselves rest until they have defeated it,
                        then Virginia must, indeed, have lost the breed of noble blood.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Excerpt from the Dispatch predicting that taxes under the proposed
                    Constitution would be nearly three per cent of the value of all property in the
                    State, and arguing that the effects that this would have on the economy would
                    impoverish property holders and paupers alike.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Evans</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Col. John B. Baldwin was appointed president of the Virginia delegation to
                    the Democratic National Convention, and Thomas J. Evans secretary.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Commencement Exercises for the Wesleyan Female Institute</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hewitt</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brooke</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shafer</ln>
                        <fn>Bettie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trotter</ln>
                        <fn>Kate</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foutz</ln>
                        <fn>Sue</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strasburg</ln>
                        <fn>Laura</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>Sidney</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trotter</ln>
                        <fn>Haywood</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deffenbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Annie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maupin</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strasburg</ln>
                        <fn>Laura</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shafer</ln>
                        <fn>Fannie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Wesleyan Female Institute celebrated closing exercises with several
                    addresses from ministers and a musical performance under the direction of Prof.
                    J. H. Hewitt.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1868.07.07.03" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Hands Off!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper quotes the Lynchburg Virginian in arguing that they would prefer
                    that African Americans ran their own candidates for office rather than making
                    alliances with carpetbaggers. Election of black men to Congress would put
                    Republicans in a bind since their admission might cause a backlash against black
                    suffrage in the North.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Root, Hog, or Die</head>
                <origin>Richmond Whig</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article quotes the New York Tribune in asserting that after completion
                    of reconstruction, "root, hog, or die," will be the principle of life for
                    African-Americans. There will be no Freedmen's Bureau, and blacks will be left
                    by their so-called northern friends to fend for themselves.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Alexandria Gazette</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article attacks those who insist opposition to Republican rule is
                    useless. Instead, opponents should protest, if only to have their message heard.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Butterfly</ln>
                        <fn>Martha M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stringer</ln>
                        <fn>W. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George Harman and Mrs. Martha M. Butterfly, both of Augusta, were married
                    at Waynesboro on June 28th by the Rev. W. R. Stringer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Adams</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richards</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richards</ln>
                        <fn>George B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mason</ln>
                        <fn>R. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Joseph M. Adams of Rockbridge and Miss Sarah G. Richards, daughter of the
                    late George B. Richards, were married near Warm Springs by the Rev. R. H. Mason.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>William R. Dunlap and Mrs. Blair, both of Augusta, were married at the home
                    of the bride's father near Newport, Augusta County on July 2nd by the Rev. J. O.
                    Miller.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henry</ln>
                        <fn>Jannie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henry</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jannie Henry, daughter of James Henry, died of typhoid fever on June 12th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanna</ln>
                        <fn>Franklin J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Franklin J. Hanna died on June 28th of disease contracted while in the
                    Confederate Army. He was 28 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1868.07.07.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
