<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1868/va.au.ss.1868.04.14">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/19/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1868-04-14">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day norm="">14</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1868.04.14.01" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Unconstitutional Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Proceedings of the state constitutional convention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Is he Dictator Yet?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article suggests General Grant is overstepping his duties and assuming
                    the role of military dictator in his support for the removal of Andrew Johnson
                    from office.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>The Penalties for a New Crime</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In Virginia less than in almost any other State, are the whites divided in
                        political sentiment, and the efforts to brand patriotic devotion to our
                        section as "treason," and to render it "odious," have simply rendered the
                        vile apostates who have tried to play this game themselves so "odious" that
                        they are shunned like lepers by nine-tenths of their old
                        associates.--Indeed, to avoid the infamy which is likely to attach to the
                        memory of those renegades, their descendants will some day be petitioning
                        the courts to be allowed the privilege of changing their names.</p>
                    <p>After having exhausted all the effots of malice, vindictiveness and slander,
                        the Radicals find that the people of Virginia cling to their disfranchised
                        civil and military leaders with an affection which has been intensified by
                        the persecution to which they have been subjected.</p>
                    <p>And as long as this noble spirit pervades our people, the negroes and their
                        wretched parasites can inflict nothing more than a little temporary
                        annoyance upon us. All that we have to do is to oppose to every act of these
                        creatures a resistance, either passive or active, which can only be overcome
                        by a standing army. Let the negroes and the carpet-bag adventurer learn that
                        when the bayonet is withdrawn, down topples their power, and up again go the
                        old standards of the white man as in days gone by.</p>
                    <p>The traitors to their race who are advocating the disfranchisement of our
                        best citizens, must be taught that the penalty of their crime is utter and
                        complete excommunication by the race which they have betrayed. If the
                        soldiers who defended Virginia are unworthy of association with the
                        proscribed.--Let them have their fill of the negroes and of the unwashed,
                        codfish-eating scallawags to whom they would give all the offices and power
                        in the State. Let them eat with them, sleep with them, intermarry with them,
                        live and die with them, for they cannot expect the countenance of those who
                        do not believe that a negro is as good as a white man. What right has any
                        apostate Confederate, who would disfranchise General Lee, and make a
                        suffragan of his black hostler, to associate with the gentlemen upon whom he
                        openly wars.</p>
                    <p>The crime proposed by such men is a far graver one than that for which
                        offenders are sent to another hill than that upon which stands the Capitol.
                        The Romans regarded the crime of parricide as impossible, and for a time
                        enacted no law for its punishment. The offence of giving Virginia to the
                        negro and to the rapacious mercenaries who laid waste her soil and ruined
                        her people, was, until recently, a sin, which seemed too hideous to be
                        possible. ALthough the laws do not punish it, yet every reflecting white who
                        thinks of the consequences of negro rule, knows that it is the blackest
                        crime ever contemplated. It is nothing less than the murder of the State and
                        the dishonor of a noble race by putting the foot of the late slave upon the
                        neck of his old master.--<emph rend="italic">Enquirer</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Quoted a Richmond paper which warned Virginians of the consequences of
                    collaborating with Republicans and thus putting blacks in power. Called anyone
                    who did so a traitor to the white race, and called on the majority of Virginians
                    to keep Virginia in the hands of whites.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1868.04.14.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Arouse to Action</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We repeat our admonition to the Conservatives, that they should be at work.
                        There is no time to be lost. When the Convention shall adjourn it is
                        probabale that but little time will be allowed--the object of the majority
                        of its members, looking to the interests of the Radical party, will be to
                        have the election as soon as possible after the adjournment of the
                        Convention. The Conservatives should not postpone action till after the
                        adjournment of the Convention. They should take time by the forclock, and go
                        at once to work. Speakers should be appointed, and should enter at once upon
                        a vigorous canvass. All that we hold dear will be at stake. Every man should
                        do his duty. There should be no drones in the Conservative hive.</p>
                    <p>The "Old North State" is acting nobly, and setting an example which our good
                        State would do well to follow. "In that gallant Old Commonwealth," says the
                            <emph rend="italic">Norfolk Virginian</emph>, "her sons are moving
                        forward to the rescue of her interests and her honor in three solid columns,
                        which sweep her territory from east to west with a fire of irresistible
                        eloquence. It is a grand spectacle to see her hoary-headed patriots, her
                        mature statesmen, and her youthful orators dedicating themselves to the
                        service of their State with an unselfish and heroic devotion which is above
                        all praise. From her mountain gorges down to her spreading coast, from her
                        centre to her uttermost boundaries, her children are working with head and
                        heart for her salvation. It is a sublime spectacle! Each day two hundred
                        noble speeches, noble in sentiment, noble in design, noble in pluck, and
                        noble in unselfish devotion are made within her borders. The 'fiery cross'
                        is borne aloft within her borders by the swiftest runners of her Clans, and
                        from high land and lowland they rally to the rescue. We repeat, it is a
                        sublime spectacle, and the most bitter Radical in Congress must admire the
                        heroic force of the Anglo-Saxon spirit which glows with such rare brilliancy
                        in so dark a night as that which now gathers over the orators of North
                        Carolina. We accord them our admiration and salute them with honest pride,
                        from Vance and Graham, and Ashe down to the merest tyro among them all, and
                        we say to the people of Virginia that we should observe our sister State and
                        emulate her example. Let the Central Committee give the signal for the men
                        of Virginia to be up and doing, like the men of the Old North State. It is
                        time we were at work!"</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Called on the Conservative men of Virginia to campaign vigorously in the
                    upcoming elections for the interests of the South. Gave the example of speeches
                    and energy in North Carolina as the perfect model for Virginia to follow.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Great Issue--Norfolk Virginian</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It is no disparagement to the other able journals of the State to express the
                        opinion that the <emph rend="italic">Norfolk Virginian</emph>, edited by the
                        distinguished poet, Jas. Barron Hope, is doing more efficient service at
                        this time than any other journal. It is a favorite with us. It appreciates
                        the magniture of the issue, and labors energetically to save the State from
                        Radical rule and negro domination. We quote from it frequently as our
                        readers have observed. It is an efficient co-laborer. From various numbers
                        we have clipped the following paragraphs:</p>
                    <p>The issue before the people of the State in the coming election is a single
                            one--<emph rend="italic">negro equality</emph>. Will all men, Whigs,
                        Democrats, Rebels and Union men unite on that one issue and vote down the
                        Constitution?</p>
                    <p>If you do not believe in letting the negroes do all the voting and pay none
                        of the taxes, vote against the Constitution.</p>
                    <p>No time for sleeping or dreaming. The work before us is a serious one. Come
                        out white men, on the day of election, and vote down the Constitution.</p>
                    <p>White Men, remember that all persons now registered can vote on the
                        Constitution. Let every man in the State who has not registered do so when
                        the opportunity offers, and vote against the Constitution.</p>
                    <p>THE DEVIL'S DEVOTIONS:--</p>
                    <p>"For him we preach</p>
                    <p>For him we pray,</p>
                    <p>For him we labor night and day</p>
                    <p>That colored cuss from Africa</p>
                    <p>VITAL QUESTIONS.--Shall negroes and knaves rule and ruin Virginia, or shall
                        her own true sons, the representatives of the intelligence, the worth and
                        the property of the State, save her from such shame. This is the question
                        for every citizen who has not registered to ask himself. Every vote is
                        important, and no man can fail to secure his right to vote without being
                        criminally derelict.</p>
                    <p>VOTE IT DOWN.--The ratification of the odious negro constitution will entail
                        negro equality on the people of Virginia beyond hope of redemption. Come out
                        on the day of election, and defeat Radical dreams of personal aggrandisement
                        by voting down the Constitution.</p>
                    <p>THINK OF THIS.--Shall white men be enrolled in the militia with
                        negroes--perhaps under negro officers? This is one of the results for which
                        those who refuse to register will be held responsible.</p>
                    <p>White Men, read, ponder and weigh well, what the Radicals demand from the
                        Southern States, and then, if you can, stand with folded arms and see the
                        negro Constitution carried by default in Virginia:</p>
                    <p>1. A national debt.</p>
                    <p>2. Increased taxation.</p>
                    <p>3. Untaxed bonds for capitalists.</p>
                    <p>4. High protective tariffs for New England manufactures.</p>
                    <p>5. Shinplasters for the poor.</p>
                    <p>6. Gold for the bondholder.</p>
                    <p>7. Negro mongrelism at the polls and in the jury box.</p>
                    <p>8. Disfranchisement of a large proportion of our citizens.</p>
                    <p>9. Confiscation of Southern lands.</p>
                    <p>10. Military satraps at an expense of one hundred million dollars annually to
                        the government instead of civil officers paid by the States.</p>
                    <p>11. Negro Senators and negro Congressmen.</p>
                    <p>12. Negro judges and negro jurors.</p>
                    <p>13. Negro Vice-President.</p>
                    <p>14. Trials by military commissions instead of civil courts.</p>
                    <p>Keep it before the people, that the policy of the hybrid Republicans is to
                        impoverish the country, centralize power, paralyze industry, multiply
                        taxation and elevate the negro while degrading the white man.</p>
                    <p>Keep it before the people, that the ringed, streaked and striped negro
                        constitution allows white children to be bound servants to negro masters,
                        and allows negroes to become guardians of white children.</p>
                    <p>Keep it before the people, that the carpet baggers' constitution allows white
                        men in the militia to be commanded by negroes.</p>
                    <p>WHICH IS BETTER, a Government administered by intelligent and virtuous WHITE
                        MEN, or a Government administered by needy squatters, ignorant Africans and
                        impudent allies of mixed blood?</p>
                    <p>Unless you are in favor of requiring voters to swear <emph rend="italic"
                            >never</emph> to oppose the equality of the races, go to the polls and
                        cast your vote AGAINST Constitution.</p>
                    <p>The proposed Constitution once adopted, any man who opposes negro equality
                        will be laughed at. It will then be too late. VOTE IT DOWN!</p>
                    <p>Unless you are in favor of COMPELLING the little children of the country,
                        whose parents are too poor to educate them, to associate with little
                        negroes, go to the polls and vote AGAINST the proposed Constitution.</p>
                    <p>Do you want a negro guardian for your child when you are dead and gone? This
                        is a searching question and one which you should answer to yourself, for it
                        may happen that a court of negroes may decide so to dispose of your little
                        flaxen-haired girl, or your bright eyed boy. If the new Constitution is
                        adopted it will be competent for the negroes to do this very thing, i.e.
                        give the daughter of John Stokes, white carpenter, to Mumbo Jumbo, black
                        reprobate, as his ward. There is no fancy in this picture. It is grim truth.
                        Who wants to see it painted in reality? We answer the question, and say that
                        the White Man who can register and does not, is the fellow. Mark him! Hunt
                        him!--Brand him! Make him an outlaw!</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Quoted extensive passages from a Norfolk newspaper outlining the horrors
                    that would follow passage of the proposed constitution. Talked about blacks
                    taking over the government and subjecting whites to humiliation. Urged all
                    whites to save the white race by voting down the Constitution.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Railroad Elections</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The vote on the proposed subscription by Augusta County for $300,000 in
                    Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad stock will be held on Saturday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Negro--What is to Become of Him?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Editorial from the Richmond Whig advocating distribution of funds to
                    African-Americans to allow them to emigrate to Liberia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>A Trap to Catch Voters</head>
                <origin>Norfolk Vir.</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article suggesting that the proposed Homestead exemption in the new state
                    constitution is merely a trap to entice voters to ratify the radical document.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1868.04.14.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Federal Tax collector will be in Staunton at the end of the month.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Adkins</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilbert</ln>
                        <fn>Charles R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stover</ln>
                        <fn>Christopher</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Joseph Adkins and Charles R. Gilbert were released for insufficient
                    evidence in the murder case of Christopher Stover. The accused proved they were
                    elsewhere at the time of the killing.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Protestant Eclectic</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn>Y. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Y. H. Peyton of Staunton is proposing to begin a magazine entitled "The
                    Protestant Eclectic." It will be devoted to "diffusion of moral and religious
                    truth."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Augusta County Fair</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John B. Baldwin, president of the fair committee, announces the completion
                    of the purchase of the fair grounds. The paper applauds the move and celebrates
                    the importance of holding a fair to show the industrial and agricultural output
                    of the county.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Ladies' Fair</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter encouraging the citizens to attend the fair held by the ladies of
                    Trinity Church. The proceeds will go to construction of an iron railing to
                    surround the church yard.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>K. K. K.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Kuklux Klan are kalled upon to kastigate or kill any kullered kusses who
                        may approve the konstitution being koncocted by the kontemptible
                        karpet-baggers at the kapitol. Each Klan is kommanded by a karniverous
                        kernel who kollects his komrades with kare and kaution kommensurate with the
                        magnitude of the kause. Whenever konvened, they must korrectly give four
                        kountersigns. Those are: Kll the kullered kuss; klean out the
                        karpet-baggers; krush the konvention; karry konservatism; konfusion to
                        kongress; konfederates will konquer. Of kourse the klan kreates konsiderable
                        konsternation among the Kongos and their kunning konducters, who kalculate
                        that their kareer may be kut short by katasrophies.--Kowardly kurs, they
                        kan't komplain.--<emph rend="italic">Dispatch</emph>. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Printed the goals, signs, and actions of the Klan, started nearly every
                    word in the article with a "k" to boost the emphasis.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Argenbright</ln>
                        <fn>James M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ward</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Getzendanner</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James M. Argenbright and Miss Elizabeth W. Ward, both of Augusta, were
                    married at Elizabeth Furnace on April 5th by the Rev. H. Getzendanner.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Giles</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dunlap</ln>
                        <fn>Mary C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dunlap</ln>
                        <fn>William R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>William E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel N. Giles of Staunton and Miss Mary C. Dunlap of Augusta, daughter of
                    William R. Dunlap, were married at the residence of the bride's father on April
                    8th by the Rev. William E. Baker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Opie</ln>
                        <fn>H. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Simmons</ln>
                        <fn>Sue W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cosby</ln>
                        <fn>J. V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>H. L. Opie of Staunton and Miss Sue W. Simmons of Bardstown, KY, were
                    married in Kentucky on March 31st by the Rev. J. V. Cosby.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zirkle</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coiner</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coiner</ln>
                        <fn>Franklin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>See</ln>
                        <fn>C. S. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jacob B. Zirkle of Shenandoah County and Miss Sarah M. Coiner, daughter of
                    Franklin Coiner of Augusta County, were married near Fishersville on April 9th
                    by the Rev. C. S. M. See.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hupman</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>Alex</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>P. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lewis V. Hupman and Miss Mary E. Anderson, daughter of Capt. Alex Anderson,
                    were married on April 9th by the Rev. P. C. Walker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1868.04.14.04" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Poland</head>
                <origin>Charlottesville Chronicle</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The kind-hearted philosopher, H.G., is working himself up into a great state
                        of indignation at the wrongs of Poland. "The decree for the absorption of
                        Poland into Russia is an act of monstrous iniquity, which has <emph
                            rend="italic">hardly</emph> a parallel in the history of the nineteenth
                        century."</p>
                    <p>It is very well indeed that this assertion should be qualified for one can
                            <emph rend="italic">hardly</emph> conceive how the impudence even of the
                            <emph rend="italic">Tribune</emph>, could lead it to consider this
                        "monstrous iniquity" as <emph rend="italic">without</emph> a parallel in
                        view of the history which its Radical friends are making at the South.--The
                            <emph rend="italic">Tribune</emph> but expresses the unanimous judgment
                        of the civilized world, when it denounces the course of Russia towards
                        Poland, as <emph rend="italic">monstrous</emph> in its <emph rend="italic"
                            >inquity</emph>. There is but one crime, which one nation can commit
                        against another, (except total extermination.) greater than that of
                        overwhelming a brave and free born people by force of arms, and subjecting
                        them to the absolute rule of a foreign Military authority, and that has been
                        discovered and put in force on the Southern people by the criminal ingenuity
                        of the Radical Demagogues--in their attempt to put the whites under the rule
                        of the negroes--their former slaves. The Poles complain of the very Military
                        Despotism which the people of the South ask as a boon instead of the deep
                        degradation with which they are threatened by the so-called Philanthropists
                        of the North. In the view of the <emph rend="italic">Tribune</emph>, the
                        Czar of all the Russians is guilty of a monstrous iniquity, but the Congress
                        of the United States in its course towards the unreconstructed States, using
                        its power to hold them down, to be oppressed by half civilized blacks, urged
                        on by the most utterly depraved white men that ever cursed any country, is
                        only doing what is just and right.--Nothing is more suprising than the
                        manner in which men, who, in their private relations, are honest and even
                        benevolent and humane, when they become politicians are blinded by
                        fanaticism and self-interest, and commit without hesitation the greatest
                        crimes and outrages, on humanity. Almost every word that Mr. Greely has
                        written with the pretence of virtuous indignation, of Russia and Poland can
                        be made to apply with double force, to the case of the South. "It is
                        difficult to see how a Government in many respects so far sighted as that of
                        the <emph rend="italic">United States</emph> should ever have conceived the
                        idea of suppressing by decree <emph rend="italic">ten
                            nationalities</emph>."--<emph rend="italic">Charlottesville
                        Chronicle</emph>.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper used the example of Poland as way to criticize Republican
                    reconstruction policies. Cited how Northern papers denounced Russia for
                    subjugating Poland and asked how the subjugation of the South by Republicans was
                    any different. In fact, the editor said it was worse because the Republicans put
                    blacks in power over whites in the South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
