<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1868/va.au.ss.1868.09.01">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/30/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1868-09-01">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day norm="">1</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1868.09.01.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1868.09.01.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Railroad Subscription</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Although a majority of the vote cast was in favor of the county subscription
                        to the Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad, yet inasmuch as the law requires
                        three-fifths of the whole vote cast in order to carry it -- the mere
                        majority is insufficient. Augusta for the first time in her history takes a
                        step backwards from the front to the rear rank in the march of public
                        enterprise, and is the only county in Virginia which has yet refused aid to
                        this great State work.</p>
                    <p>We trust that this vote may not be construed into opposition to the Railroad
                        itself -- or even into an ungenerous disposition to avail of its advantages
                        without the honesty to pay our fair share of the cost. There were side
                        issues which decided many to vote against it who were otherwise favorable to
                        the subscription, and under other circumstances it would certainly have been
                        carried.</p>
                    <p>But we fear that a golden opportunity has been lost for securing <emph
                            rend="italic">to this generation</emph>, the advantage of seeing this
                        great Valley, the highway for the trade and travel of nations -- the home of
                        thousands of industrious and enterprising immigrants from all countries --
                        the seat of busy manufactures of all kinds. And we are sure that no one who
                        votes against it would begrudge ten times the amount of his paltry tax to
                        see this great end accomplished.</p>
                    <p>The subscription of Augusta was necessary to make sure of completing the
                        amount required to let the work to contract. We hope her failure will not
                        give other counties the pretext to withhold payment of their subscriptions
                        and thus the whole scheme be thwarted for years to come. If such should be
                        the case our advancing prosperity will be severely set back. This whole
                        generation will pass away before the $4,000,000 will be raised by voluntary
                        subscription for the Valley Railroad "so-called," before the Central
                        Railroad can be induced or able to build its "short track" to Richmond.--
                        And we must for a life-time be content to be at the mercy of a single track
                        worm-fence line of railroad around by Gordonsville, and pay taxes annually
                        on 31 miles of unnecessary road.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Because the law requires a three-fifths vote in favor of the subscription
                    to the Railroad, Augusta county will not subscribe, even though the majority
                    vote was cast in favor of the subscription. The Spectator views this as a missed
                    opportunity.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Radical Prospects North and South</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The correspondent at Washington of the New York <emph rend="italic"
                        >Herald</emph>, writing to that paper under-date August 23, says:</p>
                    <p>All the advices received here recently from the South represent carpet-bagism
                        as on its death bed. With the exception of Florida and South Carolina all
                        the Southern States are conceded as certain to go for Seymour and Blair. The
                        Radical organization in the reconstructed regions are dwindling away
                        rapidly, and defection has reached their very strong hold with such alarming
                        results that the carpet-bag heroes see nothing but ruin ahead. They have
                        discovered their great weakness in the very spot where they looked for an
                        impregnable tower of strength. The negroes whom they relied upon as their
                        right arm of power have become disgusted and proclaim that the white Radical
                        is a greater enemy to them than the white rebels who were lately their
                        masters. The most intelligent blacks, therefore, have determined to join
                        hands with their old masters and thus drive away the carpet bag adventurers
                        from the South to their native element. This repudiation of Radicalism by
                        the colored citizens is overwhelming the Republican leaders of the South,
                        and consequently they are beginning to realize that they have been caught in
                        their own trap. Several shrewd Republicans who have just returned from
                        different parts of the South admit that Sambo has turned the tables upon
                        them completely, and that now their only hope of success is in the North.
                        This last hope seems not to have a very firm hold of them either, judging by
                        the manner in which they write to their friends in this city. The
                        correspondence sent here from different States in the East and West by
                        Radical stumpers and managers is of the most desponding character. They
                        admit that Pennsylvania, Indiana, and Ohio are lost to Grant and Colfax
                        beyond redemption, and one of them declares that Illinois will go the same
                        way unless the strongest efforts are made to save it. Logan's defeat as
                        Congressman at large from the State is spoken of as certain, but the
                        electoral ticket it is urged, may be carried by clever engineering. The most
                        sanguine Republican I have seen here from Colfax's State only figures up a
                        Republican majority of three thousand in Indiana. In fact the impression is
                        very general here now that Seymour and Blair will be elected by a very
                        decisive majority, not on account of any great popularity of their own, but
                        because the people of the country are determined to have a change
                    anyhow.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Quoting from a correspondent of the New York Herald, the editors predict
                    that the Republicans will lose the upcoming election, and will lose not only in
                    the Southern States, but in several Northern States as well.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>The Pattern City of Radicalism</head>
                <origin>New York World</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article asserts that Republican rule which includes African-Americans
                    has left the city of Washington, D. C. bankrupt.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>The Colored Democracy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports and applauds the formation of African-American Democratic
                    clubs in North Carolina.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1868.09.01.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Pic Nic</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Sunday School of the M. E. Church South will hold a picnic for its
                    members.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Memorial Dinner</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Memorial Committee will hold a dinner on Monday the 28th. Ladies are
                    requested to send their contribution lists so all can know what to expect.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Official vote of Augusta, Aug. 27th, 1868, on the proposition for the county
                        to subscribe to $300,000 to the 8 per cent preferred stock of the Chesapeake
                        and Ohio Railroad Company:</p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>
                                <emph rend="italic">For</emph>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <emph rend="italic">Against</emph>
                            </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Court House,</cell>
                            <cell>536</cell>
                            <cell>26</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Union Hall,</cell>
                            <cell>83</cell>
                            <cell>24</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Middlebrook,</cell>
                            <cell>32</cell>
                            <cell>43</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Craigsville,</cell>
                            <cell>97</cell>
                            <cell>23</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Swoope's,</cell>
                            <cell>35</cell>
                            <cell>10</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Newpost,</cell>
                            <cell>5</cell>
                            <cell>42</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Greenville,</cell>
                            <cell>66</cell>
                            <cell>90</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Stuart's Draft,</cell>
                            <cell>No poll opened.</cell>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Midway,</cell>
                            <cell>00</cell>
                            <cell>19</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Waynesboro,</cell>
                            <cell>143</cell>
                            <cell>137</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Fishersville,</cell>
                            <cell>46</cell>
                            <cell>20</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Sherando,</cell>
                            <cell>8</cell>
                            <cell>30</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>New Hope,</cell>
                            <cell>9</cell>
                            <cell>165</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Mt. Meridian,</cell>
                            <cell>6</cell>
                            <cell>53</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Mt. Sidney,</cell>
                            <cell>23</cell>
                            <cell>184</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Spring Hill,</cell>
                            <cell>47</cell>
                            <cell>46</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Mt. Solon,</cell>
                            <cell>26</cell>
                            <cell>121</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Parnassus,</cell>
                            <cell>21</cell>
                            <cell>2</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Churchville,</cell>
                            <cell>22</cell>
                            <cell>34</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Deerfield,</cell>
                            <cell>10</cell>
                            <cell>00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Sherando,</cell>
                            <cell>00</cell>
                            <cell>00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>--</cell>
                            <cell>--</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Total</cell>
                            <cell>1205</cell>
                            <cell>1077</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A report of the official vote of Augusta county on the proposed Railway
                    subscription.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Augusta County Fair</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bayley</ln>
                        <fn>Ed. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hotchkiss</ln>
                        <fn>Jed</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announcement of some guidelines for the fair. In order to encourage
                    participation, county entries will win at least one prize in every category.
                    Useful items will receive recognition even if they do not fall into any of the
                    prepared prize categories, and railroads will lower rates. Speakers, music, and
                    sports will round out the entertainment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Daugaerty</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wiseman</ln>
                        <fn>Mary C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shreckhise</ln>
                        <fn>James M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William H. Daugaerty and Miss Mary C. Wiseman, both of Augusta, were
                    married on August 27th by the Rev. James M. Shreckhise.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heflin</ln>
                        <fn>Bettie A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heflin</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heflin</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bare</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Bettie A. Heflin, daughter of John M. and Mary E. Heflin, died at the
                    Staunton residence of Henry Bare. She was 12 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heizer</ln>
                        <fn>James H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James H. Heizer died of cancer at the residence of his father in Greenville
                    on August 9th. He was 23 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brownlee</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Brownlee died of dropsy of the heart near Greenville on August 9th.
                    He was 30 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Engle</ln>
                        <fn>Carrie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Engle</ln>
                        <fn>J. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Engle</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Carrie Engle, infant daughter of the Rev. J. J. and Mary Engle of New Hope,
                    died on August 2nd.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1868.09.01.04" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Radicals Distrusting the Negroes</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article gloats that Republicans have been taking pains to keep
                    African-Americans away from Democratic meetings. They wish to only expose them
                    to Republican views, but their actions suggest they may be receptive to other
                    arguments.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
