<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1868/va.au.ss.1868.07.14">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/26/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1868-07-14">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day norm="">14</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1868.07.14.01" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>National Democratic Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Report of the proceedings of the second day of the Democratic National
                    Convention in New York.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1868.07.14.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Democratic Conservative Ticket</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On Thursday last, the great National Democratic and Conservative Convention
                        in New York City, nominated <emph rend="italic">unanimously</emph> the above
                        ticket for the support of all who prefer liberty to tyranny, prosperity to
                        ruin, honor to disgrace. Better nominations could not have been made. Hon.
                        Horatio Seymour is one of the ablest statesman in the United States, and his
                        character for honesty, integrity, and devoted patriotism is as distinguished
                        as his unquestioned abilities. He has been twice elected Governor of the
                        Empire State -- in 1852, and in 1862. He is about 57 years of age. The <emph
                            rend="italic">National Intelligencer</emph> says that, "as chief
                        magistrate of the State of New York, he made himself everywhere known as a
                        public man of commanding ability, enlarged comprehension, and practical
                        capacity. And since retiring from a sphere which he honored so much, there
                        is no single individual in the nation whose counsel has been more generally
                        sought, or whose wisdom has been more universally accepted."</p>
                    <p>The same journal says: "Gov. Seymour is too well known to the whole country
                        to need any eulogy or explanation of his public career. It is no
                        disparagement to others, in whatever category they may stand, to say that he
                        ranks <emph rend="italic">among the very foremost of our living
                        statesman."</emph> Seymour being nominated for President, Gen. Francis P.
                        Blair, jr. of Missouri was, of all others, the very person who should be
                        nominated for Vice President, and he was, accordingly, <emph rend="italic"
                            >unanimously</emph> nominated on the <emph rend="italic">first</emph>
                        ballot for Vice President. He is a son of F. P. Blair, senr., the able
                        editor of the "<emph rend="italic">Globe</emph>," and the particular friend
                        of "Old Hickory." Gen. Blair occupies the true position, to wit: That all
                        the unconstitutional legislation of the Radical Congress should be treated
                        by the Executive of this nation as null and void and of no effect. He is a
                        man of strong will, determined purpose, and intrepid, unflinching courage.
                        He will not suffer the Radicals to cheat him out of an election if he wins
                        it fairly. The times demand the services of such men.</p>
                    <p>The ticket combines outstanding talents with distinguished courage, and
                        should be cordially supported by every lover of liberty. We not only cherish
                        the earnest hope, but entertain the honest belief that it will be fairly
                        elected in November next. Our people should be of good cheer. "There's a
                        good time coming." Victory will perch on our banners in November, and with
                        the sere leaves of that autumn month will fall the blasted hopes of the
                        Radical party.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports the unanimous nomination of former N.Y. Governor Horatio Seymour as
                    the Democratic candidate for President, and the nomination of Gen. Francis P.
                    Blair as the candidate for Vice President.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Democratic Platform</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In another column will be found the platform in full, adopted at the recent
                        National Democratic Convention in New York City. With the <emph
                            rend="italic">National Intelligencer</emph>, we think that it is worthy
                        of the occasion of the Convention, and of the great cause which it
                        represents. There is no equivocation, subterfuge, or evasion in any
                        declaration. Every principle is set forth boldly, clearly, and emphatically,
                        so that he who runs may read. Instead of the ambiguities adopted at Chicago
                        to cover up doubtful purposes, or to conceal a mongrel policy, this platform
                        confronts each issue distinctly, deals with it broadly, and leaves no doubt
                        to combat by the employment of artful phrases.</p>
                    <p>The abuses, frauds, usurpations, and corruptions of Radicalism are exposed
                        with a candor and courage which the emergency demanded, and the remedies
                        proposed are announced in language equally emphatic and satisfactory. --
                        What the platform demands is absolute and unqualified reform in the
                        Government as the only means of preserving our institutions. We seek to
                        restore the country to its former position of peace and prosperity, to
                        revive the Constitution in all its vigor, and to set up again the
                        time-honored landmarks which radicalism had torn down. All these objects,
                        and others of material interest, are included under the general idea of a
                        thorough and efficient reform in the Government, which shall sweep away
                        every vestige of that factious domination that has brought us to the very
                        verge of national bankruptcy, and made imminent another civil war.</p>
                    <p>The platform requires no explanation or commentary. It speaks its own praise
                        in the national creed which is laid down, and which, we venture to say, will
                        enlist the sympathy and active support of a vast majority of the American
                        people. It will carry cheer to thousands of hearts, and rouse a feeling such
                        as has not been witnessed for a quarter of a century. The nominees of the
                        Convention will be elected upon the platform. The fiat has gone forth. It is
                        not a question of party, but of patriotism. -- Hundreds of thousands of old
                        Whigs and moderate Republicans, who stood by their political organization
                        while it was possible to adhere to it, have renounced all connection with
                        Radicalism, and will go forward as zealous supporters of this noble cause.</p>
                    <p>Every word of the platform deserves to be treasured up, and we cannot too
                        strongly commend it to earnest reflection.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Praises the platform adopted by the National Democratic Convention. The
                    platform calls for reform of government and a restoration of lost constitutional
                    liberties.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Election in Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We invoke the voters of this State to vigilance. They should hold themselves
                        in readiness, and should see that every man is registered before the
                        election. The Radicals are proposing to take "snap-judgment" upon them. Be
                        ready. When the time comes for action the cry should be: "Up guards and at
                        them."</p>
                    <p>A bill has passed the lower house of Congress ordering the elections in this
                        State on the Constitution and for State officers, Legislature, and Congress,
                        on the 13th, 14th, and 15th of August. The bill will no doubt pass the
                        Senate, and Old Virginia will, in her turn, run the gauntlet prepared for
                        her by the Washington savages! Let us stand by the State like men, and prove
                        our loyalty and devotion, and our determination to save her from degradation
                        and ruin. Go to work men, and never rest until it is done.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Another article exhorting Virginians to prepare for the vote on the
                    ratification of the state Constitution. A bill within the Virginia Congress, if
                    passed, will place the vote on the 13th, 14th, and 15th of August.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Imperative Duty</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper calls registering and voting against the proposed state
                    constitution an "imperative duty." "The ratification of the scallawag
                    constitution would be the 'direful spring of woes unnumbered' to Virginians and
                    their posterity."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>National Democratic Platform</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper prints the platform of the Democratic Party, which includes:
                    restoration of all states to the union, amnesty for southern citizens, payment
                    of the public debt, equal taxation of property including bonds according to real
                    value, one currency for all classes, economy in government through reduction of
                    the army and cessation of the freedmen's bureau, abolishment of corruption in
                    government, assertion of American nationality in foreign affairs, denunciation
                    of the reconstruction acts, aid to veterans, and wide distribution of the public
                    lands.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1868.07.14.03" exists="no">
            <div type="l">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Allow a brief space, if you please, for a few lines which we would herewith
                        address to the PRAYING CHRISTIANS! of our town:</p>
                    <p>Where are you upon Sabbath evenings, when the town clock strikes five? The
                        leader of the union prayer meting is not cheered by your presence! Any who
                        may feel the need of prayer, whether young or old, do not see you when they
                        then go up "to the house of the Lord." Ah! Have we forgotten how gracious
                        God has been to us -- what an outpouring of the spirit there was some months
                        back? And shall those who were <emph rend="italic">then</emph> blessed
                        ceased to pray that greater blessings may be poured out upon this community
                        -- that others, too, may receive a blessing! And when we meet ought we not
                        to concentrate our prayers? If the leader would request especial prayer for
                        the old -- for the young ladies -- for the young men -- for the ministers --
                        for the lawyers, and other professional men -- for the merchants -- and for
                        all other callings; and last, but not least, for special blessings upon the
                        efforts of the Bible Society so recently inaugurated, and which has started
                        two colporteurs to labor among the destitute of this large county, would not
                        our heavenly Father answer these special requests?</p>
                    <p>In conclusion, Christian brethren, let not the sun's rays be warmer than your
                        love of Zion and of God, but come up to the help of the Lord against the
                        night.</p>
                    <p>Staunton. July, 1868.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A letter to the editor calling for increased participation at the "union
                    prayer meeting."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>A Blow at Ambitious Scallawags</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In the South the scallawags and carpet-baggers say by their actions, and
                        words, too -- "Come forward, Sambo, and give me your vote; but don't <emph
                            rend="italic">ruin the country by trying to go to Congress</emph>."</p>
                    <p>This is the scallawag platform. In every State in the South where elections
                        have been held this has been the sublime announcement of principle. "Don't
                        ruin the country by aspiring to Congress, don't destroy the hopes of your
                        race by aspiring to $5,000 per session."</p>
                    <p>This is the universal argument, and we know of only one darkie who has the
                        pluck to stand against it. Thus far the scallawags and carpet-baggers have
                        owned the negroes, and ruled them out without remorse from places of honor
                        or comfort.</p>
                    <p>But it may comfort aspirants to know that the Radicals of the North look down
                        on the scallawags and carpet-baggers just as the scallawags and
                        carpet-baggers do to the negroes.-- We have evidence of this in a bill just
                        reported to the Senate by Senator Patterson, of New Hampshire, intended to
                        insure greater efficiency in the diplomatic service of the United States.
                        This bill provides that "hereafter no appropriation shall be made for the
                        salary of any diplomatic or consular officer, nor shall any such officer be
                        allowed compensation for official fees, unless, prior to his nomination by
                        the President and confirmation by the Senate, he shall be found competent to
                        perform the duties of the office to which he may have been appointed."</p>
                    <p>The plain English of this is, Mr. Patterson and his party see that scallawags
                        and carpet-baggers will imitate San Salvador Holden and apply for places
                        abroad. The passage of this bill will defeat their ambition; for what
                        scallawag or carpet-bagger could pass an examination -- especially if he was
                        asked a few questions as to what constitutes decent behavior!</p>
                    <p>It may console Sambo to know that this "white trash" is looked down upon in
                        Washington by the masters who own them. -- <emph rend="italic">Norfolk
                            Virginian.</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article from the Norfolk Virginian claiming that white Radicals throughout
                    the South have been successful in persuading their Freedmen supporters not to
                    run for office. However, Northern Radicals and Southern whites look down on
                    these scallawags, and are passing legislation to keep them out of diplomatic
                    offices.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1868.07.14.04" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Amnesty Proclamation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Full text of Andrew Johnson's proclamation of amnesty.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
