<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1868/va.au.ss.1868.04.21">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/19/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1868-04-21">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day norm="">21</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1868.04.21.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1868.04.21.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Canvass--Short, Sharp, Decisive</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The canvass upon which we are now about entering will be short--let it also
                        be sharp, energetic, and decisive. There will be but few weeks in which to
                        work, but few as they are, they are pregnant with the fate of Virginia and
                        the liberties of Virginians. The Virgininan who shall fail to do his duty
                        from now to the day of election, and especially on the <emph rend="italic"
                            >day of election</emph>, is unworthy to be the sone of the State which
                        gave him birth.</p>
                    <p>His mother, Virginia, should curse him as Eve cursed Cain, and drive him from
                        her presence with the malediction:</p>
                    <p>"May the grass wither from thy feet! the woods</p>
                    <p>Deny thee shelter! earth a home! the dust</p>
                    <p>A grave! the sun his light! heave her God.</p>
                    <p>This is no time for mincing words and hesitating action, but for plain
                        language and honest, bold, manly conduct. To hesitate is to be lost, to
                        doubt is to be damned. Those who fail in their duty now are traitors not
                        only to liberty but to their race--they are unfit to die and should live in
                        the agonies that other men die with. No decent man should speak to them, nor
                        should any notice them save by pointing the finger of scorn at them. The
                        time for plain language and honest conduct has arrived. Our canvassers
                        should be on the hustings--their voices should be ringing clear and loud. It
                        is not the soft tones of the lute, but the clarion notes of the bugle that
                        we now need. Let the bugles be sounded, and the conservatives rallied to the
                        rescue of all that freemen, and Virignians especially, hold dear. If any
                        dastards fail to respond, or hesitate to take position in alignment, let the
                        brand be put upon them.</p>
                    <p>Next Monday will be court-day in this county. Several speeches from our
                        number of eloquent speakers should be made in the court-house on that day.
                        Stuart and Baldwin and others should speak. It is not too soon to begin.
                        Col. Baldwin opened the canvass in Rockbridge last week in good style. Let
                        him do the same here on next Monday. The people must be aroused. They are
                        apathetic, and some, like the terrapin, need to have fire put upon their
                        back to make them move. Now is the time for the "thoughts that breathe, and
                        the words that <emph rend="italic">burn</emph>." Let no one be able to plead
                        the excuse that he did not know his duty. Let all be informed in time, so
                        that if any fail in the performance of duty it will be not from the want of
                        knowledge but from the want of will, and the judgment, "ye knew your duty,
                        but ye did it not," will be pronounced against them.</p>
                    <p>Those who shall fail to do their duty at this time will live to pray for the
                        rocks and the mountains to fall upon them. As we used to say, "<emph
                            rend="italic">register and vote, and vote against the
                        Convention</emph>," so we now say, "<emph rend="italic">register and vote,
                            and vote against the Constitution</emph>"--that concentrated
                        quintessence of diabolical iniquity.--Live to cast that vote, and cast that
                        vote that you may live freemen.</p>
                    <p>P.S.--Since the above was written, we have been authorized to state that Col.
                        Baldwin will address the people at the Court-House, on Monday next on the
                        dangers and duties of the hour. Come one, come all. Other speeches will
                        probably be delivered.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Called on all Virginians to get out and prepare to campaign and vote
                    against the proposed constitution. The editor said that anyone who failed to
                    vote did not deserve to be called a true Virginian.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Good News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echols</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf>jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>Bolivar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper breathes a sigh of relief at the adjournment of the "mongrel"
                    convention. A Radical Convention will be held on May 4th to nominate candidates
                    for state office and congress. The Conservative State Executive Committee will
                    meet on May 7th for the same purpose. The vote on the constitution will be held
                    on June 2nd. A number of prominent citizens of Augusta were appointed
                    Conservative canvassers for the 6th Congressional District.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Frederick S. Tukey</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We learn from a correspondent of the Richmond <emph rend="italic"
                        >Dispatch</emph> that, at a Radical meeting of negroes and carpet-baggers at
                        the Court-house in Caroline county, on the 13th inst., "Fred. S. Tukey and a
                        vile mulatto named Crockett" were nominated as candidates for the
                        Legislature to represent the county of Caroline. As Old Will Boniface would
                        say, Fred. S. Tukey "is pretty well known in these parts, as the saying
                        is."--He spent some time here in connection with the Freedmen's Bureau, and
                        whilst here claimed to be quite conservative. He illustrated his idea of
                        conservatism (?) by becoming the candidate of the Loyal League for the
                        Convention for the District composed of the counties of Augusta, Albemarle
                        and Louisa. As there are more negroes in Caroline than Augusta his chances
                        for election to office are more promising than when he lived here.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Incensed that a former conservative white man, Fred Tukey, accepted a
                    nomination from a Republican convention in Caroline county to run for the
                    legislature alongside a black man.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Prepare for Action</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In a few days, says the Lynchburg <emph rend="italic">Republican</emph>, the
                        battle on the negro constitution will open in Virginia, and the moment has
                        now come for every white man who is worthy of his race or color to buckle
                        his armor on and prepare for the conflict. There is no time for delay, no
                        room for hesitancy, no time for faltering. The white people of Virginia can
                        defeat the Constitution by thirty thousand majority, and they must do it.
                        Every man who has not registered must register when the books are again
                        opened, as they will be in a few weeks; every man who can work must work;
                        every one who has influence must exert it; and every one who has a vote must
                        give it whether sick or well. Many did not vote in the last fall election
                        for delegates to the Convention for some cause or other; but any who refuse
                        to vote in the coming struggle for self preservation, will incur the merited
                        indignation and lasting dishonor of the men and women of the present and
                        future generations. Virginia and her people must be saved from negro rule at
                        all hazards and the white people who do not help to save her are enemies of
                        their race and color, and will be so treated. Radical speakers, whether
                        black or white, must be met on the stump, and boldly and successfully
                        combatted and overwhelmed in argument. They had the whole field to
                        themselves before, and propagated their falsehoods without limit.--They must
                        not be permitted to do so again, and thus impose upon negro credulity. Let
                        every speaker, therefore, put on his armor and prepare for the conflict
                        which will open in a few days.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Sounded a call to all white men to work to defeat the "negro constitution",
                    as the editor called it. Claimed anyone who refused was a traitor to his race
                    and state.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Be on your Guard</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Our readers may rest assured that every possible device will be adopted to
                        prevent the whites from defeating the iniquitous Constitution which will be
                        submitted to the voters of this State by the Mongrel COnvention. The whites
                        should be upon the <emph rend="italic">qui vive</emph>, and should remember
                        that "eternal vigilance is the price of liberty." Every white voter should
                        be impressed with the fact that no sacrifice of time is too great to be made
                        to defeat that Constitution.--None should fail to vote, however distant the
                        place of voting, or however bad the weather may be. The <emph rend="italic"
                            >Dispatch</emph> says that it has the best authority for stating that
                        the registration lists, which, as our readers are aware, the law requries to
                        be re-opened fourteen days previous to every election, <emph rend="italic"
                            >will be opened only at the various County-seats or Court-houses</emph>.
                        This is an unfortunate decision for the white voters, large numbers of whom
                        neglected to register their names last fall. They must, however, make the
                        necessary sacrifice of time and money, and have their names registered. This
                        is an important matter, and should be remembered by the leaders of the
                        Conservative party in the several counties.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Demanded that every qualified white voter make whatever sacrifices
                    necessary to register and vote down the proposed state constitution.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Attempt to Bribe</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper again denounces the $2,500 exemption clause in the new
                    constitution as a trick to entice the voters of Virginia to ratify a radical
                    document. "People of Virginia! can you stand this? Are you going to be kicked by
                    negroes, and then take sixpence to heal the sore?"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1868.04.21.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that a car load of African-American convicts passed
                    through Staunton on their way to work on the turnpike between Covington and
                    Healing Springs.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Colonel Baldwin will speak at the Court House on the "duties and dangers of
                    the hour." The paper urges people to attend.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The ladies of Staunton's Trinity Episcopal Church raised $600 at their
                    fair. The money will go toward erecting an iron railing around the church yard.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Those who attended the concert at Staunton's Baptist Church enjoyed the
                    music very much. The event raised $100.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harlan</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blanton</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Connell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Staunton jailor George Harlan recently discovered that the imprisoned horse
                    thieves Blanton, Harris, and Connell nearly escaped by sawing out the steel
                    window frames.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Robbery-Nearly Murder</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Henry Miller was knocked in the head and robbed near Deerfield, Augusta
                    County. "A negro man who had a stout cane was with him a short time before the
                    occurrence and was upon the spot shortly after. Suspicion very naturally
                    attaches to him."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Industrial Enterprise</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seawright</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>An 8 foot, 2000lb wheel for the mill of George Seawright was cast at
                    William A. Burke's Foundry. The paper hails Burke as an "avant courier" of
                    expected industrial innovation in and around Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>R. R. Election in Staunton</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On Saturday last, the vote of Staunton was taken on the question of
                        subscribing the town's proportion of the proposed subscription of $300,000
                        by Augusta County to the 8 per cent preferred stock of the Chesapeake and
                        Ohio Railroad. The election resulted as follows:</p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>For</cell>
                            <cell>Against</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Whites</cell>
                            <cell>254</cell>
                            <cell>32</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Colored</cell>
                            <cell>59</cell>
                            <cell>1</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <p>Majority of whites 222. Majority of colored 58--combined majority 280 Whole
                        vote cast, including the 60 unconstitutional votes of the colored voters,
                        346.</p>
                    <p>Should the subscription for the county, like that for the town, be carried by
                        the required majority of the legal tax-paying voters, it would be a
                        consummation greatly desired, but if it should be carried by the votes of
                        those who not only pay no taxes, but have <emph rend="italic">no legal right
                            to vote</emph>, it would be an outrage upon every principle of right and
                        justice. The recognition as valid of such a decision at the ballot-box by
                        our people would be a surrender of the great principle at issue between the
                        Radicals and the Conservatives. It would be the most emphatic recognition of
                        negro suffrage which could be exhibited. If Conservatives recognise the
                        validity of negro suffrage they are estopped from complaining of the
                        Radicals for doing the same thing. Our anxiety for the Railroad should not
                        be allowed to betray us into the commission of a fatal blunder.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reported on the vote in favor of subscribing stock in the Chesapeake and
                    Ohio Railroad. Despite the favorable vote, insisted the vote be voided because
                    otherwise it would implicitly recognize the right of blacks to vote in the
                    state, something the editor considered "unconstitutional".</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Staunton Lyceum</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Latane</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>Marshall</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pierce</ln>
                        <fn>A. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>English</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ryan</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>James H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Staunton Lyceum debated whether the signs of the times forcast the
                    approach of the millennial era. The question was decided in the negative.
                    Members were chosen to debate the groups' next question.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Chesapeake and Ohio Rail Road</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">To the Citizens of Augusta County:</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>A tax of $2,750 per annum, will pay in 28 years the whole principal of the
                        bonds which will be given at 90 cents on the dollar to meet the subscription
                        of $250,000, which you are asked to make.</p>
                    <p>It has been demonstrated to you in a former address that the passenger fare
                        and freights, (taking the business of 1867 from the Books of the Company)
                        which will be saved by shortening the Road, will be more than the average
                        interest to be paid on the Bonds. Assuming this to be correct, and it is so
                        beyond any reasonable doubt, then the 8 per cent Guaranteed Dividends on the
                        stock will be a clear gain to reduce the taxes of the county; or the
                        Dividends may be used to pay the interest after the road is finished, and
                        then the saving from the short track will be a clear gain.</p>
                    <p>Putting out of view the saving to result from getting rid of the circuitous
                        route by Gordonsville--I now propose to show you that the trifling sum of
                        $2,750 per annum raised by taxes, put to interest at 8 per centum per annum,
                        and reinvested annually, will in 28 years raise the whole sum of $275,000,
                        for which the bonds of the county will be given. I will not go through the
                        whole calculation, but will give you a brief illustration to show how
                        rapidly any given sum increases at compound interest:</p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Tax 1st year</cell>
                            <cell>$2,750</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Interest</cell>
                            <cell>220</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>2,970</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Tax 2nd year</cell>
                            <cell>2,750</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>5,720</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Interest</cell>
                            <cell>457.60</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>6,177.60</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Tax 3rd year</cell>
                            <cell>2,750.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>8,927.60</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Interest</cell>
                            <cell>714.21</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>9,641.81</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Tax 4th year</cell>
                            <cell>2,750.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>12,391.81</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Interest</cell>
                            <cell>991.34</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>13,383.15</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Tax 5th year</cell>
                            <cell>2,750.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>16,133.15</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Interest</cell>
                            <cell>1,290.65</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>17,423.80</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Tax 6th year</cell>
                            <cell>2,750.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>20,173.80</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Interest</cell>
                            <cell>1,613.90</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>21,787.70</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <p>It thus appears that $2,750, paid annually and put to interest at 8 per cent,
                        will in six years amount to $21,787.70 and if continued for 28 years the
                        whole $275,000 of bonds will be paid off with only a tax of $2,750, per
                        annum.</p>
                    <p>Is there a man in Augusta who is not willing to pay his share of the trifling
                        sum of $2,750 to accomplish so great a work as the Chesapeake and Ohio
                        Railroad. Remember you are furnished nearly 10 times the amount of this tax,
                        in the saving from the short track between Charlottesville and Richmond; but
                        if there was no such saving the benefits you will derive in many other ways,
                        from making the road, would far more than compensate you.</p>
                    <p>Your Court can issue their bonds payable in 30 years, appoint a Board of
                        Sinking Fund Commissioners, and before the bonds become due, you may have in
                        hand every dollar to meet the principal of the bonds at maturity.</p>
                    <p>I cannot believe if the people of Augusta understood this question they would
                        hesitate to vote for the proposed subscription. A consideration of the
                        foregoing view of the subject, shows that there is nothing in the
                        apprehended taxation to alarm them.</p>
                    <p>Respectfully. E. FONTAINE</p>
                    <p>Presd't. Va. C.R.R. Co.</p>
                    <p>Richmond, April 16th, 1868.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The president of the Virginia County R.R. Company gave a detailed argument
                    for why adopting a small tax to pay for the Chesapeake and Ohio R.R.
                    subscription would result in great benefits in the long run. He also printed
                    stats to back up his argument.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Col. Baldwin's Address</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In accordance with the announcement in our paper of last week, Col. Baldwin
                        addressed the people of Rockbridge, in the Court-house, on Monday last. The
                        house was crowded with a most intelligent audience, and the gallery was
                        filled with freedmen who listened respectfully and attentively to the able
                        and eloquent speaker, as he glowingly depicted the present deplorable state
                        of affairs in our country. To all who have had the pleasure of hearing Col.
                        B. on former occasions, we need not say that a more forcible presentation of
                        the wrongs and outrages which the Southern people have suffered, and are
                        still suffering at the hands of the Radicals, could not have been made, and
                        his stirring appeal to all who have not yet done so, to come forward and
                        register and vote against the New Constitution, we deeply regret was not
                        heard by every white voter in the county. We know that every one who heard
                        it will feel his heart stirred with a new and a holier zeal, in doing all
                        that he can, to preserve himself, his children and his brethren of the old
                        Mother Commonwealth, from the degradation and disgrace of Radical domination
                        through the ascendancy of the negroes. We think that great good will result
                        from this address to the Conservative cause, and that its influence will be
                        seen and felt in every section of the county. We regret that we have not a
                        full report of the speech, that we might publish it, so that every one in
                        the county could read and digest it for himself. A synopsis of it would do
                        injustice both to the speaker and his subject, but it has furnished us with
                        texts which we hope to use hereafter in our efforts to awaken the people to
                        a full sense of their danger and their duty.--<emph rend="italic">Lexington
                            Gazette &amp; Banner</emph>.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Highly praised a recent speech by Col. Baldwin condemning Republican rule
                    in Virginia and urging all Virginians to vote down the new constitution. Editor
                    remarked that even many "freedmen" attended to hear the speech.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Childress</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Marion</ln>
                        <fn>E. Mildred</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stringer</ln>
                        <fn>W. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Childress and Miss E. Mildred Marion were married near Fishersville
                    on April 9th by the Rev. W. R. Stringer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Drake</ln>
                        <fn>D. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Slaughter</ln>
                        <fn>Kate Murat</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>D. W. Drake of Staunton and Miss Kate Murat Slaughter of Rappahannock
                    County were married on April 15th at the Episcopal Church in Little Washington
                    by the Rev. Mr. Brown.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gibbons</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Elizabeth Gibbons died at the residence of Samuel Paul. She was 75
                    years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1868.04.21.04" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>K. K. K.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Mr. "Meshach Horner" thus describes the K.K.Ks as he saw them in the middle
                        of the night in Abingdon, Washington county, Va., a few weeks since:</p>
                    <p>"On lookin down from the winder, the fust thing I saw was a great big black
                        flag, with a white skull and two cross-bones painted on it. Lookin a leetel
                        lower, seed a great company of black hosses marchin along silently two and
                        two, and on each hoss was a pale lookin rider dressed in a long white robe,
                        and each held in his boney fingers a bright two-edged sword, with drops of
                        blood sprinkled about on 'em.--As I was lookin strate down on 'em, a great
                        big skeleton lookin feller as big as the giant David killed, raised his
                        blood-shot eyes rite in my face, and puttin his finger on his lips, he ses
                        in a whisperin tone, "these silent riders are the Ku-Klux-Klan, and I'm the
                        head giant." "What if you are," ses I, "you haven't got nothin to do with
                        me." "That depends on whether we have or not," ses he. "If you're a true
                        man, honest in your dealins, just in your politicks, in favor of your own
                        race, above hunnyfuggling with niggers, divide your bred and meat with the
                        widders and orfants of soldiers, and aint for makin niggers better than
                        white people and givin 'm land that don't belong to you, you're not the
                        sorter man we're after; but, if you're a Radical or a nigger--and one is
                        about as good as tother, and better too--you'd better keep your eye skinned,
                        or we'll have you, and then you may call upon the Lord to have mercy on your
                        soul."</p>
                    <p>"Well," ses I, "I've heard a heap over in Bear Cove about these Ku Klux
                        Klans, but I never seed enny before--will you tell me who you are and where
                        you come from?"</p>
                    <p>"Yes," ses he, "we have no secrets on that pint. We are the sperrets of the
                        Confederate ded, come back to see our livin comrads right-who have jined the
                        niggers agin their own kin and color, and to protect all who are sufferin
                        from the meanness and maliciousness of bad men, both black and white. We
                        started in Tennessee, where we intend to return as soon as we have finished
                        the work we have to do in ed, and to punish the bad white men Virginny."</p>
                    <p>As he finished talkin, they all marched on their horses along the street,
                        makin no more noises than if they had bin walkin on feather beds, and in a
                        few minutes I went to sleep and saw no more of the awful lookin company.</p>
                    <p>Yourn till deth,</p>
                    <p>MESCHACH HORNER.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Printed an account from a black man in Abingdon who recounted his
                    conversation with a squad of KKK men. Related the KKK's mission, which was
                    basically to keep whites superior to blacks and punish anyone who advocated
                    otherwise. The whole account was printed in dialect.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
