<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1868/va.au.ss.1868.05.19">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/21/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1868-05-19">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day norm="">19</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1868.05.19.01" exists="no">
            <div type="l">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pilson</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swink</ln>
                        <fn>Lavelette</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Atkinson</ln>
                        <fn>Alice</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Atkinson</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eskridge</ln>
                        <fn>Bettie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swink</ln>
                        <fn>Calvin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swink</ln>
                        <fn>Milton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The school at Mint Spring held closing exercises with a number of
                    entertaining and educational "dialogues, declamations, charade and etc., which
                    were as well performed as if the persons had been practiced actors." This
                    reflects well on Mr. John Pilson's direction of the school.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>The Conservative Ticket</head>
                <origin>Petersburg Index</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article introduces the men nominated as Conservative candidates for
                    office.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>07</column>
                <head>Church Property</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article alleging that a clause in the new state constitution regarding
                    church property is designed to transfer property owned by the Methodist
                    Episcopal Church South to the Methodist Episcopal Church North.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1868.05.19.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>White Man's Ticket</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper announces the conservative ticket for state offices: Col. Robert
                    E. Withers, for Governor; Gen. James A. Walker for Lieutenant Governor; J. L.
                    Marye, Jr., for Attorney General; and Col. Marmaduke Johnson for Congress for
                    the State at large.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Lexington Outrage</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper denounces "mean, low, dirty white men" for making "incendiary"
                    speeches in favor of the Republicans. An incident in Lexington that resulted in
                    a shooting in which an African American man refused to give way on the sidewalk
                    for a white woman is used as proof of the damage such men cause.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Conservative Candidate for the Presidency</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The question, who is to be the Conservative candidate for the Presidency, is
                        beginning to occupy a large share of public attention. In view of recent
                        events, it has become a question of great political importance, and one, on
                        the wise determination of which the welfare of the country mainly depends.
                        It is now obvious, that if the Conservative party act wisely and
                        patriotically, discarding all mere personal preferences in the selection of
                        a candidate, and looking only to the choice of the man who combines the
                        largest elements of popularity, success must crown their efforts. But if, on
                        the other hand, they fall into contentions and strifes and bickerings, as to
                        who shall be their standard bearer, defeat, and four years more of
                        disastrous misrule, must be the consequences of their folly.</p>
                    <p>The great battle for the Constitution and free institutions is to be fought
                        in the North, and by the people of the North. The South is powerless, and
                        must continue to be so until she is restored to her rights in the Union. It
                        is therefore proper, that the North should have the right to determine who
                        shall be our candidate. They can judge better than the people of the South,
                        who is best calculated to ensure success in the North. The Southern
                        delegates to the Convention, should, therefore, say to their Northern
                        associates, "deliberate calmly, cautiously, and dispassionately -- make your
                        selection of a candidate, and we will cheerfully sustain him."</p>
                    <p>So far as the South is concerned, we wish it to be distinctly understood that
                        we have no preferences and no prejudices, in regard to men -- we will
                        sustain any sound Conservative man, whether he comes from the North, the
                        East, or the West. All we ask is, give us the man who is strong enough to
                        win. We go for success. -- What we desire above all things, is a release
                        from racial domination. The man who can most certainly accomplish that end,
                        is the man of our choice. We go for results -- we care not for the means, or
                        the men who are to achieve them. We will go for Pendleton, Hancock,
                        Doolittle, Seymour, Hendricks, or any other good man. We indulge in no
                        narrow sectional or personal jealousies. We seek to gratify no personal
                        partialities. Victory in the coming contest is our first object.</p>
                    <p>The signs of the times are all auspicious. -- They show that we can be
                        successful if we act wisely. And what a burning shame it would be, if we
                        were to hazard the result by petty squabbles about men! The issues are too
                        important for us to stop and quarrel about the merits of this or that
                        candidate. We should cultivate the broadest and most catholic spirit.
                        Everything for the cause -- nothing for men -- should be our motto. The
                        split in the Democratic party between the friends of Breckinridge and
                        Douglas, brought all the trouble on the country. Let us not repeat that
                        folly. Lincoln was a minority President. The combined votes of Douglass,
                        Breckinridge and Bell, exceeded those cast for Lincoln by nearly a million.
                        The Conservative vote now, if united, will outnumber the radical, by
                        probably more than a million.-- Shall we now by discords in our own ranks
                        allow Grant -- a minority candidate, to be elected? We trust not. When we
                        hear a conservative say, I will not support Pendleton, or Hancock, or
                        Seymour, or any other good man, we are disposed to set him down as a radical
                        ally. It matters not what his motives may be, or how much he may profess to
                        hate radicalism -- he is practically giving aid and comfort to the Radicals
                        and seeking to hold the South in subjection.--When New York men say they
                        will not support Pendleton, or Western men say that they will not sustain
                        Hancock or Seymour, what is it in effect, but saying they go for men and not
                        for principles -- for their favorites and not for the cause.</p>
                    <p>Let us then have no more of these idle declarations. Let us remember that the
                        constitution -- the cause of civil liberty -- the great interests of the
                        country are in peril. Let us remember that our first duty is to our country,
                        and our first obligation is to redeem it from tyranny and misrule. Every
                        feeling of personal partiality must be subordinated to this great end.
                        Redeem the country first, and then consult private inclinations afterwards.</p>
                    <p>We hope the Conservative Convention will come together in a spirit of mutual
                        concession and conciliation--comparing opinions honestly and fairly, with an
                        eye single to success. When victory is accomplished--when the conservative
                        party is established on a firm basis, it will be time enough to consult
                        personal preferences for men, and contend for particular lines of
                        administrative policy. Now, the question is, not how the government is to be
                        administered, but whether we are to have a government which is worth
                        preserving. We must rescue that from ruin, and settle other matters
                        afterwards. We care not what our candidate may think on this or that
                        question -- the great inquiry is, can he win the battle? Has he the capacity
                        to beat the radicals? In other words does he profess what John Randolph
                        called, "the turning out faculty?"</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Claims that the North should select a candidate for the Conservative party
                    capable of winning the election, and that Southerners should support this man,
                    despite their own personal preferences.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1868.05.19.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>County Canvass</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echols</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>Bolivar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Schedule of political addresses by conservative county canvassers to take
                    place in towns throughout the county.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn>Y. Howe</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George Baylor and Maj. Y. Howe Peyton will deliver speeches against the
                    proposed constitution in New Hope and Mt. Meridian.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fry</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fry</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lewis</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. and Mrs. Fry, assisted by Miss Lewis, will give two vocal concerts in
                    the town hall.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Memorial Celebration</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Staunton's Ladies' Memorial Association "will perform the sad and tender
                    duty of decorating the graves of the fallen, heroic dead, whose bones lie
                    mouldering in our midst, with wreaths of roses and the myrtle" on June 13th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>West Augusta Base Ball Club</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baird</ln>
                        <fn>R. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gladke</ln>
                        <fn>Charles A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ackerman</ln>
                        <fn>D. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>A. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scherer</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>E. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The young men of Staunton have organized a base ball club, with R. W. Baird
                    as president. They hope to play "neighboring organizations."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>County Canvass</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Our canvassers are at work with an energy which shows it will not be their
                        fault if the people do not appreciate the vital importance of the crisis.
                        The whole burden of the canvass for the common cause, should not be left to
                        fall upon the appointed "canvassers" alone. There are other gentlemen who
                        should share it with them, who have equal ability, time and means to devote
                        to it. So far Messrs. Peyton and Phillips have rendered efficient aid.</p>
                    <p>Let, too, the superintendents of districts, the chiefs of fifty, and the
                        leaders of ten, co-operate by urging the people to attend the meetings so as
                        to awaken a general interest. When the speakers go to the trouble and
                        expense necessary to get to distant points in the county, they deserve to be
                        welcomed and encouraged by good audiences.</p>
                    <p>The ladies, too, should attend. Heretofore there might have been objection to
                        ladies taking part in politics, because it tended to create controversies
                        and feelings between neighbors, when they were divided between opposing
                        political parties. But now all ladies are on the same side and can work
                        together in mutual sympathy for a cause in which they have the most vital
                        concern. If the ladies appreciate the dangers of the hour to themselves,
                        there will be few men who will dare to be laggards at this election.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phillips</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Praises the efforts of canvassers, particularly Messrs. Peyton and
                    Phillips, and encourages other local Conservative leaders to organize and
                    energize the citizenry, including women.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greaver</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mizer</ln>
                        <fn>Eliza Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bushong</ln>
                        <fn>A. A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George W. Greaver and Miss Eliza Jane Mizer, both of Augusta, were married
                    at the residence of the bride's father on May 7th by the Rev. A. A. J. Bushong.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>William N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Poague</ln>
                        <fn>Mary V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Poague</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowman</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William N. Wilson and Miss Mary V. Poague, daughter of James Poague, both
                    Augusta residents, were married on May 7th by the Rev. Frank Bowman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Berry</ln>
                        <fn>Susan T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Berry</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Susan T. Berry, wife of David Berry, died on May 7th near Waynesboro.
                    She was 49 years old. "The deceased had been for over 20 years a professed
                    Christian and died trusting in the merits of the Savior's blood."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ide</ln>
                        <fn>Estelle Sophie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ide</ln>
                        <fn>E. Louis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ide</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Estelle Sophie Ide, daughter of Prof. E. Louis and Sarah Ide of Staunton,
                    died on May 12th. She was 4 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1868.05.19.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
