<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1868/va.au.ss.1868.06.30">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/26/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1868-06-30">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="06">June</month>
            <day norm="">30</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1868.06.30.01" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>The New Constitution</head>
                <origin>Norfolk Journal</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>NO. VL -- REPRESENTATION AND TAXATION.</p>
                    <p>The representative apportionment of the new constitution not only secures for
                        the negro perpetual ascendancy, but it arms him with a prerogative which
                        should startle the tax payers of the State.</p>
                    <p>It confers upon the negroes the whole vast power of taxation, and the power
                        is irreversible. The white man cannot help himself if he would. With
                        twenty-one negro majority against him, he is as helpless against negro
                        rapacity as the infant against the brawny giant's arm. Whatever burdens the
                        negro chooses to put upon the white men, we are bound to submit to on pain
                        of having our property distrained perhaps by a negro sheriff, armed, it may
                        be, with a <emph rend="italic">posse comitatus</emph> of negro militia.</p>
                    <p>Observe first, that those who are to lay the taxes on the white man's
                        property have little or no property themselves. They can tax the property of
                        the white people <emph rend="italic">ad libitum</emph>, without feeling
                        themselves the burdens they put on the others. They may tax the white man
                        until he groans and writhes under the grievous infliction, and until he
                        trembles lest the wife and the children go half fed and half clothed! -- But
                        what of it? His negro superior and tax master is moved to no sympathy, and
                        surveys the work of his exactions with stoic indifference, because he and
                        his class, having little or no property to have taxes levied on, is not a
                        common sufferer.</p>
                    <p>Now, in all good governments, the security of the tax paying property-holders
                        against undue exactions, is the liability of those who impose the taxes to
                        pay the like taxes themselves. When a representative cannot impose a tax
                        upon his constituents without putting it upon himself also, his tax-paying
                        constituents are safe, never otherwise.</p>
                    <p>But the miserable bungle of the motley ignoramuses that met in Richmond to
                        frame a form of government for the descendants of Virginia statesmen,
                        provides no security whatever for the tax payers. Even the pauper wandering
                        in the streets or tenant of the alms-house, may participate in the laying of
                        taxes on the merchants, the professional man, the holder of stocks, the
                        business man of every sort, and the landholder. Not a solitary intellectual
                        or property qualification is required of the imposer of taxes. He is not
                        required even to have exhibited the common interest in the community of
                        having paid his share of the taxes, and not having paid a dollar of taxes
                        himself, he may, with impunity, put what taxes he pleases on others.</p>
                    <p>Let us see how the thing works in other States where negro ascendancy
                        prevails.</p>
                    <p>The late Constitutional Convention of South Carolina was composed of
                        forty-seven white and seventy-four colored men. The colored delegates paid
                        an aggregate tax of $171, of whom fifty-nine paid no tax at all. Of the
                        whites, more than one-half had no visible estate, but the carpet-bags and
                        contents with which they commenced trade in the Palmetto State.</p>
                    <p>Now these penniless Africans and these penniless white adventurers from afar
                        made a constitution, and of course provided a system of taxation for the
                        once rich owners of the rice fields of South Carolina, and the like classes
                        will prescribe the taxes for them until, by some means or other, negro rule
                        shall be broken.</p>
                    <p>So in Virginia. Unless the people avert negro rule by voting down the
                        constitution, they must submit to be ground down by just what taxation shall
                        be imposed by a totally irresponsible set of negroes and squalid rogues from
                        the North, owning not a dollar beyond the dirty and tarnished wardrobe on
                        their hands.</p>
                    <p>White men of the Old Dominion! you had better look on this thing. You had
                        better discover, before it is to late, what loosed the field in which is
                        <del/>tax payers and tax policemen.</p>
                    <p>An increase of the number of <unclear>renegade</unclear> then, as already
                        shown, will induce a very heavy additional expenditure, depending for the
                        amount, altogether on the will of a penniless negro majority.</p>
                    <p>The new county officers, to use the language of the Conservative address, are
                        a <emph rend="italic">swarm</emph>. We are to have a multitude of officers
                        never before heard of, and never needed in the past economical and quiet
                        days of the old Virginia.</p>
                    <p>We are to have county judges, county treasurers, county superintendents of
                        the poor, county superintendents of schools, township supervisors,
                        commissioners of roads, overseers of the poor, and school trustees, and
                        overseers of roads.</p>
                    <p>The number of these new county officers is no less than sixty in the smallest
                        counties. In the aggregate, they will absolutely blast the several counties
                        by an insupportable taxation, and as unnecessary as insupportable, except to
                        furnish places for the cormorants whose hungered stomachs yearn anxiously
                        for the flesh pots.</p>
                    <p>Then we are to have a free school system, incapable of successful application
                        to a sparse population, and which will cause the property-holders to agonize
                        under the taxation it will inflict.</p>
                    <p>Now bear in mind: first, that the whole taxes to be raised from these
                        multiplied subjects of taxation, will be levied by those who, having no
                        property to bear its share of the public burdens, will have no concern
                        whatever as to the amount to be levied. And then remembering that nearly the
                        entire taxes will be levied and raised on property alone, we shall at once
                        see the infinite mischief and oppression that will befall the white
                        property-holders of the State if the constitution be adopted.</p>
                    <p>That the taxation will be pushed to the extremest point, is perfectly
                        apparent. We have but to see what the negroes and their mean white comrades
                        have already done in this regard, to know what they will do hereafter.--
                        They spun out the session of the convention to the extraordinary length of
                        four months and a half, when four weeks would have been ample -- paid
                        reporters and doorkeepers and pages and clerks extraordinary compensation --
                        and voted into their own pockets eight dollars per day of the hard earnings
                        of an impoverished, almost starving people, thus recklessly squandering the
                        sacred fund dedicated to the payment of the interest on the public debt, and
                        the preservation of the good faith and honor of the State. "Verily by their
                        works shall ye know them."</p>
                    <p>Property-holders of Virginia -- tax payers of Virginia! If you would not be
                        ground to the dust by a merciless, totally selfish, irresponsible taxation,
                        go to the polls, and to a man vote against the constitution!</p>
                    <p>GEORGE MASON.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A letter from "George Mason", predicting that, should the constitution be
                    ratified, the property-less classes that will control Virginia will raise taxes.
                    They will do so not only because they bear no part of the burden of taxation,
                    but also because higher taxes will be required to support the public school
                    system and newly created county offices.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Exhibition and Entertainment at Mt. Solon</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McAlister</ln>
                        <fn>Hattie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cupp</ln>
                        <fn>J. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Busey</ln>
                        <fn>E. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cupp</ln>
                        <fn>Ida</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cupp</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cupp</ln>
                        <fn>Mattie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cupp</ln>
                        <fn>Willie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hopewell</ln>
                        <fn>Fannie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hopewell</ln>
                        <fn>Sallie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huffman</ln>
                        <fn>Mattie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>Emma</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn>Isabella</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>John</ln>
                        <fn>George M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blakemore</ln>
                        <fn>Ben Ami</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn>P. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carson</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hopewell</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A letter signed "Mossy Creek" describes the closing exercises of the
                    private school of Hattie McAlister in the patronage of J. J. Cupp. The
                    celebration consisted of a supper, followed by a concert and tableau.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1868.06.30.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper takes consolation from Mississippi voters' rejection of their
                    proposed constitution. A majority of voters in Mississippi are African-American,
                    and, according to the paper, the results prove that most blacks are prepared to
                    vote with "the Southern Whites who are their best, if not, in fact, their only
                    friends."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Wake Up</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper chides members of Virginia's "White Man's party" for complacency,
                    and urges them to redouble efforts to ensure the defeat of the constitution.
                    "Let us realize the fact that a member of the convention which framed this
                    abominable constitution proclaimed that the white men of Virginia are to 'drink
                    negro rule as high as heaven and as deep as hell.'"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1868.06.30.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Ice Cream--Magnus Cease</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cease</ln>
                        <fn>Magnus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Magnus Cease has ice cream at his shop and served it for free last
                    Wednesday, earning him the praises of the children of Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Concert by the Blind Pupils</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turner</ln>
                        <fn>A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Vast numbers attended a concert by the blind pupils of Staunton's Deaf,
                    Dumb and Blind Institution. Prof. A. J. Turner directed the music.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Virginia Female Institute</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dunnington</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>Marion</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Matthews</ln>
                        <fn>L. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kirk</ln>
                        <fn>Nannie B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Benedict</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>Ellen</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Saunders</ln>
                        <fn>Alice F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kirk</ln>
                        <fn>Belle</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Benedict</ln>
                        <fn>R. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chapman</ln>
                        <fn>Ella J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Upshur</ln>
                        <fn>Sallie P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pendleton</ln>
                        <fn>Sallie B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Preston</ln>
                        <fn>Janie G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Preston</ln>
                        <fn>William Ballard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>Jennie F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Steptoe</ln>
                        <fn>M. Grace</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Archer</ln>
                        <fn>Nannie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phillips</ln>
                        <fn>J. Kate</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamilton</ln>
                        <fn>Emma J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Virginia Female Institute held closing exercises. The young ladies
                    performed vocal and instrumental music including "Scena et Aria" from
                    Freischutz. Hugh W. Sheffey addressed the graduates. Diplomas and medals for
                    academic achievement were awarded.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGinty</ln>
                        <fn>Robert A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>Jinnie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>R. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Robert A. McGinty and Miss Jinnie Jones, both of Augusta, were married by
                    the Rev. R. C. Walker on June 18th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>William F. Hite and Miss Sue E. Wilson, daughter of Dr. Joseph Wilson of
                    Churchville, were married on June 24th by the Rev. R. C. Walker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Hiram</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Elizabeth Myers, wife of Rev. Hiram Myers, died at an advanced age of
                    asthma in Waynesboro on June 17th. "The deceased had been a member of the M. E.
                    Church for upwards of 20 years, and her Christian walk and conversation were
                    such as would command the respect and admiration of all. She had been a sufferer
                    for a long period of years during which time she uttered no complaint, but often
                    spoke of her approaching death as a relief from the trials and afflictions of
                    this life."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1868.06.30.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
