<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1868/va.au.ss.1868.01.14">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/15/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1868-01-14">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day norm="">14</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1868.01.14.01" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Unconstitutional Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Record of the proceedings of Virginia's State Constitutional Convention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1868.01.14.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Conservative County Committee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Col. Baldwin will hold a meeting of the County and District Superintendents
                    at his offices.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article asserting that disarray in the Republican Party has opened
                    political opportunity for the Democrats.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article criticizing the hypocrisy of Hunnicutt, who was once "a violent and
                    proscriptive enemy of the blacks," but who has now become a Radical leader.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article asserts that the Radical Republican "war upon cotton culture"
                    threatens to destroy the South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1868.01.14.03" exists="no">
            <div type="o">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jackson</ln>
                        <fn>Ben</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>J. Wayt</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Ben Jackson, ex-slave of J. Wayt Bell, died in Staunton on December 31st.
                    "He was a faithful servant, a good man, and died with the consolation of
                    religion."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Staunton Lyceum</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>W. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pierce</ln>
                        <fn>A. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fauntleroy</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Powers</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hewitt</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>C. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Staunton Lyceum debated whether or nor there was hope for restoration
                    of the Union. Rev. W. A. Harris, Pierce, and Fauntleroy argued in the
                    affirmative; Powers, Peyton, Hewitt, and C. R. Harris in the negative. The
                    question was decided in the affirmative. The next question for consideration is:
                    "Can divine goodness be proved without the aid of revelation?" Rev. J. L. Clark
                    and Coleman will argue in the affirmative; Dr. Fauntleroy and A. M. Pierce in
                    the negative. Dr. C. R. Harris will lecture before the Lyceum next Monday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Sunday School Society</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Neel</ln>
                        <fn>A. A. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cross</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ross</ln>
                        <fn>William O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hedrick</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fauver</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamrick</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitmer</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Edmunds</ln>
                        <fn>J. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitmore</ln>
                        <fn>J. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Sunday Schools of the Churchville Circuit of the M. E. Church South met
                    in Parnassus. The meeting established the "Valley Sunday School Society."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Death of a Valuable Citizen</head>
                <origin>Register</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Forrer</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Daniel Forrer of Mossy Creek, Augusta County, died in his residence of
                    rheumatism of the heart on January 2nd. He had not been ill long, and was 67
                    years old. "He was a gentleman of great strength of character and determination
                    of will. Whatever he undertook he did with all his energies enlisted. He had
                    been, originally, a very strong and decided Union man; but when the struggle
                    came, and the South was overrun, no man was more firm and determined in his
                    devotion to the cause of his section. He was the friend and patron of education,
                    and his neighborhood will miss his influence which he exerted in favor of this
                    great interest."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gochenour</ln>
                        <fn>Martin J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roadcap</ln>
                        <fn>Virginia C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>R. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Martin J. Gochenour of Augusta and Miss Virginia C. Roadcap of Rockbridge
                    were married on January 9th by the Rev. R. P. Kennedy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>Henry H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Price</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shreckhise</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Henry H. Taylor of Rockbridge and Miss Mary Jane Price of Augusta were
                    married near Newport on January 2nd by the Rev. J. M. Shreckhise.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Jane G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Jane G. Crawford died at her residence near Deerfield on January 1st.
                    She was 73 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn>Lucy J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn>John L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Lucy J. Clarke, wife of Rev. John L. Clarke, pastor of Staunton's
                    Southern Methodist Church, died in the Virginia Hotel after a lingering illness.
                    She was 86 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Poage</ln>
                        <fn>Robert T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Major</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Major Robert T. Poage died on January 11th near Mt. Sidney. "Like most of
                    his county men he was opposed to the war, but when it came upon us he buckled on
                    his armor and fought gallantly--having had two horses killed under him, and was
                    severely wounded at the battle of the Wilderness. The disease of which he
                    died--consumption--was contracted from exposure in the field. He leaves a
                    disconsolate widow and an infant daughter. Peace to his ashes."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1868.01.14.04" exists="no">
            <div type="l">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Letter of Mr. Stuart</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Hon. A. H. H. Stuart, having been invited by a committee to join in a
                        banquet in Washington, on the 8th inst., the anniversary of the battle of
                        New Orleans, thus beautifully and appropriately replied. The letter speaks
                        for itself.</p>
                    <p>Staunton, Va. January 2, 1868.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Gentlemen:</emph>--I pray you to accept my thanks for
                        your kind invitation to attend a banquet to be given at the Metropolitan
                        Hotel, in the city of Washington, on the 8th instant, under the auspices of
                        leading members of the Conservative Democratic Party.</p>
                    <p>Under ordinary circumstances it would be peculiarly gratifying to me to
                        participate in the festivities of that occasion, and to enjoy "the feast of
                        reason and flow of soul" which, I doubt not, will give zest to your
                        entertainment. But situated as I am--disfranchised as a citizen, denied the
                        political privileges which are accorded to my negro servant; repelled from
                        the hall of the House of Representatives, to which I was elected almost by
                        acclamation; my native State, the proud old mother of Washington and Henry,
                        and Jefferson, unrecognized save as Military District No. 1--I must confess
                        I would feel somewhat out of place at your board.</p>
                    <p>In former days, when I visited Washington as representative of the people, or
                        as the associate of Webster, Crittenden and Corwin, in the executive
                        councils of the nation, I felt that, in the eye of the law at least, I was
                        the peer of the loftiest in the land. I was privileged to think freely and
                        to speak freely on all matters of public concern. Were I to join your circle
                        now, I should feel painfully conscious of the difference between your
                        position and mine. No military order can consign you to a dungeon beyond the
                        reach of <emph rend="italic">habeus corpus</emph>, and no persuasive
                        bayonets admonish you to speak with "bated breath." With me the case might
                        be different. But be that as it may, while Virginia mourns I cannot rejoice.
                        While the cypress encircles her brow I cannot twine the myrtle round my own.</p>
                    <p>But may I not hope that the present condition of things is temporary? If I do
                        not misinterpret the signs of the times, the day is near at hand when, by
                        the mandate of a magnanimous people, the shackles will be stricken from the
                        limbs of Virginia and her Southern sisters, and there shall be given unto
                        them "beauty for ashes, the oil of joy for mourning, and the garment of
                        praise for the spirit of heaviness." When that glorious day shall have
                        arrived I shall be happy to meet you and your fellow patriots around the
                        festive board, and on behalf of Virginia to offer a willing and hearty
                        tribute of gratitude to the noble Conservative Democrats who set her free.</p>
                    <p>Respectfully, your ob't serv't,<lb/> Alexander H. H. Stuart.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letter of Alexander H. H. Stuart to a committee of conservative Democrats
                    turning down an invitation to speak at a banquet. The devastated condition of
                    Virginia and his humiliation at the loss of his civil rights prevents him from
                    taking part in the festivities.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
