<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1868/va.au.ss.1868.07.28">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/27/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1868-07-28">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day norm="">28</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1868.07.28.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote>The first page is devoted to a list of prizes to be awarded at the county
                fair.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1868.07.28.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Outrageous Radical Legislation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>As the prospects of the defeat of the Radical party increase the Radical
                        Congress devises schemes of the most outrageous character to secure the
                        retention of power and the success of the party <emph rend="italic">per fas
                            aut nefus</emph>. In contrast with the blazing iniquity of its recent
                        legislation, even the diabolical legislation heretofore enacted by the Rump
                        Congress shines with a mild and gentle radiance -- beside the flaming
                        diabolism of its recent legislation its former "pales its ineffectual
                        fires." The Radicals seem conscious that their party is in an extremely
                        dangerous condition, if not absolutely in <emph rend="italic">articulo
                            mortis</emph>, and, to save it, if possible, they hesitate not to resort
                        to any device however wicked and violative of the constitution and every
                        principle of liberty. To effect that purpose they refuse to allow Virginia
                        an opportunity to vote upon this constitution, and deny her the exercise of
                        her indubitable right to vote for Presidential electors. For the same
                        purpose the Radical Senate passed a bill to arm the "loyal militia" -- <emph
                            rend="italic">i. e.</emph> negroes and scallawags -- with Springfield
                        rifles. For the same purpose the Radical House of Representatives passed a
                        bill putting the States of Virginia, Mississippi, and Texas -- the remaining
                        "unreconstructed" States -- completely in the power of their respective
                        scallawag Conventions, providing that the Convention of Virginia and
                        Mississippi shall reassemble within four weeks -- that of Texas being now in
                        session -- empowered by this outrageous bill to remove all officers, from
                        Governor down; to appoint others; to revise the registration lists; to
                        appoint registers and judges of elections; to count the vote; to appoint a
                        constabulary force; and, in a word, to render them absolute masters of the
                        people.</p>
                    <p>For the same purpose, the electoral College bill which in substance, deprives
                        every Southern State of the right to vote for President, that does not vote
                        for the Radical candidates, was passed over the President's veto by an
                        overwhelming majority in both Houses of Congress. In the Senate the vote was
                        45 to 8 and in the House 134 to 36.</p>
                    <p>For the same purpose, the Freedmen's Bureau has been extended for another
                        year from the 16th of July, at a cost of fifteen or twenty millions of
                        dollars, to be paid by the oppressively taxed people who are forced to
                        defray the expenses of their own enslavement.</p>
                    <p>We have not the space even to mention briefly half of the various diabolical
                        schemes of the Radicals to outrage the rights of the people that they may
                        retain the possession of that power which they so infamously abuse. The
                        vocabulary of our language is inadequate to express in proper terms the
                        character of the Radical legislation. Though it excites indignation, we do
                        not regret it, but rather rejoice at it, for we consider it satisfactory
                        evidence that the Radical party is in <emph rend="italic">extremia</emph>,
                        and feel assured that it will add to the force of that reaction in the North
                        which is our only hope of deliverance from the living death of Radical
                    rule.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Criticizes recent Radical legislation, including acts that remove
                    Virginia's right to select Presidential electors, acts that arm "loyal
                    militias", and acts that extend the life of the Freedmen's Bureau.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Not So</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper disputes Horace Greeley's comments that the Republicans are
                    treating the South fairly, and that Virginia's constitution was drafted by the
                    state. Instead, "carpet-baggers and scallawags" drafted the document that
                    Republicans wish to force upon Virginia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Election in Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper asserts that a bill mandating Virginia elections was allowed to
                    lapse because Republicans feared they would not win in the state.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Cheering Democratic Prospects</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The New York <emph rend="italic">World</emph> says:</p>
                    <p>No person can watch the developments around him without becoming convinced
                        that there is a large class who, for several years past, have voted for the
                        Republican ticket, who will this year vote the Democratic. There is a
                        feeling among a large class of non-partisans, who voted with the Republicans
                        during the war, that a change will produce a beneficial result. They believe
                        that the time for military rule to cease has arrived; and furthermore, that
                        if the Radicals succeed this year there will be no end to the revolutionary
                        schemes that they will propose and carry out. Their success will be taken by
                        the leading Jacobins to mean a full endorsement of all their extreme
                        measures, and they will become rampant. The business interest of the country
                        is now for a change. The mechanics and laboring men are becoming tired of
                        spending their time and labor for the benefit of the revolutionists who are
                        keeping the country in a turmoil and unsettled condition, in order that they
                        may profit by a continuation of an excessive expenditure of money. Democracy
                        of to-day means opposition to the corruption, profligacy and revolutionary
                        measures of the Radicals, and those opposed to those measures compose a
                        large majority of the people of the country. In vain the Radicals will labor
                        to prove to the contrary. Radicalism to-day means military rule, oppressive
                        taxation, profligate expenditures, depreciated currency and dictatorial
                        power concentrated at Washington. On the other hand, Democracy of to-day
                        means the supremacy of civil law over the military, economy in all
                        expenditures and reduction of taxation. Is there any person who doubts upon
                        which side a majority of the people stands on these issues?</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article from the New York World, claiming that the Radicals have lost many
                    of their supporters, and will lose the election.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1868.07.28.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper applauds the organization of a new Building Association in
                    Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>George P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The executive committee of the Augusta County Bible Society will meet in
                    the house of George P. Baker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hendry</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Hendry and Mr. Lumbaugh have a steam door, sash, and blind factory in
                    operation near the central depot. They can do a variety of carpentry work.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Augusta County Fair</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Augusta County Fair will be held the 27th, 28th, and 29th of October.
                    The paper prints a list of prizes and urges citizens to enter. "Exhibitions of
                    this kind are calculated to do an incalculable amount of good in the rivalry
                    they excite among the manufacturing and producing interests, and we feel
                    confident old Augusta can compete favorably with any of her sister counties."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1868.07.28.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
