<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1868/va.au.ss.1868.02.11">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/18/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1868-02-11">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="02">Feburary</month>
            <day norm="">11</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1868.02.11.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1868.02.11.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Grant and the President</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Baltimore <emph rend="italic">Gazette</emph> says that "the
                        correspondence between the President and General Grant, which was laid
                        before Congress on Tuesday, confirms the view we took of General Grant's
                        conduct when he surrendered the War Department to Mr. Stanton. General
                        Grant's statement is vague and inconclusive, and is evidently the work of a
                        man who feels that he is in an awkward and not creditable position. He is,
                        moreover, flatly contradicted by the President and the members of the
                        Cabinet, and however much of a warrior and hero some people may at present
                        consider him, his personal character has never been so high as to make his
                        word of any special weight in the estimation of the country. But the case is
                        one that admits of no explanation which relieves General Grant from the
                        charge of having been guilty of the grossest perfidy. He was placed by the
                        President on the list of his official and confidential advisers, and he was
                        bound by every obligation that controls men of ordinary integrity to leave
                        no room for any misunderstanding in regards to his intention in case Mr.
                        Stanton should attempt to resume his place in the War Department. The
                        subject has been deliberately discussed several times, and therefore General
                        Grant was not taken by surprise. He had informed the President that he would
                        pursue a very different course from the one which he subsequently did adopt,
                        and it was thus made the more incumbent on him to give Mr. Johnson the most
                        explicit and detailed statement of his change of purpose. No amount of
                        shuffling and no amount of denial will suffice to clear General Grant's
                        reputation. That he is thoroughly allied with the Radical party is a
                        confessed fact and it is now perfectly clear that in the interests of that
                        party he has dealt treacherously with the President. His flourish about his
                        "personal honor and character" comes with a singularly bad grace from a man
                        in the position in which General Grant has placed himself -- a position, we
                        may add, in which it is scarcely possible for a frank and upright man to
                        have gotten by any sort of accident."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Criticizes General Grant's character on the basis of his failure to deal
                    with President Johnson fairly regarding Stanton and the War Department.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Convention in the South</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In speaking of the outrage imposed upon the Southern States by the Radicals
                        through the instrumentality of Constitutional State Conventions, so called,
                        the <emph rend="italic">Enquirer and Examiner</emph> asks:</p>
                    <p>Will the patience of the Northern people allow this monstrosity much longer?
                        It is not merely an absurdity. It is not merely a disgust. It is a terror.
                        It is that most diabolical of plots and of dramas -- a frightful tragedy in
                        the garb of a farce. It is the dagger of the assassin with the disguise of
                        harlequin and the gibberish of the idiot. It is the dance of the Ethiopians
                        over the dust of Washington. It is the humiliation of the Caucasian by the
                        African -- the exaltation of barbarism and fetishism over civilization and
                        christianity. It gives to republican forms their deadliest blow, by making
                        them supremely contemptible. Shall a proceeding at once so fatal in its
                        character and so loathsome in its details, at once a great crime, a great
                        peril, and a great indecency, continue to offend and disgust the world? Is
                        it necessary that the worst of ends should be pursued by the worst of means?
                        Can despotism devise no more decent formula for its dirty ends? For <emph
                            rend="italic">shame</emph> that the people of the North should so long
                        have tolerated the brutal exhibition! If they are utterly oblivious to every
                        political principle they have ever professed; -- if they are utterly
                        insensible to every pledge of honor they have ever made; -- if they, indeed,
                        desire to pour only vitriol in the Southern wounds, and educate Southern
                        hearts to the very gall of hate under a sense of enormous and perfidious
                        wrong, -- at least let them put away the pitiable monstrosity of negro
                        constitutional conventions as the instruments of their malignity. They have
                        abundance of as despicable stuff as tyrants were ever made of, -- let them
                        send the negro behind the scenes, and fly their Popes and Sheridans and
                        Meades and other like tigercats, directly at our throats.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A dramatic attack on the Constitutional State Conventions as terrible
                    instruments working towards an unjust end.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The reiterated and continued statement of the Radical leaders, that the
                        people of the Southern States are hostile to "the Government," is to be
                        explained, says the <emph rend="italic">Alex. Gazette</emph>, by
                        recollecting that the long possession of power in the hands of these
                        leaders, and their complete control of the administration of affairs for
                        seven years, have induced them to assume that <emph rend="italic"
                        >they</emph> are the "government," and they, therefore, expect and require
                        fealty and allegiance to their faction, just as if it were an organized
                        institution, recognized by the Constitution. The Southern people <emph
                            rend="italic">are</emph>, and acknowledge themselves to be, in
                        opposition to the political sentiments, purposes, policy, and designs of the
                            <emph rend="italic">Radical leaders</emph> -- as are a large and
                        respectable portion of the Northern people. Thus far they go -- and no
                        farther. This opposition is reasonable, legitimate, legal, constitutional.
                        It is not, and cannot be prohibited except by brute force or the excercise
                        of illegal military authority. It is, simply, the excercise of what is left
                        of the right of speech, of the liberty of the press, of the privelege of
                        forming an opinion and expressing it, with regard to public matters. It is
                            <emph rend="italic">no</emph> hostility to "the government" -- no breach
                        of faith -- no severance of allegiance. Those who represent it otherwise, do
                        so for purposes of wrong, oppression, and tyranny.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Claims that the Radicals mistakenly view Southern opposition to their
                    policies as disloyalty or illegal opposition to the government, when in fact
                    such opposition is both legal and legitimate.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>President Johnson and Gen'l Grant</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prints correspondence between Johnson and Grant concerning the firing of
                    Stanton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Prompt Action Needed</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Clarke <emph rend="italic">Journal</emph> says that "it is evident that
                        Congress, or the unconstitutional body so-called, is only instigated by the
                        late reaction in the North to more reckless and destructive legislation than
                        it has ever before been guilty of. It is evident, too, that they will
                        require in the next Presidential election, the electoral vote of the South,
                        to ensure the success of their candidate. They will, therefore, hesitate at
                        nothing in their effort to effect the reconstruction of the Southern States
                        at once. They have no time to lose, for the day is not far distant when the
                        final decisive struggle for power will have to be made. Their political
                        machines, the mongrel Conventions of the South, will be required to complete
                        the framing of Constitutions for the States at a very early day, and as
                        little time as possible will be given before the question will be submitted
                        to the people.</p>
                    <p>The question of the ratification of the Constitution will be sprung upon us
                        so suddenly that we will not have time to arouse the people to the necessity
                        of turning out <emph rend="italic">en masse</emph> to save the State. In the
                        meantime while they are thus preparing for our total enslavement, we are
                        doing nothing. We are organizing, 'tis is true, but organizing to begin the
                        campaign <emph rend="italic">when</emph> the Constitution is framed and
                        submitted to the people. This is the very worst policy conceivable. We
                        should begin the campaign at once. Every man who is Conservative, and who
                        has the interest of the State at heart, should at once go to work.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Clarke Journal predicts that the State Convention will present the
                    Constitution with little warning, and urges Southerners to organize and prepare
                    in advance.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In speaking of the issue of veracity between the President and Grant, the
                        Lynchburg <emph rend="italic">Republican</emph> says: "The President openly
                        charges Grant with falsehood and treachery, and proves it upon him by the
                        testimony of four members of his cabinet; while Grant lamely attempts to
                        escape the odium by appealing to the public in behalf of his reputation as a
                        soldier and a gentleman! Most lame and impudent dodge! He betrayed the
                        President in order to subserve the revolutionary designs of Stanton and
                        Congress and he now resorts to special pleading and falsehood to escape the
                        public odium and disgust which attaches to such disreputable conduct. -- We
                        presume that, of all the public men of distinction that ever figured in this
                        country, Grant has gone up as the most "like a skyrocket and come down like
                        a stick." He has neither the brains of a smart man nor the principles of a
                        correct one; and the laurels he won in the field by extraordinary numbers,
                        will be eternally lost in civil life by stupidity and deception.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Discusses the President's charges of treachery against Grant, and
                    criticizes Grant's character.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1868.02.11.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Question for Debating Societies</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper compares the "mongrel convention" at Richmond to a zoo, and
                    suggests charging admission to observe the constitutional debates.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Staunton Musical Association gave a concert, showing off the extensive
                    musical talent in town.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Staunton Lyceum</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fauntleroy</ln>
                        <fn>A. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Powers</ln>
                        <fn>Pike</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn>Y. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>George B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pierce</ln>
                        <fn>A. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>James H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. A. M. Fauntleroy delivered a lecture before the Lyceum on "The
                    Indestructibility of Forces." He argued that forces were not lost, and heat and
                    light were not matter, but the effect of the motion of matter. A debate followed
                    on the question of whether or not Divine Goodness could be proven without the
                    aid of scripture. Prof. Pike Powers, Col. George Baylor, Y. H. Peyton, and Rev.
                    George B. Taylor argued in the affirmative; Capt. A. M. Pierce, Col. B.
                    Christian, and Col. James H. Skinner in the negative. It was decided in the
                    negative 13 to 9.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Cast Steel by Sibert's Process</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We have frequently made mention of the newly-discovered process, by Lorenzo
                        Sibert, of making cast-steel in an ordinary blast furnace, and have
                        previously mentioned the fact that several tires for the wheels of
                        locomotives have been made by this process at the foundry of Perkins, Nelson
                        &amp; Co., of this place, ordered by Mr. Whitcomb, the Superintendent of
                        the Va. Central Railroad. Having ordered two more, and other citizens being
                        informed that the casting would take place on Saturday evening last, a
                        number of intelligent gentlemen were in attendance to witness it. As on
                        former occasions, the most satisfactory success was attained. It is claimed
                        for the metal thus easily and cheaply made, that it possesses all the
                        qualities of the best steel. Lorenzo Sibert, the patentee, has the credit
                        for making one of the most valuable discoveries of the present age. It will
                        establish his claim as a benefactor of the world. He will not need marble or
                        bronze to perpetuate his memory, as steel made by his process will be more
                        effectual and more enduring. Of cast-steel his monument should be made. His
                        promises to be<lb/> "One of the few, immortal names<lb/> That were not born
                        to die."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sibert</ln>
                        <fn>Lorenzo</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Describes casting of locomotive wheels at a local factory using the process
                    invented by Augusta's Lorenzo Sibert.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Corporation Court</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Quarterly Grand Jury term of the Corporation Court of Staunton commenced
                        on Wednesday last.</p>
                    <p>Quite a large number of cases have been tried and many more are still to
                        try--the Court being still in session. We will give the result in some of
                        the more interesting cases. It will be seen that the "wards of the nation"
                        have gotten into the prisoners' box instead of on the jury as they are
                        striving to do.</p>
                    <p>Commonwealth vs. Patrick Carter and Sidney Watson,(both colored).
                        Offence--Grand Larceny. Verdict--conviction in the case of Patrick Carter,
                        who was sentenced to three years' imprisonment in the penitentiary;
                        acquittal in the case of Sidney Watson.</p>
                    <p>Commonwealth vs. Ben Jackson (colored.)--Offence--petit larceny.
                        Verdict--acquittal.</p>
                    <p>Commonwealth vs. Hughes and Jackson (colored). Offence--Petit Larceny.
                        Verdict--acquittal in the case of Hughes and conviction in the case of
                        Jackson who was sentenced to 90 days' confinement in jail.</p>
                    <p>Commonwealth vs. Geo. Johnson (colored).--Offence--Petit larceny.
                        Verdict--conviction and sentenced to 5 days' confinement in jail.</p>
                    <p>Commonwealth vs Wm. Johnson and Henry Jailer alias Henry Douglas.
                        Offence--Petit larceny. Verdict--Johnson convicted and sentenced to 60 days'
                        confinement in jail; Henry Jailer acquitted.</p>
                    <p>Commonwealth vs. Marquis Rodney (colored) Offence--Petit larceny.
                        Verdict--Guilty and sentenced to 5 days' confinement in jail.</p>
                    <p>Commonwealth vs. Raleigh Towes alias Raleigh Gordon (colored). Offence--Petit
                        Larceny. Verdict--acquittal.</p>
                    <p>Commonwealth vs. Alex. Nellous (colored).--Offence--Petit larceny.
                        Verdict--Guilty and sentenced to 10 days' confinement in jail.</p>
                    <p>Commonwealth vs John W. Keller(p ain).--Offence--Petit larceny.
                        Verdict--Guilty, and sentenced to 90 days' confinement in jail.</p>
                    <p>To learn the distinction between <emph rend="italic">meum et tuum</emph>
                        seems to be a difficult lesson to the "wards of the nation," and the
                        Constitution-makers for the Southern States.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carter</ln>
                        <fn>Patrick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Watson</ln>
                        <fn>Sidney</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jackson</ln>
                        <fn>Ben</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hughes</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jackson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jailer</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Douglas</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rodney</ln>
                        <fn>Marquis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Towes</ln>
                        <fn>Raleigh</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn>Raleigh</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nellous</ln>
                        <fn>Alex</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keller</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Proceedings of Staunton City Court.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Issue in the Presidential Campaign</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Let us see, what is the true and great issue to be decided in the
                        Presidential campaign which, as has been said, is now opening in two of the
                        New England States. It is whether the glorious republican government which
                        was handed down to us by the fathers, and which has made us a mighty,
                        prosperous, and happy people, shall be subverted by the radical
                        revolutionary party now in power or be preserved by a repudiation of that
                        party at the polls. -- It is whether a military dictatorship -- the
                        assumption of despotic power by one branch of the government and the virtual
                        abolition of the other -- and the creation of a negro barbarian balance of
                        political power in the republic are to take the place of constitutional law
                        and those wise checks and balances between the different departments which
                        the constitution established, or whether the best government ever devised is
                        to be perpetuated. Our radical Congress is fast destroying the constitution
                        and the government, both in theory and in practice, for no other object than
                        to perpetuate power in the hands of the radical party. The Jacobins of the
                        French Revolution were not more reckless or ambitious. All the clap-trap
                        about the poor negro, universal liberty and equality, with all the
                        declaration about loyalty, rebels, and so forth, reminds us of the cry of
                        liberty, equality and fraternity and the loud mouthed talk of tyranny by the
                        French Jacobins at the time they were trampling every vestige of liberty
                        under foot and deluging the country with blood. The issue is between this
                        party and the conservative party. It matters little what the conservatives
                        be called, democrats or anything else, the issue is the same, and is all
                        important. The name is nothing, the cause everything. If the people decide
                        in the New Hampshire and Connecticut election, then -- as would be the case,
                        probably, in the Presidential election afterwards -- against the radical
                        revolutionists our constitutional republic will be established; but if,
                        unfortunately, they should not so decide, we shall march rapidly on to
                        despotism, corruption, and to another form of government. Such is the issue
                        now before the country, and a more important one never arose in the United
                        States.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Presents the coming Presidential campaign as a choice between revolutionary
                    tyranny and republican government.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Riley</ln>
                        <fn>Berry L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Lizzie A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn>John L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Berry L. Riley and Miss Lizzie A. Brown, both of Staunton, were married on
                    January 6th by the Rev. John L. Clarke.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rusmisell</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fix</ln>
                        <fn>Isabella</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fix</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Getzendanner</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>David Rusmisell and Miss Isabella Fix, both of Augusta, were married at the
                    house of the bride's brother, Joseph L. Fix, on January 30th by the Rev. H.
                    Getzendanner.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McPheeters</ln>
                        <fn>Robert P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Speer</ln>
                        <fn>Mary M. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Preston</ln>
                        <fn>T. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Robert P. McPheeters and Miss Mary M. P. Speer, both of Augusta, were
                    married at the residence of the bride's father on February 5th by the Rev. T. L.
                    Preston.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nimmo</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>Laurena A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Killian</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel P. Nimmo and Laurena A. Taylor, both of Augusta, were married near
                    Bethlehem Church on December 28th by the Rev. Jacob Killian.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ward</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>Mattie C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>Harrison</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Killian</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William H. Ward and Miss Mattie C. Koiner, daughter of Harrison Koiner, all
                    of Augusta, were married near Bethlehem Church on January 9th by the Rev. Jacob
                    Killian.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baily</ln>
                        <fn>John William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baily</ln>
                        <fn>George F. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baily</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John William Baily, infant son of George F. A. and Mary Baily, died near
                    Bethlehem Church on January 21st. He was 8 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wiseman</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Margaret C. Wiseman died near Greenville of typhoid fever on February
                    1st. She was 19 years old and leaves many friends to mourn her loss.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1868.02.11.04" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Cultivate the Soil</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Gloomy as are the prospects of all the departments of Southern industry,
                        agriculture still offers to every Virginian more assured prospects of fair
                        returns for labor employed and capital expended than anything else. -- While
                        our farmers may not since the close of the war have realized large profits,
                        yet their losses have been insignificant as compared with those of the
                        planters of the Cotton States. * * * * * * *</p>
                    <p>We sincerely hope that during the next two months every young man in Virginia
                        who does not see his way clearly to support in commerce or the professions,
                        will try his hand at farming. Half the best land in Virginia is lying idle
                        for want of <sic>hads</sic> to till it, and however unpropitious the seasons
                        may prove, the cultivation of corn, wheats, oats, and tobacco is sure to
                        yield a support to the industrious laborer. We do not mean that an incurably
                        lazy white man, whose "farming" consists of hiring a worthless negro or two,
                        whom he overlooks by sitting on a stump with an umbrella over his head is
                        likely to succeed. God forbid that such a cumberer of the earth should
                        demoralize the youth of the South by succeeding at anything -- for his
                        example would be a bad one.</p>
                    <p>But, looking to the cheapness of lands in Virginia, and to their fertility,
                        and the great ease with which they are cultivated, and to their
                        accessibility to the very best markets for grain, the industrious farmer is
                        sure to do better for the present than the struggling merchant or the
                        unemployed professional man. There can be no real prosperity in Virginia as
                        long as agriculture anguishes. <emph rend="italic">Enquirer</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that agriculture offers the best returns to labor and capital in
                    Virginia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
