<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1864/va.au.rv.1864.03.25">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andrew Chancey</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/14/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>1st Pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 6/22/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1864-03-25">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day>25</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1864.03.25.01">
            <pageNote>On this page are a reprinted list of deserters from the 52nd Regiment of
                Virginia Volunteers, advertisements, a poem, the text of President Davis's
                proclamation calling for a day of prayer and fasting, a serial entitled "The
                Cat-Tail Letters No. II, The Witherington Ruins, Jefferson County, Virginia,"
                "Yankee News," war news, and other news items.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1864.03.25.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A New Call</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lincoln has just issued a call for 200,000 additional men in the military,
                    an action the editor of the Vindicator perceives to reflect desperation on the
                    part of the North. The conflict that was to take a few men and a short amount of
                    time has instead lasted three years, with "the Confederacy further from
                    subjugation than at any period since the onset of the struggle." The people of
                    the South have adjusted to the fact that the war will be long, but the people of
                    the North are grumbling and dissatisfied.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Caution</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A Caution.</p>
                    <p>We have heard of several cases of what we believe to be downright roguery
                        practised upon several of the unsuspecting farmers of our county, under the
                        alleged pretense of gathering supplies for Gen. Lee's army. The party or
                        parties engaged in this, presented themselves to the farmers and with the
                        most sympathetic appeals requested them to contribute supplies, such as they
                        could spare, for the purpose of relieving the immediate wants of the army of
                        Northern Virginia, which they declared to be in great want, accompanying
                        their appeals with the seeming candid assertion that they were not empowered
                        to impress, but were authorized by General Lee to collect supplies by
                        voluntary contribution, and at the same time declaring that unless they were
                        successful in gathering supplies Gen. Lee's army would be compelled to fall
                        back and consequently give up our State. The ordinary feelings of humanity,
                        with the great desire of our people to see that army remain an invincible
                        barrier to the unprincipled foe, induced several to comply and furnish them
                        with what they could spare, thus heavily loading several wagons, which we
                        believe were not intended for and will never reach Gen. Lee's army. We
                        caution our farmers to be certain to whom they give, for Gen. Lee's army has
                        never been in the great strait represented, for if it had been such
                        applications would have been made through one or both of the Quarter Masters
                        at this post.</p>
                    <p>Would it not be well for the farmers in this district to know to whom they
                        pay their tithes, since there is an authorized Q.M. and a regularly
                        organized agency among us for the recognition of the tithes. We call
                        attention to the latter from the fact that we have heard it stated that a
                        number are collecting the tithes in this district, who are unknown to the
                        Post Quartermaster. We are sure that some of those [illegible] the tithes
                        are authorized to do so, whose receipts are valid, of the others we know
                        nothing. We merely speak of the above as a matter of caution to our
                    farmers.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor warns the farmers of the area of unauthorized persons collecting
                    supplies, representing themselves as agents for General Lee's army or for the
                    local quartermaster's office. The editor reminds readers that an authorized
                    quartermaster and a regularly organized agency are present in the county to
                    collect taxes in kind and impressed supplies.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Our Status</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor reviews the status of the Confederacy and determines that
                    present conditions should make Southerners hopeful. The editor reviews the
                    status of each state, concluding that most of the Confederacy is intact. The
                    aggressive legislation of the Confederate Congress addressing finances is
                    encouraging, the favor with which foreign governments are beginning to view the
                    Confederacy, and the ability of the military leaders and patriotism of the
                    people are all positive signs of the South's well being.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor alerts readers to the notice of Captain Avis stating he is ready
                    to receive men ages 45 to 50 in his service. They are required to enlist, and
                    the editor encourages them to do so soon so they might be able to stay close to
                    home. Otherwise, the late enrollees may have to go to distant fields.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Underground Railroad Agents--Through Tickets--How to Make the Connections</head>
                <origin>Enquirer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Former prisoners of war report that an underground railroad that helps
                    deserters escape from the Confederate military service appears to exist.
                    Apparently, it is funded with Yankee money.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hildebrand</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Reverend</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ruckman</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Maggie Ruckman married Lieutenant Elisha Wilfong, of Pocahontas County and
                    a member of the 31st Virginia Volunteers, on March 15, 1864, at the home of her
                    father, near Hermitage, Augusta County. Reverend Jacob Hildebrand of the Tunker
                    Church officiated.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gaver</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fitch</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGilvray</ln>
                        <fn>Hester A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Hester A. McGilvray married George Fitch, of the 5th Virginia Infantry, in
                    Greenville on March 10, 1864, with Rev. Mr. Gaver officiating.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Also on this page are other articles on the war, advertisements, and legal and
                political notices.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
