<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1864/va.au.rv.1864.04.08">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andrew Chancey</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/02/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>1st Pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 6/22/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1864-04-08">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day norm="08">8</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1864.04.08.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>A Discontented Contraband</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article contains a letter to an African-American preacher in Nashville
                    from a former slave from Alabama who accompanied Yankee troops to the North but
                    who now feels more enslaved than he did in the South. He is unable to write but
                    found a free woman to write for him. He says he was foolish to leave a good home
                    and kind friends to join the "cruel, lying, swindling Yankees," who promise him
                    everything but deliver nothing.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Spurgeon on Negroes</head>
                <origin>Illinois State Journal</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This excerpt from an interview with Rev. Mr. Spurgeon reflects his belief
                    that people in England have tired of helping America's African Americans. At
                    first the British were glad to help African Americans gain freedom. However, too
                    many of them have immigrated to Britain, and they often want too much. The
                    writer of the article comments that thousands of other people are beginning to
                    agree with Spurgeon.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Also on this page are a reprinted list of deserters from the 52nd Regiment of
                Virginia Volunteers, a reprint of President Davis's proclamation calling for a day
                of prayer and fasting, the text of "An Act to provide for the Purchase and
                Distribution among the People of the State, of Cotton, Cotton Yarns, Cotton Cloths
                and Hand Cards," an excerpt from Southern Punch on the arrival of prisoners of war
                in Columbus, Ohio, war and miscellaneous news, advertisements, and a
            poem.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1864.04.08.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Purchase of Cotton &amp;c.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor alerts the readers to the bill passed by the Virginia Assembly
                    on the purchase of cotton supplies for distribution and sale to citizens of
                    Virginia and refugees. The editor calls on the county court to appoint an agent
                    for Augusta County at its next meeting to serve as purchaser in order to meet
                    the needs of the area.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Municipal Elections</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>N. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Balthis</ln>
                        <fn>W. L.</fn>
                        <sf>Sergeant</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sterrett</ln>
                        <fn>W. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Points</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bruce</ln>
                        <fn>A. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scharer</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kayser</ln>
                        <fn>W. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Evans</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>F. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hardy</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGuffin</ln>
                        <fn>D. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Colonel</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Wednesday's municipal election in Staunton produced the following results:
                    N. K. Trout, Mayor; W. L. Balthis, Sergeant; and the following Council
                    members--W. G. Sterrett, B. F. Points, J. W. Crawford, A. M. Bruce, J. B.
                    Scharer, W. B. Kayser, W. H. Wilson, J. B. Evans, F. M. Young, J. M. Hardy, and
                    D. C. McGuffin or Colonel George Baylor. The latter two received an equal number
                    of votes, but because F. M. Young has not been a resident long enough to be
                    eligible for office, both McGuffin and Baylor will be on the Council.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>For the Vindicator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>John B. Watts</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Watts</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John B. Watts, deputy clerk of the Circuit Court of Augusta County,
                    graciously refuses to be a candidate for the office of Clerk. He adds that in
                    his time as deputy clerk he has not conducted other business in that office and
                    calls on other candidates to make such a pledge. Because the building was built
                    for a specific reason and is a public facility, it should not be used for other
                    business, as has been the case in the past.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hammack</ln>
                        <fn>C. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Reverend</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reubush</ln>
                        <fn>David H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rubush</ln>
                        <fn>C. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss C. F. Rubush and David H. Reubush, both of Augusta County, married
                    March 27, 1864, with Reverend C. B. Hammack officiating.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>Eveline</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Eveline Bell, wife of William H. Bell, died of paralysis on March 26, 1864,
                    at her residence in Augusta County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Also on this page are war news from Illinois, Kentucky, and northern Virginia;
                an article on the exchange of prisoners; letters and announcements regarding an
                upcoming election; and advertisements and notices.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
