<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1864/va.au.rv.1864.12.16">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andrew Chancey</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/25/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>1st Pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 7/1/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1864-12-16">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="12">December</month>
            <day>16</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1864.12.16.01">
            <pageNote>On this page are excerpts from a speech of Governor Smith, war news,
                advertisements, and a poem. Part of column seven is missing.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1864.12.16.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Message of Abraham Lincoln</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Message of Abraham Lincoln.</p>
                    <p>We are prevented by want of space from publishing the Message of Abraham
                        Lincoln, but we incline to the opinion that our readers lose nothing thereby
                        a its perusal would scarcely pay, there being but little in it of interest
                        to us.</p>
                    <p>In regard to the present position of affairs he states, that his armies hold
                        and maintain all the important points possessed by them at the time of
                        inditing [sic] his previous Message, while we know that the campaign in
                        Louisiana and Arkansas resulted in driving the enemy from nearly every
                        portion of those States, except a narrow strip adjacent to the Mississippi
                        River. He speaks of the movement of Sherman as the most remarkable military
                        operation of the year, yet hesitates to speak of its success. When its
                        result is known if we can judge from the tenor of the news, partly
                        unwritten, from that section we will be surprised if Sherman shall escape
                        from the hazardous position in which he has placed himself, while we doubt
                        not from the success which has crowned the advance of Hood into Tennessee
                        that ere long not only a portion of but that entire State will be freed from
                        the rule of Lincoln and his man Friday Andy.</p>
                    <p>He continues to hold out the same inducements to us which he has so
                        cheerfully offered us on previous occasions--to lay down our arms, and
                        submit to the edicts of Lincoln. In this connection it must be remembered
                        that he avows his determination not to deviate a hairs-breadth from his
                        action in reference to our peculiar institution.</p>
                    <p>With these splendid (?) inducements held out it is highly probable that the
                        only true conclusion at which he seems to have arrived will obtain, that
                        between the contending forces, it must be decided by victory and defeat. No
                        negotiation will be effective. Nothing but victory will be decisive. This we
                        believe and hope ere long our cause may be crowned with a victorious
                    result.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor reports that the lack of space prevents the publication of the
                    text of a message of Abraham Lincoln. However, he writes that readers are spared
                    a waste of their time, as the speech contains nothing worth perusing. The editor
                    refutes several of Lincoln's points, such as the President's claim that
                    Sheridan's movements were among the most remarkable military operations of the
                    year. To this claim, the editor notes that Sheridan will be lucky to escape from
                    the Valley. Lincoln invited the South to lay down its arms but, the editor
                    claims, offered no incentives or negotiations.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Obituary</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guy</ln>
                        <fn>Virginius Rodes</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guy</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Virginius Rodes Guy, 25, died at Glen Home, the home of his father, Robert
                    Guy, in Augusta County on November 13, 1864. Guy died of a "lingering and
                    complicated disease of the heart and lungs." Guy volunteered as a member of the
                    1st Virginia Cavalry, commanded by J. E. B. Stuart. When his father died, he
                    returned home to run the farm but soon contracted the disease.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Obituary</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bare</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bare</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James W. Bare, 25 and son of Henry Bare of Staunton, died in the General
                    Hospital in Staunton on October 19, 1864. He was wounded in the battle near
                    Winchester on September 19, 1864, and later had a limb amputated. He lingered
                    for three weeks but died in the care of his sisters and friends.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blackley</ln>
                        <fn>M. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fauntleroy</ln>
                        <fn>A. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>M. L. Blackley, hospital steward, on behalf of A. M. Fauntleroy, surgeon in
                    charge of the General Hospital in Staunton, advertises that he wants to hire
                    eight women as laundresses for $25 per month.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Wanted a Negro</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mitchell</ln>
                        <fn>T. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>T. N. Mitchell wishes to purchase or hire for the year an African-American
                    female for cooking, washing, and ironing.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Also on this page are other war news, advertisements, and notices.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
