<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1864/va.au.rv.1864.05.06">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andrew Chancey</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/07/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>1st Pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 6/23/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1864-05-06">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day norm="06">6</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1864.05.06.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Lieut. Gen. Jackson</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor reminds readers of the plan to erect a tomb over Stonewall
                    Jackson's remains, a privilege bestowed by Jackson's family to the soldiers of
                    the Stonewall Brigade. This memorial is different from the statue to be erected
                    and paid for from contributions from the general public. Only past, present, and
                    future members of the Stonewall Brigade are eligible to contribute to this
                    cause, a privilege conferred upon them rather than a favor asked of them. About
                    six thousand dollars has been raised thus far, a sum that needs to be doubled at
                    least.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Prices Falling</head>
                <origin>Mobile Tribune</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An overall decline in prices of general provisions is a good sign,
                    according to this article from the Mobile Tribune. Butter, for example, fell
                    from $10-$12 a pound three weeks ago to $5-$6 per pound.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Also on this page are advertisements, a poem, war news, other news items, and
                the text of President Davis's address to the Senate and House of Representatives of
                the Confederate States of America on May 2, 1864.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1864.05.06.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Word to All</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor notes the hopefulness of the present time and reminds readers of
                    their duties to the cause, particularly in terms of finances. He warns that some
                    people will hoard money or sell at high prices out of interest of personal
                    profit but contends that the well-being of the Confederacy is in everyone's
                    interest.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Sorghum</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoshour</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The editor promotes the production of sorghum as a suitable substitute for
                    citizens when meat is so badly needed by the troops. Samuel A. Hoshour, Steward
                    of the Central Lunatic Asylum, has planted fourteen acres. Another local farmer
                    has studied the subject of sorghum production and offers advice on how area
                    farmers may obtain maximum output, including recommending planting at intervals
                    so that the entire crop does not become ready at the same time.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Organization</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Honorable</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mauzy</ln>
                        <fn>R. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Colonel</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The society devoted to distributing artificial limbs free to maimed
                    soldiers was organized last Tuesday evening after hearing addresses by the Rev.
                    Mr. Stirewalt and Honorable H. H. Stuart. The society elected Stuart President,
                    R. H. Mauzy Secretary, and Colonel George Baylor Treasurer. The society
                    appointed committees of women and men to solicit and receive contributions. The
                    editor reminds the people of Augusta that contributing is a duty they owe the
                    soldiers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Randolph</ln>
                        <fn>Beverly</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Major</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The editor alerts the readers to the notice in another column by Major
                    Beverly Randolph calling for the immediate return of guns issued to Raid Guards,
                    as they are needed urgently.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>From the Lower Valley</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>From the Lower Valley.</p>
                    <p>There are several reports of the movements of the enemy in the Valley. The
                        most reliable report is that the enemy are encamped at Fisher's Hill, three
                        miles this side of Strasburg and have occupied Woodstock--It is generally
                        believed that the movement up the Valley was to cover the movement of Sigel,
                        who is reported to have crossed to Meade's army by way of Front Royal.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The most reliable report of the enemy's movement in the Valley indicates
                    that the enemy is encamped at Fisher's Hill, three miles from Strasburg, and has
                    captured Woodstock. This movement up the Valley is believed to have been a cover
                    for Sigel, who is reported to have met up with Meade's army by way of Front
                    Royal.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>S. H.</fn>
                        <sf>Esquire</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blakemore</ln>
                        <fn>N. L.</fn>
                        <sf>Esquire</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The advisory board for granting exemptions from service for farmers,
                    mechanics, and others has been in session in Staunton for several days. S. H.
                    Bell and N. L. Blakemore, Esquires, constitute the board. Their reputation as
                    businessmen and men of integrity promises that their decisions will meet with
                    approval by both the people and the government.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Notice</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Randolph</ln>
                        <fn>Beverly</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Major</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Major Beverly Randolph announces that all arms and supplies issued the
                    previous autumn for use by the Raid Guards should be returned immediately for
                    use by the Reserves.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>$150 Reward for Davy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>$150 Reward for Davy.</p>
                    <p>He is about 16 years old and well grown, black sin with a small scar I think
                        about his face. He had on when he left a slouch hat and blue yankee coat. He
                        was hired to Maj. H.M. Ball, Quartermaster at Staunton,</p>
                    <p>J.L. Timberlake.</p>
                    <p>Spec copy.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>H. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Major</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Timberlake</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. L. Timberlake offers a reward of $150 for the return of Davy, about 16
                    and well grown, black skin with a small scar "I think about his face," wearing a
                    hat and blue Yankee coat. He was hired to Major H. M. Bell, Quartermaster at
                    Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Also on this page are war news, political announcements, and
            advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
