<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1864/va.au.rv.1864.01.08">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andrew Chancey</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/09/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>1st Pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 6/22/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1864-01-08">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day norm="08">8</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1864.01.08.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Confederate Woman and the War</head>
                <origin>Mobile Advertiser and Register</origin>
                <commentary>"So much has been said of the women of the South for the noble part
                    taken in our struggle for independence. [all of which we endorse.] It may not be
                    amiss to give a slight glimpse of the reverse of the picture. We copy from a
                    lady correspondent of the Mobil Advertiser and Register. She says:"</commentary>
                <excerpt>"As long as they can buy glittering baubles, and throw their treasures into
                    the extortioner's hand, so long will he press his iron heel upon the aching
                    heart of the sunny South."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The writer warns women of the Confederacy against their vanity and their
                    desire for costly pleasures, noting that such things impede the cause of the
                    South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Also on this page are a reprinted list of deserters from the 52nd Regiment of
                Virginia Volunteers, the inaugural address of Governor Smith, and
            advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1864.01.08.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Augusta Raid Guards</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Augusta Raid Guards.</p>
                    <p>We read the interesting article of our co[n]temporary of the "Rockingham
                        Register" descriptive of the arrival of the Yankees at Harrisonburg, their
                        doings while there and their hasty exit, and although disappointed in seeing
                        the mention made of those men of Augusta, who had but just undergone such
                        severe and unaccustomed hardships at North and Shenandoah Mountains, and who
                        again assembled and with commendable alacrity started to meet the enemy then
                        threatening the neighboring county of Rockingham, and perhaps through it to
                        our own beloved Augusta, yet gratified to think that our neighbor of the
                        "Register," with all his discrimination, was unable to distinguish the
                        "Augusta Raid Guards" from regular soldiers. This must have been the case,
                        and is very complimentary to the Guards, for we are satisfied that our
                        neighbor's kindly feelings for Augusta and her citizens would not have
                        permitted him knowingly to have omitted to notice the men of Augusta, who
                        had hurriedly, unhesitatingly, willingly gone forth to assist in defending
                        the homes of Rockingham.</p>
                    <p>It is needless to mention the services of those who were connected with the
                        Guards, for that is well known, but it may not be known that there were
                        others not connected with any organization who accompanied them. This is
                        greatly to their praise, some of them having no pecuniary interest here. The
                        few that remained who were able to go have no twitchings of conscience
                        perhaps but must bear the censure of all for time to come.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor notes an article from the Rockingham Register that discusses the
                    arrival and quick departure of Northern troops at Harrisonburg, but that fails
                    to mention the involvement of the Augusta Raid Guard in the operations there.
                    The Augusta Guard had "just undergone such severe and unaccustomed hardships at
                    North and Shenandoah Mountains" but assembled and went to Rockingham County
                    anyway. The Vindicator's editor assumes that the Register's editor must not have
                    been able to distinguish the Augusta Guard from the regular soldiers, a
                    situation highly complimentary to the home guard. The editor praises the men of
                    the county who participated even though they were not members of the home guard
                    and hopes that everyone eligible will participate or else risk public censure.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>To Our Patrons</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>To Our Patrons.</p>
                    <p>Many of our patrons have called to enquire the reasons of the failure to
                        receive their papers for the last three weeks and as it is not generally
                        known we take this occasion of informing all, and earnestly hope the reason
                        may be as satisfactory to others as to those we have seen. We have not
                        published it. And why? Every one connected with the office who could go went
                        with the "Augusta Raid Guards" to North Mountain to assist, if possible, in
                        meeting the threatening raid of Averill from that direction, and returning
                        thence on Thursday the 17th December, consequently too late to issue it. On
                        the following Sunday they went down the Valley with the Guards again to meet
                        the enemy, who came as far as Harrisonburg, and only returned, after the
                        enemy were driven below New Market on the Next Friday, the day it should
                        have been issued and again too late when Christmas week intervened, and on
                        account of their incessant labors for the year and their late, cold,
                        disagreeable and arduous campaigns, we thought it but just that they, weary
                        and nearly broken down, should rest. We sincerely hope that there may be no
                        impediments in the way of issuing the "Vindicator" continuously hereafter,
                        and as far as in us lies will endeavor that it shall reach all
                    regularly.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor responds to numerous inquiries as to why the Vindicator has not
                    been published for the three preceding weeks. During the first week, much of the
                    office staff went with the Augusta Raid Guards to North Mountain and returned on
                    Thursday, the day before the paper should have been issued. During the second
                    week, they were involved with the Guard in Harrisonburg and returned home on
                    Friday, the day the paper should have been issued. During the third week the
                    editor gave his employees time off for Christmas. The editor hopes that no
                    further impediments lie in the way of continuous publication in the future.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Tax Payers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor draws the attention of readers to the due date for taxes for the
                    last quarter of 1863.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Inaugural Address of Gov. Smith</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor praises Major General William Smith upon his inauguration as
                    governor of Virginia and commends outgoing Governor Letcher.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Treason</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A treatise entitled "An appeal to the honest and reasoning-minded people of
                    the Northern and Southern States of America" supposedly was published in
                    Petersburg, but the editor suspects it is the product of the traitorous Raleigh
                    (North Carolina) Standard. The treatise advocates buying and freeing slaves and
                    reuniting with the North at the end of Lincoln's administration. The editor
                    hopes that the people of Petersburg will trace the authorship of the treatise
                    and "relieve that noble city of the stigma of having issued such a treasonable
                    production."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Lieut. Carter Berkely.</p>
                    <p>Lieut. Carter Berkely, of Captain McClanahan's Battery, Gen. Imboden's
                        command, is now in town recruiting for his company. This battery offers
                        great inducements to those who expect to enter the service, being a mounted
                        battery, (permission having been given to mount themselves) under excellent
                        and accomplished officers and likely to operate near the homes of those
                        living in the Valley. Give Lieut. Berkely a call before going elsewhere.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lieutenant Carter Berkely of Captain McClannahan's Battery under General
                    Imboden's command is in Staunton recruiting for his company. The editor
                    recommends signing up with this company because it is a mounted battery, it has
                    "excellent and accomplished officers," and it is likely to operate in the
                    Valley, near where most men live.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Substitutes From Augusta</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Substitutes from Augusta.</p>
                    <p>We have frequently heard it stated that there were twelve hundred Substitutes
                        from the County of Augusta alone, and as we had no data to go upon we
                        supposed those who asserted it knew best and of course did not refute the
                        statement, but we have lately taken occasion to ascertain the number and
                        find it to be three hundred and sixty-seven. Quite a difference.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor has heard that Augusta County had twelve hundred substitutes and
                    has never had reason to question the source of that information. The editor has
                    learned, however, that the real number is 367.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Substitute Bill</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Congress of the Confederate States has passed a bill repealing the
                    privilege of substitution and requiring service of all who previously had
                    substitutes. Included with this article is a list of names from the House and
                    the Senate of those voting for and against the bill.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parker</ln>
                        <fn>Charles W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Charles W. Parker of Staunton married Miss Samantha O. Foster of Ivy
                    Spring, Nelson County, at the home of her father on December 1, 1863, with
                    Reverend William Shipman officiating.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wheat</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Reverend</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Atkinson</ln>
                        <fn>Lizzie G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Atkinson</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lizzie G. Atkinson, elder daughter of Alexander Atkinson of Augusta County
                    and formerly of Maryland, married James E. Sale of Rockbridge County on December
                    15, 1863, with Reverend J. C. Wheat of Staunton officiating.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dice</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Reverend</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garbert</ln>
                        <fn>William W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dull</ln>
                        <fn>Mary C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary C. Dull of Staunton married William W. Garbert in Staunton on December
                    17, 1863, with Reverend J. C. Dice officiating.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garber</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Reverend</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bates</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Towberman</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary Towberman married John H. Bates on December 17, 1863, with Reverend
                    Martin Garber officiating. All are from Augusta County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>William E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Reverend</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bayly</ln>
                        <fn>E. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>Eddie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Colonel</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Eddie Bell, daughter of Colonel William A. Bell of Augusta County,
                    married Captain E. W. Bayly on December 29, 1863, with Reverend William E. Baker
                    officiating.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Also on this page are advertisements, including two regarding the payment of
                taxes or taxes-in-kind.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
