<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1864/va.au.rv.1864.03.11">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andrew Chancey</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/14/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>1st Pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 6/22/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1864-03-11">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day>11</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1864.03.11.01">
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>To the Farmers of Augusta, Rockingham and Shenandoah</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>J. D. Imboden, Brig. General, Commanding Valley District</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn>J. D.</fn>
                        <sf>Commanding Valley District</sf>
                        <pf>Brig. General</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>General J. D. Imboden writes the farmers of Augusta and surrounding
                    counties to encourage them to continue furnishing supplies for the Valley
                    troops. He knows they have been faithful in supplying crops and reassures them
                    that spring growth will soon replace any larders that are getting low. Rather
                    than their making extreme sacrifices, he would rather that everyone join in
                    making smaller sacrifices. If a wagon cannot be filled at one house, for
                    example, surely it can be filled at three. He says that "'A little here and a
                    little there' will furnish all I need." Imboden requests that those people who
                    do not normally see each other elsewhere use their time at church to discuss who
                    can supply what. Surely, he believes, conducting such business on the Sabbath
                    cannot be a desecration if the cause is so sacred.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>From Point Lookout</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>About nine thousand Confederates are imprisoned at Camp Lookout, including
                    372 officers. Each Confederate prisoner is asked to take an oath of loyalty to
                    the Union government, among other things. About three thousand troops guard the
                    prisoners, including an African-American regiment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Also on this page are a reprinted list of deserters from the 52nd Regiment of
                Virginia Volunteers, war news, a poem, and advertisements. The page also includes an
                article on the special orders and instructions to troops found on the body of Union
                Colonel Dahlgreen, who was trapped and killed by Lieutenant Pollard of the 9th
                Virginia Regiment.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1864.03.11.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Enemy's Designs Confirmed</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor is grateful that the recent raids on Richmond were warded off
                    and that the local area was not in the line of the troops' movement. He hopes
                    when troops do move toward Staunton that local citizens will be able to fend
                    them off as the citizens of Richmond did. The recovery of letters on the body of
                    Union Colonel Dahlgreen confirms that the enemy has villainous and destructive
                    plans on raids.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Gen. Imboden's Card</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn>John D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>General</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The editor calls the attention of the readers to General Imboden's letter
                    printed on page one and encourages people to spare whatever they can to sustain
                    "a sufficient cavalry force in this section."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"The efforts of the Yankees to put the negroes upon an equality with
                    themselves only proves that they are good judges of who are their equals, and
                    goes to prove the old adage that 'birds of a feather flock together.'"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dice</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Reverend Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Raines</ln>
                        <fn>William J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hensley</ln>
                        <fn>Emma E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Emma E. Hensley of Augusta County married William J. Raines on March 3,
                    1864, with Reverend Mr. Dice officiating.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eskridge</ln>
                        <fn>William C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Alexander Perry Eskridge, 28, member of the 12th Virginia Cavalry, died
                    March 2 after a few hours illness at the home of his brother, William C.
                    Eskridge, in Staunton. His body was buried with Masonic honors. He was a member
                    of the Richmond Randolph Lodge.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Also on this page are other articles on the war and advertisements and
                notices, including a series of political announcements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
