<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1864/va.au.rv.1864.04.22">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andrew Chancey</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/02/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>1st Pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 6/22/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1864-04-22">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day>22</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote>The edition from April 15, 1864, number 15, is missing.</editionNote>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1864.04.22.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Negro Soldiers in the North--A Novel Picture of What the Negroes Have Gained
                    by Freedom</head>
                <origin>Albany Argus</origin>
                <commentary>"The Yankees are going on in their mad passion for the elevation of the
                    negro. They are not content at putting them on an equality with their whites,
                    but they want to make even more of them. The Albany Argus is even forced to make
                    the following confession:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Negro Soldiers in the North--A Novel Picture of What the Negroes Have Gained
                        by Freedom.</p>
                    <p>The Yankees are going on in their mad passion for the elevation of the negro.
                        They are not content at putting them on an equality with their whites, but
                        they want to make even more of them. The Albany Argus is even forced to make
                        the following confession:</p>
                    <p>In awarding apparent equality of pay between white and black troops, the
                        administration, however, goes beyond, in fact, and gives to the negro
                        soldiers a much greater rate of compensation. It assumes the support of his
                        family, and for every negro soldier enlisted, it finds from five to eight
                        women or children, or invalid or decrepid [sic] men, thrown absolutely upon
                        it for daily food. The negro troops, therefore, will under this system of
                        equality, be the highest paid troops in the world.</p>
                    <p>Wendell Phillips spoke of them as our nobles to whom the land of the South
                        were to be awarded, as William the conquerer [sic] divided England among his
                        Norman chiefs. They are already upon the pension list to an extent that few
                        realize, and which the heads of department, refuse to reveal. But even this
                        vast expenditure gives no relief to this fated class. They suffer and perish
                        in their new condition.</p>
                    <p>We have published some evidence from abolition sources upon this point. A
                        letter from Chaplain Fisk, dated the 14th instant, to the Springfield,
                        (Mass) Republican, presents some facts which are new. He says:</p>
                    <p>There are, between Memphis and Natchez, not less than fifty thousand blacks,
                        from among whom have been called all the able bodied men for the military
                        service. Thirty five thousand of these, viz: these in camps between Helena
                        and Natchez, are furnished the shelter of old tents and subsistence of cheap
                        ration by the Government, but are in all other things in extreme
                        destitution. Their clothing, in perhaps the case of a fourth of this number,
                        is but one single worn and scanty garment. Many children are wrapped night
                        and day in tattered blankets as their sole apparel. But few of all these
                        people have had any change of raiment since, in midsummer or earlier, they
                        came from the abandoned plantations of their masters.</p>
                    <p>Multitudes of them have no beds or bedding--the clayey earth the resting
                        place of women and babes through these stormy winter months. They live of
                        necessity in extreme filthiness, and are afflicted with all fatal diseases.
                        Medical attendance and supplies are very inadequate. They cannot, during the
                        winter, be disposed to labour and self support, and compensated labour
                        cannot be procured for them in the camps. They cannot, in their present
                        condition, survive the winter. It is my conviction that, unrelieved, the
                        half of them will perish before the Spring. Last winter, during months of
                        February, March and April, I buried, at Memphis alone, out of an average of
                        about four thousand, twelve hundred of these people, or twelve a day. One
                        day we buried thirty five. Those who have been gathered into camp this
                        summer are quite as destitute as those who were on our hands last
                    winter.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Discusses how equal pay for African-American troops actually results in
                    their receiving higher pay than white soldiers because the pay is based on the
                    size of family in need of support, and African-American families are larger than
                    white families.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Also on this page are a reprinted list of deserters from the 52nd Regiment of
                Virginia Volunteers, an article describing General Grant as a pork-and-beans man, an
                article on the unsuccessful attempt to expel Mr. Harris of Maryland from the United
                States Congress, articles on hog cholera and other miscellaneous topics,
                advertisements, and a poem.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1864.04.22.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Baggage of the 5th Va. Regiment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hardy</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Extra baggage of the 5th Virginia Regiment has arrived in Staunton and may
                    be picked up at Mr. J. M. Hardy's shop.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>To The Reserves</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>To the Reserves.</p>
                    <p>We call attention to the orders, published in another column, of Brig. Gen.
                        J.D. Imboden in reference to the organization of the Reserves.</p>
                    <p>By section III it will be seen that all applications for details or
                        exemptions by persons within the ages of 17 and 18 and 45 and 50 will be
                        forwarded to Gen. Imboden's Head Qr's. in stead of the Conscript Bureau for
                        action. This we doubt not will be especially agreeable to our people since
                        Gen. Imboden is so well acquainted with the needs of this section and will
                        be better able to do even handed justice to all than the Bureau at Richmond.</p>
                    <p>Those who should be detailed need not fear the result, only those who are
                        applying on some flimsy pretext in order to avoid service will bet he losers
                        by this change.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn>J. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Brig. General</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The editor alerts the readers to the orders, published in another column,
                    of Brig. General J. D. Imboden calling for the organization of Reserve troops.
                    The editor notes that applications for details or exemptions should go to
                    Imboden's headquarters instead of to the Conscript Bureau in Richmond, a
                    procedure particularly appealing to the people of Augusta County since Imboden
                    is so familiar with the needs of the area. In the same regard, those with flimsy
                    excuses will likely not receive exemptions because Imboden will know the
                    situations of true need.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor announces the appointment of Lieutenant Colonel C. S. Peyton of
                    Albemarle as enrolling officer for the congressional district and Lieutenant
                    Joseph E. Mallory of Louisa as enrolling officer of Augusta County. The editor
                    states that "no better appointments could have been made."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>Horatio</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Reverend</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ott</ln>
                        <fn>D. D. Enos</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCormick</ln>
                        <fn>Virginia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCormick</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf>Esquire</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Virginia McCormick, daughter of Robert McCormick, Esq., and D. D. Enos Ott,
                    all of Augusta County, married April 12, 1864, with Reverend Horatio Thompson
                    officiating.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>W. J. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Robert E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Robert E. Crawford, 48, died April 3, 1864, of typhoid fever, at the
                    residence of W. J. D. Bell near Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>A Card! To the Farmers of Southern Augusta</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koerner</ln>
                        <fn>P. W. Oscar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>1st Lieutenant</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>P. W. Oscar Koerner, First Lieutenant and Engineer, announces that
                    surveying parties will being in the area of south Augusta for the next two
                    months. They are gathering information for a map and have been working
                    throughout the Valley for some time. Koerner requests that farmers provide them
                    with supplies, at market value, and assures them that he has not impressed any
                    supplies.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Also on this page are other articles on the war, the text of special orders
                from General Imboden calling for the creation of Reserve troops, political
                announcements, and advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
