<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1864/va.au.rv.1864.02.19">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andrew Chancey</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/12/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>1st Pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 6/22/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1864-02-19">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day>19</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1864.02.19.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>A Picture for the War</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Gillian Gray</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gray</ln>
                        <fn>Gillian</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>This three-part story relates the experience of a mother cradling her son
                    Willie as a child, watching him go off to war eighteen years later, and then
                    having him die in battle.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>A Beautiful Extract</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"We copy the following beautiful extract from the Lenten Address of the
                    Right Rev. Bishop Johns, of the Protestant Episcopal church of Va., and commend
                    it to the attentive perusal of our readers."</commentary>
                <excerpt>"Our strength is not in the multitude of our hosts, but in the justice of
                    our cause . . ."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Bishop Johns uses the occasion of Lent to encourage Southerners not to be
                    discouraged. Instead, they must remember that God is on their side and may have
                    a more difficult path to peace planned for them than they can anticipate.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Only a Private</head>
                <origin>Atlanta Southern Confederacy</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Praises the role of the private and argues that the whole military service
                    rests on his presence.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Prospect</head>
                <origin>Richmond Whig</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Provides a positive assessment of the Confederate army and contrasts it
                    with the poor condition of the Union forces. For example, in the North, fewer
                    men are reenlisting, thereby filling the Union ranks with raw recruits. In
                    addition, these new enlistments join the army for the enlistment bounties rather
                    than because they believe in their cause.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Home Defence [sic]</head>
                <origin>[Richmond] Dispatch</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Home Defence.</p>
                    <p>It is said with, we hope, no just cause, that the House of Delegates intend
                        to defeat the plan propased [sic] by Governor Smith for rendering the
                        protection of the country against raids more efficient. We cannot see the
                        sense of such a proceeding, and we are well convinced that it will not be
                        popular. The people have already suffered too much from these marauding
                        expeditions, the avowed object of which is to produce a famine in the
                        country. A great outcry was raised against Congress for placing on the list
                        of conscription ite[m]s over forty-five engaged in agricultural labors, and
                        the reason given was that, unless a sufficient number was left at home,
                        supplies of provision could not be raised, and a famine must come. It
                        strikes us that such famine will fully as likely be the consequence of
                        destr[o]ying the crops after they shall have been raised, as of never
                        putting them in the ground.</p>
                    <p>It has been said that we cannot prevent these raids by an armed force. We
                        can, nevertheless, greatly diminish their number. We can compel the
                        marauders to act in large bodies, and thus greatly circumscribe the sphere
                        of their opperations [sic]. We can by this means greatly reduce the number
                        of slaves and cattle which they may have it in their power to carry off. We
                        very much doubt whether we may not put an end to such exploits altogether by
                        placing on a war footing a sufficient number of men, always ready to
                        assemble and give battle on the shortest notice. When Stoneman's men passed
                        through the country last summer they moved as though the avenger of blood
                        were behind them. They expected to be attacked, and were ready to fly at the
                        first appearance of an armed force. Had there been such a force they would
                        all have been killed or captured. The mere fear of encountering such an one
                        saved the country from a degree of pillage infinitely more destructive than
                        that which it experienced.</p>
                    <p>We hope the House of Delegates will think twice before they put this bill to
                        death. The country require[s] such measures as it inaugurates, and will not
                        be satisfied without them.--<emph rend="italic">Dispatch.</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The House of Delegates intends to defeat Governor Smith's plan for making
                    home guards more efficient. This editorial argues for increased support of the
                    home guards and contends that their expansion will greatly aid in staving off
                    raids.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Independence</head>
                <origin>Sumpter Watchman</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The South is moving towards independence in ways other than political, as
                    it is forced to manufacture its own products, supply its own cloth, and draw on
                    its own resources. The "pressure of necessity" has been beneficial for the
                    South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Enlistment of Colored Troops</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A resolution passed the United States House of Representatives recently
                    calling for a "more vigorous policy" in recruiting African-American troops. The
                    resolution passed eighty to forty-five.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Also on this page are a reprinted list of deserters from the 52nd Regiment of
                Virginia Volunteers, advertisements, and war news.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1864.02.19.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Central Lunatic Asylum</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stribling</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A report of the President and Directors of the Central Lunatic Asylum for
                    the period ending September 30, 1863, indicates that the asylum received 84
                    patients in the previous two years, cared for 464 patients, witnessed 133
                    patients be discharged, elope, or die. The institution has cared for 1828
                    patients in its history and has an average death rate of 5.96 percent. The staff
                    and administration have succeeded in preventing the spread of small pox, in
                    providing patients with necessary supplies, and in continuing their good work
                    even in the absence of the Superintendent, Dr. Stribling, who has been sick for
                    much of the past two years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Soldier Killed</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Soldier Killed.</p>
                    <p>About dusk on the 11th inst., Lt. David Ream of the 18th Va. Cavalry shot and
                        killed, near the Virginia Hotel, in this place, a member of Capt.
                        McClannahan's Battery, named Casper Phenenger, who approached on horseback,
                        to halt, which command Phenenger being unwilling or unable to obey, being
                        very much under the influence of liquor, Lt. Ream fired as Phenenger moved
                        beyond him, the ball entering the back on the left of the Spine, passing
                        through the lung and lodging near the skin on the right side. Phenenger fell
                        from his horse and expired in a few minutes. We were exceepingly [sic] sorry
                        that the occurrence took place but especially so from the fact that both
                        parties, were said to be excellent soldiers. The case will undergo
                        examination soon in a civil tribunal when the facts will be elicited.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ream</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieutenant</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phenenger</ln>
                        <fn>Casper</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lt. David Ream of the 18th Virginia Cavalry shot and killed Casper
                    Phenenger, a member of Captain McClanahan's Battery, at dusk on February 11 near
                    the Virginia Hotel in Staunton. Phenenger was intoxicated and ignored or did not
                    hear Ream's order to halt. Ream shot him from behind, and he fell from his horse
                    and died within a few minutes. A civil trial will elicit the facts in the case.
                    Both men were said to be excellent soldiers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Currency Tax and Military Bill</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Vindicator will publish the full bills in the next edition but offers a
                    summary of them here.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Announcements</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burnett</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>General</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William A. Burnett writes the editor of his willingness to run for clerk of
                    the county and of his qualifications for the position.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Negroes at Public Auction</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peck</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Peck and Taylor, Auctioneers, offer two African Americans for sale at
                    public auction on Monday, Court Day. One is female, age 16, and the other is
                    male, age 17.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>To the Preachers of the Baltimore Conference in Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A regular meeting of the Baltimore Conference of preachers is impractical
                    again this year, as it was in 1862 and 1863, but all who can participate will
                    gather in Bridgewater, Virginia, the second Thursday in March at 10:00 a.m. to
                    conduct business.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rennolds</ln>
                        <fn>T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. T. Rennolds, 68, died in Staunton January 28, 1864. He was born in
                    Caroline County in 1795 and moved to and began practice in Augusta County in
                    1827. The obituary praises his intellect, honesty, and character.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Also on this page are advertisements and war news.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
