<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1865/va.au.vv.1865.12.20">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>11/24/04</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1865-12-20">
            <year>1865</year>
            <month norm="12">December</month>
            <day norm="">20</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1865.12.20.01" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Fruit Belt of the Blue Ridge</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article discusses the abundant fruit production in the Blue Ridge
                    Mountains and surrounding areas.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Resources of Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Governor Pierpont went on a tour highlighting the mineral wealth of western
                    Virginia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>07</column>
                <head>The Geographical Position of Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article from Harper's Monthly for December argues that Virginia is
                    geographically well-situated to take advantage of western trade.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1865.12.20.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The State Legislature passed a bill funding the liabilities incurred before
                    July, 1865, of Staunton's Western Lunatic Asylum.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Valley Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Valley Virginian applauds the Staunton Spectator's stand in favor of
                    construction of the Valley Railroad.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The ladies of Tinkling Spring are planning a dinner at Fishersville to aid
                    the students of the Theological Seminary.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Virginians Buried at Gettysburg</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waller</ln>
                        <fn>L. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper prints a list compiled by L. B. Waller, of Staunton, containing
                    the Confederate Soldiers from Virginia units who are buried at Gettysburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Scraps From My Haversack (No. 3)</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper prints the third installment of a series recounting the campaigns
                    of Stonewall Jackson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>The Great Valley Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Mr. John W. Garrett, President of the Balt. &amp; O. R. R., by whose
                        magnificent management that road has risen to its present greatness and
                        prosperity, has been re-elected. In his report he shows the great benefits
                        to be derived by building a road through our great Valley and, as this is
                        our only chance for developing our resources, we hope the Legislature will
                        not hesitate to give the right of way to the Balt. &amp; O. R. R. Co.
                        The time for legislating to build up any particular city has passed and if
                        Richmond can't compete with Baltimore, then let Baltimore have the trade:
                        Mr. Garrett says:</p>
                    <p>In the new era that has opened, another subject of the greatest importance to
                        the country, and especially to the people of Virginia and Maryland, has been
                        presented. Many of the most distinguished citizens of Virginia have
                        expressed their anxiety of the early construction of a line of railway
                        leading from Harper's Ferry, threw Winchester and Strawsburg, to connect
                        with the great Virginia and Tennessee road in the southwestern part of the
                        State, and thus open a direct and effective line of communication from
                        Baltimore to New Orleans, presenting to the States of Virginia, Tennessee,
                        Georgia, Alabama, Mississippi, and Louisiana, an admirable, economical and
                        direct line to the national capital, and the great seat of commerce at the
                        head of the Chesapeake. The Valley of Virginia, fertile, rich in mineral
                        resources, with fine water power, with a most beautiful climate, possesses a
                        region of wonderful attractiveness and characteristics for great populations
                        and extensive development. The entire region through Virginia, Tennessee and
                        the connecting States, presents the greatest advantages for emigration, and
                        these advantages are sure to give absolute assurance of prosperity and
                        wealth.</p>
                    <p>During the existence of slavery in Virginia, a jealousy existed of any line
                        leading to the free States by which slave property became less safe. That
                        obstacle having been removed, all jealousies appear also to have ceased, and
                        I have been called upon by many of the most eminent and sagacious citizens
                        of that great State, who urge that the attention of the people of Baltimore,
                        and the managers of the Baltimore and Ohio Road, should be directed to this
                        subject. Their region has been desolated, their capital has been almost
                        destroyed, and now they are most anxious that the enterprise and capital of
                        this community shall be thrown to their aid, in accomplishing objects which,
                        whilst vastly benefiting them, will also yield a rich fruition in increasing
                        fraternity and commercial fraternity. Such a lind will accomplish much in
                        the restoration of kindly feelings, and assure mutual interests and the best
                        and greatest commercial advantages, and will aid in binding in iron bands
                        those great commonwealths to the union of our fathers.</p>
                    <p>A natural route, full of local and general advantages, is thus presented. It
                        is true that, whilst a portion of traffic which now comes up the Ohio river,
                        and is received by Western railways from the Southwest, thus passing over
                        the whole three hundred and seventy-nine miles of the Baltimore and Ohio
                        road, would, through a valley line, pass over but eighty miles of the main
                        stem; yet, in view of the great objects to be achieved for those interests,
                        and in securing a direct communication to Washington, and adding vastly to
                        the commercial strength and importance of Baltimore, I do not hesitate to
                        commend to the most earnest and favorable consideration of this community
                        and to this board this interesting subject.</p>
                    <p>The Baltimore and Ohio road built up the region of Virginia through which it
                        passes. It has aided largely in the construction of the Parkersburg road,
                        which has cost more than seven millions of dollars, and whilst it has
                        enormously increased business and prosperity upon that line and mad
                        millionaires of the owners of oil lands, of coal lands, and largely advanced
                        the values of all properties in that region, that road has thus far failed
                        directly in paying any interest upon the investment; yet in the future it is
                        believed that remuneration can be secured, whilst the general commerce of
                        Baltimore has been benefited, and that region so specially improved. Like
                        difficulties may embarrass the enterprise proposed, but its results in the
                        future will justify every effort in its behalf.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>John W. Garrett, President of the Baltimore and Ohio Railroad, speaks out
                    in favor of building the Valley Railroad. The road would allow the Valley of
                    Virginia to recover quickly from the war, foster reconciliation between the
                    sections, and provide Virginia with a link to the West. The editors argue that
                    as long as the Valley prospers, it does not matter if Baltimore or Richmond
                    benefits more from its trade.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Precautionary</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We do not think there is any ground for fear in regard to a "negro
                        insurrection" in this County, but to quiet any fear and show the remedy, we
                        publish the following order issued last month--</p>
                    <p>Sub-District of Staunton,<lb/> Staunton, VA., Nov. 13th 1865.<lb/> General
                        Order No. 7</p>
                    <p>In view of the repeated depredations committed in Augusta County, Va., the
                        citizens of said County are hereby authorized to organize parties to patrol
                        the County day and night, for the purpose of arresting the persons
                        committing the said depredations. Parties so organized have permission to
                        carry fowling pieces when patrolling, and will turn over such persons as
                        they may arrest, if Soldiers or Freedmen, to the Provost Marshal, if white
                        citizens to the Civil Authorities.<lb/> By Command of<lb/> Major Robert C.
                        Redman,<lb/> Commanding Sub-District<lb/> Antony A. Clay,<lb/> 1st Lieut.,
                        58th Pa., Vol., and A. A. A. G.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>These military orders allow Augusta citizens to organize night patrols to
                    cut down on the number of "depredations" in the area. The paper applauds the
                    measure even though the odds of "negro insurrection" are slim.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Price</ln>
                        <fn>Ellen</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Meridith</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Capt. Lewis Harman, 12th Va.Cavalry, Rosser's Brigade, and Miss Ellen Price
                    were married at the Winchester residence of the birde's father on December 13th
                    by the Rev. Mr. Meridith. "None but the brave deserve the fair."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Meeks</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rohdenizer</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. John Meeks and Miss Susan Rohdenizer, both of August, were married on
                    December 5th by Rev. E. Jones.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Long</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Funkhouser</ln>
                        <fn>Martha E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tallhems</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Benjamin F. Long, of Page County, and Miss Martha E. Funkhouser, of
                    Augusta, were married at the residence of the bride's father on November 22nd by
                    the Rev. Mr. Tallhems.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>James A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Holtz</ln>
                        <fn>Mary M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shirey</ln>
                        <fn>J. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. James A. Snyder and Miss Mary M. Holtz, both of Augusta, were married
                    near Middlebrook on November 30th by the Rev. J. D. Shirey.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dubley</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wiseman</ln>
                        <fn>Anne E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shirey</ln>
                        <fn>J. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. G. W. Dubley and Miss Anne E. Wiseman, both of Augusta, were married
                    near Middlebrook on November 30th by the Rev. J. D. Shirey. They were married at
                    the same time as the above.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hawks</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>R. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George W. Hawks, a member of Col. R. W. Baylor's Cavalry, died of
                    consumption on September 25, 1862. He was 23 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pelter</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Samuel Pelter, "long a citizen of this county," died on November 3rd at
                    his residence near Waynesboro. He was 63 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1865.12.20.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Over 180 people arrived at the American Hotel last week.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Darden</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Darden and Bros. are selling lady's walking shoes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Horse stealing is common in the lower valley.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richter</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Richter's Brewery is in full production, and is working on a double beer
                    "as good as ever."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peck</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>According to Captain Peck, the Gas Works will be back in full operation by
                    next week.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Warm and rainy weather has arrived after a "freezing cold" spell which gave
                    "the boys some fun skating."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kief</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lt. Kief was sentenced to 20 years in prison for the murder of Dr. Martin
                    of Albemarle.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A fair and supper will be held tonight at the Virginia Hotel. Admission is
                    25 cents for adults and 10 for children.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dold</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Dold of Lexington was appointed Deputy Collector of U. S. Internal
                    Revenue for Augusta, Rockbridge, Bath, Alleghany, Botetourt, and Highland
                    counties.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Religious</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duncan</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Staunton M. E. Church hosted the Rev. Dr. Duncan of Richmond who
                    "preached two eloquent and impressive sermons to large congregations.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Baylor of Augusta County introduced a bill in the legislature for
                    paying James W. Crawford for supplies furnished to the penitentiary during the
                    war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>A Christmas Fair</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The ladies of the Episcopal Church will be holding tonight's fair and
                    supper at the Virginia Hotel. "Besides a fine supper a magnificent assortment of
                    toys and Christmas gifts will be offered for sale."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Distinguished Arrival</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peck</ln>
                        <fn>W. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Brig. General W. R. Peck, Louisiana Brigade, "Army Valley District," who
                    was one of the "bravest and most noted officers of Gen. Stonewall Jackson's
                    Army," arrived in Staunton "and was warmly welcomed by his numerous friends."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echols</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Catlett</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper directs the intention of capitalists intent on making money to
                    iron, lead copper and other mineral lands offered for sale by Echols, Bell and
                    Catlett. The lands will be developed quickly and will make "immense fortunes" at
                    present prices.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>E. Clampus Vitus</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper advocates the reorganization of Staunton's E. Clampus Vitus
                    Society, and notes that Staunton was responsible for starting, under the name of
                    Town Ball, the "great National Game of Base Ball.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Should Be Fixed</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The fall of Mr. Jones into the creek reinforces the need to repair the
                    bridge opposite the hay scales.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Our Honored Dead</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Below we continue the list of our honored dead, buried in Thornrose Cemetery.</p>
                    <p>Virginians</p>
                    <p>Josiah Jordan, 25; John Come, 31; J. H. Golladay, 33; John O. Harris,
                        Caskey's Battery; J. A. Ellis, 23; G. W. Steele, 2; T. Craddock, 23; James
                        Moore, 37; Samuel Wilson, 48; Geo. L. Weaver, 1st Cavalry; Silvanus Hedrick,
                        25; John McMullen, 52; Wade Michael, 42; H. A. Kingree, 42; Grandville
                        Hundly, 42; Robert W. Walker, 21; David Pate, 58; James A. Terry, 42;
                        Pleasant Carter, 42; M. Bird, 31; Lt. M. M. Rider, 31; W. Folks, 31; Ephraim
                        Hartly, 17; C. J. Dodson, 23; T. B. Alexander, 2; Wm. A. Lemon, 31; J. J.
                        Robinson, 13th; J. D. Rhodes, Cutshaw's Battery; J. F. Crook, 37; George S.
                        Beufoot, 5; Alex Ingren, 52; J. Smith, 52; A. M. Willhellem, 2nd Va. Bat.;
                        Jas. Hedrick, 28; J. W. Peters, 5; Samuel Matheny, Alleghany Bat.</p>
                    <p>Georgia</p>
                    <p>Lt. B. T. Bland, 38; John C. Powers, 61; L. T. Hollis, 31; R. H. Edis, 61; L.
                        H. Smith, 13; H. H. Jones, 13; C. Rosser, 60; D. Pitts, 60; John Arding, 31;
                        S. Anderson, 38; W. H. Powers, 38; Jesse Williams, 26; A. Farmer, 38; T. M.
                        Wilson, 38; Geo. Adams, 13; R. W. Perkinson, 13; Jesse Boyce--; J. Allen,
                        13; Jas. Cooke, 60; J. Carlisle, 38; J. J. Brown, 12; J. A. Leonard, 1st
                        Lieut., P. A. C. S.; J. E. Dorset, 21; Henry Upchurch, 12; Dr. John F.
                        Tripp, 12; S. Colbert, 12; G. P. West, 38; M. G. Hodges, 38; M. Willis, 13;
                        H. J. Miller, 38; J. A. Cooke, 38; Lt. Gober, 38; A. K. Wigginton, 6; R. A.
                        Parkinson, 13; E. Danils, 26; A. Lewis--; J. W. Farston, 38; M. Jones,--; R.
                        F. Jones, 60; R. H. Evans, 26; M. F. Floyd, 26; W. Antony, 26; A. Myers, 26.</p>
                    <p>Louisiana</p>
                    <p>W. H. Wine, 9; Martin Brackey, 7; George W. Story, 9; Christopher Carrol, 14;
                        A. G. Murphy, 14; Lt. W. Mills, 9; Harrison Hobbs, 9; James Jacquet, 10.</p>
                    <p>Alabama</p>
                    <p>W. B. Dulan, 48; Henry Green, 47; J. T. Williams, 47.</p>
                    <p>North Carolina</p>
                    <p>H. H. Mickals,--</p>
                    <p>Texas</p>
                    <p>J. Michael, 5.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper prints a list of soldiers buried in Staunton's Thornrose
                    Cemetery.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1865.12.20.04" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>State Proxies and Directors</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Waddell of Augusta County wrote a resolution asking that the Committee
                    of Roads and Internal Navigation "withdraw all State Proxies and Directors from
                    the control and management of the public improvements," instead leaving state
                    interests to be managed in common with private stockholders; appoint inspectors
                    and accountants to examine annually the management of the improvements; and to
                    exchange the stock of the State in such improvements for "State stocks or bonds
                    at par."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
