<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1866/va.au.ss.1866.07.24">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>John Riedl</taggerName>
            <tagDate>05/30/00</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1866-07-24">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="07"/>
            <day>24</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1866.07.24.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Veto of the Freedmen's Bureau Bill</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Extracts of President Johnson's veto message, urging Congress to avoid
                    "class legislation, so well calculated to keep the public mind in a state of
                    uncertain expectation, disquiet and restlessness." The bill was passed over his
                    veto.</summary>
                <note>For a full transcript of the veto message see the 7/25/66 issue of the Valley
                    Spirit.</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>06</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>A. B.</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Disagreeing with an editorial in last week's Spectator, the author argues
                    that Virginia should be represented at the upcoming Philadelphia Convention and
                    calls on readers to "organize a great Constitutional Union Party."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Southern Devotion</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>That female energy and devotion which brought the grave of Washington, which
                        once erected a statute to Henry Clay, which, by deeds of mercy and kindness
                        lined the darkest clouds of our war with gleams of holy light, that
                        wonderful strength and love of woman, so beautiful in self-sacrificing
                        charity -- are now being felt throughout the Southern country. This is a
                        great and powerful element. It is a gigantic agent of benevolence.--It is by
                        means of fairs and other agencies, public and private raising the funds to
                        rebuild and repair our destroyed and desecrated churches; to found orphan
                        asylums; to furnish poor maimed soldiers with legs an arms; to feed, clothe,
                        shelter and educate the destitute children and windows of our Confederate
                        heroes, who left their loved ones only inheritance of their glory; to
                        relieve suffering and poverty caused by the war whenever they can find it --
                        these are the noble, lovely and immortal aims of that active sympathy and
                        charity which now emanate, in rays of holy effulgence all over the South,
                        under the magic invocation of woman's influence.</p>
                    <p>These efforts make no noise. They are silent but full of power. In our cities
                        and remote country towns, we see frequent notices what the "ladies will hold
                        a fair" on a certain day for certain benevolent purposes. This is all that
                        the public know about the matter. Charity and benevolence are not
                        ostentatious. They do not seek notoriety. But like drops of pure water on
                        granite in some retired dell, <emph rend="italics">they wear the
                        rock</emph>. So these humble, modest efforts of the women of the South are
                        making an impression upon the sordid selfishness of every community in
                        behalf of poverty and religion.</p>
                    <p>AS we have had occasion heretofore to remark, the city of Baltimore stands at
                        the head of these charitable movements. It is a proud and glorious
                        distinction to be leader in such a cause, and Baltimore never shone so
                        luminously as now. There we see both the means and inclination to do good
                        and relieve the sufferings of humanity. But here, in our own midst, tho' our
                        people have a hearty will, their means are contracted. Still this will find
                        a way to administer relief to our poor, who never needed aid as now.</p>
                    <p>It is highly creditable to the Southern heart and character that, in a
                        section when distress is universal, where the condition of the people
                        differs only in degrees of want and suffering, there should be so deep an
                        interest, so warm a sympathy for their destitute
                        fellow-citizens.--Especially are these remarks applicable to our ladies. It
                        demonstrates that the war has not crashed out and destroyed the most lovely
                        features in the character of our people. Whatever calamities have befallen
                        us it is a proud satisfaction to reflect that our hearts are still rich in
                        all that adorns and beautifies humanity. This is a treasure worth
                        preserving.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Praises the "ladies" of the South for keeping alive "the most lovely
                    features in the character of our people" by displaying "so warm a sympathy for
                    their destitute fellow-citizens."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1866.07.24.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Radical Caucus</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Excerpts from a recent caucus of Radical members of Congress. The author
                    concludes that "in brutal and revolutionary threats the Radicals at this caucus
                    passed far beyond the boundary which divides loyalty from treason."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1866.07.24.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News--Painful Accident</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitezell</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitezell</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George Whitezell, age 13, recently drowned while his cousin was attempting
                    to teach him to swim.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chaney</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Isaac Chaney, who was held in jail while awaiting transport to Richmond for
                    his execution, was hung last Monday. The rope snapped on the first attempt, and
                    Chaney reportedly took a chew of tobacco while the rope was adjusted.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mitchell</ln>
                        <fn>Lindsey</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Murray</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Two freedmen recently escaped from the local jail by sawing through the
                    grating. They were being held for larceny.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Editor of Spectator.--Sir:--I was sorry to see from the last number of your
                        paper that you are not inclined to favor the Philadelphia Convention. I
                        think you have come to your conclusion hastily and unadvisedly, and I hope
                        more mature consideration will induce you to abandon your opposition.</p>
                    <p>This Convention is called by the most conservative men in the North. Its
                        objects are to strengthen the hands of the President, and to restore the
                        true principles of the Constitution. Both of these objects are of vital
                        importance to the South. Gratitude to the President for all that he has done
                        to protect us from the aggressive policy of the Radicals, requires that we
                        should stand by him, and enlightened self-interest demands that we should
                        sustain those who are seeking to help us.</p>
                    <p>The call of the Convention is an overture by the conservatives of the North
                        for conciliation. If we reject it, or show a sullen indifference to it, we
                        shall occupy a false position before the country; and we will deprive the
                        proceedings of the Convention of much of the moral weight that would
                        otherwise belong to them.</p>
                    <p>By being present we may remove many prejudices, and gain and impart much
                        valuable information. We may give tone and shape to the action of the body.
                        If we stand back, and refuse to help ourselves, how can we expect other to
                        help us?</p>
                    <p>It is rumored, (and I believe truly,) that Millard Fillmore, Franklin Pierce,
                        R. C. Winthrop, Horatio Seymour, Washington Hunt, John A. Dix, Senators
                        Guthrie, Corwin, Doolittle and Davis, will all be present at the Convention.
                        We have nothing to fear, and every thing to hope from the action of men like
                        these.</p>
                    <p>Let Virginia and the others States be represented by their best men. Let us
                        show a disposition to do all that fair and honorable men can do to restore
                        harmony to our people. If contrary to our expectations, any disposition
                        should be manifested to do wrong to the South, her representatives can
                        easily withdraw. But I have no fears on this head. The Convention will bring
                        together the conservative elements of all parts of the country, and enable
                        them by proper organization, and concert of action, to banish the unclean
                        birds from their nests in Washington.</p>
                    <p>Surely this is an object which should address itself to the favorable regard
                        of every true patriot. Let us, then, meet our friends in council. Let us
                        explain to them our condition and wants, and source the co-operation of all
                        good men in establishing, the government of a firm foundation. The
                        Convention is the best means of doing this, and by all means let us end
                        delegates to it.</p>
                    <p>Augusta</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Augusta</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Disagreeing with a recent Spectator editorial, "Augusta" argues that
                    Southerners should support the Philadelphia Convention, which represents "an
                    overture by the conservatives of the North for conciliation."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gulley</ln>
                        <fn>George A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keblinger</ln>
                        <fn>Lutie F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>George B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lutie Keblinger and George Gulley were married in Staunton on July 19 by
                    Rev. George B. Taylor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1866.07.24.04">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
