<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1866/va.au.ss.1866.05.01">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>John Riedl</taggerName>
            <tagDate>05/22/00</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1866-05-01">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day>01</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1866.05.01.01">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1866.05.01.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Our Town</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scheffer</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>Francis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Points</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hope</ln>
                        <fn>R. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hotchkiss</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kline</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hall</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>G. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Praises the "spirit of improvement" animating Staunton, as evidenced in
                    "all sorts of improvements which promise a profitable return."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1866.05.01.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>J. Marshall</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Marshall McCue, presiding Justice of the County Court, was unanimously
                    reelected.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News--To Be Hung</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A black man held in the local jail for some time will be transported to
                    Richmond where he will be hung next Friday. He was found guilty of killing a man
                    and his wife and burning their house.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Mr. Editor:--You will be kept busy to notice all the dark, sneaking,
                        underhanded a petitions, which are being circulated among a certain class of
                        our citizens, for sinister and unworthy purposes. To-day, (the 26) my
                        attention has been called to one, said to have been prepared, by that <emph
                            rend="italics">creature</emph>, Dews, who has brought disgrace upon the
                        worthy <emph rend="italics">freedmen</emph> of our county, by being made a
                        member of their Court.--Have not seen the petition, but learn that it has
                        been numerously signed by the so-called Union men of Pendleton county, known
                        as "Swamps," and is <emph rend="italics">now</emph> circulating in this
                        county. <emph rend="italics">Here</emph>, it is presumed, it will be
                        cheerfully signed by that class of our people, who, under the late monstrous
                        and outrageous order of that <emph rend="italics">martinet</emph>, at
                        Richmond, one Gen. Terry, assembled in our Court House a few weeks since, to
                        say under oath, whether men of their kidney, could <emph rend="italics">get
                            justice</emph> done them before our civil tribunals.--I am one, Mr.
                        Editor, who thinks they cannot <emph rend="italics">get justice</emph>, but
                        in a view entirely different from a certain ex-Capt. of Militia, residing
                        about four miles from your town, who said he did not believe that nay one
                        who thought and felt as he did, during the war, could get a show of
                        justice," at the hands of our Courts. But to the petition. It has been
                        gotten up for, and at the instance of, a certain individual living in White
                        Oak Lick, on the road, <emph rend="italics">via</emph> North River Gap, to
                        Pendleton county. This individual, for a short time, carried water
                        successfully <emph rend="italics">on both shoulders</emph>, in the early
                        part of the war. For some months Gen. Ed. Johnston employed him as a guide
                        and scout to his forces, whilst on Alleghany. Even at that time, he was
                        aiding the enemy. Afterwards his house became the rendez-vous of deserters
                        from our ranks, as well as those who ran off before they were placed in the
                        army, and he piloted them thro' successfully to New Creek and other points
                        and brought back the mail for their friends from the now numerous class of
                        deserters <emph rend="italics">within</emph> the Yankee lines. Coming under
                        the suspicion of the authorities, his premises were on one occasion invested
                        by some of Capt. Avis' guard, and this <emph rend="italics">same
                        individual</emph> killed one of them from his own domicil.</p>
                    <p>All familiar with his premises know that ever since he has lived there, near
                        a quarter of a century or more, it would puzzle a dozen wayfaring sheep to
                        survive, from year's end to year's end. This petition represents to the
                        Congress of the United States that this most devoted and self-sacrificing
                        Union man, had his <emph rend="italics">valuable</emph> property destroyed
                        by the rebels, and asks thousands of dollars of indemnity. For the several
                            <emph rend="italics">thousands</emph> of <emph rend="italics"
                        >deserters</emph> he aided, in running thro' to Yankeedom, he asks heavy
                        remuneration.--For the God's service he rendered in murdering one of his own
                        countrymen perhaps; he asks at the hands of Stevens, Sumner &amp;c.,
                            <emph rend="italics">big pay</emph>.--This is a faint outline of what
                        this infamous papers, prepared by <emph rend="italic">Dews's</emph> hands
                        and for a most unworthy individual, is being circulated for.--<emph
                            rend="italics">What next</emph> do you ask?</p>
                    <p>WE WILL SEE</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>We Will See</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dews</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Claims that "dark, sneaking, underhanded petitions" are circulating in the
                    area "for sinister and unworthy purposes."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Judge Lucas P. Thompson</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>Lucas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Michie</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>A. H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echols</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henderson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Resolutions issued from a meeting of the Staunton Bar praising the recently
                    deceased Judge Lucas P. Thompson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lawrence</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James Lawrence died on April 19 at age 67.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1866.05.01.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Foreshadowed Fate of the Negro</head>
                <origin>Richmond Examiner</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Claims that blacks in the South are "destined to extinction," a fate that
                    will prove "a merciful deliverance, not to the South alone, nor to the North,
                    but to the ill-starred negro himself."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
