<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1866/va.au.ss.1866.02.20">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>John Riedl</taggerName>
            <tagDate>05/08/00</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1866-02-20">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day>20</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1866.02.20.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Interview Between Mr. Johnson And The Virginia Delegation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Summary of a meeting between President Johnson and a delegation of white
                    Virginians who urged the President to continue his current course.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1866.02.20.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Prospect Before Us</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Matters are fast tending to an issue at Washington. The President is
                        determined to stand by the Constitution and the Radicals are equally
                        determined to disregard it. A collision, therefore, between the Executive
                        and Congress seems imminent -- one or the other must back down, or a fearful
                        contest must ensue. The President cannot back down. His oath of the office
                        forbids it. He has sworn to support the Constitution, and all his measures,
                        heretofore, have been directed to that end.</p>
                    <p>On the other hand, the Radicals are obstinate and ferocious and fatally bent
                        on mischief.</p>
                    <p>We must confess we can see the peaceful solution of the difficulty. Slighter
                        disagreements have, in other countries, been referred to the arbitrament of
                        the sword.</p>
                    <p>How do matters now stand? The President assume -- and properly assumes --
                        that the Southern States did not succeed in getting out of the Union. They
                        made the attempts, but failed. Their rights, as members of the Union, were
                        suspended, but not annihilated. When they conform to the coalitions required
                        of them, they are entitled to be restored to all their rights as co-equal
                        States.</p>
                    <p>This they have, in good faith, done, and the President, carrying out the
                        pledges given both by Mr. Lincoln and himself, will shortly issue his
                        proclamation declaring that the rebellion is over the Union restored -- and
                        that the Southern States are entitled to all their rights and duties as
                        co-States, including the right to be represented in Congress.</p>
                    <p>The Radicals deny the President's theory.--They say that the Southern States
                        were out of the Union, and have been conquered. That they now stand as
                        conquered provinces, with no constitutional rights, and subject to such
                        terms sa the dominant party may impose of them.</p>
                    <p>It is easy to see the motive which prompts the Radicals to falsify their own
                        declarations, and assume a position so much at war with the Constitution,
                        with justice and with common sense.</p>
                    <p>Their object is to perpetuate their own power. They wish to retain a
                        two-thirds majority in Congress so as to override the action of the
                        President, and, if need be, to override the President himself. They are
                        unwilling to let Southern Representatives into Congress because they know
                        that Southern members would stand by the President and frustrate their
                        unhallowed and revolutionary plans.</p>
                    <p>What is to be the next act in the grand drama? Time only can disclose the
                        answer to this question.</p>
                    <p>Suppose the President issues his proclamation declaring all the States <emph
                            rend="italics">in</emph> the Union and entitled to representation in
                        Congress -- what next?</p>
                    <p>Congress will refuse to admit them. Will it not then be the duty of the
                        President to refuse to acknowledge the authority of this "rump parliament,"
                        which persists in disregarding the Constitution, by excluding men having as
                        good a right as themselves to seats in Congress?</p>
                    <p>The Constitution provides for representation <emph rend="italics">of all the
                            States</emph>. Is Congress properly organized until it yields obedience
                        to this provision of the Constitution?</p>
                    <p>What is rebellion but resistance to the Constitution, and laws of the U. S.
                        passed in pursuance thereof? Rebellion may be made by Congress as well as by
                        common people.</p>
                    <p>One of the highest duties of the President is to suppress unjustifiable
                        rebellion, come from what quarter it may.</p>
                    <p>He has fulfilled what he conceived to be his duty in regard to the Southern
                        States. Their rebellion has been put down.</p>
                    <p>Is he now to stand by, and see rebellion raise its head in other quarters,
                        without seeking to crush it? We think not. We think it is his duty to
                        suppress unjustifiable rebellion, come from what quarter it may, and to
                        employ such agencies as are necessary to accomplish the end.</p>
                    <p>Suppose this "rump-parliament" were, in a moment of reckless desperation, to
                        seek to impeach, and remove the President? By their constitutional exclusion
                        of Southern members, they may have the numerical strength to do it. Would
                        the President fulfill his duty to the country, by standing by, passively,
                        and allowing himself to be made the victims of Danton, Marat and Robespierre
                        -- re-incarnated in the persons of Stevens, Sumner and Howe?</p>
                    <p>We think not. We think it is his duty to protect himself, as the embodiment
                        of the Executive government.</p>
                    <p>If no milder means will avail, the Constitution gives him, as
                        commander-in-chief, the right to employ the military power to save the
                        Constitution and preserve the Union.</p>
                    <p>Possibly if some of the Congressional rebels were indulged with quarter, free
                        of charge, in the case-mates of Fortress Monroe, their health and possibly
                        their manners, might be benefitted. This may be a new phase of the "Monroe
                        doctrine," but we think it would prove more wholesome to the body politic
                        than the original pronunciamento.</p>
                    <p>We are for equal and impartial justice. Rebellion has been whipped out of us
                        of the South by force of arms. We have knocked under.--We have thrown
                        secession and rebellion to the winds. We recognize our duty and allegiance
                        to the government of the U. S. But we wish the same measure of compulsion --
                        the same salutary discipline extended to other offenders.--We are for
                        putting down rebellion come from what source it may, and show itself in what
                        form it may. The rebellion of 1861 was hatched in Congress. By delaying the
                        suppression too long, time was given for the brood to spread itself over the
                        whole South. President Johnson had better profit by experience and crush
                        this second rebellion in <emph rend="italics">the nest</emph>.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that "a collision" between Johnson and Congress "seems imminent" and
                    urges Johnson to crush the rebellion of "Danton, Marat, and
                    Robespierre--re-incarnated in the persons of Stevens, Sumner, and Howe."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Freedmen-$125,000</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Uses a Philadelphia Quaker subscription to establish a freedmen's school as
                    a pretext for encouraging emigration. The author asks "why should our Israelites
                    not go to the land of promise in Massachusetts?"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Nominations for Judges</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>L. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A list of nominations for judgeships, including Hugh Sheffey for Augusta
                    county.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>A Good Shot</head>
                <origin>Rockingham Register</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Byers</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A debate between the Spectator and the Rockingham Register over the issue
                    of which county is home to greater marksmen, since men in each county have
                    recently downed bald eagles.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Loyns</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cease</ln>
                        <fn>Harriet</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J. I.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Henry Loyns and Harriet Cease were married on Feb. 15th by Rev. J. I.
                    Miller.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greiner</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGuffin</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pinkerton</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Greiner and Susan McGuffin were married on February 8th by Rev.
                    William Pinkerton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hester</ln>
                        <fn>Parmelia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ast</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Parmelia Hester died at the residence of her father on January 5th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1866.02.20.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Painter</ln>
                        <fn>Julia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Julia Painter, of Greenville, was charged with hog stealing and placed in
                    jail.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Levell</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>O'Hare</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James Levell was committed to jail last Wednesday, charged with knowingly
                    passing counterfeit money.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News--A Sad Death</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mayse</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James Mayse, "an old citizen," froze to death last Friday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News--Baptist Fair</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hiden</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnitz</ln>
                        <fn>P. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that the Baptist Fair held at the Virginia Hotel in Staunton was a
                    success, raising over 500 dollars for the repair of the Baptist church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News--A Debt To Departed Soldiers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Calls for subscriptions to improve the status of "cemetery hill," where the
                    graves of Confederate soldiers are in an "exposed condition."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamilton</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tate</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Geeding</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hailman</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walters</ln>
                        <fn>B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Proceedings of the Churchville Agricultural Club, which convened last week.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Mass Meeting of the People of Augusta</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woodward</ln>
                        <fn>S. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stribling</ln>
                        <fn>Francis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garber</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Price</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>A. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pitzer</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>P. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kayser</ln>
                        <fn>Davis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>F. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lara</ln>
                        <fn>A. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Timberlake</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harper</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eidson</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf>Sr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McChesney</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>Edwin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trotter</ln>
                        <fn>A. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baskin</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Catlett</ln>
                        <fn>N. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stevenson</ln>
                        <fn>L. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mason</ln>
                        <fn>C. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allan</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bledsoe</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Witz</ln>
                        <fn>I.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>A. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>Bolivar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Michie</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shelton</ln>
                        <fn>T. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>H. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>J. Wayt</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Calls for all "citizens" of Augusta to assemble on the next court day to
                    express their support for President Johnson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1866.02.20.04">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
