<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1866/va.au.ss.1866.02.06">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>John Riedl</taggerName>
            <tagDate>4/21/00</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1866-02-06">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day>06</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1866.02.06.01">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1866.02.06.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Unionists and Disunionists</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Who are the Union men, at this time, in the true and proper acceptation of
                        that term, and who are the disunionists? Those who are in favor of the Union
                        as it existed before the war, who are supporters of the Constitution and of
                        the rights and immunities it guarantees, who desire peace and amity between
                        the people of all the States who favor the admission into the Congress of
                        Representatives from all the States who possess the <emph rend="italics"
                            >Constitutional</emph> qualifications, who recognize the equality of
                        rights in the citizens of the several States, are, by whatever name they may
                        be called, Union men in the true sense and proper acceptation of the term.</p>
                    <p>On the contrary, those who oppose the Union as it existed before the war, who
                        violate the Constitutional and deny to any the rights and immunities it
                        guarantees, who create distrust, dissension and discord between the people
                        of the State, who deny admission into Congress of Representatives who
                        possess all the <emph rend="italics">Constitutional</emph> qualifications,
                        who deny equal rights to the citizens of the several States, are, by
                        whatever name they may be called, disunionists.--The extreme men in the
                        North and the3 extreme men in the South who claim to be, <emph
                            rend="italics">par excellence</emph>, the Union men, are, in fact, the
                        disunionists of the two sections of the Union. President Johnson is a Union
                        men, and the policy he maintains, and which he would have all others to
                        maintain, is a Union policy. He wishes to restore the Union as it was before
                        the war, with all the rights of the citizens of all the States unimpaired.
                        He says that the people of the Southern States "should be trusted."--They
                        have not only acknowledged their defeat stacked arms and abandoned the
                        contest for independence, but have solemnly sworn to support the
                        Constitution of the United States.--They are no longer secessionists, but
                        have all become, in the true sense of the term, Union men. Those who are
                        unwilling to "trust the people of the South," who maintain that they should
                        not be granted the rights belonging to citizens of the States <emph
                            rend="italics">in</emph> the Union, who are in favor of governing the
                        Southern States as conquered provinces, who maintain that they should be
                        ruled by a military authority, are neither Union men nor the friends of
                        Republican government. There are, unfortunately, much in the North and in
                        the South -- in the North, they are numerous, and have a majority of
                        Representatives in Congress; in the South, the number is small. Though these
                        extremes <emph rend="italics">profess</emph> to be Union men, they are <emph
                            rend="italics">disunionists</emph> of the very word character. Under the
                        guise of Union men, they labor, "with might and main" -- openly in the
                        North, secretly in the South -- to prevent the restoration of the Union, and
                        to destroy the Republican character of the Government. As hypocrites in
                        religion</p>
                    <p>"Steal the livery of Heaven</p>
                    <p>To serve the Devil in,"</p>
                    <p>so these impostors in politics, assume the mask of Unionism the more
                        effectually to perpetrate their vile disunion purposes. These extremes,
                        North and South, are co-operating to effect the same object -- the
                        prevention of the restoration of the Union, and the denial to the people of
                        the South of their Constitutional rights in the Union. those who petition
                        the authorities to keep the citizens of the South under military rule, who
                        represent that the people of the South should not be trusted, that they are
                        indisposed to grant injustice to any class of citizens, are co-operating
                        with the Radicals of the North, who are making was upon the Union policy of
                        the President. Thought this party is small in the South, yet its members
                        have the power to do more harm to the people of the South than ten times
                        their number at the North, for their misrepresentations of Southern
                        sentiment are considered by the North as true representations of Southern
                        feeling. An enemy to the restoration of the Union and to Republican
                        Government in the South will affect the greatest dread; and, with pallid
                        cheeks and trembling frame, will avow to the authorities that his life is in
                        peril, that the cannibal secesh will be sure to devour him if they be not
                        bound hand and foot by the strong bonds of military authority. He makes such
                        and other false avowals knowing that that is the most effectual way to
                        effect the base and treacherous purposes of his heart. Let no man who is in
                        truth a Union man suffer himself to be deceived and imposed upon by wolves
                        in sheeps' clothing.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that those who seek to restore the Union as it existed before the
                    war are the true Unionists and those "who deny equal rights to the citizens of
                    the several States" are the disunionists.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Memorials, Secret Petitions, &amp;c.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dews</ln>
                        <fn>W. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Details the latest developments in a controversy involving W. J. Dews, who
                    served on the Freedmen's Court and, according to reports, has been circulating
                    petitions of an unknown character.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>W. J. Dews</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It is patent, we think, to the observation of all men who have the least
                        perception, that W. J. Dews is anxious to provoke an assault upon himself
                        through the Press that he may occupy the position of a persecuted Union men,
                        that he may gain that kind of notoriety which would enable him to get some
                        more desirable position than the one he at present holds, and also a <emph
                            rend="italics">pretext to have troops sent to this place</emph>. We
                        readily assented to allow him to correct any misrepresentations which may
                        have been in the article we published last week. Whilst we acknowledge no
                        obligation to allow him to do more, we yet grant him, as an act of grace,
                        the privilege of publishing the article he furnished, though it seems to
                        have been written more with the view to provoke such comments from us as
                        would subserve the purposes we have mentioned than to correct misstatements,
                        which might have been done with a few lines. "In vain is a net set in the
                        sight of any bird." We will not walk into the meshes he has spread. If the
                        public interests were not involved, we might gratify his vanity by
                        commenting in such terms as we might feel inclined to use. We refrain, from
                        the motives mentioned, from indulging in comment or repartee, and refer our
                        readers to his communication that they may judge of his motives, and of the
                        wisdom of the course we have adopted. This view of his motives is confirmed
                        by the fact that he has sent communications to every paper in this place.
                        Like the Irishman at Donnybrook fair, he is exceedingly anxious for some one
                        to tread on the rail of his coat.</p>
                    <p>It is due to our informants to say, that they are gentleman of character and
                        veracity and in no wise connected with the rebellion.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that W. J. Dews is attempting to goad the editors into casting
                    aspersions upon him so that he can posture as a persecuted Union man and bring
                    federal troops back to Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>A Glimpse of Light</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Praises the passage of a bill authorizing the creation of the first link of
                    the Valley railroad.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>To The Editor of the "Spectator."</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We have been informed that Mr. Richard Mauzy, a man living in this place",
                        took occasion, in the last issue of his paper, to comment in regard to a
                        petition which he had learned was being circulated in this vicinity; and
                        that he further "made bold" to hurl his thunderbolts (Jove like) at my
                        devoted and unprotected self.</p>
                    <p>First, "ye Editor" saith that I "was chosen by the Freedmen's Court." Further
                        he saith that since the soldiers left "no Freedmen have been mistreated."
                        Again he speaketh and says, (in regard to the petition,) "the petition was
                        not shown to the citizens of the town, but taken some distance into the
                        country." Again he affirmeth that "petitions secretly circulated should be
                        brought to light." And there he asketh, feelingly, "upon what
                        representations were the signatures of the signers obtained.--And then he
                        again asketh, with touching tenderness, "will not one or more signers
                        apprise us, that the public may know, and that they may stand justified"? He
                        further appealeth to <emph rend="italics">somebody</emph>, and saith, as
                        gently as the dew falls upon the blushing Rose, "are not the citizens
                        peaceable, quiet harmless." Further he saith, with Roman dignity, "when we
                        desire or need them, we will ask for them ourselves"!</p>
                    <p>"The people of the South who are sending such petitions to the President, as
                        spoken of in the above dispatch, under the name of "Union men," are not, in
                        truth, true Union men, but trifling characters who have gotten into some
                        positions which they do not deserve to fill where they can exercise "a
                        little brief authority, and desire to retain them, and, do so bring reproach
                        upon better citizens by assuming to call themselves "Union men."</p>
                    <p>It is proper, now, for me to say that I called upon the Editor of the
                        "Spectator," after carefully perusing the article in question, and asked him
                        if he vouched for the <emph rend="italics">truth</emph> of the assertions
                        contained in the article, or was he simply <emph rend="italics"
                        >informed</emph> that the assertions embraced in the article were true. He
                        replied that he <emph rend="italics">did not</emph> vouch for their
                        truthfulness, that he received <emph rend="italics">information</emph> that
                        the assertions were true. This statements is given in justice to myself and
                        the Editor.</p>
                    <p>I now pronounce all assertions relating to myself <emph rend="italics"
                        >false</emph>, including the <emph rend="italics">alleged</emph> fact that I
                        was chosen by the Freedmen as their Judge in Freedmen's Court. I except the
                        fact of my originating "that petition;" and I assert the fact that there is
                        nothing in "that petition" that will induce any ill feeling <emph
                            rend="italics">whatever</emph> between persons of different political
                        sentiments. And I further remark that no person has imbibed such
                        impressions; nor has any former Confederate evinced any interest to see the
                        petition, except the Editors of Staunton. May Allah preserve them. At least
                        if such a desire has been manifested, it was not to me.</p>
                    <p>With a reference to the application of the term "trifling characters" to the
                        signers of petitions, in the paragraph above quoted, I will say that the
                        Editor disclaims any intention to apply the offensive terms to the signers
                        of the petition <emph rend="italics">now in my possession</emph>. Hence
                        there is nothing to reply to or controvert. The Editor has killed himself
                        (not literally, however, thank Heaven,) with his own hand, and it only
                        remains for the disconsolate mourners to assemble, with tearful eyes, around
                        his grave and scatter freshly culled flowers thereon -- retire remembering
                        his many virtues and sobbing in the fullness of their hearts.</p>
                    <p>"Twas thine own order gave the final blow,</p>
                    <p>And helped to give the wound that laid him low;</p>
                    <p>So the struck eagle, stretched upon the plain,</p>
                    <p>No more through rolling clouds to soar again,</p>
                    <p>Viewed his own feather on the fatal dart,</p>
                    <p>And winged the shaft that quivered in his heart."</p>
                    <lb/>
                    <p>And -- that's all.</p>
                    <lb/>
                    <p>William J. Dews.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>William J. Dews</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mauzy</ln>
                        <fn>Richard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dews</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William J. Dews responds to an article in the previous issue of the
                    Spectator which alleged questionable motives in relation to his circulation of a
                    petition.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1866.02.06.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News--A Serious Accident</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCutchen</ln>
                        <fn>Philander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Philander McCutchen was thrown from his horse yesterday and fractured his
                    skull. His condition is believed to be critical.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News--A Sad Accident</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dudley</ln>
                        <fn>Washington</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamilton</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dudley Washington suffered a badly broken leg on Monday and is reported to
                    be suffering greatly.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Soiree at the Seminary</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ettinger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClung</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that the soiree at the Augusta Female Seminary last Wednesday
                    demonstrated an admirably managed institution.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Concerts</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the two concerts given at the local Presbyterian church were
                    highly successful and entertaining.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>W. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coyner</ln>
                        <fn>Barbara</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennerly</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>W. A. Hanger and Barbara Coyner were married on January 28 by Rev. Samuel
                    Kennerly.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1866.02.06.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Woman</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Mrs. Stevens offers her ruminations on the nature of woman, concluding that
                    "woman is a miracle, a mystery."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
