<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1866/va.au.ss.1866.11.06">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>John Riedl</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/26/00</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1866-11-06">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="11">November</month>
            <day>06</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1866.11.06.01">
            <div type="l">
                <column>06</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>John B. Baldwin</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Baldwin proposes to introduce a bill during the next session of the
                    Legislature that would establish and incorporate the Augusta County Fair.
                    Includes a copy of the proposed bill.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1866.11.06.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Home Manufactures</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We have frequently urged upon the people of the South the propriety of
                        engaging to a much greater degree than heretofore in manufactures of all
                        kinds, and have mentioned many advantages possessed by the South for
                        engaging successfully in that branch of industry. Labor employed in
                        manufactures is much more remunerative than when employed in raising grain
                        or ever cotton. The conversion of cotton by manufactures into the plainest,
                        commonest and cheapest cloth doubles, trebles and quadruples its value. It
                        only requires one-third as many hands to manufacture as it does to raise a
                        certain amount of cotton. It will be seen then that if the conversion of the
                        raw material into cloth or yarn only doubles its value one-third of the
                        number of hands required to raise the cotton make as much money as all the
                        hands employed in raising the crop. In other words, the labor employed in
                        manufactures is at least <emph rend="italics">three</emph> times as
                        profitable as that employed in raising the raw material. When our readers
                        remember that the culture of cotton is more profitable than raising any kind
                        of grain, they will be able to see how very profitable manufactures are. As
                        the South raises the raw material, if it act wisely, it can have the benefit
                        of all the profits of both planting and manufacturing. Even now, the infant
                        factories in Georgia ship them North, and then sell them at a profit to
                        Southern merchants. What we have said of cotton applies to factories of all
                        kinds. It is the duty of the people of the South to encourage and patronize
                        factories of all kinds which are established in the South. Money should not
                        be sent off to benefit other communities when it can be expended for the
                        same articles at home.</p>
                    <p>A small amount of money kept in the community will pay hundreds of debts and
                        relieve hundreds of people. Money sent abroad is so much lost to the
                        community. If there be factories in the neighborhood or county or State
                        which can supply the article you need, do not send off to other
                        neighborhoods, counties or States for them. Keep the money at home.--To
                        illustrate -- if our merchants wish to buy brooms, they should buy them from
                        the factory recently established at Churchville -- if they wish to keep for
                        sale any articles, (stoves for instance) manufactured at our foundries they
                        should buy them of those who make them here, and so of any articles made in
                        any kind of factories in our county or State.</p>
                    <p>Every Southern State should now be busily engaged in establishing factories
                        of all kinds.--The State of Georgia is leading off handsomely in the right
                        direction. Georgia has seventy-two mills for the manufacture of cotton and
                        woollen goods now in the course of construction, some of which will
                        manufacture calicoes. Upon which the Mobile Gazette comments: Well done,
                        Georgia! that is the way to reconstruct yourself. But would it not be funny,
                        if one of these days, our friend, Alexander H. Stephens, should be found
                        voting in the Senate of the United States, along with tariff-king, Morrill,
                        for high duties on cotton goods, to protect Georgia manufactures?</p>
                    <p>After Rome had conquered Greece, by force of arms, Greece turned around and
                        conquered Rome, by literature, and the arts, and sciences. If in process of
                        time, cotton growing States should manufacturing all their own raw material
                        -- and this our policy -- would not New England be flat of her back? Like
                        Macaulay's New Zealander, sitting on the ruins of London Bridge, and
                        wondering what people once inhabited the great city, some future traveler
                        might wander to Lowell, and ask for an explanation of the wreck and ruin
                        around him. The answer would be, that Georgia, soon after the war, put up
                        seventy-two cotton mills, and the other cotton States followed her example.</p>
                    <p>P. S. -- After the above was put in type, we received the National <emph
                            rend="italics">Intelligencer</emph> containing the following in
                        reference to the profits of manufacturing in New England:</p>
                    <lb/>
                    <p>"The very large dividends made by the manufacturing companies of the Eastern
                        States, for some years past, have stimulated inquiry, if not competition, in
                        other States. The best business that is done in the country is in
                        manufactures. If joint-stock companies, with large operations, the success
                        of which depends upon the fidelity and skill of salaried agents can divide
                        from twenty to forty per cent a year among the shareholders, how much more
                        profitable are smaller mills, or private work, that are conducted under the
                        vigilant personal superintendence of their individual owners!</p>
                    <p>The demand for domestic goods of all kinds is on the increase. Their
                        consumption is yearly increasing. The manufactures of New England are now
                        the most profitable branch of business there, or anywhere in the country. So
                        far as their prosperity depends upon the present high tariff, it will
                        continue for years, for while the public debt remains the revenue from the
                        customs will not be much reduced. The first reduction of the revenue that
                        will be effected, after the debt shall be diminished to moderate proportion,
                        will be in the internal taxation.</p>
                    <p>In this state of things it will be surprising indeed if New England can find
                        no competition, in the best business that is open to enterprise, either in
                        the Middle, Western, or Southern States."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Encourages Southerners to "keep the money at home," arguing that "every
                    Southern State should now be busily engaged in establishing factories of all
                    kinds." Georgia, the article suggests, is offering a model of enterprise for
                    other Southern states to follow.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Augusta County Fair</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Supports the proposed bill to establish an Augusta County Fair found on
                    another page of the Spectator and suggests that it could help make Augusta
                    county "by far the most prosperous county in the State."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Encourages "the people of the South" to "avoid all partnerships and all
                    entangling alliances" with Conservatives in the North and instead to "paddle our
                    own canoe." Suggests that eventually the political support of the South will be
                    sought out since "disfranchisement and ostracism cannot long continue in a
                    country whose boast is freedom."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Cause of the War</head>
                <origin>Baltimore Evening Transcript</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues "that slavery was not the cause, but only the occasion of the
                    war--that Puritanism was the true cause of the war."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1866.11.06.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News--Mr. J. C. Johnston Discharged</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>Patrick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnston</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. C. Johnston, who was charged with shooting and killing Patrick Thompson
                    in Lexington and arrested in Fishersville, was discharged from court in
                    Lexington.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that, while several persons in the county have recently died of
                    neglected diarrhea and cholera morbus, "there is no cause for panic and special
                    dread." Residents are encouraged "to be careful in their diet."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>R. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>Rachel E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Wilson and Rachel Hanger were married on November 1 by Rev. R. G.
                    Walker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dull</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jacob Dull died suddenly on November 1. He was 60.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cashman</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Michael Cashman died on October 31. He was about 60 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1866.11.06.04">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
