<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1866/va.au.ss.1866.04.03">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>John Riedl</taggerName>
            <tagDate>05/17/00</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1866-04-03">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day>03</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1866.04.03.01">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1866.04.03.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Duty to Dead Soldiers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In our issue of the 20th of February we mentioned the fact that "a brigade of
                        noble souls and gallant soldiers, about 2,000 in number, who not only
                        perilled, but sacrificed their lives in defence of the South, were sleeping
                        the sleep which knows no waking on the Cemetery Hill of this place," and
                        urged upon our people the duty of subscribing money for the purpose of
                        enclosing their graves in proper style, and decorating them with sod and
                        flowers and shrubbery. We expected an immediate and satisfactory response,
                        but are pained to confess that we were disappointed. These soldiers did
                        their duty towards us when living, shall we fail to do our duty towards
                        them, now that they are dead. When living, they performed their duty
                        bravely, lagged not in the rear, but formed</p>
                    <lb/>
                    <p>"A picture in the foreground,</p>
                    <p>Nigh the flashing of the guns."</p>
                    <lb/>
                    <p>They will no more endure the "pelting of the pitiless storm" of leaden
                        missiles, nor hear the stunning thunder of artillery, nor feel the terrible
                        shock of contending hosts, for</p>
                    <lb/>
                    <p>"On Fame's eternal camping ground,</p>
                    <p>Their silent tents are spread,</p>
                    <p>And Glory guards with solemn round</p>
                    <p>The bivouac of the dead."</p>
                    <lb/>
                    <p>The appeal we made to the men in our issue of the 20th of February was
                        unheeded, but it reached the willing cars, and touched the tender hearts of
                        the women and we now feel confident that the object desired will be
                        accomplished through their instrumentality. A committee of ladies of this
                        place, representing every congregation in town has been organized for the
                        purpose of securing subscriptions to defray the expense of enforcing the
                        graves of those who were buried on the battle field at Piedmont, and bury
                        them in the cemetery of this place. We hope the men will co-operate with
                        this committee of ladies and give them the benefit of practical
                        counsel.--Other towns and counties are performing their duty in this regard
                        -- Staunton and Augusta must not be remiss.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor laments that men have not heeded the call made in the February
                    20 Spectator to improve the condition of the soldiers half-buried on Cemetery
                    Hill. But, the article reports, the appeal has reached "the tender hearts of
                    women, and we feel confident that the object desired will be accomplished
                    through their instrumentality."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Veto of the Civil Rights Bill</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In speaking of the Presidents message vetoing the civil rights bill, the
                        Richmond <emph rend="italics">Times</emph> says that the President has made
                        another patriotic and determined effort to save the Constitution and the
                        rights of the State from utter annihilation. The veto message is a powerful
                        and noble argument, and in weight of logic and cogency of thought, fully
                        sustains the high reputation won by the President at home and abroad by his
                        former veto.</p>
                    <p>While the "civil rights bill," gainst which this veto is directed, is a far
                        more dangerous and atrocious measure than that heretofore vetoed, we are by
                        no means as confident as we have been of the power of the President to
                        speedily and utterly demolish the strength of the Radical party. It must be
                        to every patriotic citizen of the country a source of profound regret, that
                        the President has not received in the free States that united, cordial and
                        prompt support which was generally anticipated. While his patriotism and
                        integrity are not questioned by any others than the "dirty ducks" of the
                        Radical press, like Forney, Dana, Tilton and Greeley, the Radical influence
                        with the Northern people is much greater than we had anticipated.</p>
                    <p>Notoriously hostile as that party is to the President's policy, it is giving
                        at this time much fewer signs of disintegration and dissolution than it did
                        a month hence. If the Radical party, of which Sumner and Stevens are the
                        leaders, were not sustained by the masses at the North, the President's veto
                        of the Freedmen's Bureau bill and his speech on the 23d of February would
                        have long since shattered that party from capstone to foundation.</p>
                    <p>But recent State and municipal elections, the resolutions of various
                        Legislatures, the tone of the Radical press, and the resolutions of various
                        public meetings show that the influence of Congress is still very great with
                        Northern people.</p>
                    <p>There is, too, upon the part of Congress, a rapidly increasing hostility to
                        the President, which forebodes successful attempts, as no distant day, to
                        pass bills which have been vetoed over the President's head.</p>
                    <p>In the Senate, especially, we behold an utterly lawless majority deliberately
                        ejecting Senators whose votes are not in accordance with that majority's
                        plans and wishes.</p>
                    <p>It was announced by a Radical Senator a few days ago, that a Republican
                        Legislature in New Jersey was actually "meeting on their oars" until they
                        could elect a Radical Senator in the place of Mr. Stockton, whose fate had
                        been decided in caucus.</p>
                    <p>While no one can doubt the ultimate triumph of the President's policy, we can
                        see at this time no indications of its speedy success.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Expresses surprise that Johnson's veto "has not received in the free States
                    that united, cordial, and prompt support which was generally anticipated."
                    Argues that "while no one can doubt the ultimate triumph of the President's
                    policy, we can see at this time no indications of its speedy success."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1866.04.03.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News--Child Burnt to Death</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baskin</ln>
                        <fn>Lucy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baskin</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baskin</ln>
                        <fn>Amanda</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lucy Baskin was burned to death when a spark from the wood stove ignited
                    her dress. Her father's hands were severely burned while trying to extinguish
                    the flames. Lucy was 5 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News--Churchville Oil Company</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that a meeting of the stockholders of the newly formed Churchville
                    Oil Company will be held next Saturday to attempt to secure a charter.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Gallantry Extraordinary</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A mocking piece recounting the stunning sight of "a white man escorting a
                    negro woman" and points out that "it is needless to say that he is a Northern
                    man," a teacher at a local Freedmen's school.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News--Alarm of Fire</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wood</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Evans</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Two fires broke out last Thursday in local stores, but both were saved by
                    the swift action of the Fire Company.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News--House Burned</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennerly</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>An accidental fire consumed the home of Dr. Samuel Kennerly, Jr. eight days
                    ago.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The President's Veto</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A summary of Johnson's veto of the Civil Rights bill.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>A Marriage Extraordinary</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pinkerton</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dinkle</ln>
                        <fn>Lizzie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dinkle</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swink</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>In an extravagant ceremony, Lizzie Dinkle and George Swink were married on
                    March 29 by Rev. J. Pinkerton, apparently over the objections of Lizzie Dinkle's
                    father.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>K.</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Karney</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Karney, from Ireland, died on March 29. He was "respected by all who
                    knew him."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1866.04.03.04">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
