<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1866/va.au.ss.1866.06.26">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>John Riedl</taggerName>
            <tagDate>05/25/00</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1866-06-26">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="06">June</month>
            <day>26</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1866.06.26.01">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1866.06.26.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Public Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the "people of this county" met yesterday at the Courthouse
                    where they "adopted resolutions protesting in the strongest terms against the
                    proposed amendments of the Constitution" which, if passed, would "place the
                    brand of degradation upon the people of the State."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Valley Virginian; Staunton Vindicator</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Counters claims about circulation made by the Valley Virginian and the
                    Staunton Vindicator by stating that the subscription list of the Spectator is as
                    great as the lists of those two papers combined.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>National Republican</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Summarizes an article in the National Republican which declares "that the
                    vote of the southern States shall be counted in the Presidential election of
                    1868" and that any attempts to prevent their inclusion "would 'provoke a
                    conflict quite as 'irrepressible,' if not as bloody, as that which has just
                    terminated.'"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Law and Order</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dews</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harlan</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mauzy</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Criticizes two recent local court decisions as too lenient and attacks W.
                    J. Dews as lacking both "the bravery of a dunghill rooster" and "the spirit of a
                    cowardly mangy cur."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"A negro who attempted an outrage upon the person of a respectable lady
                    near Faber's Mill, in Nelson county, was caught and immediately hung."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Rates of Confederate Money</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lists the rates at which contracts made in Confederate money are to be
                    settled, with rates varying from 1.20 for contracts made in January of 1862 to
                    60.00 for those made in March of 1865.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1866.06.26.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News--High School at Augusta Church</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowman</ln>
                        <fn>Jno. Rice</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowman</ln>
                        <fn>Francis H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The "High School for boys" will begin its first session on September 1 at
                    Augusta Church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News--Maimed Soldiers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burnett</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>In an effort to compile a list of all those who lost limbs in the war, all
                    county residents in this category are requested to report their amputation to
                    the Clerk of the County Court.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News--"Staunton S. S. Union"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Simpson</ln>
                        <fn>A. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>G. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strasburg</ln>
                        <fn>D. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Candler</ln>
                        <fn>W. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Staunton S. S. Union, designed to "cultivate unity of feeling and
                    action in the furtherance of the Sabbath School cause," recently elected
                    officers for its organization.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Local News--Work at the Cemetery</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In accordance with th request of the ladies of the Cemetery Committee, on
                        Thursday last the citizens of Staunton close their houses of business and
                        repaired to the Cemetery with picks, hoes, spades and shovels to dig graves
                        to receive the remains of the soldiers buried on the battlefield of Piedmont
                        and of such others as were buried at Stribling Springs and other places in
                        the county. Such of the citizens as were not able, from sickness or other
                        cause, to go to labor themselves hired persons to work in their stead. Some
                        colored persons volunteered to assist, and many were hired. All worked well,
                        and by 5 o'clock in the evening they dug, it is supposed, a sufficient
                        number of graves to receive the remains of all the soldiers buried in the
                        Cemetery. The next labor will be to disinter and have the remains of the
                        soldiers buried at Piedmont, Stribling Springs and others places, brought to
                        the Cemetery and properly buried. The Cemetery Committee will not cease
                        their labors till this be accomplished, and then they will probably succeed
                        in having suitable monument erected in the Cemetery.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Work at the cemetery continued last Thursday, as residents closed their
                    businesses and homes to spend the day improving the grave sites of the
                    Confederate dead.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burkholder</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vines</ln>
                        <fn>Virginia F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stringer</ln>
                        <fn>W. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Virginia Vines and John Burkholder were married on June 19 by Rev. W. R.
                    Stringer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wills</ln>
                        <fn>S. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wills</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bennett</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary E. Wills and S. C. Wills were married on June 7 by Rev. J. W. Bennett.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1866.06.26.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>To Be Amended</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The "civil rights," or negro equality bill, which has lately been passed over
                        the President's veto, is, it is said, to be amended shortly, imposing the
                        following penalties on those who refuse to recognize "Cuffee" as
                        abolitionism thinks he should be recognized.</p>
                    <p>For neglecting to step off the pavement as Dinah or Sambo passes, a fine of
                        five dollars.</p>
                    <p>For neglecting to bow and take off your hat to them a fine of three dollars
                        and a half.</p>
                    <p>For refusing to shake hands, eight dollars.</p>
                    <p>For refusing to kiss a wench when you meet her, seventy-six dollars and
                        thirty day's imprisonment.</p>
                    <p>For neglecting to nurse their babies in streetcars or churches, thirty-six
                        dollars and ten day's imprisonment.</p>
                    <p>For refusing to see one home from church ten dollars.</p>
                    <p>For passing them on the street without smiling, two dollars.</p>
                    <p>For asking them to work, ten dollars.</p>
                    <p>For believing that you are as good as a negro, five hundred dollars and three
                        year's imprisonment.</p>
                    <p>For saying that you are better than a negro, ten thousand dollars and fifty
                        year's imprisonment.</p>
                    <p>For refusing to marry one, imprisonment for life and the confiscation of your
                        property.</p>
                    <p>For saying the government was made by white men, for white men, six thousand
                        dollars fine and fifteen year's imprisonment.</p>
                    <p>For saying that white soldiers fought as bravely as did the "colored troops,"
                        a fine of two thousand dollars.</p>
                    <p>For refusing your daughter to any buck that wants her, to be hung by the
                        thumbs until dead, and have your wife and children turned out on the
                        highways to starve.</p>
                    <p>The fines in all cases to be handed over to the executive committee of the
                        abolition party, and when the money is not to be had, Bottled Butler is to
                        be sent in order to collect it in spoons or whatever else he may be able to
                        find.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A mocking piece that suggests that amendments will soon be added to the
                    Civil Rights Bill imposing "penalties on those who refuse to recognize 'Cuffee'
                    as abolitionism thinks he should be recognized."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
