<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1866/va.au.ss.1866.12.04">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>John Riedl</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/27/00</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1866-12-04">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="12">December</month>
            <day>04</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1866.12.04.01">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1866.12.04.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Future of the South</head>
                <origin>National Intelligencer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We utter but a trite sentiment, says the National <emph rend="italics"
                            >Intelligencer</emph>, when we say that the future of the South is in
                        the hands of its young men. How many of them are qualifying themselves to
                        manage its factories, control its railroads, mine its ore, work its
                        machine-shops, and cultivate its plantations? Professional men it has in
                        abundance -- able lawyers, accomplished physicians, eloquent speakers. These
                        have their uses, but the growth of a State depends less on them than on the
                        character of the men who manage its industrial enterprises. What is most
                        needed in the South to-day is that the young blood which fought for it so
                        gallantly should work it as determinedly. On the plantations, in the shop,
                        in the factory, there the South is to effect its true restoration. The young
                        men who dug trenches and fed on hominy and pork, who went clad in homespun
                        gray, and slept is cold or rain or shine under the canopy of the heavens to
                        further the fortunes, as they believed, of their native land, can now do
                        noble service by laying hold of its plough-handles, turning its lathes,
                        guiding its spindles, handling its locomotives But there is want of capital.
                        No matter. They have youth, health, hope, ambition, and good abilities. They
                        have every incentive for which to work. Begin with a will and success will
                        crown their efforts.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Explains that, while the South contains plenty of lawyers, doctors, and
                    eloquent speakers, "the growth of a State depends less on them than on the
                    character of the men who manage its industrial enterprise." Consequently, the
                    article encourages young men to pursue careers in industry and the railroad.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Constitutional Amendment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Suggests that if the Congress tries to pass the amendment with
                    three-fourths of the states currently in Congress rather than three-fourths of
                    all states then "the judiciary would disregard it entirely."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Richmond Enquirer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges "the people of the South" to avoid politics and instead work toward
                    the "development of our resources." With wealth and prosperity, they "will not
                    only be courted by the North, but will be able to command anything [they] may
                    wish of that people."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>How We Might Have Been Re-constructed</head>
                <origin>Richmond Times</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that reconstruction and reunion would have been easier under either
                    Confederate victory or negotiated peace than under Northern victory since
                    kindness would have guided the process. The piece warns that "reconstruction
                    built upon any other than a kind foundation, will fall like a house of folly
                    reared on sand."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1866.12.04.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The discussion next Monday at the Staunton Lyceum will address the question
                    "Is Republican Government a failure?"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News--Soldiers' Cemetery</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>About the latter part of March 1866, a few ladies of Staunton determined they
                        would fix up the graves of the Soldiers buried at this place, and ornament
                        the ground by planting suitable trees and shrubbery in it. It then being too
                        late in the season to put trees in the ground, it was though best to defer
                        it until late in the fall. On the 4th of May, it was determined to invite
                        the ladies of Staunton and vicinity to assemble at the Lutheran Church, for
                        the purpose of concerting measures to honor our dead heroes. Consequently, a
                        meeting was held on the 7th of May, and it was concluded to have a floral
                        procession on the 10th of May, it being the anniversary of the death of
                            "<emph rend="italics">Stonewall Jackson</emph>." As the readers of the
                            <emph rend="italics">Spectator</emph> are all well aware of the
                        proceedings of that day, we deem it unnecessary to say anything more about
                        it.</p>
                    <p>We believe the collections made on the 10th of May were only about eighty
                        dollars, not one half of what might have been collected, had there been more
                        time to have matured the plans -- the whole affair having been gotten up
                        very hurriedly. Since then, about three hundred dollars more have been
                        collected. Of this less than twenty-five dollars was contributed out of the
                        country; the rest was collected in Staunton, and other parts of Augusta
                        county. A large amount of work has been done at the Cemetery, in fixing up
                        the graves, and grading the roads and walks; and the remains of all the
                        soldiers (except those in private lots,) have been taken out of the old part
                        of the Cemetery, and interred in the Soldiers' Cemetery; and a large number
                        of graves dug in two days, by th citizens of the town and vicinity, to bury
                        soldiers who are now lying in the battle-fields of McDowell, Port Republic
                        and Piedmont, and various other places uncared for. On Saturday and Monday,
                        the 24th and 26th November, thirty-five to forty bodies were brought up from
                        Piedmont, and on Tuesday and Wednesday, seven from Fishersville, all of
                        which have been <orig reg="interred">intered</orig> in the Soldiers'
                        Cemetery at this place. Of those brought from Piedmont, the names of only
                        six are known, viz: H. A. Lane, 27th Va. Battalion; Capt. J. M. Webb, 6th N.
                        Carolina Regt., Thomas' Legion; W. L. Morehead, Co. B 60th Va. Inft.; Lt. M.
                        Blue, Hampshire Co. Va; Serg't D. W. Suttle, Co. E. 60th Va. Inft; Capt. J.
                        P. B., Co. G. 30th Tenn. Regt. From Fishersville, C. T. Bibb, Co. F. 50th
                        Va. Regt., died Jan. 17, 1865; W. Dawson, Co. E. 22nd Va. Regt. died Jan.
                        1st 1865; Geo. Walker, Co. C. 22nd Va. Regt., died Oct. 9th 1866; J.
                        Williams, Co. G. 60th Va. Regt., died Feb. 3rd 1865. These names and dates
                        are obtained from the head boards. Two are so nearly defaced that the names
                        cannot be made out. One appears to be marked, so far as visible, S. L. M.
                        .... ge, Co. K. 36th Va. Regt., died Feb. 5th 1865. The other looks like it
                        might be ...... Farro, or Frazer .... Battery, thought to be Kutshaws, died
                        Jan. 11th 1865; and one in a new coffin, no name on it.</p>
                    <p>The people in the neighborhood of Piedmont, and for several miles around,
                        assembled on Saturday, the 24th November, and disinterred a number of
                        bodies, but were compelled to stop for want of boxes not coming to hand,
                        could nothing.--They expect to meet there again some day this week, when it
                        is hoped they will be able to complete the work of disinterring the remains
                        of our dead Soldiers. For the prompt and careful manner in which they and
                        the people of Tinkling Spring congregation have attended to this matter,
                        they deserve great credit and have the thanks of Ladies of the Soldiers'
                        Cemetery Committee at Staunton.</p>
                    <p>Much more work remains to be done at the Cemetery, and money is wanted to pay
                        for it. It is hoped that our citizens will not forget that the bones of many
                        of our brave Soldiers are lying about in the woods, and old fields, almost
                        uncovered, and totally uncared for. At Piedmont, we understand, the feet of
                        some are sticking out of the ground.</p>
                    <p>The Ladies have recently called on all our citizens -- through the newspapers
                        -- not only those in town, but those in the country, to bring rich earth.
                        Not one response has yet been made. These poor men died while guarding your
                        soil. Will you not give one load of this soil as a grateful offering to
                        their memory? This earth is needed to plant the trees and shrubbery in.</p>
                    <p>Persons have been written to at McDowell, Port Republican, Stribling's
                        Springs and other places, and it is expected that a great many bodies will
                        be sent in to be interred in this Cemetery.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An update on the work done on the soldiers' cemetery since May, when the
                    Ladies of Staunton determined to fix up the graves, and a request for citizens
                    to contribute fresh earth to continue the work at the cemetery.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Local News--Circuit Court</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>O'Brien</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doyle</ln>
                        <fn>Allen</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stout</ln>
                        <fn>T. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robertson</ln>
                        <fn>Geo. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stout</ln>
                        <fn>T. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bastable</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunton</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Glendy</ln>
                        <fn>R. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hope</ln>
                        <fn>R. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brock</ln>
                        <fn>Arch.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>Jas.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>Jno.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tate</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fultz</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Michie</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>Alex.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A brief summary of the past week's proceedings in the circuit court.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kerr</ln>
                        <fn>James T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garber</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sarah Myers and James Kerr were married on November 25 by Rev. Martin
                    Garber.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGuffey</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. H.</fn>
                        <sf>L. L. D.</sf>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowman</ln>
                        <fn>Francis H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Benson</ln>
                        <fn>Rosalie Freeland</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Benson</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. Francis Bowman, of Augusta, and Rosalie Benson, of Charlottesville,
                    were married on November 22 by Rev. William McGuffey.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>James L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turk</ln>
                        <fn>James G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mauzy</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sarah Mauzy, of Highland, and James Turk, of Augusta, were married on
                    November 22 by Rev. James L. Snyder.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Propes</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Link</ln>
                        <fn>Eliza A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Eliza Link and John Propes were married on November 25 by Rev. C. Beard.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Getzendanner</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cale</ln>
                        <fn>John P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cale</ln>
                        <fn>Susan F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Susan Cale and John Cale were married on November 22 by Rev. H.
                    Getzendanner.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>James A.</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Nannie E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Nannie Smith and James Patterson were married near Middlebrook on November
                    22 by Rev. C. Beard.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1866.12.04.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Suggests that the "Indian famine" may have already claimed as many as two
                    million lives in the U. S. and argues that a calamity of similar magnitude in
                    Europe "would have filled the world with horror" but in America the subject
                    receives "only a few newspaper paragraphs."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
