<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1866/va.au.ss.1866.07.17">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>John Riedl</taggerName>
            <tagDate>05/26/00</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1866-07-17">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="07"/>
            <day>17</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1866.07.17.01">
            <div type="l">
                <column>05</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>E. L. Houff, One of the Jurors</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houff</ln>
                        <fn>E. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greaver</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harlan</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>E. L. Houff responds to a letter from "Law and Order" in the June 26
                    Spectator which criticized the verdicts in two recent cases. Houff, who served
                    as a juror on one of those cases, defends the decision of the court.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1866.07.17.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Philadelphia Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Conventions have been called in one or two of the Congressional Districts of
                        Virginia to appoint delegates to the Philadelphia Convention. We regret this
                        course and much prefer that the whole matter should be left in the hands of
                        the State Central Committees of 1860. These Committees might judiciously
                        appoint a few gentlemen to be present in Philadelphia during the session of
                        the Convention, to confer with the members, as suggested by several of our
                        leading newspapers; but we can conceive of no good to result to us or the
                        country generally from the appointment of delegates. The presence of
                        delegates from the South at Philadelphia would only embarrass the
                        proceedings. It is probable that at the outset an attempt would be made to
                        exclude at least a portion of our delegates, on account of their alleged
                        disloyalty, and there would be a fracas right away. If admitted into the
                        Convention without opposition, every act, word and look of Southern
                        delegates would closely watched by hostile outsiders, and some evidence of
                        disloyalty discovered, and heralded to the country, as a reason why the
                        Radicals in Congress should impose new pains and penalties upon us. No fears
                        of this sort should restrain us from sending delegates, if they could effect
                        any good; but we see no use in being represented in a popular Convention
                        while we have no voice in the National councils. The object of such
                        Conventions is to combine popular sentiment with a view to political action.
                        The South having no power to act politically, no combination of the sort is
                        needed here -- it would be idle for us to go through the forms when no
                        result could possibly follow. Will the presence and co-operation of Southern
                        men in the Philadelphia Convention help to give a right direction to popular
                        sentiment at the North, where the power of action lies? That is the
                        question. As we have said, it seems to us that only embarrassment and new
                        troubles would result.--But let us, in every proper way, testify our
                        interest in the proceedings at Philadelphia, and our respect for the
                        gentlemen who have called the Convention. It is eminently proper that they
                        should meet as proposed, and we heartily wish them success in their effort
                        to restore "national unity, fraternity, and harmony."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Questions whether Virginia should send delegates to the upcoming
                    Philadelphia Convention, suggesting that "only embarrassment and new troubles
                    would result" and doubting that the involvement of Southern men would be able to
                    "help to give a right direction to popular sentiment at the North."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Who are the Disunionists?</head>
                <origin>Virginia Free Press</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that "Sumner and his fanatical band" are "disunionists in every
                    aspect of the case" and should be arrested by President Johnson for treason.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1866.07.17.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News--Appointments</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Watts</ln>
                        <fn>Jno. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kerlin</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blakemore</ln>
                        <fn>U. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Local appointments for the positions of Notary Public and postmaster.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Watson</ln>
                        <fn>Egbert R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woodson</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lewis</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craig</ln>
                        <fn>R. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greaver</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Offers a brief account of the proceedings of last week's special term of
                    the local Circuit Court.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baily</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baily</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baily</ln>
                        <fn>Catherine E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Baily, the infant son of Jacob and Catherine Baily, died on July 13.
                    He was 9 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1866.07.17.04">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
