<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1866/va.au.ss.1866.09.11">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>John Riedl</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/09/00</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1866-09-11">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day>11</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1866.09.11.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Bridesmaids</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that "every young lady likes to be a bridesmaid," and that each
                    bridesmaid is "looking to that day of triumphant weakness when it shall be their
                    turn to be 'poor dear creatures'" at their own weddings.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1866.09.11.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Brave Men and Cowards</head>
                <origin>Richmond Times</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It has been manifest ever since the war that the soldiers of the North, who
                        bravely met our Southern soldiers in the field of deadly conflict, have
                        exhibited less hostility to the South than those white-livered wretches who
                        staid securely at home and "snuffed the battle <emph rend="italics">afar
                            off.</emph>" This is not to be wondered at, for the brave are always
                        generous, and cowards nearly always malignant. The brave will never strike
                        the fallen -- cowards will strike none other.</p>
                    <p>Another reason is, that the soldiers in the North enlisted and fought for the
                        preservation of the Union, and are consequently the friends of restoration,
                        and the opponents of the policy of the Radicals which would prevent the
                        restoration of the Union, and trample ruthlessly upon the rights of the
                        people.</p>
                    <p>In the language of the Richmond <emph rend="italics">Times</emph>, they
                        fought to restore the Union, and seventeen months after the obtained the
                        victory -- after the last Confederate banner was lowered, they find that the
                        Union is not restored; and they are at no difficulty in placing the
                        responsibility upon the right shoulders. These considerations explain why it
                        is that the soldiers and sailors are rallying so enthusiastically round the
                        President and the new party. They find themselves stultified by the
                        doctrines and acts of Radicalism, and in the stubborn facts of <emph
                            rend="italics">continued disunion they see the failure of the war, and
                            recognize the triumph of secession</emph>.</p>
                    <p>It is being fully recognized by the thinking men of the North that if the
                        political organization of the country be not restored upon the basis of
                        conservatism, they will have, perhaps, in their own section one of the
                        bloodiest civil wars this continent has ever witnessed. The sober, common
                        sense of the Northern people, irrespective of party, will more and more
                        snuff the dangers of Radical victory, and will surely shrink from plunging
                        this land in all the multiplied terrors of another civil war.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that "the soldiers of the North, who bravely met our Southern
                    soldiers in the field of deadly conflict have exhibited less hostility to the
                    South than those white-livered wretches who staid securely at home."
                    Additionally, the article claims, if the Radicals continue on their present
                    course, the North may be faced with a civil war in their own region.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Lynchburg Republican</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that the "Jacobins" are "using the negro as a subject of political
                    capital for themselves, with out caring one cent what becomes of him so they
                    accomplish their odious purposes."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Virginia Delegation in Philadelphia</head>
                <origin>New York Tribune</origin>
                <commentary>"Those who may wish to see the position taken by the delegates from
                    Virginia in the Radical Convention which met in Philadelphia on the 3rd inst.
                    will be interested in the following extracts from the New York Tribune."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Extracts from the New York Tribune indicate that the Virginia delegation
                    cast their influence "unanimously for universal suffrage."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1866.09.11.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that Maj. James Crawford has produced the finest wheat in the
                    county, equal in quality to Mediterranean wheat.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Local News--Picnic</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Baptist and Methodist Sunday Schools held a picnic last Saturday where
                    many "spent the day in one unbroken chain of merriment and festivity."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Local News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hogshead</ln>
                        <fn>M. W. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hailman</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Election results for officers of the local militia, chosen last Saturday at
                    Middlebrook.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Local News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greaver</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Frank Greaver, who was found guilty of stealing in the local court and
                    sentenced to the penitentiary, has been pardoned by Gov. Pierpont.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armstrong</ln>
                        <fn>J. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harlan</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Eliza J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Eliza Smith and Samuel Harlan were married on September 4 by Rev. J. E.
                    Armstrong.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armstrong</ln>
                        <fn>J. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>Henry J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Herndon</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary Herndon and Henry Davis were married on September 9 by Rev. J. E.
                    Armstrong.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1866.09.11.04">
            <div type="l">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Colored Sketches</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Believing, as we do, since the sullen wholesale freeing of the negroes, that
                        in the course of a few generations, they will become extinct, we have
                        thought it might be interesting to some of the readers of the <emph
                            rend="italics">Spectator</emph> to give a short sketch of a few of the
                        most noted negroes that lived here in time gone by; and, perhaps, in after
                        years, to read about a people extinct, who one numbered in the South two or
                        three millions, might be regarded as curious and entertaining.</p>
                    <p>In giving these sketches, we don't propose to relate them in regular
                        chronological order, but just at random as they happened to occur to us.</p>
                    <p>At the old "Wayne Tavern," there were several noted servants. There was "Old
                        Dennis," a little old black man, who had been in his time a valuable dining
                        room servant, but lived, as far back as my own memory of him goes, as a
                        retired old gentleman. He was always, neatly dressed, kept a horse, and was
                        frequently to be seen taking rides to the country, for his health and
                        pleasure, we suppose.</p>
                    <p>"Billy Gordon," a yellow man, brother of "old Aunt Daphne." But was the
                        hostler, an industrious, well-behaved man when sober, but would sometimes
                        get drunk; then, he was crazy, and would fancy himself a free mason.--He
                        might be seen at such times with a masonic apron on riding a horse to water,
                        holding one hand over his head in a peculiar position, crying but every now
                        and then, "<emph rend="italics">a free and accepted mason</emph>."</p>
                    <p>"Daniel Webster," a large, pretty looking black man, well and favorably known
                        to travellers, was an excellent servant, always pleasant and attentive to
                        the guests.</p>
                    <p>At the old "Washington Tavern," the most noted servant was "Ben Watson,"
                        better known, perhaps, as "Harman's Ben." He was famed for making delicious
                            <emph rend="italics">Mint Juleps</emph> and <emph rend="italics">Hail
                            Storms</emph>. We have heard Ben's juleps spoken of nearly a thousand
                        miles from Staunton.</p>
                    <p>Another well known old black man, was "Old Uncle Tom" -- Aunt Daphne's
                        husband -- he was a Revolutionary character. We believe he claimed to have
                        been the body servant of some officer in the American Revolution.--Uncle Tom
                        was generally neatly dressed, polite, and dignified, at times somewhat
                        pompous, and found of using big words. We remember one of Tom's speeches.
                        One evening, he was waiting on some young men in one of the stores, who were
                        indulging in a social glass when some one stepped in, that he considered
                        rather an intruder. Tom said to him, "Sir, you must be a <emph
                            rend="italics">perlitical character</emph>." The man said, "Uncle Tom,
                        what kind of a character is that?" Tom immediately straightened himself up,
                        and with all the dignity of manner possible, replied: "It <emph
                            rend="italics">ar</emph> a man what steps up <emph rend="italics"
                        >whar</emph> a parcel of gentlemen <emph rend="italics">ar</emph> conversing
                        together, and looks brazen, and flings forth an idea onto a <emph
                            rend="italics">certin</emph> branch of business, farther forth than he
                        can rightly ascertain; that, sir, is what I term a <emph rend="italics"
                            >perlitical character.</emph>"</p>
                    <p>Many years ago, there were several colored clergymen about the town and
                        neighborhood. there were "Uncle Louis," "Uncle Abraham," "Parson Joe Mead,"
                        and one or two others.--"Louis" was once telling us that, between himself
                        and "Brother Abram," there was a great difference. "Now," said he, "Brother
                        Abram can't take a text and wander, and come back again; but I can take a
                        text and wander away off, and come back again to the very same place <emph
                            rend="italics">whar</emph> I started from." We heard Joe Mead, one
                        Sunday afternoon, in Hopkins' wagon-maker's shop, discoursing on the <emph
                            rend="italics">Judgment Day</emph>. "Ah!, my friends," said he, "in that
                            <emph rend="italics">great day</emph>, the Lord will come, and He will
                        place one foot on the sea shore and the other on dry land."--These preachers
                        were mostly, what the boys called, <emph rend="italics">Wet Baptists</emph>.
                        That is, they were quite fond of a dram.</p>
                    <p>In these colored sketches, we must not forget two old negro women, one was
                        called Old Doctor Jane, that lived with Mrs. Edmundson.--She was in the
                        habit of visiting the sick all over town, and we believe never failing to
                        prescribe for them. She was a tall, venerable looking old woman, and walked
                        with a very long cane. The other was "Aunt Nellie" that lived with Mr.
                        Tremper. She was a great Methodist, a good old woman, very fond of religious
                        excitements. Many a time we have heard her lecturing a negro man, named Jim.
                        She would shake her fist at him, and say, <emph rend="italics">Ah, Jim! you,
                            sinner! you, reprobate! you better go 'long and say your prayers</emph>,
                        and then, Nellie was <emph rend="italics">tricked</emph>, as the negroes
                        call it. She fancied, at time, that she had lizards, &amp;c, in her
                        arms. We will now say something about an old black man who belonged to Dr.
                        Waddell, "Old Isaac." He was not the most intelligent servant we have known,
                        yet, "Uncle Isaac," fancied himself quite smart and useful. On one occasion,
                        his master sent him to the country to purchase a pig; when Isaac came back,
                        he reported to his master that the woman he got the pig from <emph
                            rend="italics">axed</emph> him "four and six pence for the pig, but he
                        beat her down to a dollar." Another time, he was directed to count the
                        sheep; he returned, saying "Master, I counted all the sheep, but the old
                        black <emph rend="italics">Yo</emph>, (Ewe) and she jumped so, and kicked
                        so, I couldn't count her."</p>
                    <p>A famous personage of African descent, that resided in Staunton a long while
                        ago, was known by the name of Mathew B. Truss, shoemaker, peddler and hack
                        owner, and we are not sure that he did not sometimes preach a little. At any
                        rate, we have heard that when he was out on his peddling trips, he would
                        occasionally make collections for the support of the Gospel, and put it into
                        his own pockets. Truss built the house in which B. F. Points now resides. He
                        had his shop in an old frame house that stood on New Street, opposite to
                        where Graves and Stoddard have their tailor's shop, a large sign swung out
                        at the door, with a boot and shoe painted on it, an underneath them these
                        lines:</p>
                    <lb/>
                    <p>"As you pass by,</p>
                    <p>On me, cast an eye,</p>
                    <p>If you have any money to spend,</p>
                    <p>Please leave it with a friend."</p>
                    <p>--M. R. Truss.</p>
                    <lb/>
                    <p>For a long while, Truss carried on the most extensive shoe shop in town. He
                        generally worked from ten to fifteen hands. "Cy Curry" and "Andy Roman" were
                        among the most noted. By the way, we had the pleasure of meeting with Andy,
                        some months ago, looking pretty much as he had done for twenty years past,
                        with this difference, whiskey and old age had somewhat impaired his memory
                        and eyesight. At one time, the workmen in Truss' shop held a kind of court
                        in the shop a case being before the court, in which "Cy Curry" was counsel
                        for one of the parties, and another workman, named Tate, had something to do
                        in the matter. WE don't know whether he was judge, or was counsel for the
                        opposite side.--All we now remember of having heard about the trial, was a
                        short sentence from Curry's speech, he said, "had I the dictatorial powers
                        over the court that my friend Tate has, I and my client would have justice!
                        did I say justice? yes, sir, and more than justice."</p>
                    <p>Another quite noted negro man that lived in our town, about thirty-five years
                        ago, was Dr. Boyd's "Jim," or as the Doctor usually called him, "London
                        Beggar." Jim was a pretty large man, and very strong and active. He was a
                        considerable wit among his colored associates, and, indeed, afforded a great
                        deal of amusement often to white persons. Many a hearty laugh have we had of
                        Jim's funny stories.</p>
                    <p>We remember, when a boy, there was a custom among the Baptist negroes, long
                        since -- we believe -- given up. It was this: some weeks after any one of
                        their members died, the funeral ceremonies would take place, they would
                        gather at the house where the person had died, and would, we suppose, have
                        services of some kind there. Then they would walk in procession from the
                        house to the grave singing as they went some solemn, good, old Baptist tune,
                        and principal singers among the brethren walking with their heads uncovered.</p>
                    <p>Among the colored folks, particularly the aristocracy, "Nick Johnson, Sr.," a
                        yellow man that belonged to old Mr. Mathews, was quite a noted character. He
                        was a large, good looking man, a pleasant countenance, hair somewhat gray,
                        sometimes he powdered; the finest dresser almost in town, particularly on
                        Sundays. Many a time have we seen him in the summer dressed in a fine,
                        large, flowing morning gown, nankin pantaloons, white vest and cravat, and,
                        we believe, he occasionally wore breeches or short, and now and then, fair
                        top boots. "Uncle Nick" was very polite and graceful in his manners.</p>
                    <p>We intended these sketches to be about home folks alone, but in the
                        following, we go to Richmond for our subjects. A few years ago, we stepped
                        into a barber's shop in that city to get shaved. We found the proprietor of
                        the shop, a fine looking yellow man, very pleasant and very polite, indeed,
                        quite the gentleman in his manners. Whilst we were in there, he was engaged
                        in conversation with a very plain looking white man that he was shaving.
                        Foreign and domestic politics, and religion were extensively discussed. In
                        the course of the conversation, the barber talking of St. Paul, said, "Now,
                        there was St. Paul, <emph rend="italics">you know</emph>, he was prosecuting
                        attorney for the Jews, and he was sent to Jerusalem with sealed proposals
                        persecuting the christians."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Antiquary</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn>Dennis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn>Billy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn>Daphne</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Webster</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Watson</ln>
                        <fn>Ben</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn>Tom</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn>Louis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn>Abraham</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mead</ln>
                        <fn>Joe</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn>Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Edmundson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn>Nellie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tremper</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn>Jim</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Truss</ln>
                        <fn>Mathew B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Points</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Curry</ln>
                        <fn>Cy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roman</ln>
                        <fn>Andy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn>Tate</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyd</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn>Jim</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>Nick</fn>
                        <sf>Sr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mathews</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>"Antiquary" offers a "short sketch of a few of the most noted negroes that
                    lived here in times gone by," a reading that he believes "might be regarded as
                    curious and entertaining" in the future when freedom causes the extinction of
                    blacks.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>All About Women</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Women, as a general rule, are not usefully educated in this country. They are
                        chiefly taught those accomplishments which the experience of their mothers
                        has proven to be best calculated to attract young men, and consequently, to
                        insure husbands. Music, dancing, French and Italian, are considered
                        indispensable to the "finish" of any young lady, in these degenerate days,
                        but the more solid qualities which, in the olden time, were esteemed so
                        necessary in the female catalogue of charms in the "good old times," are out
                        of date. In sooth, they are pronounced in elegant society de trop, and
                        stigmatised as vulgar. The woman who not many years ago, was a
                        non-proficient in the culinary art, and inexpert with her needle, was deemed
                        unfit candidate for matrimony. If she could not make a rare pie, dish up a
                        meal in peculiarly attractive style, turn out a superior loaf of bread, knit
                        a pair stockings with taste, and sew up garments with exemplary celebrity,
                        she was shunned by the male sex, and pitied by her own, as sadly defective.
                        But now, tout vela est change. The woman dexterous in such performances
                        demonstrates her own unfitness for position in the world of fashion.
                        Husbands are supposed to live upon the sound of a piano, and to be ready, in
                        the most distressing moments, to go off into harmonic ecstasies at the first
                        intimation of a brilliant duct. They are presumed to be totally indifferent
                        in respect to what they eat or wear -- to have a noble contempt for such
                        vulgar things as shirt or button -- to contemplate a woman too imaginatively
                        to suspect her culpable of a knowledge of anything but the toilette and
                        belles lettres.</p>
                    <p>With this ideal conception of the character of a husband in their minds,
                        young ladies necessarily aim only at the acquisition of corresponding
                        qualifications. They aim at sentimentality and romance, instead of
                        substantial common sense, and permanent information! The result is an
                        exuberance of satisfaction during the halcyon days of courtship, and the
                        saccharine hours of the honeymoon; but when the "angel of a wife" subsides,
                        in time, into the incapable domestic partner, and the "love of a husband"
                        degenerates into the satiated master of the house, then comes a season of
                        remorse, of melancholy, of mutual recrimination and mutual animosity. Should
                        fate make such a helpless wife of a widow, and necessity throw her upon her
                        own resources for the support of herself and family, unhappy indeed must she
                        be in her destitution. Her expensive accomplishments will neither provide
                        bread for her children nor consolation for herself. music will not silence
                        the cry of hunger; dancing will not exercise the gaunt fiend we call Want.
                        Sorrow refuses to submit to the syren song of an affected mirth. Seldom can
                        one of the wasted talents be turned in such a dilemma, to available, to
                        available account; and all the precious years invested in the accumulation
                        of those showy nothings, present themselves like so many ghosts of misspent
                        moments, but to chide the past for its extravagance, and fill the future
                        with apprehensions.</p>
                    <p>Who has not seen instances of just such calamity? Whose experience is not
                        fraught with some such scenes of anguish? And yet, how slight an element of
                        hope would alter the picture -- how small a knowledge of the business of
                        relations of life -- how little an acquaintance of those homely arts which
                        enable the feeblest by their industry, spirit, taste, or enterprise
                        remunerative, to completely change the view, cheer up the despondent, add a
                        silver lining to the cloud of grief, and produce a vision of comfort,if not
                        of independence! Why not -- oh! why not -- make them practical, as well as
                        interesting members of society?</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Laments the fact that women are neglecting "practical" skills like cooking
                    and sewing in favor of music, dancing, and foreign languages, making them
                    "incapable domestic partners."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
