<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1866/va.au.ss.1866.04.10">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>John Riedl</taggerName>
            <tagDate>05/17/00</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1866-04-10">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day>10</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1866.04.10.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Churchville Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Geeding</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walters</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tate</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A copy of the proceedings of a farmers meeting in Churchville.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1866.04.10.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>New Duties of Southern Ladies</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The ladies of the South have been justly celebrated for their many excellent
                        qualities -- their cultivation, manners, and virtue -- their devotion,
                        patriotism and fortitude. The fiery ordeal though which they have passed,
                        has but served to prove them pure gold. The men of the South are justly
                        proud of them. In all the relations of mother, sister and wife, they have
                        acquitted themselves not only handsomely, but nobly. In the past, they have
                        proved themselves equal to every emergency. The change which has been
                        wrought by the results of the war, (just now proclaimed by the Executive of
                        the nation to be at an end,) imposes new duties upon the fair daughters of
                        the South. They should now be not only ornamental, but useful. They should
                        learn to perform many domestic duties from which they have heretofore been
                        exempt. The arts of sewing, knitting and cooking should be learned by every
                        daughter of Southern parents. The performance of these duties should not
                        bring the blush of shame, but the flush of pride to their checks. The
                        knowledge of these duties, and the willingness to perform them, when
                        circumstances render it necessary, should be recognized as great and
                        desirable accomplishment, more valuable than the knowledge of a little
                        French, the latest Paris fashions, and the rudiments of the science of
                        music. To a sensible man, these useful accomplishments would be the highest
                        recommendation. There is not incompatibility between the useful and
                        ornamental accomplishments -- the same lady might and should posses both. We
                        would not have the ladies to become drudges -- it was not designed by nature
                        that they should be, and none but savages and semi-civilized people would
                        have them to be; but we would have them to be useful, and the helpmeets of
                        their mothers, who were once as fair and lovely as themselves, and as much
                        entitled to exemption from such domestic duties. The fact that Southern
                        ladies, we mean single daughters, have not been expected or required to
                        perform domestic duties, has diminished not only their value, but their
                        attractiveness; as, for the want of proper exercise of both mind and body,
                        their beauty and health have been impaired. The girl that performs these
                        duties has both mid and body properly developed. She needs no rouge for her
                        cheeks, no india-rubber bust, no false calves -- she spurns all devices of
                        art, and moves with grace and pride the conscious possessor of the rich gift
                        of nature.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that women "should now be not only ornamental, but useful" and urges
                    every daughter to learn "the arts of sewing, knitting, and cooking."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Lo! The Poor Negro</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>What is to become of the negro? This is a question which now addresses itself
                        to the minds of all reflecting men. Shall he remain here where he will be
                        brought into ruinous competition with a superior race, or shall he seek a
                        home elsewhere? If he remain here, poverty, wretchedness, and ultimate
                        extinction will be his sad fate. If it were not that we have the kindest
                        feelings for the negroes, we should like to see them move <emph
                            rend="italics">en masse</emph> into the Northern States, that they might
                        test the <emph rend="italics">professed</emph> friendship of the Northern
                        people for them. We are satisfied that the best friends of the negroes are
                        the people of the South, who, with few exceptions, have for them none other
                        than kind feelings. The Southern people do not blame the negroes for
                        anything which has occurred. Their emancipation, which we believe to be a
                        curse instead of a blessing to them, was effected without any agency of
                        theirs. They, as a mass, acted well and faithfully during the war, and have
                        comported themselves remarkably well since the war. No blame attaches to
                        them, and this the Southern people appreciate and acknowledge, and hence
                        attach no culpability to the negro.</p>
                    <p>If the negroes are to be considered the <emph rend="italics">wards</emph> of
                        the Government, and this guardianship is to continue for an indefinite time,
                        we think that they should be distributed among the several States of the
                        Union, North and South, in proportion to the population of the several
                        States. In this way, the <emph rend="italics">blessing</emph> be equitably
                        distributed, and none could complain that they were denied their just share
                        of it.</p>
                    <p>But as we know, notwithstanding their loud professions of friendship, that
                        the people of the Northern States do not desire, the negroes to become
                        residents of their States, would treat them worse than the Southern people
                        ever did, or ever will do, we must decide whether it is better for them to
                        remain in the Southern States, in unequal and ruinous competition with the
                        whites, or to seek a home in some favorite clime where they can live to
                        themselves and for themselves alone. If the latter could be, it should be
                        done. We confess that we fear the emancipation of the negro heralds the doom
                        of his race. Are they willing to be colonized, and can colonization be
                        rendered practicable? We will recur to this subject in future.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that "emancipation, which we believe to be a curse rather than a
                    blessing to them, was effected without any agency of theirs," and professes to
                    "fear the emancipation of the negro heralds the doom of the race." The author
                    recommends colonization to "some favorite clime where they can live to
                    themselves and for themselves alone."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Valley Railroad Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Michie</ln>
                        <fn>T. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>Franklin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>J. Wayt</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mohler</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kunkle</ln>
                        <fn>D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn>H. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>Bolivar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allan</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>A. H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shelton</ln>
                        <fn>T. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McChesney</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tate</ln>
                        <fn>W. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>C. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gambill</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf>Sr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echols</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grattan</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>D. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schreckhise</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shuey</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McPheeters</ln>
                        <fn>A. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>W. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Abney</ln>
                        <fn>W. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craig</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hotchkiss</ln>
                        <fn>Jed</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>A. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McChesney</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garber</ln>
                        <fn>A. M.</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>A. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McChesney</ln>
                        <fn>W. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Proceedings of the Valley Railroad Convention, held in Staunton on April 4
                    and dominated by delegates from Augusta county.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Meeting of Stockholders of Valley R. R.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echols</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>N. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>Bolivar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn>H. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>A. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grattan</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gray</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yost</ln>
                        <fn>S. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The stockholders' selection of directors for the Valley Railroad Company,
                    including a number of residents of Augusta.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1866.04.10.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News--Corporation Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>N. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parent</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Evans</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kayser</ln>
                        <fn>W. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Points</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bruce</ln>
                        <fn>A. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hardy</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Jas. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hope</ln>
                        <fn>R. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickle</ln>
                        <fn>R. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Balthis</ln>
                        <fn>W. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scherer</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Results of elections for local offices.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News--Churchville Oil Company</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamilton</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>Chesley</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echols</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sterrett</ln>
                        <fn>F. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nelson</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoover</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The newly formed Churchville Oil Company elected officers last week.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News--Broom Factory</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoover</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Two men in Churchville are establishing a broom factory, a suggestion made
                    by the editor of the Spectator a few weeks ago.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Local News--The Soldiers' Cemetery Committee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The ladies of Staunton have formed a committee to enclose and improve the
                    soldiers' cemetery.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hill</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kunkle</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hildebrand</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Elizabeth Kunkle and John Hill were married on April 3 by Rev. Thomas
                    Hildebrand.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Devericks</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rodgers</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hildebrand</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary Rodgers and Thomas Devericks were married on March 29 by Rev. Thomas
                    Hildebrand.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gorman</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Collins</ln>
                        <fn>Julia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bixio</ln>
                        <fn>Father</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Julia Collins and W. H. Gorman were married on April 4 by Rev. Father
                    Bixio.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wood</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ast</ln>
                        <fn>Lizzie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ast</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Latano</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lizzie Ast and Charles Wood were married on April 5 by Rev. J. A. Latano.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCutchen</ln>
                        <fn>Jas.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crist</ln>
                        <fn>Sallie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swink</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>See</ln>
                        <fn>C. S. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jas. McCutchen and Sallie Crist were married on April 5 by Rev. C. S. M.
                    See.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ast</ln>
                        <fn>William Byron</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ast</ln>
                        <fn>William F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ast</ln>
                        <fn>Rose</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Byron Ast died on April 4. He was 7 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>"Gallantry Extraordinary"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Mr. Editor:--Under the above caption, appeared a short article in the
                        "Spectator," of the 3rd inst.</p>
                    <p>No names were called, but the person who was said to be the gallant, was
                        designated as "one of the teachers in the Freedmen's school," and was
                        arraigned before the public for "escorting a negro woman!" This gallantry
                        was attributed to the taste of the individual, as no comments of note, were
                        made further; it would seem as if the Editor rather invited an explanation.</p>
                    <p>The facts are as follows: At the close of the Sunday school, which is held in
                        the building used by the colored people as a church and school-house, one of
                        our pupils came, and asked for a hymn-book, which we have for sale, and use
                        in Sunday schools.</p>
                    <p>She was told that if there were any not yet sold they were at our house.
                        Being determined to have one, she watched us start for home, and came down
                        the walk at the same time, claiming not to know where we lived. Once or
                        twice we thought of sending her back, or asking her to walk behind, lest
                        unfavorable remarks might be made, and our intentions misunderstood, which
                        seems to have been the case. But the fact that we were passing only directly
                        from our place of business to our home, and with a pupil, would, we though,
                        protect us from any false representation.</p>
                    <p>We are called upon at almost all times and everywhere by these poor
                        dependents -- the Freedmen. Letters are to be written, contracts are to be
                        made, books wanted, difficulties settled, suffering relieved, &amp;c,
                        and these people do not know but that we are walking Freedmen's Bureau, and
                        everything else almost when they seem to want counsel. But aside from our
                        business we have never walked with any man or woman, in this place or any
                        other.</p>
                    <p>Had we been in the habit of promenading the streets with colored women, or
                        had we come down the walk arm in arm with this girl, the case would have
                        been different.</p>
                    <p>But we are free to admit that while <emph rend="italics">we do not believe in
                            the doctrine of "Amalgamation,"</emph> or social oneness; yet, as the
                        restraint of force, which controlled these people, while slaves, is somewhat
                        abated; the proper ways to respect themselves as a means of culture, and to
                        fit them for society in their new condition as freedmen.</p>
                    <p>We trust we shall be better appreciated when better understood.</p>
                    <p>As to the matter of "taste," we consider the insinuation an insult, to which
                        we do not propose to reply at this time.</p>
                    <p>Respectfully,"</p>
                    <p>JOHN SCOTT.</p>
                    <p>Staunton, April 4</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>John Scott</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scott</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Scott replies to a piece in the Spectator which expressed surprise and
                    derision at the sight of Scott "escorting a negro woman." Scott explains that
                    while he is not in favor of "'Amalgamation,' or social oneness," he does believe
                    that the "proper way to train them to civility, is to be civil in our dealings
                    with them."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1866.04.10.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>President's Proclamation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Text of Andrew Johnson's proclamation declaring an end to the war and the
                    political equality of the states.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Schools for Freedmen</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>John Scott</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scott</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Scott, the superintendent of the local Freedmen's School, answers some
                    frequently asked questions about the nature of his school. He explains that his
                    teachers do sometimes whip their students, and are endeavoring to teach them
                    "the necessity of labor and respect to the white people at all times."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
