<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1866/va.au.ss.1866.02.13">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>John Riedl</taggerName>
            <tagDate>04/24/00</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1866-02-13">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day>13</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1866.02.13.01">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1866.02.13.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>President Johnson</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that Johnson's "steady hand, firm will, and sagacious judgment" can
                    restore the Union, since Johnson is above the political machinations of
                    "Radicalism" and is motivated only by patriotism.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that a convention of "colored people" in Georgia adopted
                    resolutions in favor of limited suffrage for "colored men" who "can read and
                    write well" and called for the Freedmen's Bureau to be given the power to
                    "compel negroes to work" if they don't do so voluntarily.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Frederick Douglass is lecturing in Alexandria and, referring
                    to a local controversy in recent issues of the Spectator, asks whether someone
                    will initiate a "secret petition" to invite him to speak in Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>President's View on Negro Suffrage</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On Wednesday last, a delegation of colored men, headed by Fred. Douglass and
                        R. H. Downing, called on the President for the purpose of expressing their
                        ideas on the questions now being considered affecting their interests and
                        also to learn the views entertained by the President in the same connection.
                        He was addressed by both Downing Douglass, who strongly urged that the
                        colored race should be endowed with all rights, privileges and immunities of
                        citizens of the United States, and desired that the right of suffrage be
                        given to them not only in the District but all over the land.</p>
                    <p>The President responded, saying if his past course was not evidence of his
                        good will to the colored race, he could say no more. He had said, and
                        repeated then, that if they could find no other Moses to lead them to the
                        Land of Promise and liberty, he would be that Moses, but he was not willing
                        to adopt a policy which would result in danger to the colored man, and
                        possibly lead to a war of races. Nothing but evil would result from forcing
                        upon the people in direct opposition to the expressed will of the which
                        majority. At the conclusion of his remarks, which were of considerable
                        length, Douglass said the question would have to be settled by the people,
                        to which the President expressed his assent, saying he had great faith in
                        the people.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A report on the meeting of a "delegation of colored men" with President
                    Johnson, in which he explained that he was willing to be the "Moses" of the
                    "colored race" but would not pursue a course that might "lead to a war of
                    races."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Suffrage Question</head>
                <origin>Richmond Sentinel</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Suggests that the South can avert "negro suffrage" by passing a "wise
                    homestead law" and a property qualification, thereby excluding "the great mass
                    of negroes, though not for color."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Still Rebellious Of Course</head>
                <origin>Richmond Whig</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>There is nothing more certain than that the Radicals of the North, and their
                        allies in the South, desire the people of the South to manifest some
                        evidences a of rebellious spirit. The Radicals of the North, with the view
                        of perpetuating their power, <emph rend="italics">profess</emph> to believe
                        that the people of the South are not loyal, not to fortify their positions,
                        have induced their allies in the South to make such representations by means
                        of secret petitions, or otherwise, as may be deemed most effectual. After a
                        close observation says the Richmond Whig, of the course of the leading men
                        of the dominant party, we have come to the conclusion that no amount of
                        evidence that can be adduced will satisfy them as to the loyal disposition
                        of the Southern people. They would not believe though one were to rise from
                        the dead. There are none so blind as those that will not see. These men have
                        willfully shut their eyes that they may not see.--To see would be to
                        believe. They therefore refuse to look. Extort from them the confession that
                        the South is not longer rebellious in spirit; that it is sound, true and
                        loyal, and that moment their Radical agitation must cease. If continued,
                        after such an admission, they would stand before the country as
                        self-convicted factionists, and would be at once deserted by the Northern
                        masses. It is their policy to mislead their party as to the true feeling in
                        the South, in order that they may be sustained by that party in their
                        persecution of the South. How could they confess that the Southern people
                        are animated by the proper sentiments, and are fit for re-admission into the
                        Union, and at the same time appeal to their party to exclude them from the
                        Union? They not only do not wish to believe that the Southern people are
                        loyal, but they actually wish to prevent them from becoming loyal. There is
                        nothing they so much dread. It would frustrate all their deep-laid schemes.
                        They irritate and insult them that they may draw complaints from them, and
                        then point triumphantly to those complaints as evidences of continued
                        disaffection. An outbreak in the South would give them sincere pleasure; a
                        secession of outbreaks would transport them with joy. The credulity of the
                        masses has been severely taxed -- there is danger that sooner or later they
                        will see that their leaders have made dupes of them -- hence these leaders
                        are systemtically endeavoring to goad the South into some demonstration of
                        insubordination that will justify them before the Northern masses in their
                        exactions and oppressions.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that "the Radicals of the North" are "endeavoring to goad the South
                    into some demonstration of insubordination that will justify them before the
                    Northern masses in their exactions and oppressions."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1866.02.13.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News--Books And Tracts For Sale</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fry</ln>
                        <fn>C. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. C. F. Fry has a large selection of religious books and tracts for sale.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News--Whisky Tax</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Risk</ln>
                        <fn>Harvey</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that Harvey Risk inspected 3,871 gallons of whisky in Augusta in
                    the month of January and collected taxes totalling $7,742. The author suggests
                    that county residents may pay as much as $108,000 in whisky taxes in the course
                    of the year.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News--A Smart Horse Thief</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>Mich. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bethel</ln>
                        <fn>Tom</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parker</ln>
                        <fn>Maurice</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duggen</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A horse thief swindled at least five local residents one day last week.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News--Boots, Shoes, &amp;c., Stolen</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jackson</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Williams</ln>
                        <fn>C. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that a local "Freedman," Henry Jackson, stole approximately 60
                    dollars worth of footwear from a local merchant. The Spectator hopes that
                    Jackson is sent to the penitentiary.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News--Whom To Blame</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the petition referred to in recent issues of the Spectator was
                    in fact designed to bring troops to the region, a design averted by the
                    Spectator's swift denunciation of the "schemers."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ramsey</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ham</ln>
                        <fn>Lucy Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClanahan</ln>
                        <fn>William S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lucy Ann Ham and Andrew J. Ramsey were married by Rev. William McClanahan
                    on Feb. 1st.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robinson</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Landacre</ln>
                        <fn>Hannah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jacob Robinson and Hannah Landacre were married on December 12th by Rev.
                    Peter Miller.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dull</ln>
                        <fn>Alice Kate</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dull</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dull</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Alice Kate Dull died on December 23rd at her father's residence near
                    Greenville. She was 2 years and 4 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hart</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Daniel Hart died on December 26th. He was 23 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1866.02.13.04">
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Poor Sambo</head>
                <origin>Richmond Whig</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that Radicals will "have to atone to the whites for the injury they
                    are now doing them, by a persecution of the poor blacks, whom they elevate only
                    to destroy."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
