<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1859/pa.fr.fr.1859.03.23">
    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Drew VandeCreek</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote>1st Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1859-03-23">
            <year>1859</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day>23</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.03.23.01">
            <pageNote>Page covered by fiction and miscellaneous national news.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.03.23.02">
            <pageNote>Page covered by transcript of the lecture "A History of the Chambersburg Bar."
                End in 1802.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.0..03">
            <pageNote>More of "A History of the Chambersburg Bar"</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.03.23.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Disorganizer's Convention</head>
                <origin>Harrisburg Sentinel (Gov. Packer's Organ)</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary/>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column/>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The state convention which assembled here on Wednesday last, ostensibly to
                    act as the organ of Democratic sentiment, proved faithless in its mission; and,
                    controlled by a will superior to its own, instead of counselling union and
                    harmony, boldly declared for schism and war."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Article from Gov. Packer's Harrisburg Sentinel denounces the state
                    Democracy as passing an aggressive platform at the behest of the national
                    administration, itself controlled by Southerners.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The "Soap" Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The "Soap" convention took upon its shoulders all teh hideous sins of the
                    National Administration, and the defeat of its nominees is a rebuke to the
                    powers at Washington, and they will hear it trumpet-tongued."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Editorial denounces the Pennsylvania Democracy for its pro-Southern
                    convention activities. Argues that they will need a lot of soap to wash away
                    their sins.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.03.23.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items: Graduated</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maurer</ln>
                        <fn>J.L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes Mr. Maurer's reception of the Doctor of Medicine degree from the
                    Medical College of Philadelphia.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Get the Best</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hurst</ln>
                        <fn>A.R.</fn>
                        <sf>of the Agricultural Store</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A reminder to purchase high-quality seed potatoes from Mr. Hurst.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Fire</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gontz</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gontz</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes the destruction of Mrs. Gontz's barn, about 1 1/2 miles East of
                    Greenvillage, by fire. The property was occupied by her son, who lost one horse,
                    six head of cattle and a quantity of corn and hay, as well as all of his farming
                    implements.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Terrible Effects of Rum</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The supposition is, that he undertook to build a fire in the stove; in
                    doing so, he set fire to the entire pile of shavings. In his efforts to
                    extinguish it, the fire was communicated to his clothing; and being helpless
                    from the effects of the liquor, he fell a victim to the flames."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--On the evening of the 9th inst., a man named Jacob Reed, aged about 65
                        years, a resident of Horse Valley, this county, was burned to death. The
                        circumstances connected with his melancholy affair, as they have been
                        detailed to us, are as follows:</p>
                    <p>On the evening named, Reed procured half a gallon of whiskey at the Horse
                        Valley Tavern, and proceeded towards his home, distant some 4 miles. On the
                        way, he must have taken frequent potations, and become deeply intoxicated,
                        as in this condition he called at a neighbor's, on the road, and requested
                        permission to remain for the night, which was refused.--He proceeded further
                        and came to an unoccupied shanty, on the premises owned by Mr. Jacob S.
                        Trostle, of this place, located in an unfrequented, out-of-the-way place, in
                        that mountainous district, and into it, it is supposed, Reed entered to
                        spend the night. In the shanty was a cooking-stove, without a pipe, and in
                        the corner of the room was a large pile of shavings. The supposition is,
                        that he undertook to build a fire in the stove; in doing so, he set fire to
                        the entire pile of shavings. In his efforts to extinguish it, the fire was
                        communicated to his clothing; and being helpless from the effects of the
                        liquor, he fell a victim to the flames. The fire from the shavings soon
                        enveloped the shanty, and not before the Saturday following, (the 12th
                        inst.,) was it discovered that it had been burned.--He was missed by his
                        family, but as he was in the habit of being away for a day or two at a time,
                        his absence occasioned no uneasiness; but the discovery of the shanty having
                        been burned, caused and examination to be made, and sad to say, among the
                        embers were found a small portion of the remains of a human being, the
                        broken fragments of a jug, and a pocket knife which was identified as having
                        belonged to Reed.</p>
                    <p>Whether there was an inquest held, we have not been informed; but the
                        circumstances taken together, are conclusive that the remains discovered are
                        those of Jacob Reed, and that he perished thus terribly from the effects of
                        intemperance, another victim on the alter [sic] of the insatiable monster,
                        the Molloch of Rum.</p>
                    <p>Reed leaves a wife and four or five children to mourn this sad fate of the
                        husband and father, and, from no fault of theirs, are made to endure this
                        terribly afflicting blow.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes Mr. Reed's death as a result of overindulgence in liquor.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/frmar59.html#3.23a</note>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.03.23.06">
            <pageNote>Page covered by advertisements and miscellaneous curiosities.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.03.23.07">
            <pageNote>Page covered by advertisements and miscellaneous curiosities.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.03.23.08">
            <div type="s">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rebok</ln>
                        <fn>H.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johns</ln>
                        <fn>Mary A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Raifsnyder</ln>
                        <fn>Washington</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Marriage of March 10, at Pleasant Hall. Both parties from Franklin County.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>West</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCurdy</ln>
                        <fn>Mary L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCurdy</ln>
                        <fn>S.O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mackey</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Wedding of March 17. Both parties of Spring Run, Franklin County. No church
                    noted.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Culbertson</ln>
                        <fn>Laura Virginia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Culbertson</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Culbertson</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Death of Laura Culbertson, aged 7 years, at Culbertson's Row, Green
                    Township.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Death of Mrs. Walker on March 20, in Hamilton Township, "very sudddenly,"
                    of Syncope. She was 64 years of age.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
