<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1859/pa.fr.fr.1859.09.21">
 <header>
  <title type="uniform">Franklin Repository</title>
  <tagger>
   <taggerName>Sally Henninger, 1st pass</taggerName>
   <tagDate/>
   <tagNote/>
  </tagger>
  <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
  <date n="1859-09-21">
   <year>1859</year>
   <month norm="09">September</month>
   <day>21</day>
   <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
  </date>
  <frequency>weekly</frequency>
  <extent>08</extent>
  <editionNote/>
 </header>
 <paperBody>
  <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.09.21.01">
   <div type="a">
    <column>1</column>
    <head>Look Out!</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript>
     <p/>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>A criticism of the Valley Spirit's fickle political opinion of the rights of
     naturalized citizens. The article begins with a story of a French man who realizes "look out!"
     can mean two things. The Repository prints the Spirit's two conflicting positions. See entry
     9/14/59, p. 4, Col. 3 article "Cap'n, Which Am De Right Left Foot" for more information.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>2</column>
    <head/>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript>
     <p/>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>The Repository notes that the Valley Spirit is the only Democrat newspaper to have
     printed libels of Col. McClure.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="l">
    <column>5</column>
    <head>A Visit To Franklin County</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt>"With what joy we return to the places in which we whiled away the tedious hours of
     restless boyhood. How our bosoms throb with emotion, as we approach the hallowed influences
     that threw their shielding wings around us, to guard and guide us on our important journey over
     the sea of life. The first sound of our own Village Blacksmith's anvil is sweeter to us than
     all the music of harmonious instruments."</excerpt>
    <transcript>
     <p>Springfield, O., Sep. 9, 1859.</p>
     <p>Messrs. Editors:--After an absence of a couple years duration, I determined to return to
      your vicinity, for the purpose of rusticating two months amid my old familiar friends, and the
      attractive haunts of other days. While on my way hither my mind was highly delighted with the
      majestic mountain scenery, which met our vision everywhere along the Pennsylvania Railway,
      me-thought that I had never realized their grand sublimity with a due degree of appreciation
      before. After arriving in Chambersburg, my attention was arrested by the evidences of
      improvement that met my vision on every hand. Splendid temples of trade, and excellent private
      residences, were taking the places of antiquated structures in rapid succession. After
      remaining a short time in your substantial borough, we started on our way to the hospitable
      village of Marion which had nourished and cherished us in our earlier years. With what joy we
      return to the places in which we whiled away the tedious hours of restless boyhood. How our
      bosoms throb with emotion, as we approach the hallowed influences that threw their shielding
      wings around us, to guard and guide us on our important journey over the sea of life. The
      first sound of our own Village Blacksmith's anvil is sweeter to us than all the music of
      harmonious instruments. After meeting with my dear friends and relatives at home, I went to
      visit an esteemed and venerable Uncle, and assisted him to gather in his harvest of golden
      grain. From his orchard we procured the golden apples and pears with much less bodily exposure
      than did Hercules obtain the same, from the garden of the Hesperides; and this luxury we have
      enjoyed many more times already than we shall in all probability enjoy again. We also passed
      by the "old Cedar School House."--Here, in former times, we underwent a domiciliation, and in
      all candor, we believe that then, the pupils gave many more practical examples of "Barter,"
      than arithmetical computations of the same. The chief commodities used in these shrewd
      business transactions were apples, nuts, rulers, balls, pencils, and pen-knives; and wo betide
      the unlucky urchin, who failed to get his goods concealed before the master approached too
      nearly; for if so fortunate as to aviod [sic] the confiscation of their property, there was
      imminent danger of their contracts being made void, and a proclamation in the "imperitive
      [sic] mood," requiring the restoration of exchanged articles, and these although apparently
      complied with were never actually obeyed, and the traffic though perilous was profitable.</p>
     <p>After wandering in delightful rumination through parts of your county, for the space of nine
      weeks, our time had arrived for leaving. This was the most regretful part of the visit. To
      turn my back on that time-honored village, with only one Federal officer, and the population
      of which is numerically diminished one per cent, by every emigrant from its precincts. But
      wonderful to tell; sometimes the quality is made much better by the exit of its inmates.
      Farewell, Dear Marion! mayest thou ever be worthy of the most devout reverence of thy departed
      sons. MARION PHILO.</p>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>A letter to the editor written in Springfield, Ohio by a former resident who comments
     on the physical growth of the town of Marion and reminisces.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look>frbrowser/frsept59.html#9.21a</look>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>5</column>
    <head>(No Title)</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt> "If the <emph rend="italic"> Spirit</emph> and the Convention kick leading men out of
     the Locofoco party, the party will soon be conveniently small and beautifully less." </excerpt>
    <transcript>
     <p>We protest against the late Locofoco County Convention reading its leading men out of the
      party. The <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> tried its hand at that and received a handsome
      rebuke from the party for it; and afterwards the Convention passed a resolution which condemns
      Judge Nill and Mr. Reilly in positive terms.--It denounces the use of money to carry
      elections; and it is well know that Messrs. Reilly and Nill used more money last fall in this
      County to carry their elections than all the People's candidates put together! If the <emph
       rend="italic"> Spirit</emph> and the Convention kick leading men out of the Locofoco party,
      the party will soon be conveniently small and beautifully less.--If it was right for Nill and
      Reilly to use money freely a year ago to carry their elections, why should they be denounced
      for it now?--Was it done to cover the retreat of Douglas?--or was it done to wipe out a few
      small bills still standing against the party in this place?</p>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names>
     <name>
      <ln>Nill</ln>
      <fn/>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Judge</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Reilly</ln>
      <fn/>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Mr.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Douglas</ln>
      <fn/>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
    </names>
    <summary>Another complaint by the Repository of the shameful mistreatment by the Democratic
     Party of some of its leading people. The party denounced the use of money to carry elections--a
     condemnation of Judge Nill and Mr. Reilly, but the two men had spent even more the year before
     with no censure from the party. The Repository wonders if it was done to cover the retreat of
     Douglas.</summary>
    <note>frbrowser/frsept59.html#9.21e</note>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <pageNote>A letter from Pike's Peak; Facts and Fancies</pageNote>
  </page>
  <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.09.21.02">
   <pageNote>Anecdotes; advertisements.</pageNote>
  </page>
  <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.09.21.03">
   <pageNote>Story of death by lightning stroke; Advertisements.</pageNote>
  </page>
  <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.09.21.04">
   <div type="a">
    <column>1</column>
    <head>"Old Buck" Subdued</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt> "Thus the <emph rend="italic">bruiser</emph> of the <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph>,
     'Jackey the giant killer,' proclaims to the astonished world that it is altogether too
     dangerous a game for timid men to engage in--crossing his path, or thwarting his schemes. The
     fighting editor, the raw-head and bloody-bones, of the Spirit, must certainly have a private
     grave yard of his own, in which he has interred the victims of his bloody rage; for he speaks
     quite familiarly of <emph rend="italic">our</emph> cabinet-makers." </excerpt>
    <transcript>
     <p>Soon after his inauguration "old Buck" became seized with the belief that he could
      accomplish more than has ever fallen to the lot of a Northern chief executive--secure a second
      term. He, therefore, the withered old celibate, the tenant at will of the people, assumed the
      most arbitrary course toward his life-long friends in order to drive them a little space from
      him to make room for those who had denounced him, in unmeasured terms for many long years. He
      did not design to quarrel with those who materially assisted in elevating so unworthy a man to
      the highest position in the world--the chosen ruler of a free people---he only intended
      pushing them a little beyond arm's length, within hailing distance however, so that he could
      call them to his aid when the proper time would arrive for their assistance; but they did not
      understand the harsh treatment and, taking him at his word, stepped outside of the circle of
      his immediate influence, and are now, for the first time since they commenced serving him,
      free men.--He made nothing by the movement. He only produced half-way friendship in the bosoms
      of his old foes by gathering them around him, and filling up his best offices with them and
      their friends; while he raised up an army of relentless enemies in those for whom his cold
      heart should have beaten with undying gratitude. Nor will he, thereby, succeed in having
      himself re-elected; for there are "giants" fighting against him.</p>
     <p> Other longing eyes are also turned in the direction of the "White House." Other covetous
      hearts, even among his principal advisers, desire to succeed the old man feeble. One of the
      most painful thorns in the old man's flesh is the "little giant"--the "lion" of the west. The
       "<emph rend="italic">Unicorn</emph> of official power" has had, and is now engaged in, a
      fierce and bitter conflict, with the "<emph rend="italic">lion</emph> of popular sovereignty."
      They, the "<emph rend="italic">lion</emph>" and the "<emph rend="italic">Unicorn</emph>," are
      fighting for the crown, when up jumps the little dog--the editor of the <emph rend="italic"
       >Valley Spirit</emph>--and threatens to knock them both down.</p>
     <p>Johnny Cooper, the editor of the powerful organ, (?) the Chambersburg <emph rend="italic"
       >Valley Spirit</emph>, and his employer, Jerry-go-nimble, have determined, in the wise
      counsel-chamber of the nation's Attorney, that one of them shall carry off the palm of
      victory, at the Charleston Convention. The matter is all settled. It is scarcely worth while
      for that mighty body to assemble. All the plans were fully agreed upon before the matter was
      considered sufficiently prepared for the eye of the party. For many long months they have been
      cogitating this very important step. Even for this same purpose--having himself puffed into
      notice by a powerful, (?) influential, (?) able (?) newspaper--did the astute Judge promote
      the editor of the <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> from a third class clerkship, at
      Harrisburg, to being the private, confidential clerk of himself, at Washington. In view of the
      President's mania upon this subject, it was a bold step for the valiant pair to take.--The two
      great men of this mighty nation--Johnny Cooper and Jerry Black--knew that they were about
      playing a desparate [sic] game; were about to risk the fat places they now so lazily fill for
      the shadowy prospect of a doubtful honor--the nomination of one of them for President, in
      1860, with the almost certain prospect of defeat staring him boldly in the face.</p>
     <p> They had fully determined to risk the throw of the political dice box; but resolved, at the
      same time to subdue "old Buck." Accordingly, something like the following scene occurred at
      the rooms of the Attorney General, preparatory to its being reacted [sic] in the August
      presence. We push the door ajar, and, peeping into the private office of the Judge behold
      Johnny Cooper, mounted upon stilts, painted in full Indian war fashion, brandishing an adz for
      a tomahawk, grasping the chief of the Black-hawk tribe by the top-knot, apparently in the act
      of adding his reeking scalp to the many trophies of victory already attached to his belt. The
      chief, however, in acting his part of the farce, draws back, apparently terror-stricken, when
      the valiant Johnny finds himself master of the scalp without shedding blood--his hand holds
      the sham-work covering of the sham filled cranium. The Judge, seeing how well the thing was
      done, and observing how <emph rend="italic">brave</emph> the little hero looked, declared it
      the height of perfection of the tragi-comedy [sic]. This being the rehearsal, and proving
      entirely satisfactory, the next step was to prepare the mind of the man before whom the scene
      was to be re-acted, so that it would produce upon him the desired effect--subdue him. Johnny
      not being a <emph rend="italic">real Indian</emph>; only being a make-believe, it was
      necessary, before the performance at the white house, that he should acquire some kind of
      reputation as a <emph rend="italic">desperate character</emph>. Accordingly, in order to
      appear courageous, and even <emph rend="italic">terrible</emph>, the <emph rend="italic"
       >Spirit</emph> of the 7th inst., just one week before the appearance of the heavy leader,
      "Judge Black for President," through the pen of the redoubtable Johnny, gave utterance to the
      following ominous, threatening sentence:</p>
     <p>"Walnut and cherry are indigenous to our soil, and our cabinet-makers furnish coffins on the
      most reasonable terms."</p>
     <p> Thus the <emph rend="italic">bruiser</emph> of the <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph>,
      "Jackey the giant killer," proclaims to the astonished world that it is altogether too
      dangerous a game for timid men to engage in--crossing his path, or thwarting his schemes. The
      fighting editor, the raw-head and bloody-bones, of the Spirit, must certainly have a private
      grave yard of his own, in which he has interred the victims of his bloody rage; for he speaks
      quite familiarly of <emph rend="italic">our</emph> cabinet-makers. <emph rend="italic"
      >One</emph> could not, it seems, make enough coffins to bury Johnny's dead; it takes a number
      of them. If we can learn who Johnny's cabinet-makers are, we will enquire how much money they
      have made by making <emph rend="italic">coffins</emph> for the <emph rend="italic"
      >thousands</emph> whom <emph rend="italic">he</emph> has slain.</p>
     <p> We can readily imagine the subduing effect of the <emph rend="italic">grand scene</emph>
      upon the feeble occupant of the chair of State, after reading this bloody prelude. The old man
      trembled in his boots--affrighted out of measure--as troops of ghosts from Johnny's grave yard
      passed in almost endless procession before his terror-stricken vision. No wonder then, that he
      was fully prepared to be subdued by the tragic feat of the histrionic pair. Having put up his
       <emph rend="italic">chum</emph> for President, Johnny confidently calculates upon being
      Secretary of State; or piggy to lick up the dish water of the kitchen cabinet. No matter
      which, only so it pays.</p>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names>
     <name>
      <ln>Cooper</ln>
      <fn>Johnny</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Black</ln>
      <fn>Jerry</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Judge</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln/>
      <fn/>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln/>
      <fn/>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
    </names>
    <summary>An humorous article that discusses how the Valley Spirit's editor, Johnny Cooper, and
     its owner, Judge Jerry Black, desire to win the Charleston nomination for President.</summary>
    <note>frbrowser/frsept59.html#9.21b</note>
    <look>*</look>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>3</column>
    <head>Stop The Praise</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript>
     <p/>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>A complaint against Bennett of the New York Herald who states that Seward can only win
     the 1860 Presidency if the South secedes. The Repository argues that if Seward wins, it will be
     with Northern votes; they also express skepticism that the South would leave the Union and the
     benefits of the industrial North.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>3</column>
    <head>Qualifications Of Voters</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt>"ARE YOU ASSESSED?--See to it that you are assessed."</excerpt>
    <transcript>
     <p>The law requires a person who claims the right to vote, to have been a citizen of this
      Commonwealth "at least <emph rend="italic">one year</emph>, and in the Election District at
      least <emph rend="italic">ten days</emph> immediately preceding such Election, and within
       <emph rend="italic"> two years</emph> to have paid a <emph rend="italic">State</emph> or
       <emph rend="italic">County Tax</emph>, which shall have been <emph rend="italic"
      >assessed</emph> at least <emph rend="italic">ten days before the Election</emph>. But a
      citizen of the United States, who has previously been a qualified voter of the State, and
      removed therefrom and returned, and who shall have resided in the Election District and paid
      taxes aforesaid, shall be entitled to vote after residing in this State <emph rend="italic"
       >six months</emph>. But citizens of the United States, between the ages of twenty-one and
      twenty-two years, who have resided in the Election District <emph rend="italic">ten
      days</emph>, as aforesaid, shall be entitled to vote, although they shall not have paid taxes.</p>
     <p> ARE YOU ASSESSED?--See to it that you are assessed. SATURDAY, <emph rend="italic">the 1st
       of October</emph>, is the <emph rend="italic">last day</emph> on which this duty can be
      attended to secure a vote at the ensuing Election--as the Election takes place on <emph
       rend="italic">Tuesday</emph>, the 11th of October.</p>
     <p> Voters of Peters Township.--We are requested to say, that the Assessor of your township,
      Capt. McGrath, will be at home on NEXT SATURDAY, the 24th inst., for the purpose of attending
      to the Assessment of all who are not already assessed; and on <emph rend="italic">Saturday,
       the 1st of October</emph>, he will also be at home, which will be the <emph rend="italic">lst
       day</emph> on which you can attend to this duty, so as to secure a vote at the ensuing
      election.</p>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names>
     <name>
      <ln>McGrath</ln>
      <fn/>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Capt.</pf>
     </name>
    </names>
    <summary>A description of the qualifications for voting in the general election. A reminder that
     Oct. 1st is the last day by which citizens must be assessed, in order to vote. The Repository
     notes that Capt. McGrath will be at his home on Sept. 24th and Oct. 1st to do assessments.</summary>
    <note>frbrowser/frsept59.html#9.21c</note>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>4</column>
    <head>Attend The Meetings!</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript>
     <p/>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names>
     <name>
      <ln>McLellan</ln>
      <fn>William</fn>
      <sf>Esq.</sf>
      <pf/>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Clarke</ln>
      <fn>Lyman S.</fn>
      <sf>Esq.</sf>
      <pf/>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Strickler</ln>
      <fn>Snively</fn>
      <sf>Esq.</sf>
      <pf/>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Rankin</ln>
      <fn>A. N.</fn>
      <sf>Esq.</sf>
      <pf/>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Carlisle</ln>
      <fn>William</fn>
      <sf>Esq.</sf>
      <pf/>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Ross</ln>
      <fn>James S.</fn>
      <sf>Esq.</sf>
      <pf/>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Ditzler</ln>
      <fn>John</fn>
      <sf>Esq.</sf>
      <pf/>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Criswell</ln>
      <fn>John H.</fn>
      <sf>Esq.</sf>
      <pf/>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Bonebrake</ln>
      <fn>E. J.</fn>
      <sf>Esq.</sf>
      <pf/>
     </name>
    </names>
    <summary>Mention of meetings that will be held prior to the election: William McLellan, Esq.,
     will speak in Welsh run, Upton, New Franklin, Marion, Greencastle, Scotland and other places;
     Lyman S. Clarke, Snively Strickler, A. N. Rankin, William Carlisle, James S. Ross, John
     Ditzler, John H. Criswell, E. J. Bonebrake, Esqrs., and others will also speak.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>4</column>
    <head/>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript>
     <p/>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names>
     <name>
      <ln>McClure</ln>
      <fn/>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Col.</pf>
     </name>
    </names>
    <summary>The Repository prints some of the Spirit's incorrect statements about Col.
     McClure--that Gov. Pollack dismissed him from office (he actually resigned and was appointed
     elsewhere) and that six years ago, McClure did not run for Auditor General as well as Douglas
     did for Senator (McClure's numbers were higher in Franklin and Adams).</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>4</column>
    <head>(No Title)</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt> "We bid the <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> speed in its work of defamation and
     falsehood. Let it give seven columns of such vituperation against Col. McClure each week from
     now until the election and he will receive one thousand majority over Douglas in October next!" </excerpt>
    <transcript>
     <p>The <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> of last week devotes seven columns to Col. McClure. It
      evidently is afflicted with convulsions resembling hydrophobia, whenever it sees or hears the
      name of McClure. To follow it through its tortuous windings and slimy filth would be as
      distasteful as it is needless, and we shall leave it to enjoy its systematic blackguardism
      alone.--To vindicate Col. McClure from its impotent ravings, would be to attach degree of
      importance to its madness that no one either in or out of its own party concedes to it. That
      Col. McClure has ever libeled Dr. Boyle, no one for a moment believes. He has never named Dr.
      Boyle on the stump or elsewhere in his political efforts, and we presume he will be scarce of
      employment when he amuses himself in that way. That Col. McClure has been a faithless man
      betraying his friends and defeating his ticket, was left for the blind ravings of the <emph
       rend="italic">Spirit</emph> to discover. The peculiar zeal of his friends throughout the
      County, abundantly shows his fidelity to his principles and to his friends; and the <emph
       rend="italic">Spirit</emph> might save its falsehoods on that point. The last speech made by
      the lamented Crooks was made in Greencastle in 1857 to contradict and denounce the slanders of
      the <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> clique. He declared there that no man supported him with
      more zeal and fidelity than Col. McClure. We bid the <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> speed
      in its work of defamation and falsehood. Let it give seven columns of such vituperation
      against Col. McClure each week from now until the election and he will receive one thousand
      majority over Douglas in October next!</p>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names>
     <name>
      <ln>McClure</ln>
      <fn/>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Col.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Boyle</ln>
      <fn/>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Dr.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Crooks</ln>
      <fn/>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
    </names>
    <summary>Another article criticizing the Spirit for its lies about Col. McClure; a defense that
     McClure never libeled Dr. Boyle, and that he is very faithful to his principles and friends, as
     is noted by a speech made by Crooks in Greencastle in 1857.</summary>
    <note>frbrowser/frsept59.html#9.21d</note>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>5</column>
    <head/>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript>
     <p/>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names>
     <name>
      <ln>Douglas</ln>
      <fn/>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Seacrist</ln>
      <fn/>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
    </names>
    <summary>A new insight into the motivations of the slaughter-house leaders--that Seacrist was
     removed because they did not think Quincy would carry Douglas with Seacrist.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>5</column>
    <head/>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript>
     <p/>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names>
     <name>
      <ln>McClure</ln>
      <fn/>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Col.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Nill</ln>
      <fn/>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Nead</ln>
      <fn>B. F.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln/>
      <fn/>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
    </names>
    <summary>Correction of another misquote of Col. McClure by the Spirit, which relates to a civil
     suit against B. F. Nead, and involves a note written by Judge Nill that admits the allegation
     could not be proved.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look>*</look>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>5</column>
    <head/>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript>
     <p/>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names>
     <name>
      <ln>McClure</ln>
      <fn/>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Col.</pf>
     </name>
    </names>
    <summary>The Repository jokes at how the Valley Spirit either complains that Col. McClure spends
     either too much or too little money and liquor to promote his election. The Repository points
     out that it is to McClure's credit that the Spirit has never approved of him.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <pageNote>Praise for Republican candidates; Story of a devestating fire in Chicago; Anecdotes and
    general news.</pageNote>
  </page>
  <page n="05" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.09.21.05">
   <pageNote>General news; advertisements.</pageNote>
  </page>
  <page n="06" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.09.21.06">
   <pageNote>Stories and anecdotes; advertisements; the proclamation of the General
   Election.</pageNote>
  </page>
  <page n="07" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.09.21.07">
   <pageNote>Advertisements; general and national news.</pageNote>
  </page>
  <page n="08" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.09.21.08">
   <div type="s">
    <column>4</column>
    <head>Married</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript>
     <p/>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names>
     <name>
      <ln>McHenry</ln>
      <fn>S.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Rev.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Stump</ln>
      <fn>A. H.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Mr.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Miller</ln>
      <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Miss</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Ollen</ln>
      <fn>Jacob F.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Rev.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Royer</ln>
      <fn>George I.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Mr.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Stover</ln>
      <fn>Barbara C.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Miss</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Ferguson</ln>
      <fn>W. G.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Rev.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Straw</ln>
      <fn>John Nelson</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Mr.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Lemon</ln>
      <fn/>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Mr.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Lemon</ln>
      <fn>Lydia Jane</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Miss</pf>
     </name>
    </names>
    <summary>On Sept. 15th, Rev. S. McHenry married A. H. Stump to Elizabeth Miller, all of the
     vicinity of St. Thomas. On Sept. 1st, Rev. Jacob F. Ollen married George I. Royer, to Barbara
     C. Stover, both of Washington Twp. On Sept. 15th, at the home of the bride's father, Rev. W. G.
     Ferguson married John Nelson Straw, of Middle Paxton, to Lydia Jane Lemon, of Oakland.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="o">
    <column>4</column>
    <head>Died</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript>
     <p/>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names>
     <name>
      <ln>Winters</ln>
      <fn>George</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Hockenberry</ln>
      <fn>Malinda</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Mrs.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Phillips</ln>
      <fn>Mary Nannie Adalaide</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Phillips</ln>
      <fn>Samuel</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Rev.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Phillips</ln>
      <fn>Rebecca</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Mrs.</pf>
     </name>
    </names>
    <summary>On Sept. 12th, in Springfield Illinois, George Winters, aged 43 years. On Sept. 9th, in
     Chambersburg, Mrs. Malinda Hockenberry died at age 58 years, 6 months and 12 days. On Sept.
     5th, in Chambersburg, Mary Nannie Adalaide, infant daughter of Rev. Samuel and Rebecca
     Phillips, died at 19 months.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <pageNote>Advertisements; land and house sales.</pageNote>
  </page>
 </paperBody>
</hwp>
