<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1859/pa.fr.fr.1859.09.14">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sally Henninger, 1st pass</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1859-09-14">
            <year>1859</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day>14</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.09.14.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Slaughter House Nominations</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Douglas</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sellers</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McALlen</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snider</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Welsh</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Secrist</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Piper</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A record of complaints against the Slaughter House leaders and the Valley
                    Spirit clique for creating a large part of the ticket against the wishes of the
                    people of the Democrat party.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>*</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The War Against Gov. Packer</head>
                <origin>The Lycoming Gazette</origin>
                <commentary>The Lycoming Gazette--the Old Democratic organ of Lycoming county,
                    exposes the hypocrisy of such papers as the Valley Spirit, whose test of
                    democracy now is oppostiion to Gov. Packer. Here is its language:</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Complaint against abuse of Gov. Packer, for his lack of support for
                    Lecomptonism and his choice to think differently from Buchanan. That Packer is a
                    an admirable example of a Democrat.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Address of the State Committee of the People's Party To The Citizens of
                    Pennsylvania</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Pennsylvania has witnessed, during the last two years the most disastrous
                    sacrifices of the property of her people, and the most depressed condition of
                    her great industrial interests. Valuable properties have been brought to the
                    block by forced sales, and at no time have Sheriffs and other executive officers
                    of the law reaped such abundant harvests of fees, while productive labor has
                    stood idle and looked on helpless, at the sacrifice of hard-earned possessions
                    passing from the grasp of the toiling hand that gave them all their value, for
                    mere nominal prices, into the ownership, of capitalists and speculators, most of
                    whose means were wrung in usury from the very men whom they were thus dooming to
                    houseless poverty."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Levi Kline, Chairman, gives a complaint against the wishes and demands of
                    the South--The mistreatment of Kansas and the fraudulent Lecompton Constitution,
                    the South's attempts to reinstate the slavery trade, their disregard for Free
                    Labor, their support for Free Trade that is creating an incredible trade
                    imbalance and their refusal to establish a tariff that would help solve that
                    problem, the excesses, debt, and corruption of Buchanan's administration. Kline
                    urges Republicans to vote this party out of office at the General elections on
                    Oct. 11th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>The Book Table; Facts and Fancies;</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.09.14.02">
            <pageNote>Continuation of the Address of the State Committee of the People's Party from
                page one; advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.09.14.03">
            <pageNote>advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.09.14.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>As We Predicted</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We have no doubt that Southern idlers, who never earned a dollar in their
                    lives by honest labor; who live upon the sweat, tears, and muscles of other men
                    and women, for which they pay nothing, may imagine that this is the proper
                    method of making the two ends of the year meet; but the industrious farmers,
                    mechanics, and laboring men of the North, who were not born with gold spoons in
                    their mouths; who accumulated what they own by honest toil, can never be made
                    believe any such twaddle."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors note that, as they predicted, the amount of foreign goods
                    purchased has greatly exceeded the previous year's extravagant amount--due to
                    the Free trade laws. The total imported for the last three years is $457,731,273
                    and the amount exported was only $99,320,187. The administration argues that it
                    is better, economically, to borrow the money to pay the interest of the debt,
                    than to earn it.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Becoming Africanized</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The slave-holders of the South are now almost afraid to go to bed without
                    a revolver under their pillows for fear their darkeys will rise in the night and
                    inflict retaliatory vengence upon their self constituted owners--their unfeeling
                    task-masters. Then why do they insist upon increasing the danger?"</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We have often stated that the tendency of extending the area of slavery is to
                        eradicate the white population in the old Southern States. This is fast
                        becoming verified in the very strong-hold of the peculiar institution. The
                        authorities in South Carolina have instituted measures for taking the census
                        of that State, which produces such an abundance of fire-eaters. The returns
                        from seventeen parishes alone, show a <emph rend="italic">decrease</emph> of
                        more than 5000 in the white population, in the last four years, (a similar
                        census-taking having occurred in 1855,) whilst the blacks have <emph
                            rend="italic">increased</emph> very largely in numbers, in the same
                        time, in those parishes. At this rate the blood-and-thunder State will soon
                        become sufficiently Africanized to suit the tastes of the greatest
                        negro-lovers in the land.</p>
                    <p>Is it not astonishing that the simpletons who urge so strongly the propriety
                        of repealing the laws of Congress which pronounce the Slave-trade piracy,
                        cannot see that they are preparing for themselves the most horrible doom
                        imaginable? The slave-holders of the South are now almost afraid to go to
                        bed without a revolver under their pillows for fear their darkeys will rise
                        in the night and inflict retaliatory vengence upon their self constituted
                        owners--their unfeeling task-masters. Then why do they insist upon
                        increasing the danger? They had better be upon their guard, and prevent this
                        iniquity, while they have the strength, lest an opening of the Slave trade
                        should result in so completely Africanizing the Southern States as that the
                        tables might be turned--the whites becomes the slaves while the blacks bear
                        rule. The only way slavery is upheld now, or ever was, is by brute
                        force--the law of might. If, therefore, the weak of to-day become the strong
                        of to-morrow, there is nothing in the world which can prevent their
                        enslaving the weaker portion of society--from whom they have learned the
                        inhuman lessons.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Note of a census taken in South Carolina, that the white population has
                    decreased by population, and the number of blacks have increased. A warning that
                    the slaveholders are creating a very dangerous situation if the black population
                    should vastly exceed the whites--a very potential retaliation could occur and
                    perhaps enslavement of the whites.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/frsept59.html#9.14a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>"Cap'n, Which Am De Right Left Foot?"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A story of a company of black soldiers who don't know their right from
                    their left foot; it turns into a metaphor for the inconsistency of the Spirit's
                    political stances--giving the example of the debate as to whether a naturalized
                    citizen can be reclaimed by his former country (if he returns to his former
                    country) for military duty. The Spirit argues both ways on two different
                    occasions.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>A Great Law</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors refer to an Austrian law that requires any one about to marry
                    to prove he can read and write. The editors argue that if the U. S. had such a
                    law, the number of ignorant Democrats would be greatly reduced.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Senatorial Contest</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors urge that J. Wyeth Douglas take the stump, so that citizens
                    will learn of his anti-Free Labor and pro-slavery opinions. The editors wonder
                    whether the Spirit will urge McClure to take the stump.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A comment of how the Locofoco County Convention ignored Gov. Packer's
                    achievements to sell the Public works, kick out the corrupt Canal board, and
                    reduce the State debt and taxes, but they praised Buchanan's administration that
                    has greatly increased the country's debt, and is in favor of Free Trade.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reilly</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharpe</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewer</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyle</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Small</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A humorous note of the Valley Spirit's attempt to save face by (after its
                    editor, Dr. Boyle, lost the nomination at the convention) asking the convention
                    to pass a resolution that praised the Spirit for its efforts.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An article of the Valley Spirt urges support for Gen. McAllen and James
                    Kelly for the legislature so as to redeem it from McClure--but the Repository
                    editors point out that McAllen had voted for McClure in '53, '57 and '58.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A complaint by the editors that the Spirit is stirring up an old lie
                    (proven to be a lie) that McClure voted to increase the rate of interest. The
                    editors suggest that the spirit get more creative.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>A Card</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"I now take this occasion of returning my warmest and most sincere thanks,
                    with the assurance, that I shall everhold them in kind and grateful
                    remembrance."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">To The Public</emph>:--Whereas, a few hasty and
                        inconsiderate expressions to which I gave utterance, immediately after my
                        defeat before the People's Party Convention, as their candidate for
                        Sheriff--whilst I was laboring under the erronious [sic] conviction, that I
                        had been unjustly treated--have given rise to a general impression among my
                        friends )or more properly speaking, expectation on the part of our political
                        opponents,) throughout the County that I am or intend to be in the field as
                        an <emph rend="italic">Independent Candidate</emph>, against the regular
                        nominee for the office of Sheriff, at the ensuing election, I therefore deem
                        it due, not only to my numerous personal friends and the party of which I am
                        an humble member, but also to myself, thus publicly to announce, that I
                        entertain no such design, and that I will not only cordially vote for all
                        the candidates placed in nomination on the People's Ticket, including my
                        successful competitor, "Honest Billy McGrath," but use all the influence I
                        possess or can command to secure their triumphant success.</p>
                    <p>To my many friends throughout the County who advocated my nomination, during
                        the exciting Canvass, and to the Delegates one and all, who honored me with
                        their confidence and unfaltering, though unsuccessful support, throughout
                        all the ballotings of the Convention, I now take this occasion of returning
                        my warmest and most sincere thanks, with the assurance, that I shall
                        everhold them in kind and grateful remembrance.</p>
                    <p>JEREMIAH BURKE</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Greencastle, Sept. 12th, 1859</emph>.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>Jeremiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGrath</ln>
                        <fn>Billy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jeremiah Burke writes a letter to correct rumors that he intended to run
                    for Sheriff as an independent, because he thought the Republican party had
                    treated him unjustly. He has no such intention, and plans to vote for the
                    Republican candidates, including "Honest Billy McGrath," who won the nomination
                    over Burke.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/frsept59.html#9.14b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.09.14.05">
            <div type="l">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chambers</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reilly</ln>
                        <fn>Wilson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shryock</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel S. Shryock, Librarian, writes to note the donations made by Hon.
                    George Chambers (volumes of numerous works and publications) and by Hon. Wilson
                    Reilly (many volumes of several different works).</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Office of the Fire and Marine Insurance Co., Harrisburg, August 30, 1859.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We cannot see how these collections are to be made. Every policy issued
                    provides that the premium notes can only be collected, or parts thereof, after
                    regular assessments have been made, to meet losses actually sustained by the
                    Company from fire."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Office of the Fire and Marine Insurance Co.</emph>,</p>
                    <p>Harrisburg, August 30, 1859.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Sir</emph>:--The business of the above named Insurance
                        Company having passed into my hands by a writ of sequestration, it has
                        become my duty to collect the assets of the said Company for distribution
                        among its creditors.</p>
                    <p>Among its assets I find your note for $84.00 given in part payment of the
                        premium of insurance under policy No. 578 on which, as appears by the books
                        of the Company, there has been paid $---, leaving a balance of $84.00 yet
                        due; which balance you will please remit by draft or check, payable to my
                        order, at your earliest convenience. If not paid before the 1st day of
                        October, the necessary steps will be taken to recover it by law. It is hoped
                        this may not be rendered necessary, inasmuch as it will only delay the
                        settlement of the Company's affairs and impose additional costs upon
                        yourself. Very Respectfully Yours, &amp;c.,</p>
                    <p>WM. C. A. LAWRENCE,</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Sequestrator</emph>.</p>
                    <p>As appears by the above notice the "State Mutual" has gone into liquidation,
                        and Mr. Lawrence has been appointed Sequestrator.</p>
                    <p>We cannot see how these collections are to be made. Every policy issued
                        provides that the premium notes can only be collected, or parts thereof,
                        after regular assessments have been made, to meet losses actually sustained
                        by the Company from fire. No exhibit is made by this notice of any such
                        assessment, or any such losses, and we advise every person in the County, to
                        whom such a notice was sent, to resist the payment of the demand made upon
                        them. We will have more to say hereafter, about this association and its
                        management.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors have published a letter written by a sequestrator appointed to
                    collect assets of the failed Fire and Marine Insurance Co.; the letter requests
                    the balance of a payment, but the editors argue that an assessment of losses by
                    the company due to fire must be made first, and so they urge citizens to not pay
                    yet.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/frsept59.html#9.14c</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Worthy Of Note</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Leisher</ln>
                        <fn>D. M.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Praise for the efforts of D. M. Leisher, Esq., who is on the Board of
                    County Commissioners, and his sons who are running his blacksmithing this
                    summer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Very Gratifying</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>Jeremiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Praise for Col. Jeremiah Burke, of antrim, who refuses to run for Sheriff
                    as an independent, after he lost the run for the Republican candidacy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Suicide</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"It was doubtless caused by mental derangement."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A well-to-do farmer in Letterkenny township, near Upper Strasburg, in this
                        County, named John McLellan, committed suicide, on Monday morning of this
                        week, by hanging himself with a rope to a walnut tree in the meadow upon his
                        own farm. It was doubtless caused by mental derangement. A few weeks since,
                        he wandered from home and was not heard from for several days, when he came
                        back as suddenly as he had disappeared.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLellan</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John McLellan, a wealthy farmer in Letterkenny twp., near Upper Strasburg,
                    hung himself on Sept. 12th. The editors speculate that he was mentally deranged,
                    since he disappeared for a few days a couple weeks ago.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/frsept59.html#9.14d</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Disappointment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>F. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nixon</ln>
                        <fn>G. T. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sergt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Chambers Artillery, commanded by Col. F. S. Stumbaugh, went to greet
                    Sergt. G. T. A. Nixon, a hero in the Mexican War, on his return home to
                    Chambersburg from , but he was not on the train.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Attend The Sale</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robison</ln>
                        <fn>D. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carlisle</ln>
                        <fn>T. M.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The law library of D. F. Robison, dec'd, will be sold by T. M. Carlisle,
                    Esq. on Sept. 16th, in Chambersburg..</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Barn Burnt</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bert</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Last week, the barn of Peter Bert burned--caused by arson, with all his
                    crop and many farm implements.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>(No Title)</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"'I am prepared to affirm, without any fear of contradiction, that no place
                    under the sun is better adapted to the colored man than Liberia.'"</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The bark James W. Page has arrived at New York, bringing advices from
                        Monrovia to July 29th. The vessels sent from Baltimore and New York by the
                        African Colonization Society had arrived safely at Liberia, and the cargoes
                        were sold at good profit.--The liberated Africans from the slaver Echo. are
                        doing well in Monrovia. Many are distributed among private families, and
                        learn fast the habits and customs of civilized life. The intelligent colored
                        people that have emigrated from the United States to Liberia speak in the
                        highest terms of the latter country. Mr. John W. Hohn, a colored New Yorker,
                        writes to the agent of the Colonization Society in that city:</p>
                    <p>"When I left New York for Liberia it was under the impression that I would
                        not find the place suited to my desire, which impression arose from a
                        misrepresentation of Liberia to me by a few acquaintances in New York.--But
                        having been privileged to see and tread upon the delightful shores of
                        Liberia, I am prepared to affirm, without any fear of contradiction, that no
                        place under the sun is better adapted to the colored man than Liberia."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article mentions the resettling of colored people to Liberia, and one
                    man's high praise for his new country.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/frsept59.html#9.14e</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Note of information written by Horace Greeley in Oregon, that men are able
                    to purchase Indian women from their fathers, at the same price as an Indian
                    horse. Some men have two or three squaws.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>news of general interest from around the country; advertisements; market
            news.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.09.14.06">
            <pageNote>A revival in Ireland; the Proclamation of the General Election--see entry
                9/7/59; advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.09.14.07">
            <pageNote>Advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.09.14.08">
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Raber</ln>
                        <fn>W. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Muttersbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keiser</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCleary</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn>Nancy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>West</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clark</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elder</ln>
                        <fn>Nannie C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elder</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McHenry</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gniver</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob I.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wirich</ln>
                        <fn>Anna Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dickson</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kendig</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Enterline</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Sept. 7th, Rev. W. B. Raber married John Muttersbaugh to Elizabeth
                    Keiser, both of Franklin co. On Sept. 7th, Rev. W. B. Raber married George
                    McCleary to Nancy Gordon, both of Chambersburg. On Sept. 6th, Rev. William A.
                    West married Rev. John H. Clark, of Landisburg, Perry County Pa., to Nannie C.
                    Elder, daughter of William Elder, of Path Valley, Franklin co. On Sept. 6th,
                    Rev. S. McHenry married Jacob I Gniver to Anna Mary Wirich, all of Franklin
                    county. On Sept. 8th, in Orrstown, Rev. J. Dickson married Samuel Kendig to
                    Elizabeth Enterline, both of Franklin county.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kirby</ln>
                        <fn>Ann Jemima</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kirby</ln>
                        <fn>James R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kirby</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Sept. 9th, in Chambersburg, Ann Jemima, eldest daughter of James R. and
                    Rebecca Kirby, died at 30 years and 4 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>advertisements; land and house sales.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
