<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1859/pa.fr.fr.1859.08.31">
    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Rachel Onuf</taggerName>
            <tagDate>11/20/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>1st Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1859-08-31">
            <year>1859</year>
            <month norm="08">August</month>
            <day>31</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.08.31.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Basis of Union</head>
                <origin>New York Tribune</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"'Then we resisted an attempt to force slavery upon a single territory of
                    the Union. Now the design is to plant and protect that institution in all
                    existing territories of the Republic, by means [o]f legislative, executive, and
                    judicial intervention -- to acquire by purchase, or conquest, foreign
                    territories, to be in their turn blighted with the same curse, and to reopen,
                    under legal sanctions, the African slave-trade, in order to supply the necessary
                    means for thus enlarging the area of human bondage on this continent.'"</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A few candid journals, which sincerely desire the defeat of the Democracy in
                        the coming Presidential election, offer such a basis of co-operation for
                        effecting this object that the Republican party cannot for a moment
                        entertain the idea of entering into a union with them on the terms proposed.
                        Among these journals, one of the most respectable and influential is the
                        Philadelphia <emph rend="italic">North American</emph>[.] In a recent
                        elaborate disquisition on this subject it says:</p>
                    <p>"It is only by coperation, [sic] concession, and the forbearance of
                        impracticable ideas, that success can be assured. To achieve it, the
                        Opposition must unite, and sink those differences of opinion which are, from
                        education and conviction, in their very nature, irreconcilable. Similar
                        differences existed when the Constitution was formed, and yet they were
                        harmonized and subordinated to attain the great good of a more perfect
                        Union."</p>
                    <p>The "difference of opinion" mentioned in this extract relate[s] to the
                        subject of slavery. -- Not forgeting [sic] the liberal treatment which the
                        Republican cause and candidates received from the North American in the
                        severe contest of 1856, and in a State and city where aid to both was much
                        needed; and with an earnest desire on our part to have the powerful
                        assistance of such a journal in the conflict before us, we must,
                        nevertheless, assure our cotemporary [sic] that what it desires to see done
                        cannot be accomplished. The Republican party has no thought or purpose of
                        abating its opposition to the extension of slavery. To resist the schemes of
                        the negro propagandists, it was called into existence. Its first general
                        battle was fought on that ground. Though the precise question at stake then
                        -- the liberties of Kansas -- has, thanks to her brave sons, and the
                        Republican party and its anti-Lecom[p]ton allies, been settled in favor of
                        freedom, the primary principle involved in that memorable contest is as much
                        and as really at issue now as it was then. The field of combat is changed.
                        The grounds of quarrel remain the same.</p>
                    <p>But, while the question involved is of the like generic character now as
                        then, it is assuming vastly more portentous proportions in the pending
                        Presidential campaign, than those it exhibite[d] in the last. Then we
                        resisted an attempt to force slavery upon a single territory of the Union.
                        Now the design is to plant and protect that institution in all existing
                        territories of the Republic, by means [o]f legislative, executive, and
                        judicial intervention -- to acquire by purchase, or conquest, foreign
                        territories, to be in their turn blighted with the same curse, and to
                        reopen, under legal sanctions, the African slave-trade, in order to supply
                        the necessary means for thus enlarging the area of human bondage on this
                        continent. If, therefore, there was a necessity for the organization of the
                        Republican party in the years 1855 and 1856, to meet the single issue which
                        the slavery extensionists tendered to the country then, are there not far
                        stronger reasons for its continued existence to encounter, and if possible
                        master, the manifold issues which the same interest is pressing into the
                        current contest?</p>
                    <p>Even if the Republicans were themselves willing to "sink" the slavery issue
                        out of sight, to withdraw it altogether from the canvass, and abandon,
                        without further struggle, all the old landmarks of freedom set up by the
                        fathers, the attempt would be as idle as it would be criminal. The slavery
                        extenders of the south will not allow that question to be ignored. They have
                        thrust it into the Presidential arena, and they will keep it there during
                        the conflict, even though every Republican and every northern and southern
                        conservative should consent to its withdrawal. -- Can so intelligent a
                        journal as the <emph rend="italic">North American</emph> have overlooked
                        these patent palpable facts? In the recent elections in the South was not
                        slavery by far the most prominent subject, indeed almost the only subject,
                        in the press and on the stump? Was it not the Alpha and the Omega of the
                        canvass?</p>
                    <p>Is not the Democratic party, North and South, shaken to its centre by
                        antagonistic creeds and personal feuds, originating in this fruitful theme?
                        Does not everybody anticipate that, directly and indirectly, as it shall
                        modify platforms and measure candidates, it alone will agitate and possibly
                        divide the Charleston Convention? In a word, is it not <emph rend="italic"
                            >the</emph> political topic on which the great mass of the American
                        people think, feel, write and talk, more than upon all others put together?
                        To these queries but one answer can be given. We submit, then, to our
                        respected Philadelphia cotemporary, [sic] and to all others of like mind
                        that to attempt to divert the public attention from this question, and to
                        force upon the popular consideration others about which it cares relatively
                        little, would be to the last degree preposterous in purpose and fruitless in
                        result.</p>
                    <p>All that is left for patriotic men, then, is to determine on which side of
                        this controversy they will throw the weight of their influence. And, when
                        this alternative is as evident to our Philadelphia neighbor as it is to us,
                        we have no doubt of the position it will occupy in this unavoidable
                        conflict.</p>
                    <p>Recurring to the extract we have taken from its calm and conciliatory
                        article, we would suggest whether the only practicable basis of Union for
                        1860 is not that which we have from time to time proposed? We will state it
                        in the briefest terms: Let so much of the Opposition as agree in substance
                        upon the slavery issues involved in the Presidential contest, unite to elect
                        a candidate who fairly reflects its views, and will resolutely carry out its
                        policy; in the mean time "sinking differences of opinion" on other and
                        subordinate matters. Now, we admit that this is the precise opposite of the
                        basis of Union proposed by the <emph rend="italic">North American.</emph> We
                        also admit that it is more than probable that the large body of the
                        Opposition in the South might refuse to unite with the Republicans and
                        anti-Lecompton Americans and Democrats of the North, on this basis. But if,
                        by this course, they should give to the contest somewhat of a sectional
                        aspect, upon them will rest the responsibility. The basis proposed is as
                        broad as the constitution, and as national as the policy of our
                        revolutionary fathers. We believe that thousands upon thousands of high
                        minded men in the South would cordially go with us in such a union; and we
                        know that it would place in the Presidential chair a man who would rebuke,
                        by word and deed, that narrow and groveling policy which aims to make negro
                        slavery the dominant element in the federal government. -- <emph
                            rend="italic">N. Y. Tribune.</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>N. Y. Tribune</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>The New York Tribune critiques the Philadelphia North American for
                    suggesting that the Opposition drop the slavery issue in order to better unite
                    and "attain the great good of a more perfect Union." The Tribune asserts that
                    slavery is central to the Presidential election and recommends that the
                    Opposition select a candidate who "fairly reflects its views" on the slavery
                    extension issue. The article goes on to assert that if Southern Oppositionists
                    do not support their candidate, thereby giving the contest "somewhat of a
                    sectional aspect, upon them will rest the responsibility."</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/fraug59.html#8.31a</note>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Letters of Acceptance from Messrs. Cochran and Keim</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"The Committee appointed by the People's State Convention to Notify
                    Messrs. Cochran and Keim of their nomination, have received the following notes
                    in reply. They are both candid and out spoken, and there can be no doubt but the
                    nominations of the Convention will be handsomely ratified by the People at the
                    ballot-box in October next."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keim</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pomeroy</ln>
                        <fn>John S.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garretson</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seltzer</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The letters of Thomas E. Cochran and W. H. Keim, addressed to John S.
                    Pomeroy, Joseph Garretson and J. H. Seltzer, Esqs., Committee of People's State
                    Convention, graciously accepting nominations for Auditor General and Surveyor
                    General, respectively.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>News stories, many of which feature guns going off, piece about the death of
                Benjamin Franklin and anecdotes.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.08.31.02">
            <pageNote>Includes a poem, a story and advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.08.31.03">
            <pageNote>Includes a poem, stories and advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.08.31.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Shadow of Coming Events</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The unwelcome shadow of retribution which now spreads its dark wings over
                    the shrinking managers of that once aggressive party causes the knees of those
                    moral cowards, composing the leaders of that corrupt organization, to smite each
                    other with dastardly fear."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Another blast against the Locofocos asserting that they will not win the
                    next Presidential election.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Change of Time</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Casey</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McPherson</ln>
                        <fn>Edward</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Changes in times and speakers at the various meetings of the People's Party
                    throughout the county are noted. The Hons. Joseph Casey, Thomas E. Cochran, and
                    Edward McPherson are all scheduled to speak.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Glory Departing</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Another article deriding the Locofocos, this one points out the gains the
                    Opposition has made in the thirty-fifth Congress, particularly in mustering the
                    votes of congressmen from Virginia, North Carolina, Kentucky and Tennessee.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Quite Gratifying</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reilly</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reilly</ln>
                        <fn>Wilson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Cadet J. W. Reilly, son of Hon. Wilson Reilly of Chambersburg, is
                    reportedly excelling at West Point.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>A National Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>William Seibert</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seibert</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A notice from William Seibert suggesting that the local Methodist Episcopal
                    brethren meet at the upcoming Camp Meetings at Mercersburg and Newville to pick
                    delegates to a national convention of local preachers belonging to the M. E. C.
                    to be held in Baltimore October 1st.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Great Aurora</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"About half past nine. . . flashes were observed, like white waves passing
                    with a tremendous motion from the horizon to the zenith, giving to it the
                    appearance of an immense vortex, in which they buried themselves in the deep
                    bosom of night."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kane</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Description of the aurora witnessed by many the past Sunday night.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>New Democratic Paper</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"[T]here are Democratic families in Chambersburg, who are regular
                    subscribers to [the Valley Spirit], who do not permit it to come into their
                    houses; and throughout the party generally there is a wide-spread and deep
                    seated disgust at its habitual recklessness and low scurrility."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Conjecture about whether the Democrats of Chambersburg will reform the
                    "dirty, abominable" Valley Spirit or start a new paper.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Will Not be Behind</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCulloh</ln>
                        <fn>A. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Cumberland Valley Rail Road, in procuring the very latest invention for
                    issuing and stamping tickets, is subject to some gentle teasing -- "No addition
                    could improve, and less than it is imperfect" -- by the author, who was
                    permitted to examine "this superior piece of Mechanism" by the "gentlemanly"
                    Clerk, A. H. McCulloh, Esq."</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Another tirade against the Valley Spirit for "fiendish attacks" against Col.
                A. K. McClure and a reprint of the People's Party ticket.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.08.31.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Agricultural Society</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The "Farmers and Mechanics Industrial Association of Franklin County" is
                    offering certificates of life membership for $10.00.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>A. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gehr</ln>
                        <fn>D. O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tritle</ln>
                        <fn>L.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pott</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoner</ln>
                        <fn>H.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hammett</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jarrett</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mishler</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The People's Party Senatorial Conferees of the Senatorial District (Adams,
                    Fulton and Franklin counties) met at A. Mishler's Public House in Chambersburg
                    and nominated Col. A. K. McClure for Senator and Col. D. O. Gehr for Senatorial
                    Delegate to the next State Convention. William King (President; Adams Co.), L.
                    W. Tritle (Secretary, Fulton Co.), James Pott (Fulton Co.), H. S. Stoner,
                    William Hammett, George Jarrett (all Franklin Co.) were the delegates present.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Our Improvements</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lutz</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ott</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillan</ln>
                        <fn>Matthew</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Uglow</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Last week's article about the brick building boom omitted the names of J.
                    Lutz, Samuel Ott, John Miller (a mason) and John Miller (an innkeeper), all of
                    whom have buildings in progress. The article goes on to describe the two
                    three-storied buildings Matthew Gillan is building on West Market Street, with
                    bricks supplied by Benjamin Uglow for $15.00 per thousand bricks.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Chambersburg Academy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shyrock</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>Jas.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Frey</ln>
                        <fn>B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schively</ln>
                        <fn>R. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Chambersburg Academy starts classes September 1st. Mr. Shyrock is
                    Principal, aided by a "corps of teachers" including Rev. Jas. Kennedy, Mr. B.
                    Frey and Miss R. A. Schively.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Welcome Surprise</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armstrong</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel M.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The editors thank Samuel M. Armstrong, Esq. for a large basket of "the most
                    luscious plums" that he had delivered to the "sanctum" of the Franklin
                    Repository.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Balloon Ascension</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Light</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John A. Light, "youthful aeronaut," made another successful ascension from
                    the diamond in Chambersburg, witnessed by several thousand spectators. His
                    passengers were a dog and a pigeon, who were released -- the former with a
                    parachute -- from midair. The article includes another jab at the Valley Spirit,
                    this time for publishing a letter purported to be by Mr. Light, "but it savors
                    so much of a certain pill shop in West Market street where we believe it was
                    boiled that we pronounce it a humbug and decline publishing it." Curiously, this
                    "Balloon Ascension" article in the Franklin Repository is flanked by
                    advertisements for Nixon's and Miller's Drug Stores, both posing as stories
                    about the balloon ascension.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Includes an updated schedule of the meetings of the People's Party throughout
                the county, market reports, national news stories and advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.08.31.06">
            <pageNote>A poem, story about Napoleon III, anecdotes and advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.08.31.07">
            <pageNote>Miscellaneous anecdotes.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.08.31.08">
            <pageNote>Includes "Rural Matters" column and advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
