<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1859/pa.fr.fr.1859.07.06">
    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Drew VandeCreek</taggerName>
            <tagDate>October 4</tagDate>
            <tagNote>1st Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1859-07-06">
            <year>1859</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day norm="06">6</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.07.06.01">
            <pageNote>Page covered by advertisements, book reviews and a speculation on the
                "Industrial Prospects of the Country."</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.07.06.02">
            <pageNote>Page covered by another verbatim printing of the United States Declaration of
                Independence and advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.07.06.03">
            <pageNote>Page covered by advertisements and a story on "Two Daughters Emancipated by
                Their Father"</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.07.06.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>"The Disgraceful Sentiment"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taney</ln>
                        <fn>Roger</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Another blast aimed at the Democratic Chief Justice and his "cruel" Dred
                    Scott decision.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Independence Day</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The glorious Fourth has come and gone, and we have all quieted down to
                    every-day life as usual. What a delightful state of society we Americans enjoy!
                    We may quarrel and abuse each other, as much as possible, during political
                    campaigns, and it may be, at other times; but upon the recurrence of our natal
                    day, we drop our weapons of warfare and gather around the festive board, like a
                    band of brothers, not knowing any difference or distinction."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--The glorious Fourth has come and gone, and we have all quieted down to
                        every-day life as usual. What a delightful state of society we Americans
                        enjoy! We may quarrel and abuse each other, as much as possible, during
                        political campaigns, and it may be, at other times; but upon the recurrence
                        of our natal day, we drop our weapons of warfare and gather around the
                        festive board, like a band of brothers, not knowing any difference or
                        distinction.</p>
                    <p>Last Monday was duly celebrated in the different Groves adjacent to this
                        Borough by the several Sabbath Schools, mentioned below. The United Brethren
                        occupied Oyler's Grove, about a mile south of town, where they spent a
                        delightful day. The Declaration of Independence was read and an address, of
                        near an hour in length, filled with patriotism and good advice to "Young
                        America," who listened with deep attention, was delivered by our townsman,
                        Mr. Jacob Hoke. A number of the Teachers followed Mr. Hoke in short
                        instructive and appropriate addresses. Their table groaned beneath the load
                        of "fat things." All hearts were happy, and those having the management took
                        especial pains to gratify the most fastidious tastes. Those who were so
                        fortunate as to visit this celebration came away with the warmest
                        expressions of satisfaction falling from their lips.</p>
                    <p>The Methodists took possession of their old grounds, "Shetter's Grove," about
                        one mile East of the Borough. Hon. Wilson Reilly delivered the oration; but
                        we forbear saying any thing about it. We hope the gentleman will give it for
                        publication, when our readers can see for themselves, that its equal has not
                        fallen from the lips of any man, in these parts, for an age. We cannot do
                        the subject justice, so we take off our hat and remain silent.</p>
                    <p>A very long table, filled with the good things of life, was stretched along
                        the top of the Ridge, and surrounded, again and again, by the children--in
                        hundreds--and the scores of delighted visitors. Everything which kindness,
                        foresight and politeness could do, to add to the comfort of the large
                        company present, was cheerfully done, and every person went away pleased
                        beyond expression. Among the pleasing incidents of this entertainment was
                        the raising of two baloons [sic]. Their ascension was accomplished with
                        complete success. In the evening the gentlemen connected with this school
                        started off a most beautiful balloon from the diamond of the town. It rose
                        some several hundred feet, and moved slowly through the atmosphere,
                        exhibiting its handsome proportions to the whole town. It alighted about one
                        mile from town and will be put up again in a few days.</p>
                    <p>The German Reformed Sabbath School repaired to Eehman's Grove, about one and
                        a half miles North of Chambersburg. They, to the number of several hundred,
                        met at the Church at six o'clock, A. M., and left at half past six in hacks,
                        omnibusses and carriages--with banners flying. It was a pretty sight; their
                        little sparkling eyes and rosy cheeks telling of the joyful anticipations
                        which swelled their happy bosoms. The exercises upon the ground consisted of
                        singing, prayer, reading the Declaration by W. Heyser, Sr., Esq., and
                        delivering of several Addresses and a Prologue,--by the Scholars and
                        Teachers. A number of fine swings were erected by Capt. Matthew Gillan, and
                        the other gentlemen upon whom rested the labor of preparing the grounds,
                        upon which the happy attendants enjoyed themselves finely.</p>
                    <p>A sumptuous repast was prepared, and spread out upon a table almost one
                        hundred feet long, which was filled up several times by the school and the
                        invited guests.</p>
                    <p>After dinner the Rev. Mr. Bousman entertained the audience, for half an hour,
                        with an address, filled with incidents of his recent travels in Egypt. This
                        gentleman has a peculiar faculty for describing scenes connected with
                        Oriental countries, and we feel glad to know that he intends giving a series
                        of Lectures, at stated intervals, on Sabbath evenings in the German Reformed
                        Church, in this place.</p>
                    <p>Everything, at these different scenes of innocent amusement passed off as
                        pleasantly and happily as could be. Great good was done, both to the
                        children and adults, by these gatherings and rompings in the wild woods. The
                        children are happier and more contented; and the grown up folks who
                        participated, were greatly refreshed and invigorated by their exercise in
                        the open air, and by throwing off all business cares and anxieties, and
                        enjoying themselves as they were want to do in childhood's sportive, happy
                        days. We hope these health-giving festivals may be observed with
                        conscientious scrupulousness as often as the day recurs.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoke</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reilly</ln>
                        <fn>Wilson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillan</ln>
                        <fn>A. Matthew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Recounts Chambersburg's Independence Day celebration, with names of
                    speakers and principals.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/july59.html#7.6a</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Suicide</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foreman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf>residence near Quincy</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports the suicide of the 18-year-old Mr. Foreman. No first name
                    mentioned.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Sabbath School Celebration</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCauley</ln>
                        <fn>Clay</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reilly</ln>
                        <fn>Wilson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCauley</ln>
                        <fn>I.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Everett</ln>
                        <fn>W.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports the events and speeches of the sabbath school celebration of the
                    Methodist Wesleyan Church of Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Shryock About Again</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shryock</ln>
                        <fn>John K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports Mr. Shryock's leadership of the Franklin Academy boys choir in a
                    cantata. Concludes with heavy praise for the Academy as an institution in
                    general.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.07.06.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Late Hon. D.F. Robison</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robison</ln>
                        <fn>David F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Recounts Mr. Robison's last public speech on "The Pleasures of Study."</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.07.06.06">
            <pageNote>Page covered by advertisements and "Protestantism in Sardinia," plus other
                features.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.07.06.07">
            <pageNote>Page covered by advertisements and "Arrival of Gold Express"</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.07.06.08">
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>West</ln>
                        <fn>W.A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stevens</ln>
                        <fn>Hannah</fn>
                        <sf>of Clear Ridge, Fulton Co.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stevens</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf>father of bride</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf>of Shade Gap, Huntington Co.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Wedding of June 23, at Clear Ridge, Fulton Co.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Philips</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hommon</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Empich</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Wedding of July 3, at Chambersburg's German Reformed Parsonage. Both
                    parties of Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reese</ln>
                        <fn>P.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paxton</ln>
                        <fn>Alice Maria</fn>
                        <sf>of Chambersburg</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cooper</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf>of Santa Cruz, California</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paxton</ln>
                        <fn>W.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Wedding of July 4. Editor's addendum notes that the reception consisted of
                    TWO cakes, a large lot of oranges, and an entire churn of ice cream.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hefleman</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes the death of Mr. Hefleman, aged 78 years, on June 22.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robison</ln>
                        <fn>David Fullerton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robison</ln>
                        <fn>Matthew F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robison</ln>
                        <fn>Martha F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes the death of the infant Robison, in Newville, Cuberland Co., on June
                    30. He was aged five months.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnston</ln>
                        <fn>Stephen Skinner</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnston</ln>
                        <fn>D.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes the sudden death, by apoplexy, of the eleven-year- old Johnston
                    youth. Family residence near Dry Run. Date is in error, given as the "34th."</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin>Columbia City (Indiana) News</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hassler</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hassler</ln>
                        <fn>Malachi</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes the death of Mrs. Hassler on June 26, at Columbia City, Indiana. Her
                    age is obscured.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKee</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes Mrs. McKee's death on June 20, in Chambersburg, at the age of 77.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn>Maria M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn>E.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn>Elmira</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes the death of the youngster Maria Grove at the age of two years, in
                    Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blood</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes the death of Mr. Blood on July 1, in Chambersburg, at the age of
                    "about 70." He was for many years a Tutor in Chambersburg Schools.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
