<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1869/pa.fr.vs.1869.10.06">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/30/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1869-10-06">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="10">October</month>
            <day norm="">6</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.10.06.01" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>08</column>
                <head>The Situation in the State</head>
                <origin>Patriot and Union</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article predicts the sure defeat of Gov. John Geary. He has rapidly
                    lost popularity in the state because he places personal interest ahead of public
                    good.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.10.06.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Who Will You Vote For?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Every good citizen wishes to cast his vote next Tuesday for the candidates
                        who will labor most zealously to advance the interests of the people.</p>
                    <p>The Radical candidate for Governor is to be judged as to his future action by
                        his past conduct. What has that been?</p>
                    <p>John W. Geary has been a reckless pardon-broker, opening the prison-doors to
                        let the guilty go free simply because they were his political friends, or
                        for a pecuniary reward. He has violated his own published regulations in
                        this respect, and has thus made all order-loving citizens tremble for the
                        security of their property and the safety of their lives.</p>
                    <p>John W. Geary has lent his official influence and aid to the jobbers and
                        lobbyists who buy members of the Legislature as so many cattle. He has been
                        interested in the corrupt schemes which have been concocted at Harrisburg at
                        the expense of the toiling tax-payers of the State.</p>
                    <p>John W. Geary approved a bill which estimates a man's limbs at not worth more
                        than three thousand dollars.</p>
                    <p>John W. Geary signed a bill which values the life of the citizen at no more
                        than five thousand dollars.</p>
                    <p>John W. Geary has thus usurped the province of a jury and compelled the
                        widows and orphans of passengers killed on a railroad to receive this
                        inadequate sum for their support.</p>
                    <p>John W. Geary wrote a private letter, and affixed to it the great seal of the
                        Commonwealth, addressed to Hon. Edward McPherson, Clerk of the House of
                        Representatives, in which he states his opinion that John Govode, alias
                        Covode, had been elected to Congress from the 21st District of Pennsylvania.
                        And this, after he had deliberately refused to proclaim him, or Henry D.
                        Foster as the member-elect. McPherson laughed at the letter. The House
                        hooted at the idea and his own political friends dubbed him "Supplementary
                        Proclamation Geary."</p>
                    <p>John W. Geary sought to legislate an upright and honest Judge out of office.
                        At the bidding of Peter Herdic, he signed a bill by which the 9th Judicial
                        district was wiped out of existence. It was a blow aimed at the pure Judge
                        Gamble, just because he is a Democrat and a man who will not be the tool of
                        Peter Herdic.</p>
                    <p>John W. Geary sat in the Executive Chamber until midnight waiting for a
                        bribed Legislature to pass this infamous bill so that he could attach his
                        signature to it.</p>
                    <p>John W. Geary has been most signally rebuked for selling himself in this job,
                        for the Supreme Court declared the Act unconstitutional and reinstated Judge
                        Gamble in the position from which he and Peter Herdic and the other
                        "pinchers" and "roosters" had driven him.</p>
                    <p>John W. Geary has been mixed up dishonorably with other jobs of a disgraceful
                        character, such as the Metropolitan Police bill, the Twelfth and Sixteenth
                        Street Railway bill, and the Cattle bill.</p>
                    <p>John W. Geary, during the last legislative session, signed 1343 bills. Of
                        these 71 are general laws, applicable to the people of the whole State. The
                        remainder, 1272, are acts of special legislation, procured at the instance
                        and through the influence of individuals and corporations, and in the main,
                        of no benefit whatever to the public. If a calculation were made as to what
                        the projectors of each of these bills could afford to pay for its passage,
                        some idea could be given of the amount of money that John W. Geary and a
                        Radical legislature have pocketed, for the people can rest assured that they
                        have made all out of this special legislation that was in it.</p>
                    <p>John W. Geary has publicly confessed his inability to cope with "the Ring,"
                        for in a speech made at Troy some two weeks ago, he blames it on the people
                        who elect such scoundrels to the Legislature. This was a poor compliment to
                        his political friends who have been in the majority in the Legislature for
                        years, and consequently responsible for the laws that have been enacted.</p>
                    <p>John W. Geary could have prevented all this iniquitous legislation by the
                        interposition of the Executive veto. As he failed to do it, the fair
                        inference is that he was a sharer in the spoils.</p>
                    <p>John W. Geary has imposed an additional burden upon the already over-taxed
                        people of the State by increasing the rate of interest on the public debt
                        from five to six per cent.</p>
                    <p>John W. Geary has managed to grow rich in the Gubernatorial chair. Where and
                        how did he make his money?</p>
                    <p>John W. Geary has betrayed the people in the matter of negro suffrage. In
                        1866, he told them that they would be permitted to vote upon the question,
                        and that the negro could not vote until the people of the State would see
                        fit to amend their State Constitution in the manner prescribed in that
                        instrument.</p>
                    <p>John W. Geary, in open violation of these pledges, recommended the adoption
                        of the fifteenth amendment to the Pennsylvania Legislature. He advised that
                        body to snatch from the people of this State the great Constitutional right
                        to vote upon a question of such grave importance as this.</p>
                    <p>John W. Geary has thus attempted to force negro suffrage upon the people of
                        Pennsylvania.</p>
                    <p>Will honest people vote for such a man as this? Is there no virtue left in
                        the masses? Are they still ready to be led off by military clap-trap? Are
                        they still willing to drown reason with the clangor of sabres and roll of
                        drums? It can not be that virtue and State pride and sober judgment have all
                        been laid aside.</p>
                    <p>Turn to the other side of the picture.</p>
                    <p>Asa Packer has lived many years in this sinful world. And yet, the purity of
                        his character is unquestioned. Unstained by the vices to which so many
                        distinguished men have been addicted, his life has been one of singular
                        abstemiousness and correctness.</p>
                    <p>Asa Packer is an honest man. Although possessed of untold wealth, there is
                        not a creature in the wide world who will say that he knowingly ever took a
                        cent wrongfully from any one. The fortune of which he is the sole architect
                        has been amassed by honest labor. No wild speculations have marked his
                        career. He has never gambled in fancy stocks, or, for his own private gain,
                        deranged the financial affairs of his country by speculations in gold.</p>
                    <p>Asa Packer is a man of great foresight. His own intellect comprehended the
                        situation and grasped the importance of the gigantic railroad enterprise
                        which he projected. He saw where money could be made rapidly for himself and
                        for others. In building the Lehigh Valley railroad, he saw that he would
                        reap immense profits, but he saw, too, that it would add infinitely to the
                        wealth of the country through which it would pass.</p>
                    <p>Asa Packer is a man of dauntless resolution. No difficulties that stood in
                        the way of his darling railroad scheme ever dampened his ardor, or clouded
                        his reason, or stayed his arm. Forward he moved, amid circumstances that
                        would have discouraged and appalled many a stout heart, until success
                        crowned his efforts and he begun to reap the glorious fruition of his
                        labors.</p>
                    <p>Asa Packer is a man of liberal ideas on the subject of education. With
                        princely munificence he founded the Lehigh University and endowed it, thus
                        throwing wide open the doors of knowledge to the young men of the State.
                        Surely the young men ought to attest their appreciation of this praiseworthy
                        act by honoring him to whom honor is due.</p>
                    <p>Asa Packer is a man who is in perfect sympathy with the people. His early
                        life was one of almost pinching poverty. Difficulties of every kind
                        confronted him. He became a mechanic. He earned his daily bread by "the
                        sweat of his face." By frugality and industry he saved enough to start in
                        business. Such were his struggles, and every laboring man, every mechanic
                        will feel that one who has gone through such sharp trials himself will
                        readily sympathize with them, understand their wants fully, and labor
                        earnestly to enable them to gather all the fruit of their labor. Laboring
                        men, Asa Packer is the man you should elect Governor.</p>
                    <p>Asa Packer is a man whom the lobbyist and corruptionist will not dare to
                        approach. They know well the reception that would be accorded to them.
                        Uncontaminated by the companionship of such polluted wretches as those who
                        hang around Geary. Asa Packer will administer the State Government with an
                        eye to the abolition of the corrupt practices that have brought the present
                        Executive into such marked disgrace.</p>
                    <p>Asa Packer will crush the corrupt "Ring" that has cursed Harrisburg of late
                        years. By the exercise of the veto power on unjust and purchased special
                        legislation, he will take away from the "pinchers" and "roosters" the meat
                        on which they have grown fat, and their occupation being gone, they will be
                        obliged to flit also.</p>
                    <p>Asa Packer will inaugurate an era in which honesty shall take the place of
                        dishonesty and administrative ability that of blundering incapacity.</p>
                    <p>Asa Packer will refuse to lend his sanction to any project, or measure, which
                        would take away from the people of Pennsylvania the right to regulate their
                        own State affairs for themselves.</p>
                    <p>Asa Packer will stop up the immense leaks in the State treasury and insist
                        upon the curtailment of the expenses of the State administration.</p>
                    <p>Asa Packer will see to it that the surplus funds in the hands of the State
                        Treasurer be appropriated to the payment of the State debt, and that they be
                        not manipulated for the private benefit of that official, at the expense of
                        the overburdened tax-payers of the State.</p>
                    <p>Asa Packer will be one of your old-fashioned Governors, who by the selection
                        of able advisers and the practice of strict integrity, will maintain the
                        honor of your Commonwealth, and being back within her borders, the happy and
                        prosperous days which her citizens enjoyed under Democratic rule.</p>
                    <p>Choose ye between them.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Gives an extensive analysis of why voters should choose Democrat Asa Packer
                    over Republican John Geary for Governor. Lays out all of Geary's faults,
                    especially those concerning corruption and money mismanagement. Then pumps up
                    Packer's virtues, especially honesty, hard work, and integrity.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The party endorses Asa Packer for governor, Cyrus L. Pershing for supreme
                    judge, George W. Skinner and D. B. Milliken for assembly, George W. Welsh for
                    prothonotary, B. A. Cormany for clerk of the courts, Hiram T. Snyder for
                    register and recorder, William Reber for county treasurer, Jacob Brumbaugh for
                    commissioner, Frederick C. Long for director of the poor, and John Tritle for
                    auditor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Why Pensions are Not Paid</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Thousands of widows in the State of Pennsylvania are waiting anxiously for
                        the money which is due to them as pensioners, and wondering why it does not
                        come. They know that Congress has appropriated the money to pay them. They
                        know that they have empowered Attornies to collect it for them, and they can
                        not imagine the reason for the delay. Let us tell you. The agent for paying
                        pensions at Philadelphia is an eloquent fellow, named Major A. R. Calhoun,
                        who addressed the citizens of Franklin county at various places in the last
                        campaign, in behalf of Grant. Geary has dragooned him into the service, by a
                        threat of decapitation, and instead of remaining in Philadelphia attending
                        to the duties of his office and thus relieving the wants of the poor, he is
                        traveling over the State making stump speeches in favor of Geary's
                        re-election. The widows must wait until Geary is attended to.</p>
                    <p>Many maimed and disabled veterans of the war are becoming exceedingly
                        impatient because their six months pension has not come to hand. They are
                        wondering, too, why they have not been paid. Let us tell you. It is because
                        the agent for paying Invalid Pensions refuses to pay the money to Attornies
                        whom you have selected to transact the business for you. You live a
                        considerable distance from town. You come to Chambersburg and you employ an
                        Attorney to collect your pension. You know him well and have perfect
                        confidence in him. He prepares your papers for you and you authorize him to
                        receive the money. <emph rend="italic">You request him to send the money to
                            you as soon as he gets it</emph>. He sends the papers to Philadelphia
                        and the agent there sends him a check <emph rend="italic">payable to your
                            order</emph> for the money. He can do nothing with it until you endorse
                        it. He sends it to you by mail. You must endorse it and then, not being able
                        to get the money on your check at your home, unless you allow a considerable
                        discount, you <emph rend="italic">send it back to the very same
                        Attorney</emph>. He collects the money and at last sends it to you by mail,
                        after all the unasked for precaution which the Pension Department sees fit
                        to exercise. All this takes time and of course delays the payment much
                        longer than necessary. When you execute a power of attorney to one whom you
                        can trust you have no reason to thank anybody for saying that you are not
                        capable of making a selection of an Attorney, or of transacting your
                        business in the way you see fit to do it.</p>
                    <p>Now the motive which prompts this action on the part of the Government
                        officers is not any peculiar love for the soldier, or the soldier's widow,
                        but it is a desire to pocket all the fees themselves that are chargeable for
                        the collection of pensions.</p>
                    <p>Such a set of unprincipled men it is that have found their way into the
                        offices of trust through Radical influence and by Radical appointment. The
                        sooner the people rise up and drive these fellows from their places, the
                        quicker will come the day when justice will be done to the widows of those
                        who sacrificed their lives upon the altar of their country, and to the
                        scarred surviving heroes of the late war.</p>
                    <p>In this connection, we would state that we have read the masterly argument of
                        Mathews, Poulson &amp; Co., of Philadelphia, on this question of the
                        right of the pensioner to empower any Attorney of his or her choice, to
                        receive the money on the pension voucher. It is a full and clear exposition
                        of the subject and is a just rebuke of this extraordinary assumption of
                        power on the part of the Pension Agent at Philadelphia.</p>
                    <p>The Secretary of the Interior, to whom the appeal was taken, whilst he
                        decides against them, is careful to evade the issue, and does not touch the
                        question of the right of the pensioner to appoint an Attorney to receive the
                        money.</p>
                    <p>Keep the Radicals in power and before long, every citizen will find a
                        self-constituted Radical Committee insisting on attending to his own private
                        business. And if he does not watch closely, he will find himself robbed of
                        all he has by these self-appointed guardians who will pretend that they want
                        to take better care of his funds than he can exercise himself.</p>
                    <p>Vote for Packer and the whole Democratic ticket and oust these unworthy
                        officials from the places which they have disgraced.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Blames Radicals for the delays in paying out pensions, and claims they only
                    concern themselves with winning re-election. Explains the reasons for the delays
                    and insists Democrats will fix the problem if elected.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Are you in favor of the fifteenth amendment? Do you believe in the right of
                        Congress to override your State constitution and force negro suffrage upon
                        you? If so, vote for McKnight and Gantt. They will never disturb the
                        resolution of the Pennsylvania Legislature ratifying the fifteenth
                        amendment. <emph rend="italic">McKnight says he is opposed to negro
                            suffrage, but he only wants to catch Democratic votes. Should he be
                            elected, he would chuckle over the trick by which he deceived
                        Democrats</emph>.</p>
                    <p>Or, do you want the fifteenth amendment defeated? Do you wish to teach
                        Congress that they must not interfere with the right of the people of a
                        State to regulate the right of Suffrage? Do you want to prevent the negro
                        from voting? If so, vote for Skinner and Milliken. They will both vote to
                        repeal the resolution ratifying the fifteenth amendment. They deceive nobody
                        on this question. Their position is taken boldly and without equivocation.
                        They use no false pretences to obtain votes.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Boils the election down to approving or repealing the 15th amendment. Says
                    Republicans will uphold it and Democrats will defeat it, so urges voters to
                    elect Democrats not only to keep votes away from blacks but also to preserve
                    state rights.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Long</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper gloats over the Repository's revelations of the expenditures
                    during Republican administration of the Poor House. They spent three times as
                    much as Democrats. The paper advocates remedying the situation by electing
                    Democrat Frederick C. Long Director of the Poor House.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>The Radical Border Damage Record</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper charges that Republican State Legislators opposed payment of war
                    damages to residents of border counties.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Work! Work!! Work!!!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper urges all Democrats to vote, and suggests formations of
                    committees to bring laggard friends and neighbors to the polls.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palmer</ln>
                        <fn>Jonas C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper endorses Democrat Jacob Brumbaugh as candidate to replace Radical
                    Jonas C. Palmer as county commissioner. This election is especially crucial
                    since a victory would give Democrats a majority on the board.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reber</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper endorses William Reber, "an honest man," for county treasurer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.10.06.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper warns Democrats that the county will be flooded with "spurious
                    tickets" and urges them to check their own before voting.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Music</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hershberger</ln>
                        <fn>H. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Maj. H. R. Hershberger will begin giving violin lessons.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Confirmation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Bishop Stranahan administered the sacrament of confirmation in
                    Chambersburg's Catholic Church to 25 young ladies and 19 young men.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>A Festival</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The German Reformed Church of St. Thomas held a festival on the 24th and
                    25th to raise money for their Sunday School library. It was held in the
                    churchyard, and cake, ice cream, and fruit was served. The Citizen's Band of
                    Chambersburg performed. The event grossed $151 leaving a profit of $75.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Major A. R. Calhoun, Philadelphia pension agent, will speak at a Republican
                    meeting at the Court House. "Whilst he is making stump speeches for Geary, the
                    widows of soldiers are waiting, anxiously waiting for their pension money. He
                    will mail the checks the day after the election. Until then, he has no time."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Club Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Capt. George W. Skinner, candidate for the assembly, addressed the
                    Democratic Club of St. Thomas Township. "The Captain defined his position on the
                    negro suffrage question and the Border Damage claim with clearness and force.
                    The Democracy of St. Thomas seems to be wide awake, and we expect to hear from
                    them after the election."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craig</ln>
                        <fn>Jesse</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLanahan</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fletcher</ln>
                        <fn>L. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jesse Craig, "one of the most estimable citizens of Franklin County," died
                    near Welsh Run on September 23rd. He was a member of the Board of Directors of
                    the First National Bank of Greencastle. The board issued resolutions of sympathy
                    and respect.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>More About the Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Engineers are surveying routes for a railroad linking the Cumberland Valley
                    road to Loudon. Citizens of Greencastle and Mercersburg have pledged $130,000
                    for a route that goes through their towns. An alternative route would go through
                    Bridgeport in Peters Township. $75,000 would need to be raised for that route.
                    The paper urges the people of Loudon and Path Valley to do it.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mills</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Jennie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schaff</ln>
                        <fn>J. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Abraham Mills and Jennie Miller, both of Chambersburg, were married by the
                    Rev. J. G. Schaff.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Howard</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hyers</ln>
                        <fn>Mary M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schaff</ln>
                        <fn>J. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George W. Howard and Miss Mary M. Hyers, both of Shippensburg, were married
                    on September 12th at the U. B. Parsonage by the Rev. J. G. Schaff.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zarman</ln>
                        <fn>Franklin</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Meessy</ln>
                        <fn>Annie M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schaff</ln>
                        <fn>J. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Franklin Zarman, Jr., and Miss Annie M. Meessy, both of Chambersburg, were
                    married on September 28th at the U. B. Parsonage by the Rev. J. G. Schaff.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rosenberry</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mackey</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schaff</ln>
                        <fn>J. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Rosenberry of Adams County and Miss Sarah E. Mackey of Horse Valley
                    were married on September 30th at the U. B. Parsonage by the Rev. J. G. Schaff.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>William J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McNinon</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anthony</ln>
                        <fn>J. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William J. Reed and Miss Maggie McNinon, both of Franklin, were married on
                    September 25th at Spring Run by the Rev. J. P. Anthony.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heneberger</ln>
                        <fn>Christian</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Christian Heneberger died in Chambersburg on October 3rd. He was 75 years
                    old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Winger</ln>
                        <fn>Esther</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Winger</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Esther Winger, wife of Joseph Winger, died at Claylick on September
                    24th after a lingering illness. She was 54 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craig</ln>
                        <fn>Jesse</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jesse Craig died near Welsh Run on September 23rd. He was 71 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hass</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Abraham Hass died near Waynesboro on September 24th. He was 53 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.10.06.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
