<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1869/pa.fr.vs.1869.12.29">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>09/02/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1869-12-29">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="12">December</month>
            <day norm="">29</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.12.29.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.12.29.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>A State Thrown Out</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The facility with which the Radicals take a State into, or throw it out of
                        the Union, is really surprising. To some few old fogies like ourselves, it
                        seems somewhat startling, but the great body of the people keep no account
                        of it. They have come to look up on the whole action of Congress as a sort
                        of sleight-of-hand performance which can possibly do no good and, under the
                        care of Providence, no harm. Bills have been introduced in the Senate and
                        House of Representatives, which might well cause the bones of Washington,
                        Jefferson, Madison, and Jackson to rattle in their coffin. Were they in full
                        life to-day, to witness the encroachments which the legislative department
                        is making upon the other two branches of the government, they would warn the
                        people in more impressive language than any ever employed by them, against
                        the dangers which threaten their liberties. And, then, looking up the apathy
                        which characterizes the American people in relation to the destructive
                        legislation emanating from the National Capitol, they would be apt to
                        concede that the spirit of '76 had ceased to animate American citizens and
                        that the present generation are degenerate sons of noble sires.</p>
                    <p>In 1861, eleven States seceded from the Union. The whole military power of
                        the remaining States was called into requisition to force them back. Four
                        years of bloody war ensued, waged upon the basis of the celebrated
                        Crittenden resolutions. The North triumphed. The Rebels threw down their
                        arms, and since then, no act of hostility to the government has been
                        committed. Four years have passed since the war closed, and yet Virginia,
                        Mississippi and Texas have never been readmitted, while, greatest outrage of
                        all, the State of Georgia, which had been re-admitted on terms prescribed by
                        Congress, has been thrust out again.</p>
                    <p>The adoption of the fourteenth amendment was secured by notifying Georgia and
                        other Southern States that they could not be admitted to representation in
                        Congress until they would ratify it.</p>
                    <p>Next came the fifteenth amendment and, finding that there are not sufficient
                        States willing to ratify it so as to make it a part of the Constitution,
                        Congress has had recourse to the novel and shameful expedient of excluding
                        Georgia until she agrees to ratify the <emph rend="italic">fifteenth</emph>
                        amendment also. Was ever such disgraceful legislation conceived of before?
                        And shall all this tyranny be exercised in the name of liberty, and under
                        the very pretence of securing a republican form of government to that State?
                        Oh Liberty! What crimes are perpetrated in thy name! The consequences of
                        this step do not attach to Georgia alone. They affect her less than they do
                        Pennsylvania. In Georgia, the negro votes already. In Pennsylvania he does
                        not. Let this system be carried out of throwing States out of the Union
                        until they adopt the fifteenth amendment, and in that way, negro suffrage
                        will be forced upon the unwilling people of this State. Congress thus, in
                        fact, will regulate the suffrage in this Commonwealth. This is an assumption
                        of power on the part of the legislative department which no Congress would
                        have dared to attempt before the war. Shall we get back to the days of
                        constitutional government, or are we doomed to submit to the despotism of a
                        Congressional Directory?</p>
                    <p>And, through fear that this scheme will be thwarted at some future day, by a
                        decision of the highest judicial tribunal that such acts are
                        unconstitutional and, therefore, void, the Chief Magistrate is engaged in
                        selecting men for the Supreme Bench who will be the tools of Radical
                        Congressmen and hold, from their seats of justice, that Congress "can do no
                        wrong."</p>
                    <p>And, lest the Supreme Court might prove obstreperous and still feel inclined
                        to interfere with Congressional action, Congress is about to lop off from
                        the Supreme Court the power to pass upon the constitutionality of any of its
                        acts. A more ingenious plan was never devised to force such an obnoxious
                        measure as this fifteenth amendment upon an unwilling people.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes with outrage Congress' plan to refuse Georgia representation unless
                    the state passes the 15th amendment. Believes Congress is acting with
                    dictatorial power and is alarmed that people seem unaware of it. Also points out
                    how Congress has plans to stifle the Supreme Court if need be in order to ensure
                    passage of the 15th amendment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.12.29.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Border Claims</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper urges citizens to hire a member of the Chambersburg Bar to handle
                    their war damage claims.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Methodist Bishop Simpson will lecture in the Chambersburg Methodist Church.
                    He will discuss "The Cross and the Crescent." Tickets are 50 cents.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Concert by Trinity Sabbath School</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Christmas Eve concert by the Trinity Sabbath School was a success. the
                    children exhibited careful practice and training in rendering the complex pieces
                    arranged by Mr. Wright. The group will meet requests to perform again at the
                    Masonic Hall on New Year's Eve.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Cumberland Valley Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Cumberland Valley Railroad carried 18,785 passengers from Chambersburg
                    alone during the fiscal year ending September 30th, 1869. The road carried
                    24,467,231 pounds of freight from Chambersburg and brought in 38,279,204. The
                    road's passenger earnings stood at $191,831.76, freight earnings at $321,268.43
                    and mail and express earnings at $26,669.05. The expenses of the road totaled
                    $347,076.64.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Lecture of Rev. Mr. Raffensperger</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Rev. Mr. Raffensperger delivered a successful lecture in aid of the
                    Ladies' Mite Society. His talk was entitled "The Humors of the Pulpit and the
                    Pew." It combined solemn discussion of a minister's duties with many humorous
                    anecdotes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>St. Nicholas</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>St. Nicholas made an appearance at Repository Hall on Christmas Eve to the
                    joy of the children of the Trinity Church Sunday School.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jenkins</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stouffer</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brand</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Suesserott</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Franklin County Horticultural Society held their regular meeting.
                    Fruits and vegetables were exhibited, and club business expedited.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Matthews</ln>
                        <fn>A. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Earley</ln>
                        <fn>Sallie J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCullough</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A. A. Matthews and Miss Sallie J. Earley, both of Chambersburg, were
                    married in Philadelphia on December 23rd by the Rev. J. B. McCullough, pastor of
                    the Green Street M. E. Church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duffie</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hochlander</ln>
                        <fn>Mary A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schaff</ln>
                        <fn>J. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Thomas J. Duffie of Maryland and Miss Mary A. Hochlander of Greencastle
                    were married at the Washington House on December 23rd by the Rev. J. G. Schaff.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>John Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cline</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Rebecca</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hibshman</ln>
                        <fn>H. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Henry Baker from near Waynesboro and Miss Mary Rebecca Cline of
                    Maryland were married by the Rev. H. W. Hibshman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoover</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gehr</ln>
                        <fn>Annie E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hibshman</ln>
                        <fn>H. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jacob Hoover of Maryland and Miss Annie E. Gehr, from near Waynesboro, were
                    married on December 16th by the Rev. H. W. Hibshman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>D. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Matler</ln>
                        <fn>H. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Biliheimer</ln>
                        <fn>T. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>D. S. McClure and Miss H. C. Matler, both from Shippesnburg, were married
                    on December 16th by the Rev. T. C. Biliheimer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>DeHaven</ln>
                        <fn>Jeb</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Leady</ln>
                        <fn>Margie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Griffith</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jeb DeHaven of Franklin and Miss Margie Leady of Harrisburg were married on
                    December 16th at the residence of the bride's parents by the Rev. Griffith.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>French</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rowe</ln>
                        <fn>Sue M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>DeMoyer</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William H. French and Miss Sue M. Rowe, both of Waynesboro, were married on
                    December 16th by the Rev. J. A. DeMoyer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snare</ln>
                        <fn>Augustus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Embich</ln>
                        <fn>Charlotte R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gotwald</ln>
                        <fn>L. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Augustus Snare of Clearfield County and Miss Charlotte R. Embich of
                    Franklin were married on December 26th by the Rev. L. A. Gotwald.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLaughlin</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Susan McLaughlin died at Claylick on December 13th. She was 37 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Plum</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Plum</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Elizabeth Plum, daughter of Joseph Plum, died on December 17th. She
                    was 15 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nishwander</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Nishwander died near Upton on December 19th. He was 80 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.12.29.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
