<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1869/pa.fr.vs.1869.02.17">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/15/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1869-02-17">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="02">Feburary</month>
            <day norm="">17</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.02.17.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.02.17.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Proposed Amendment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The legislation of Congress with reference to the negro has at length
                        culminated in what is proposed as the fifteenth amendment to the
                        Constitution of the United States. Let every man who desires to preserve the
                        dignity of the white race and who seeks to maintain the republic, read it
                        carefully and ponder it well. Here it is:</p>
                    <p>ART. 15. <emph rend="italic">No discrimination shall be made in the United
                            States among the citizens of the United States in the exercise of the
                            elective franchise, or in the right to hold office, in any State, on
                            account of race, color, nativity, property, education, or creed.</emph></p>
                    <p>This amendment ought to arouse a spirit of indignation all over the land.
                        There is an attempt made here on the part of these negro worshipers to steal
                        a march on the people. They know well that wherever the proposition has been
                        submitted directly to the people, to give the negro the right of suffrage,
                        it has been condemned. Even in States that always elect Republicans to
                        office, this movement has met with no favor. But the leaders in Congress
                        believe that this amendment can be adopted without allowing the people to
                        vote on it. The Constitution of the United States allows amendments proposed
                        by Congress to be submitted to <emph rend="italic">the Legislatures</emph>
                        of the several States, and when ratified by three-fourths of such
                        Legislatures they become a part of said Constitution. The Radical leaders
                        imagine that they can induce three-fourths of the present State Legislatures
                        to ratify this amendment, and thus make the negro a voter, and clothe him
                        with the right to hold office, in every State of the Union, without saying
                        to the people "with your leave, dear sirs." Can any thinking man conceive of
                        a greater political outrage than this would be? None of these State
                        Legislatures were elected with reference to this question. On the contrary,
                        all the Republican members of these Legislatures were elected on the
                        platform on which General Grant was elected, namely, that "<emph
                            rend="italic">the question of suffrage in the loyal States properly
                            belongs to the people of these States</emph>." Not to the Legislatures
                        elected last fall, <emph rend="italic">but to the people</emph>.</p>
                    <p>To show the purpose of the Radicals in Congress in this respect, it is but
                        necessary to refer to the resolution offered by one of our own Senators, Mr.
                        Buckalew, when this amendment was under consideration. It was to this
                        effect, that this amendment should be submitted to the State Legislatures
                            <emph rend="italic">the more popular branch of which shall be hereafter
                            elected</emph>. The object of this resolution was to allow the people to
                            <emph rend="italic">make this a test question</emph> in deciding how
                        their votes should be cast for Representatives in their State Legislatures.
                        In this way, the people would have had an opportunity to decide for or
                        against negro suffrage to some extent at least. But Senator Buckalew's
                        resolution met with no favor with the Radicals and was voted down. They
                        preferred to trust the proposed amendments to Legislatures already elected,
                        rather than to Legislatures hereafter to be elected.</p>
                    <p>Hypocritical, unmindful of their pledges, regardless of their honor, they
                        seek to fasten this iniquitous measure upon the people in spite of their
                        abhorrence of it. We shall see whether the Legislature of Pennsylvania will
                        dare to take such a step in defiance of the wishes of her people. All that
                        the people ask is an opportunity to pass upon the question and they will
                        sink it deeper than ever plummet sounded. But if they are deprived of this
                        right, from mountain and valley, their indignation may burst forth and sweep
                        from Legislative halls the men who recklessly disregard their will and defy
                        their power.</p>
                    <p>If the established institutions of our country are to be overturned by
                        malicious demagogues--if such startling innovations are to be made upon our
                        time honored customs--if, in a Republic, the voice of the people is no
                        longer to be consulted, the sooner revolution comes the better.</p>
                    <p>Again, throughout the last campaign, what stress was put upon the closing
                        sentence of Grant's letter of acceptance, <emph rend="italic">let us have
                            peace!</emph> Is this the peace that Radicalism promised us? How the
                        country responded to that utterance! It was tired of rebellion and war--it
                        was heartily sick of the excitement and worry about the negro. It accepted
                        General Grant's statement that he, from that day forward, was in favor of
                        peace--no more negro agitation--no more infringements upon the rights of the
                        white race.</p>
                    <p>But alas! the country asked for bread and Radicalism has given it a stone.
                        The agitation is not to be stopped yet. <emph rend="italic">The negro must
                            vote and hold office in every State of the Union</emph>, and we are not
                        to have peace until then. The amendment now occupying so much of the
                        attention of Congress is to be transferred to the States to involve the
                        people in endless agitation, squabbles and, perhaps, serious outbreaks. Was
                        ever a party guilty of such perfidy as this Radical party which calls itself
                        "the party of great moral ideas?"</p>
                    <p>But there is another amendment proposed also, which, although not attracting
                        such general attention, is none the less insidious and pernicious. It is as
                        follows:</p>
                    <p>ART. 16. The second clause of the first section of the second article of the
                        Constitution of the United States shall be amended to read as follows:</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Each State shall appoint, by a vote of the people thereof
                            qualified to vote for Representatives in Congress, a number of electors
                            equal to the whole number of Senators and Representatives to which the
                            State shall be entitled in Congress; but no Senator, or Representative,
                            or person holding an office of trust or profit under the United States,
                            shall be appointed an elector; and Congress shall have power to
                            prescribe the manner in which such electors shall be chosen by the
                            people</emph>.</p>
                    <p>Some of the Radical papers say that this is intended to prevent the
                        Legislatures of the States from choosing the electors, as is the case at
                        present in South Carolina. That may, or may not be, one object. We do not
                        know. One thing, however, we are opposed to, and that is to putting any more
                        power into the hands of Congress than it has, or has assumed, already. It
                        would give a fanatical partisan majority in Congress, like that which has
                        ruled the country for the last eight years, a splendid opportunity to
                        control the election of President, if they are to have the power to
                        prescribe the manner in which electors shall be chosen by the people. They
                        might district the States so that it would be next to impossible to select
                        electors hostile to themselves and then pass the election off as the work of
                        the people.</p>
                    <p>If there is to be a change in the mode of choosing electors, let the new mode
                        be expressly set forth in the Constitution so that the people may know how
                        they are to elect President. For our own part, we are in favor of choosing
                        no electors at all. Allow the people all over the country to vote for
                        President and Vice President and let those candidates who receive the
                        highest number of votes be declared elected. But whatever course is adopted,
                        it certainly ought not to be one which will throw the making of Presidents
                        into the hands of Congress. We have had enough of Congressional
                    usurpation.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Comes out against the proposed 15th Amendment, claims Congress is trying to
                    pass black suffrage through Legislatures without the public's approval. Also has
                    harsh words for another amendment which would change the way electors are
                    chosen, editor proposes instead to do away with the electoral college
                    altogether.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Democratic County Committee Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn>John R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>H. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wunderlich</ln>
                        <fn>D. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brandt</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reily</ln>
                        <fn>James L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Loose</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>Washington</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Little</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hammond</ln>
                        <fn>Martin L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shively</ln>
                        <fn>Solomon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clugston</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palmer</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reisher</ln>
                        <fn>R. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hafer</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baily</ln>
                        <fn>T. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wistar</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilmore</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flickinger</ln>
                        <fn>S. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>DeHaven</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rhea</ln>
                        <fn>A. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skiles</ln>
                        <fn>H. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>Christian</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Unger</ln>
                        <fn>A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCleary</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sellers</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kuhn</ln>
                        <fn>W. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bitner</ln>
                        <fn>Simon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stake</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Welsh</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elliott</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Democratic County Committee met to elect delegates to the state
                    convention. John R. Orr and B. F. Winger received the nominations. They were
                    elected as friends of George W. Cass for governor and J. McDowell Sharpe for
                    Supreme Court Judge.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.02.17.03" exists="no">
            <pageNote>Page too dark to read.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.02.17.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
