<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1869/pa.fr.vs.1869.07.07">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/26/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1869-07-07">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day norm="">7</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.07.07.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.07.07.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>To The Public</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cooper</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stenger</ln>
                        <fn>William S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. M. Cooper announces he has sold his share in the Valley Spirit to
                    Augustus Duncan and William S. Stenger.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>General Meade and the Rebel Dead</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Humanity has been terribly outraged, ever since the close of the war, by the
                        revengeful teachings of the Radical party.--Its leaders have continually
                        breathed forth threatenings and slaughter against the living men of the
                        South. But this vindictive spirit has not been leveled only at the living.
                        The dead actors in the rebellion have been followed to their graves with all
                        the maledictions that Radical fanatics could make use of. On every battle
                        field which witnessed the triumph of the Union armies, the Rebel dead were
                        thrown by scores into trenches hastily dug for the purpose and there they
                        have remained to this day.--Whenever a suggestion has been made that these
                        bones ought to be collected and placed in some enclosed ground, the
                        suggester has been denounced as a sympathizer with treason. No Radical has
                        ventured to suggest the propriety of such action because he knew that it
                        would cost him his place if he holds one now or prevent him from ever
                        obtaining preferment if he is an aspirant for office.</p>
                    <p>But thanks to General George G. Meade, the suggestion has at last been made.
                        He has made it with a desire for its circulation throughout the Union, for
                        the occasion of its utterance was one which drew upon him the eyes of all
                        American citizens. Standing upon the battle field of Gettysburg--surrounded
                        by some of the men who had been his companions in arms on those eventful
                        days--with all the recollections of the bloody scenes which his eye then
                        witnessed crowding upon his memory--remembering the heroism displayed and
                        the self-sacrificing disposition manifested by the Rebel soldiery, stamping
                        them emphatically as brave men--he uttered these noble words:</p>
                    <p>There is one subject my friends, which I will mention now, and on this spot,
                        where my attention is being called to it, and on which I trust my feeble
                        voice will have some influence. When I contemplate this field, I see here
                        and there, marked with hastily dug trenches, in which the dead whom we
                        fought are gathered. They are the work of my brothers in arms the day after
                        the battle. Above them a bit of plank indicates simply that these remains of
                        the fallen were hurriedly laid there by soldiers who met them in battle. Why
                        should we not collect them in some suitable place? I do not ask that a
                        monument be erected over them; I do not ask that we should in any way
                            <sic>indorse</sic> their cause or their conduct, or entertain other than
                        feelings of condemnation for their course. But they are dead! They have gone
                        before their Maker to be judged. In all civilized countries it is the usage
                        to bury the dead with decency and respect, and even to fallen enemies
                        respectful burial is accorded in death. (Applause) I earnestly hope that
                        this suggestion may have some influence throughout this broad land, for this
                        is only one among a hundred crowded battle fields, that some persons may be
                        designated by the Government, if necessary, to collect these neglected bones
                        and bury them without commemorating monuments, but simply indicating that
                        below sleep misguided men who fell in battle for a cause over which we
                        triumphed.</p>
                    <p>At last, the voice of a great soldier has risen above the storm of passion.
                        On an occasion most appropriate, whilst paying respect and honor to the
                        brave men who laid down their lives on the altar of the Union, he seizes the
                        opportunity to remind us all that our revengeful feelings should be
                        suppressed at the portals of the grave. It is the voice of him who was the
                        central figure of the Union Army in the decisive battle of Gettysburg. It is
                        the voice of him who gave the word of command which summoned our bravest and
                        best to the conflict. It is the voice of him who watched the ever-changing
                        tide of battle for three days and who is therefore competent to attest the
                        valor of his foes. When such a man utters such words, it gives good ground
                        for hope that "the sober second thought" may soon return to the people of
                        the North and cause them to banish from their hearts the bitter feelings
                        which they have manifested towards the South--towards her living and her
                        dead--ever since the end of the war.</p>
                    <p>When we heard him say with peculiar and striking emphasis, after condemning
                        their cause and their course, "<emph rend="italic">but they are
                        dead</emph>," we felt the highest admiration for the man who would not allow
                        loyal timeservers and flatterers to sway his judgement, suppress his
                        feelings and bind his mouth shut on this subject.</p>
                    <p>But what a withering rebuke this language was to His Excellency John W.
                        Geary! He sat upon the same platform.--He was surrounded by the same
                        sleeping heroes. The same Southern valor must have been recalled by him. But
                        Geary entertains no such lofty principles. His sense of propriety never
                        taught him to speak in any terms but those of indecency of his dead foes. He
                        must have remembered, whilst these words fell from the lips of General
                        Meade, how he had outraged the nobler feelings of humanity and reflected
                        dishonor upon the American states, by the utterance of language at Antietam,
                        in relation to the Rebel dead which would have been far more becoming to a
                        Hottentot or a South Sea Islander, than to the humblest American citizen,
                        much like the Chief Magistrate of the great State of Pennsylvania. And
                        remembering this, the blush of shame ought to have mantled his cheeks as he
                        heard the victorious General of Gettysburg give expression to the high-toned
                        sentiment so totally at variance with the ignoble sentiment to which he gave
                        expression at Antietam.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Gives high praise for General Meade's speech at Gettysburg, which included
                    a call for burying Confederate dead as a matter of honor. Contrasts this noble
                    action with those of Geary, who apparently expressed nothing but contempt for
                    Confederate living and dead at Antietam.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>A New Deal</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper endorses election of an entirely new legislature this fall.
                    Republicans and some Democrats, the editors charge, need to be thrown out of a
                    house that has become corrupt.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.07.07.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Farewell Sermon</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>William F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Rev. William F. Eyster delivered his farewell sermon as pastor of the
                    Lutheran Church in Greencastle before departing for his new position as
                    principal of the Hagerstown Female Seminary.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Franklin County Graduates</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garver</ln>
                        <fn>Alice</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garver</ln>
                        <fn>E. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Alice Garver and Miss E. M. Garver of Scotland, Franklin County, both
                    graduated from the Hagerstown Female Seminary.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Our Boys</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Chambersburg's Silver Cornet Band and the Housom Zouaves militia company
                    both participated in recent ceremonies at Gettysburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roberts</ln>
                        <fn>Harriet</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roberts</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Harriet Roberts, wife of James Roberts, died in Mercersburg on June
                    18th. She was 60 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kearschling</ln>
                        <fn>Elder Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bartls</ln>
                        <fn>Sallie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Creigh</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Elder Daniel Kearschling and Miss Sallie Bartls of Maryland were married on
                    June 24th by the Rev. Thomas Creigh.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.07.07.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
