<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1869/pa.fr.vs.1869.04.06">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/23/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1869-04-06">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day norm="">6</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.04.06.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.04.07.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Tenure of Office Bill</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>By the new Tenure of Office Bill, the Senate has succeeded in tying the hands
                        of President Grant, almost without his knowing it. The absolute repealers
                        have failed miserably. The President has been tomahawked in the house of his
                        friends. And worst of all, Butler has consented to it. The President,
                        notwithstanding the confidence which the Radicals have claimed to repose in
                        him, finds that he is not the unshackled Executive that Washington, Madison,
                        Monroe, Jackson, and Buchanan were. He finds that although the fetters are
                        not riveted so tightly upon him as they were on Andrew Johnson, they
                        nevertheless are fetters still.</p>
                    <p>There is no freedom left to Grant to use the Federal patronage to secure his
                        own renomination.</p>
                    <p>For any office made vacant during the recess of the Senate, the President is
                        required to make his nominations within thirty days after the meeting of the
                        Senate. Should the Senate confirm the nominations, the officers who have
                        been suspended by the President will be considered removed. If the Senate
                        does not confirm them, then the question arises whether the office remains
                        vacant, or whether the suspended officers are thereby reinstated. We think
                        that there can be no doubt that the latter position is correct.</p>
                    <p>The Senate, therefore, has the power to reinstate an officer, of whose
                        suspension they disapprove, by simply refusing to act upon the nominations
                        made by the President of a person to fill his place.</p>
                    <p>And this bill goes so far, as in the event just stated, to prevent the
                        President from even <emph rend="italic">making another nomination</emph>.</p>
                    <p>The retention of this bill in this obnoxious shape discloses a want of
                        confidence on the part of the Radicals in the new President, which does not
                        comport well with the boasted confidence of the people with which he began
                        his Presidential career. If Grant were a man of independence, one who had a
                        will of his own, he would veto this bill, but he has not the courage to do
                        it. He would rather have peace purchased by the surrender of principle.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Comments on the new Tenure of Office Bill passed by Congress. Says the
                    repealers lost out, as Grant is still prevented from making his own nominations
                    without Congress looking over his shoulder. Claims Grant does not have the
                    courage to veto the bill.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>In Trouble</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph> labored last week under the
                        influence of a poke which we gave the Radical party under the fifth rib, in
                        our issue of the week before. It seems to be afraid that the conservatively
                        inclined portion of its party will shrink in disgust from associating
                        politically with men who are willing to degrade themselves to an equality
                        with the black fiend who perpetrated such gross outrages upon three helpless
                        females. And it grows warm and angry at our intimating that such deeds of
                        violence are the logical results of the teachings of the Radical leaders. We
                        can not help it if the people hold those responsible to some extent for the
                        effrontery which the negroes exhibit and the loose rein which they give to
                        their passions. It is their fault, not ours. And the sensitiveness which our
                        neighbors betray on this subject, shows that we struck a spot which they
                        know to be very weak.</p>
                    <p>The subject does not need a long argument. The fact which we announced forces
                        itself upon the minds of the people, and many in our own County are asking,
                        to what will this doctrine of elevating the negro lead us? Are they to be
                        thus encouraged to indulge their basest passions, thinking that the public
                        mind has been educated up to the point of not considering it criminal for
                        negroes to amalgamate with whites, even forcibly and against the will of the
                        whites? Let the <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph> continue to labor.
                        "The <emph rend="italic">galled</emph> jude winces."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Defends its position that Radical racial policies are the cause for black
                    assaults on whites. Claims even conservative Republicans are questioning the
                    wisdom of Radical policies.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Honor to the Negro</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper expresses "disgust" at Republican Senators' warm reception of an
                    African American Congressman-elect from Louisiana.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Alarming Condition</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In pursuance of their diabolical scheme of reconstructing the Southern States
                        so as to put them under the control of the Negroes, our Radical Congress
                        recently put out of office all the civil magistrates in the State of
                        Virginia and resolved that whole community back to a state of nature. A
                        murder being committed in Lunenburg, and there being no civil officer to
                        take action in the case, General Stoneman, the military commander, was
                        telegraphed to in regard to the course to be pursued, and his reply was as
                        follows:</p>
                    <p>RICHMOND, Va., March 25, 1869.--To P.M. Hatchell: The people must act as they
                        may think the circumstances demand.<lb/> "GEORGE STONEMAN<lb/> "Brevet Major
                        General."</p>
                    <p>"The people must act as they may think the circumstances demand!" There is no
                        law in Virginia. There is no legal tribunal before which a murderer may be
                        brought. The people, if they "think the circumstances demand" it, may burn
                        the suspected person at the stake, or tie his legs together and drown him in
                        a horse pond, or dispose of his life in any other way. If, after burning or
                        drowning him, it shall be found that he was innocent, the good people who
                        disposed of him will have the consolation of knowing that they acted under
                        the advice of the Military Satrap who lords it over the ancient commonwealth
                        of Virginia. They will have the further consolation of knowing that no
                        punishment can be inflicted upon them, as there is no officer to arrest them
                        and no court to try them.</p>
                    <p>What a state of affairs! Four years after Lee's surrender, the community in
                        whose midst that great event occurred is deprived of civil magistrates and
                        remitted back to a state of nature, in which every man is made the avenger
                        of his own wrongs--and this under the administration of the man to whom Lee
                        surrendered. "Let us have peace."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes with disgust Congress' recent action in abolishing all civil
                    magistrates in Virginia. Insists there is no law in that state anymore, cites a
                    telegram from General Stoneman as an example. Implies this is the natural result
                    of Radical reconstruction policies.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Another Black Beast</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper publishes reports of crimes committed by African Americans. "All
                    over the country, black scoundrels, taught by the Radicals to believe that they
                    have received wrongs at the hands of the whites which can only be avenged by the
                    most atrocious outrages, are wreaking their brutish vengeance upon unprotected
                    women and children."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Grant Going Down Rapidly</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The ignoramus who, with poorer qualifications than any of his predecessors,
                        stood up in the face of the American people on the 4th of March and
                        proclaimed that he assumed the duties of the chief magistracy of this great
                        Republic "without fear," in fast finding his level. His ignorance of the
                        constitution and laws, the shower of appointments he has conferred upon his
                        relatives and "cronies," and the general lack of good judgment he has
                        displayed, have disgusted a large number of influential Republicans.--There
                        are signs of a lively time ahead. The New York correspondent of the
                        Philadelphia <emph rend="italic">Ledger</emph> of Wednesday last notes the
                        following signs of the times:</p>
                    <p>The <emph rend="italic">Evening Post</emph> of to-day follows up its attacks
                        upon President Grant's Custom House appointees, and especially upon the
                        Naval Officer, General E. A. Merritt, who, it says, got his office simply as
                        a reward for his service in helping to make Gov. Fenton Senator. The
                        management of the Custom house is represented to be in the hands of rogues,
                        and the <emph rend="italic">Post</emph> under the new regime seems to think
                        there is no hope of reform. It likewise opens its batteries upon Senator
                        Fenton, and advised the President to have nothing to do with him, until
                        certain serious charges against him are cleared up.</p>
                    <p>The <emph rend="italic">Post</emph>, however, is not the only journal that
                        heretofore supporting Gen. Grant, is now disposed to desert him. The <emph
                            rend="italic">Sun</emph> has astonished its readers by an editorial
                        intimation in favor of such Constitutional changes as will practically
                        abolish the Executive Departments altogether, and make Congress supreme.</p>
                    <p>These simultaneous onslaughts on the new Administration from Republican
                        journals would seem to indicate concert of action, but the precise meaning
                        of them as yet is not very clear.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Cites a number of articles from Republican journals to show how Grant is
                    losing favor even among his party. Points to the disaffection of a number of
                    Republicans concerning Grant's recent appointments.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>What Say You, Metal Township?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper calls Captain Walker, from Metal, to explain his vote in favor of
                    the 15th amendment. The editors assert most of the citizens of Metal do not
                    favor the amendment. "We shall see whether or not they are for equalizing
                    negroes and whites."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.04.06.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Lecture</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Rev. Dr. Schwartz will lecture at the Court House where a collection
                    for the Young Men's Christian Association will be taken up.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Assistant Treasurer of the United States</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George Eyster has been nominated for the position of Assistant Treasurer of
                    the United States at Philadelphia. "Mr. Eyster possesses all the requisite
                    qualifications to make an efficient officer and we do not doubt that he will
                    give general satisfaction."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Confirmation at the Episcopal Church</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Rev. William Bacon Stevens, Bishop of the Diocese of Pennsylvania, will
                    visit Chambersburg's Trinity Episcopal Church to conduct Confirmation services.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Wilson Female College, Chambersburg, Pa.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Edwards</ln>
                        <fn>Tryon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Small</ln>
                        <fn>Albert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fletcher</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>I. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wightman</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wallace</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Creigh</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Raffensperger</ln>
                        <fn>E. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>List of officers of the board of trustees, Wilson Female College.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Poor House</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brandt</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Piper</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyle</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn>John R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel Brandt replaced David Piper as Steward of the Poor House. The
                    following also took up duties: Dr. William H. Boyle, physician; John R. Orr,
                    Attorney and Clerk. Alexander Martin has not yet been inducted as Treasurer.
                    "The Poor House is now in Democratic hands, and we trust its management will be
                    such as to meet the approbation of the public and promote the interests of the
                    taxpayers."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>School Exercises</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hawkins</ln>
                        <fn>William G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seibert</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Closing exercises for the winter term of the Rev. William G. Hawkins'
                    School for Young Ladies will be held next Friday. The school has recently moved
                    from the residence of Samuel Seibert to a planned building at the Episcopal
                    Parsonage. Joseph T. Wright will be installed as instructor of mathematics and
                    music.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Culbertson</ln>
                        <fn>John P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wunderlich</ln>
                        <fn>Julia E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wunderlich</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kunkleman</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John P. Culbertson and Miss Julia E. Wunderlich, daughter of Daniel K.
                    Wunderlich, all of Chambersburg, were married on April 6th at the residence of
                    the bride's parents by the Rev. J. A. Kunkleman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burns</ln>
                        <fn>Jeremiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coffee</ln>
                        <fn>Lemantha</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schaff</ln>
                        <fn>J. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jeremiah Burns and Miss Lemantha Coffee, both of Chambersburg, were married
                    on April 4th by the Rev. J. G. Schaff.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Malone</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lilley</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mowers</ln>
                        <fn>S. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Malone and Miss Susan Lilley, both of Franklin, were married in St.
                    Thomas on March 30th by the Rev. S. A. Mowers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.04.06.04" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Agricultural</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Copy of an "Essay on Manures" by J. M. Cooper delivered before the
                    Horticultural Society of Franklin County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
