<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1869/pa.fr.vs.1869.09.29">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/30/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1869-09-29">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day norm="">29</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.09.29.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.09.29.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The 15th Amendment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper denounces the 15th amendment and asserts that all citizens must
                    now choose to stand for or against black suffrage.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Poor House and the Repository</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper defends Democrats against charges by the Repository of
                    mismanagement of the Poor House.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Don't Trust Them</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>One of the best evidences of the unpopularity of negro suffrage in Franklin
                        county, is the fact that <emph rend="italic">the Radical candidates are
                            positively trying to persuade the people that they are opposed to
                        it</emph>. To hear them talk, when no Radical leaders are near, you would
                        think that they entertained a perfect abhorrence of negro equality. Do not
                        let them "pull the wool over your eyes," Conservatives. They are keeping the
                        negro in the back-ground until after they are elected. They are in hearty
                        sympathy with the principles of the party that nominated them.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Keep thinking of it until after you have voted, that
                            McKnight will vote to sustain the revolution which is forcing negro
                            suffrage upon the people of Pennsylvania against their will</emph>. Let
                            <emph rend="italic">repeal</emph> be your watchword, and support the
                        Democratic candidates.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Comes out fully against black suffrage and insists Franklin county feels
                    the same way because even Republican candidates say they are against it. Urges
                    voters not to be fooled by this and vote for Democrats who will repeal the 15th
                    amendment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Not Settled Yet</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Radicals were wont to tell us that if Slavery were abolished "the negro
                        question would be settled." Slavery has been abolished. Is the negro
                        question settled?</p>
                    <p>They tell us now, let the negro vote and "the negro question will be forever
                        settled." But this is not so. Already the further demands of the negro have
                        reached your ears. Already have a few Radical extremists intimated that
                        still further concessions must be made by the whites. Already have they told
                        us that the privileges and rights of the negroes must be extended. In the
                        District of Columbia, which is under the immediate control of Congress, the
                        negro has not only been clothed with the right of suffrage, but he has been
                        elected to official positions. He has become <emph rend="italic">a member of
                            the City Council</emph>. He dispenses justice <emph rend="italic">as an
                            Alderman</emph>. He decides upon the rights of life, liberty and
                        property of the white citizen, <emph rend="italic">as a juror</emph>. The
                        common schools are thrown open to his children just as they are to the
                        whites. The demand is made that, not only must they be allowed to enter the
                        same schools, but they must be instructed together, and <emph rend="italic"
                            >there must be no distinction of any kind made on account of race or
                            color</emph>.</p>
                    <p>In the Southern States, the same demands have been made and enforced under
                        penalty of permanent exclusion from representation in Congress. Hence, there
                        the negro votes, holds office, is a juror and assists in making laws.</p>
                    <p>Do you suppose that Radical demands will fall anything short of this in the
                            <emph rend="italic">loyal</emph> States? Inasmuch as they have
                        deliberately violated their plighted faith on the fifteenth amendment, can
                        they be trusted now, when they say that if you give the negro the ballot,
                        that will be a settlement of the negro question?</p>
                    <p>The Radical party expects to make the negro an element of strength in all
                        future elections and, for this reason, will demand for him perfect equality
                        with the whites. Once give him the ballot, and they will claim for him the
                        right to hold office here. They will make him a juror. He will not only take
                        his seat alongside of whites in railroad cars, but he must go into the
                        common schools and into the same classes with the whites. Your Colleges and
                        Seminaries will be thrown open to blacks and whites alike. Not only will
                        your Colleges and Seminaries for young men be forced to admit negroes, but
                        your female Seminaries will be subject to the same rules and your daughters
                        will be thrown into association and companionship with the daughters of
                        negroes. Give the Radicals the power, and they will soon supply the
                        legislation necessary to accomplish this.</p>
                    <p>Conservatives, your only safety lies in stopping this fanaticism at the point
                        which it has now reached. <emph rend="italic">Elect men to your Legislature
                            who will vote to repeal the resolution ratifying the fifteenth
                            amendment, and, if the negro is prevented from obtaining the ballot, the
                            demands for his elevation to political and social equality will
                        cease</emph>.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Employs a scare tactic by commenting on Radical racial policies. Claims
                    their demands will never stop until blacks achieve full political and social
                    equality, and points to the situation in D.C. as evidence. Calls on all
                    Conservatives to end the "fanaticism" by voting for Democrats who will repeal
                    the 15th amendment and end demands for black equality.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Be on your Guard</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Democrats keep you eyes open. The Radical candidate for Assembly is a shrewd
                        politician. He has been in the Legislature before. He has been moving about
                        among the people of this County giving his views privately to the Democracy.
                        We have heard of him in St. Thomas township. One of the most reliable men in
                        that neighborhood has given us the substance of a conversation with him. He
                        has been soliciting the votes of the Democrats there. He tells them that he
                        is conservative--<emph rend="italic">that he is opposed to negro
                        suffrage</emph>--that he believes in hiring negroes to labor, <emph
                            rend="italic">but he wants them to sit at a different table from
                        him</emph>. And then, he urges that he is particularly anxious to secure
                        payment of the border claims.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Don't put any confidence in these statements. They are
                            made for the purpose of obtaining votes. Wm. H. McKnight will never vote
                            to repeal the resolution ratifying the fifteenth amendment. If a vote
                            should be taken upon that question, he would vote to sustain the
                            resolution which forces negro suffrage upon the people of Pennsylvania,
                            notwithstanding all his palaver about conservatism, and opposition to
                            negro suffrage</emph>.</p>
                    <p>Vote for Skinner and Milliken. <emph rend="italic">They are both
                        Democrats</emph>. They are openly opposed to negro suffrage. They have no
                        hesitation in expressing their opinions publicly or privately. They make no
                        statements to Radicals in private differing from the platform on which they
                        were nominated.</p>
                    <p>And as to the border claims, they are just as anxious to secure the payment
                        of them, and just as able to do it, as Mr. McKnight. Dr. Milliken has his
                        heart in this business. He will not only vote, but he will exert all his
                        influence to procure the passage of a bill to pay the border sufferers. He
                        is an active, influential gentleman and may be relied on with perfect
                        safety. Capt. Skinner's interests are identified with the interests of the
                        people of this County. He will seek to serve his constituents, faithfully
                        and effectively, by urging with all his energy and ability, this act of
                        justice to our plundered people. Elect your own candidates, Democrats, and
                        let <emph rend="italic">us have a repeal of the iniquitous resolution
                            forcing negro suffrage upon us, and let us have payment too, for the
                            border losses</emph>.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Tells Democrats not to be taken in by statements from the Republican
                    Legislative candidate pledging opposition to black suffrage and paying border
                    claims. Says Democrats should vote for Democrats, since only they can be trusted
                    with Democratic principles and policies. Hammers at the issues of black voting
                    and border claims.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Candidate for Assembly</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Dr. D. B. Milliken, the Democratic candidate for Assembly in this Legislative
                        District from Perry County, paid us a visit last week. He is a very pleasant
                        gentleman and evidently a man of more than ordinary ability. Little Perry
                        has made a selection which it gives us great pleasure to endorse. The Dr's
                        visit was necessarily a somewhat hurried one, but he made the most of his
                        time while here. He visited Greencastle, Fayetteville, St. Thomas, and
                        mingled freely with the people of these places. He made the acquaintance of
                        a large number of the citizens of this Borough and impressed them all
                        favorably. We found him sound to the core in the principles of the
                        Democratic party, exceedingly hostile to all the negro suffrage and negro
                        equality notions of the Radicals, and earnestly enlisted in the cause of the
                        border sufferers. We feel sure that, if elected, he will labor for the
                        interests of our people, faithfully and energetically, and we know that
                            <emph rend="italic">he will vote to repeal that infamous resolution
                            ratifying the fifteenth amendment</emph>.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Endorses a Democratic candidate from another county who paid a visit to
                    Franklin county. The editor says he holds solid Democratic principles and will
                    repeal the 15th amendment if elected.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>False to the People</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper criticizes the Connecticut Legislature for ratifying the 15th
                    Amendment after the people of the state had clearly rejected a bill granting
                    black men the right of suffrage.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.09.29.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>New Methodist Church</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dyson</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A new Methodist congregation has been organized in Chambersburg led by the
                    Rev. Pastor F. Dyson. They leased ground on second street on which to build a
                    church. They had been worshipping in the German Reformed Church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Horticultural Exhibition</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guthrie</ln>
                        <fn>William D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schofield</ln>
                        <fn>Josiah E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henderson</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keefer</ln>
                        <fn>J. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Culbertson</ln>
                        <fn>Edmund</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dechert</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jeffries</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jenkins</ln>
                        <fn>T. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nixon</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>W. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brand</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Haselett</ln>
                        <fn>R. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hayser</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Engle</ln>
                        <fn>Enos B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>William G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stouffer</ln>
                        <fn>Adam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Linn</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyle</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Platt</ln>
                        <fn>George E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Solomon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>Albert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dietz</ln>
                        <fn>George A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoke</ln>
                        <fn>H. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nixon</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCulloh</ln>
                        <fn>A. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cressler</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guthrie</ln>
                        <fn>W. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stouffer</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allen</ln>
                        <fn>Josiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heyser</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dechert</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lippy</ln>
                        <fn>Lydia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ryder</ln>
                        <fn>B. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jenkins</ln>
                        <fn>T. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyle</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henderson</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schofield</ln>
                        <fn>J. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Suesserott</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Franklin County Horticultural Society held a successful exhibition.
                    People thronged the hall to view the specimens of fruit and vegetables, and many
                    discussed ways of improving cultivation in Franklin.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Borner</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nepper</ln>
                        <fn>Mandie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fohl</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John H. Borner and Miss Mandie Nepper, both of Franklin County, were
                    married near Quincy on September 19th by the Rev. J. Fohl.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoner</ln>
                        <fn>M. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Besore</ln>
                        <fn>R. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hibschman</ln>
                        <fn>H. H. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>M. H. Stoner and Miss R. M. Besore were married on September 9th at the
                    German Reformed Parsonage in Waynesboro by the Rev. H. H. W. Hibschman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>John S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mason</ln>
                        <fn>Agnes</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anthony</ln>
                        <fn>J. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John S. Wilson and Miss Agnes Mason, both of Franklin, were married at
                    Spring Run on September 16th by the Rev. J. P. Anthony.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spear</ln>
                        <fn>Blair Gilbert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spear</ln>
                        <fn>James H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spear</ln>
                        <fn>Lisie F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Blair Gilbert Spear, infant son of James H. and Lisie F. Spear, died on
                    September 12th. He was 6 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reisher</ln>
                        <fn>Minnie Rose</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reisher</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reisher</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Minnie Rose Reisher, daughter of Daniel and Susan Reisher, died on
                    September 9th. She was 2 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Witter</ln>
                        <fn>Anna Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Witter</ln>
                        <fn>Jeremiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Witter</ln>
                        <fn>Susan Rebecca</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Anna Mary Witter, daughter of Jeremiah and Susan Rebecca Witter, died at
                    Union Mills on September 16th. She was 2 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robinson</ln>
                        <fn>John C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John C. Robinson died at his Franklin County residence on September 7th. He
                    was 66 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilkins</ln>
                        <fn>Mollie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Mollie Wilkins died in Mercersburg on September 17th. She was 74 years
                    old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burton</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Overcash</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John A. Burton died in Greencastle at the residence of his sister, Mrs.
                    Overcash, on September 22nd. He was 40 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.09.29.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
