<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1869/pa.fr.vs.1869.04.21">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/23/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1869-04-21">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day norm="">21</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.04.21.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.04.21.02" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.04.21.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Homicide</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Frank Spital, a young unmarried man residing in this borough, was shot and
                        killed on Monday afternoon last by John Harmony, a young married man, also a
                        resident of this borough. John Harmony is the son of George Harmony, who
                        resides at the corner of Queen and Broad streets. He (John) is a tinner and
                        was in the employ of Mr. Etter, on Main Street. Frank Spital is the son of
                        Christian Spital, dec'd, and lived with his mother on East Market street. He
                        was a stone mason and had been at work on the foundation walls of the
                        Central Presbyterian Church. While at work on Friday last he injured one of
                        his fingers and was obliged to quit work for a few days. This trifling
                        injury appears to have cost him his life!</p>
                    <p>Spital and Harmony went out hunting on Monday afternoon. They took with them
                        one gun and a flask of whisky. They were seen by several persons in the
                        meadow of Mrs. Hurst, back of the McClure place, about a mile north of town.
                        Several shots were heard in the meadow, and it is supposed that they were
                        shooting at birds. What incurred to induce one of them to turn his gun
                        against the other is not known. John Embich, who lives at the Falling Mill
                        just above the scene of the tragedy, passing along the road, was hailed by
                        Harmony, who informed him that he had killed a man. Not liking to go alone
                        with him, Mr. Embich went on a short distance to where Jacob C. Strealy and
                        J. Frank Snider were collecting gravel, and told them what Harmony had said.
                        They went down into the meadow and there found the dead body of Spital. Near
                        it lay the gun, and in a clump of bushes close at hand was the flask of
                        whisky. Continuing down the creek, they found Harmony on the foot-log
                        opposite one of McClure's cottages. He said he had killed him. Being asked
                        why he had killed him, he answered that he did not know. Information was
                        given to officer Houser, who arrested him and lodged him in jail.</p>
                    <p>The body of Spital was brought in about dusk and conveyed to the residence of
                        his mother. Here an inquest was held by H. B. Davison, Esq., a Justice of
                        the Peace in this borough, at which the foregoing facts were elicited.</p>
                    <p>A post mortem examination of the body was made by Drs. McLanahan, Montgomery
                        and Boyle. It was found that a large charge of shot had entered the left
                        breast, forward of the shoulder and above the heart, passing through the
                        upper portion of the left lung and lodging in the muscles of the back. The
                        muzzle of the gun must have been close to the body when the discharge took
                        place, as some of the wadding was found in the wound.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spitel</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harmony</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harmony</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Etter</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spital</ln>
                        <fn>Christian</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hurst</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Embich</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strealy</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snider</ln>
                        <fn>J. Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLanahan</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Montgomery</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyle</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Account of a killing in Franklin County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Officers Elected</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Noetling</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elden</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Morganthall</ln>
                        <fn>A. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tritle</ln>
                        <fn>W. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Resser</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Funk</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Frantz</ln>
                        <fn>Elam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Adams</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henneberger</ln>
                        <fn>Hiram</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>List of officers elected to the Enterprise Building Association of
                    Waynesboro.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Officers Elected</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Golden</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stewart</ln>
                        <fn>Henry J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mohler</ln>
                        <fn>Fred K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamsher</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keefer</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>List of officers elected to the Odd Fellows of Orrstown.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Court Proceedings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Our Court continued in session all of last week, trying criminal causes. The
                        case on trial as we went to press last week, was that of the Commonwealth
                        vs. George E. Stewart, charged with selling liquor to minors. Verdict, not
                        guilty. Defendant to pay one-half the costs and prosecutors the other half.</p>
                    <p>The next case was the Commonwealth vs. Dr. John H. Oellig, charge of
                        procuring an abortion on the body of Mary Jane Welsh. This case occupied
                        three days, and was listened to with intense interest throughout. It was
                        given to the jury on Friday afternoon at four o'clock. The jury failed to
                        agree and by consent of the counsel, was discharged on Saturday morning
                        about eleven o'clock.</p>
                    <p>The next case called was that of the Commonwealth vs. Samuel Seylar, James W.
                        Robinson, John Laly and David Hare, charged with the <sic>buglary</sic> and
                        larceny of Michael Fallen's goods on the 19th of December last, from his
                        store in Mercersburg.</p>
                    <p>The counsel for James W. Robinson presented an affidavit stating that
                        injustice would be done to him by a joint trial and praying for a severance.
                        The Court granted a severance whereupon the District Attorney elected to try
                        Samuel Seylar first. His trial was accordingly begun and was still in
                        progress when the Court adjourned on Saturday evening. By consent of
                        counsel, the jurors were allowed to separate. The Court convened again on
                        Monday morning at ten o'clock when this trial was resumed. On Tuesday at
                        noon this case was given to the jury and the trial of Dr. James W. Robinson,
                        charged with the same offence, was immediately begun.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stewart</ln>
                        <fn>George E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Oellig</ln>
                        <fn>John J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Welsh</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seylar</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robinson</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Laly</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hare</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fallen</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Continues its coverage of the local Court session, reporting cases and
                    verdicts. Of note is a case concerning a doctor who performed an abortion.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Turnpike Road</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article endorsing the construction of a turnpike road from Waynesboro to
                    Fayetteville.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dutt</ln>
                        <fn>E. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Rev. E. D. Dutt, pastor of the Orrstown Lutheran Church, preached his
                    farewell sermon before accepting a post in Cumberland County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Installation of Officers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn>J. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Noftaker</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Earheart</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Detrich</ln>
                        <fn>J. L. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>F. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jacobs</ln>
                        <fn>P. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mahon</ln>
                        <fn>T. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheets</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Forbes</ln>
                        <fn>D. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davison</ln>
                        <fn>A. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Loutenalager</ln>
                        <fn>P. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beitch</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duncebarger</ln>
                        <fn>Leonard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seibert</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heart</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robinson</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>List of officers installed at Chambersburg Lodge, No. 175, International
                    Order of Odd Fellows.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Report of the Border Claims Commissioners</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The following is the report of the Border Claims Commissioners to the Auditor
                        General:</p>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">To Hon. J. F. Hartranft, Auditor General of the
                            Commonwealth of Penna.:</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>The undersigned commissioners appointed by the Governor under the act of
                        Assembly, approved the 9th day of April, 1868, to assess the damages
                        sustained by the citizens of the counties of Adams, Franklin, Fulton,
                        Bedford, Perry, York, and Cumberland, in the late war, by the Union and
                        rebel troops, respectfully submit:</p>
                    <p>That we organized on the 2d day of June, and appointed M. W. M'Alarney our
                        clerk (who proved to be very efficient), and having been sworn to perform
                        our duties with impartiality and fidelity, and having given the notice
                        required by the act of the times and places of our meetings, we visited all
                        the counties therein named, and held sessions at Newport, in the county of
                        Perry, at Bedford, in Bedford county, at M'Connallsburg, Fulton county, at
                        Chambersburg, Waynesboro', Greencastle and Mercersburg, in the county of
                        Franklin, at Carlisle and Shippensburg, in Cumberland county, at Gettysburg,
                        in Adams county, and at York, Hanover and Dillsburg, in York county. The
                        total number of claims presented to the commissioners was four thousand
                        three hundred and five, besides some few presented by corporations, which we
                        were forbidden to entertain by the act of Assembly. The time occupied and
                        labor required by the commission and their clerk in the assessment of
                        damages, was much greater and more onerous than they had any idea of when
                        they commenced. Besides the meetings in the different counties named, we
                        held a number of sessions in Harrisburg, to examine and adjust the claims
                        presented to us. We have set forth in the book in which the report is made,
                        and which is made part of it, a detailed statement of the claims presented
                        by the citizens in their respective counties, the losses sustained through
                        the Union and rebel armies, and whether such losses were in real or personal
                        estate, and the amount by cash and to each. We also present each claim
                        separately, and the proof furnished by the respective claimants. By these it
                        will appear the total amount of losses as claimed to have been sustained by
                        the citizens in said counties amounts to the sum of one million eight
                        hundred and twenty-one thousand and thirty-one dollars and four cents, and
                        the amount allowed is one million six hundred and ninety-three thousand
                        three hundred and fifty-one dollars and fifty-two cents.</p>
                    <p>These losses are divided among the counties as follows:</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Perry county.</emph>--Damages by Union troops to real
                        estate, $1,516.00, and to personal property, <unclear>$1,218.00</unclear>,
                        and by rebel troops to personal property, $70.00. Total amount to real and
                        personal in Perry county, <unclear>$2,698.00</unclear>, of which $2,640.40
                        is allowed.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Bedford county.</emph>--Damages by Union troops to real
                        property, $198.00; to personal, $5,025.19. Damages by rebels to real
                        property, $500.00; to personal $2,031.25. Total amount claimed, $7,186.23;
                        allowed, $7,126.23.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Fulton county.</emph>--Damages by Union troops to real
                        estate, $420.00; to personal property, $1,898.00. Damages by rebels to real
                        property, $1,389.25; to personal $50,714.07. Total amount claimed
                        $54,421.32; allowed, $48,900.57.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Cumberland county.</emph>--Damages by the Union troops in
                        real property, $32,197.23; to personal $28,873.73. Damages by rebels to real
                        property, $10,861.90; to personal property, $176,855.55. Total amount
                        claimed, $238,400.02; allowed, $216,724.46.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Adams county.</emph>--Damages by Union troops to real
                        property, $44,723.20; to personal, $35,982.41. Damages by rebels to real,
                        $117,670.87; to personal, $352,373.00. Total amount claimed, $550,383.97;
                        allowed, $507,797.37.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">York county.</emph>--Damages by Union troops to real
                        property, $1,330.30; to personal, $5,909.12. Damages by rebels to real,
                        $7,832.48; to personal, $112,630.57. Total amount claimed, $127,668.55;
                        allowed, $124,728.59.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Franklin county.</emph>--Damages by Union troops to real
                        property, $3,122.22; to personal, $19,631.28. Damages by rebels to real
                        $22,789.94; to personal, $793,854.79. Total amount claimed, $838,162.18;
                        allowed $788,733.99.</p>
                    <p>In some of these claims presented for damages to real estate, we find damages
                        claimed for the destruction of fences and the growing crops, and to addition
                        damages claimed for the passing of the armies over the fields in which the
                        crops were growing. This we have not allowed, as it appears to us to a
                        measure at least, duplicating the damage. We also found in many instances in
                        the same locality different values set upon the staple articles by the
                        different claimants, and we have endeavored to make them a uniform price in
                        the same locality, and as nearly as we could ascertain the regular market
                        prices. Some of the damages claimed for use of barns, &amp;c., for
                        hospitals, were manifestly excessive, and we have in such cases reduced the
                        amount. All of which is carefully submitted.<lb/> D. W. WOODS,<lb/> A. S.
                        ELY,<lb/> W. S. WOODS,<lb/> Commissioners.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hartranft</ln>
                        <fn>J. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woods</ln>
                        <fn>D. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ely</ln>
                        <fn>A. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woods</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Prints the report of the Border Claims Commission in full. Lists the
                    damages and amounts claimed for each county and the methods used to arrive at
                    the totals.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ryder</ln>
                        <fn>John S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hershner</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mowers</ln>
                        <fn>S. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John S. Ryder and Miss Rebecca Hershner, both of Franklin, were married in
                    St. Thomas on April 13th by the Rev. S. A. Mowers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barr</ln>
                        <fn>Jeremiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grow</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Folker</ln>
                        <fn>A. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jeremiah Barr and Miss Elizabeth Grow were married on April 6th by the Rev.
                    A. E. Folker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Primm</ln>
                        <fn>Elijah B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>West</ln>
                        <fn>Emma J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnes</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Elijah B. Primm of Schuylkill County and Miss Emma J. West of Franklin were
                    married on April 20th at the Washington House by the Rev. S. Barnes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lebernight</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lebernight</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sarah Jane Lebernight, daughter of Daniel Lebernight, died on April 6th.
                    She was 1 year old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brake</ln>
                        <fn>David Franklin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brake</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>David Franklin Brake, son of George Brake, died on April 16th. He was 10
                    months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.04.21.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
