<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1869/pa.fr.vs.1869.11.10">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>09/01/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1869-11-10">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="11">November</month>
            <day norm="">10</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.11.10.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.11.10.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Still Gaining</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The result of the election last week is particularly gratifying to the
                        Democracy. It exhibits a steady gain for them in all the States in which
                        elections were held.</p>
                    <p>In Massachusetts, West Virginia, Minnesota and Wisconsin, the Radical
                        majorities have been diminished.</p>
                    <p>In New Jersey, the Democrats carried the Legislature, thus insuring the
                        election of a Democrat to the United States Senate in place of Senator
                        Cattell.</p>
                    <p>"Maryland, my Maryland" has been swept by the Democracy as if by a whirlwind.
                        There is not a Radical in the Legislature. There is not a Radical elected to
                        any office in the whole State. From Governor to Constable the State is
                        Democratic throughout.</p>
                    <p>In New York the Democracy have achieved wonders. They have carried both
                        branches of the Legislature, thus putting the State entirely under the
                        control of Democrats.--Governor Hoffman has a Legislature now in political
                        sympathy with him. For fifteen years, the Radicals have had control of the
                        Legislature. They have passed the most infamous special legislation for the
                        purpose of putting the power of New York City into the hands of Rings of
                        Radical politicians, so that the great metropolis with its 70,000 Democratic
                        majority has been in fact ruled by the Radicals at Albany. All this will be
                        changed. The obnoxious acts which Radicals have passed will be repealed and
                        the people will see the advantage of electing Democrats to office. The fact
                        is that the Radicals, having been in power all through the war, had
                        innumerable opportunities for stealing and improved them all, and they thus
                        became so accustomed to it that they could not break through the habit. The
                        Democrats did not learn this lesson, one reason being that the temptation
                        was not thrown in their way. They may be expected, therefore, to set with
                        some degree of regard for the interests of the people. Now is their time to
                        show the wisdom of such action. Let them put the Radical party to shame on
                        account of their corrupt practices, by the exercise of economy, prudence and
                        conservatism. The <emph rend="italic">World</emph> makes the following
                        excellent comments: "There is no question but that the disgust of the people
                        with the enormous and increasing corruption in the Legislature from year to
                        year, under Republican rule, has materially aided the Democracy in securing
                        a majority in both houses this year. The question now is, will the Democracy
                        use this power in a manner that will make their supremacy permanent, or
                        merely temporary? This is a question which they themselves must decide. All
                        depends upon their own action. Nothing will please our opponents so much as
                        to see, during the next session of the Legislature, a repetition of the
                        scandalous proceedings which have characterized the Legislature under their
                        rule. The Republicans have had control of the Legislature for many years
                        without interruption, with the exception of one year in the Assembly. During
                        this period, venality and corruption have been on the increase. Now the
                        Democracy are to have full control in the State, and they are to determine
                        whether these abuses are to continue or be arrested. This responsibility
                        they cannot shirk, even if they would. If a wise course is pursued, and the
                        people see that a reform in this respect is inaugurated, there will be
                        nothing to prevent the future success of the party in the State to an extent
                        that will exceed anything in the past."</p>
                    <p>And again, writing of the abuses and corruptions of the Legislature, it says:
                        "The people have now called upon the Democracy to arrest this evil. The
                        answer to this appeal must be given at the next session of the Legislature.
                        The Democratic party cannot, if they would, <sic>fall</sic> to give an
                        answer. Their action and conduct in the Legislature and the manner in which
                        they use their power there will be this answer.--If it shall be as
                        satisfactory as that which followed the change in the Canal Board from
                        Republican to Democrat, nothing can prevent the Legislature from being
                        Democratic for years to come. The State will likewise be so firmly anchored
                        on the Democratic side that it will stand firm as a rock against the waves
                        of Radicalism. The true course of the party is so plain in this respect that
                        there is no room for doubt. We are satisfied that the counsels and influence
                        of Governor Hoffman and our re-elected State officers will be on the right
                        side, and that special legislation and schemes of all kinds will in the
                        future, as in the past, receive their earnest disapproval. In this they
                        shall have the support of <emph rend="italic">The World</emph> to the full
                        extent of its ability, and, we trust, the co-operation of the Democrats in
                        both branches of the Legislature. The Democracy of the State of New York now
                        hold the key to the situation in the nation. If wisdom and prudence prevail
                        at Albany next winter, success in both State and nation follows as naturally
                        and as easy as water rolls down hill."</p>
                    <p>The Democracy intended to do this in Pennsylvania. Asa Packer's election
                        would have been a guaranty that honesty would have taken the place of
                        dishonesty and that the work of corruptionists would have been at an end.
                        The people were cheated, however, out of their Governor, and the rule of the
                        "Ring" is not yet broken.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Expresses satisfaction at Democratic gains in the recent elections,
                    especially those of New York. Quotes from the New York World proclaiming that
                    the time has come to solidify Democratic power through honesty, good deeds, and
                    conservatism. Ends by lamenting the loss Democrats suffered in the Pennsylvania
                    gubernatorial election.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Out of Funds</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper argues that ever since the Radicals have controlled Congress,
                    every contested election has been decided in favor of the Republican candidates,
                    no matter the grounds or the size of the Democratic candidate's apparent
                    majority. This has only encouraged all defeated Republican candidates to contest
                    their election results, especially in the South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Border Losses</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The article in the <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph> on "the <emph
                            rend="italic">Spirit</emph> and the Border Damages" is really amusing.
                        It evinces such a total disregard of the facts in relation to the attempts
                        to procure payment of these losses that one would think its author had been
                        sojourning in Alaska whilst the Democrats were voting to pay our plundered
                        people. It says "the history of that party" (the Democratic) "proves, if it
                        proves anything on this subject, that a much stronger probability of their
                        payment by a Democratic Legislature would exist if they were rebel losses,
                        and not losses of loyal men." During and almost ever since the war, whenever
                        our Radical friends found themselves beaten in an argument by Democrats, or
                        confronted with ugly facts, presented by Democrats, that would not down at
                        their bidding, they raised the cry of "copperhead" and "rebel sympathizer,"
                        and thus appealed to the passions and fanaticism of their readers. We had
                        thought, however, that they had become ashamed of this cowardly way of
                        begging the question, but it seems we were mistaken.</p>
                    <p>In our columns we set forth the <emph rend="italic">uniform action of
                            Democrats in favor of the payment of the border losses whenever the
                            claims were presented to the Legislature, and the uniform hostility
                            displayed by the Radicals on the same occasions and in the same
                        place</emph>. At this, our friends of the <emph rend="italic"
                        >Repository</emph> seem to have become offended and they hurl again at the
                        heads of the poor Democrats, who have wanted to pay our people all the time,
                        the old hackneyed charge of sympathy with rebellion and anxiety to pay rebel
                        losses. If such a conclusion can be logically drawn from the promises laid
                        down by Democrats, to wit, their votes in favor of our losses, then we
                        confess that we know nothing at all about the rules of logic.</p>
                    <p>The trouble about this matter is that our statements are true, and they pinch
                        the toes of the <emph rend="italic">Repository's</emph> political friends.
                        The fault of its editors is that they try to shield them from the
                        condemnation that they deserve for so long refusing "to do a simple act of
                        justice to the border counties."</p>
                    <p>But we do not intend to indulge in further recrimination. What we want now is
                        action, harmonious action. Let the errors of the past be retrieved by doing
                        right in the future. Let the <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph> take a
                        bold stand in favor of the payment of these claims, and appeal to its
                        political friends in the Legislature to support the bill that will be
                        presented during the coming session. We will do the same. We will ask the
                        men who are in political sympathy with us to join, as they have always done
                        heretofore, in the attempt to secure payment of these claims. We will
                        endeavor to convince them of the justice of these claims and also to show
                        the need, on the part of our people, for payment. We have an abiding
                        confidence in the ability of the border counties, if they but work
                        energetically together, to procure the passage of a bill to reimburse them
                        for the losses sustained by reason of the rebellion. Let us give then, a
                        long pull, a strong pull, and a pull altogether, and let us hear no more
                        about the inclination of Democrats to pay Rebel losses.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Responds to a local Republican paper's denunciation of the former's call
                    for border damages. Claims Republicans know Democrats are right on this issue
                    and so try to deflect blame by calling Democrats rebel sympathizers. Asks
                    Republicans to bury the hatchet and unite in an effort to reimburse the damages
                    endured by Pennsylvania citizens.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.11.10.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Steeple Finished</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The steeple of the Presbyterian Church has been completed. Everyone
                    declares it the most beautiful in the state.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>New Appointment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reber</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>J. Logan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper praises Treasurer-elect William Reber's appointment of J. Logan
                    Kennedy as Clerk in the Treasurer's Office.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Immersion</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Minister of the Baptist Church has been performing immersion baptisms
                    in the Conococheague Creek. Large crowds lined the banks to witness the
                    ceremony, even though it was a cold, raw day.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>A. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Joseph M. McClure, who was admitted to the Chambersburg Bar a few years
                    ago, was appointed Deputy Attorney General by Governor Geary. He read law in the
                    office of Col. A. K. McClure.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Found Dead</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Herr</ln>
                        <fn>Philip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Philip Herr, a waterman and switchman with the Cumberland Valley Railroad,
                    was found dead in his bed. He went to bed in apparent good-health, but was found
                    the next morning by his daughter, who had not heard his usual loud breathing.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Court Proceedings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Court continued in session last week until Saturday night, Judge King
                        presiding. In addition to the cases reported in our last issue the following
                        cases were tried:</p>
                    <p>John B. McLanahan vs. The Cumberland Valley Railroad Company. This was an
                        action of ejectment to recover a piece of ground occupied by the Company for
                        their Warehouse. It was shown that portion of the warehouse stands on the
                        plaintiff's ground. But the Company proved an agreement between themselves
                        and Executors of Thos. G. McCalloh, from whom the plaintiff bought, by which
                        they were allowed to build upon this ground. They also showed that after
                        Plaintiff bought the ground the warehouse was repaired, and the plaintiff
                        saw it being done without giving notice of his rights. Verdict for
                        Defendant.</p>
                    <p>Same vs. Same. This was an action to recover for use of certain grounds of
                        plaintiff adjacent to the railroad on which the Company had unloaded lumber
                        &amp;c. Verdict for plaintiff for $300.</p>
                    <p>Wm. Sprecher vs. Jacob Barnhart. Defendant had sold a farm to plaintiff.
                        Plaintiff claimed that the grain in the ground passed with the farm,
                        defendant alleged that he had reserved the grain. There was some of the
                        hardest swearing in this case that we have ever heard in Court. Verdict for
                        the defendant.</p>
                    <p>On Saturday, Elizabeth Thompson colored woman, who was convicted at the
                        August Sessions of a conspiracy with James Hunter and others, and whose
                        sentence was not then pronounced on account of her having a young babe, was
                        brought into Court and sentenced to nine months' imprisonment in County
                        Jail. Had it not been for the child, she would have been quartered in the
                        Penitentiary also.</p>
                    <p>Daniel Baker, convicted of receiving the stolen horse of Lawrence Hamman,
                        knowing it to have been stolen, was sentenced on Saturday to two years
                        imprisonment in the Eastern Penitentiary.</p>
                    <p>The Court adjourned until Monday morning at 9 o'clock when motions were
                        heard, and cases on the argument list disposed of.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLanahan</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCulloh</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sprecher</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnhart</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunter</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamman</ln>
                        <fn>Lawrence</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Continues its coverage of the County court, summarizing cases and verdicts.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Helman</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McFerren</ln>
                        <fn>Anna E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fohl</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>G. W. Helman and Miss Anna E. McFerren, both from near Jackson Hall, were
                    married in Chambersburg on October 28th by the Rev. J. Fohl.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowman</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shatzer</ln>
                        <fn>Martha B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fohl</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. L. Bowman from near Waynesboro and Miss Martha B. Shatzer of Jackson
                    Hall were married in Chambersburg on November 2nd by the Rev. J. Fohl.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burkholder</ln>
                        <fn>B. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McFerren</ln>
                        <fn>Malinda C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fohl</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>B. L. Burkholder of Quincy and Miss Malinda C. McFerren from near Funkstown
                    were married in Chambersburg on November 4th by the Rev. J. Fohl.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wade</ln>
                        <fn>Cales</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnes</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Cales Wade and Miss Sarah Baker, both of Quincy, were married at Boyd's
                    Hotel in Chambersburg on November 4th by the Rev. S. Barnes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shultz</ln>
                        <fn>J. Nicholas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shatzer</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clark</ln>
                        <fn>J. H. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. Nicholas Shultz and Miss Maggie Shatzer, both from near Mercersburg,
                    were married on October 28th by the Rev. J. H. S. Clark.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robinson</ln>
                        <fn>Smith M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dickson</ln>
                        <fn>Emma R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dickson</ln>
                        <fn>Mark</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pomeroy</ln>
                        <fn>S. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Smith M. Robinson, editor of the Fulton Democrat, and Miss Emma R. Dickson,
                    daughter of Mark Dickson, were married at the residence of the bride's father
                    near McConnellsburg on October 25th by the Rev. S. W. Pomeroy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wagaman</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn>Clara</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Peter Wagaman of Hamilton and Miss Clara Martin of Franklin were married on
                    October 21st.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Molly</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Molly</ln>
                        <fn>Hortencia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Charles Molly and his daughter Hortencia, formerly of Franklin, died in
                    Schuylkill County on October 22nd. He was 53 years old. She was 6.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pomeroy</ln>
                        <fn>Annie E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pomeroy</ln>
                        <fn>Mary A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pomeroy</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Annie E. Pomeroy, daughter of Thomas and Mary A. Pomeroy, died in
                    Roxbury, Franklin County, on November 1st. She was 21 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Catherine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Catherine Miller died near Greencastle on October 30th. She was 64
                    years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hammill</ln>
                        <fn>Charlotte</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hammill</ln>
                        <fn>Albertus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Charlotte Hammill, wife of Albertus Hammill, died in Greencastle on
                    November 1st. She was 30 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.11.10.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
