<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1869/pa.fr.vs.1869.12.22">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>09/05/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1869-12-22">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="12">December</month>
            <day norm="">22</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.12.22.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.12.22.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Right of the Supreme Court to Decide Upon the Constitutionality of Acts of
                    Congress</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The bills introduced into Congress by Senator Drake, of Missouri, and Senator
                        Trumbull, of Illinois, which are leveled at the authority of the Supreme
                        Court, have awakened in the public mind a sense of painful insecurity. They
                        are regarded as attempts on the party of the Radical majority to deprive the
                        Judiciary of a right which clearly belongs to that Department of the
                        Government, under the Constitution.</p>
                    <p>That this apprehension is correct, is certainly manifest from the very words
                        of that instrument. Section 2nd of Article 3rd of the Constitution provides
                        that "the judicial power shall extend to <emph rend="italic">all cases in
                            law and equity, arising under this Constitution</emph>, the laws of the
                        United States and treaties made, or which shall be made, under their
                        authority," &amp;c., &amp;c. There is no limitation of power here as
                        to cases which arise under the Constitution of the United States.</p>
                    <p>The various acts relating to the reconstruction of the States that seceded,
                        the legal-tender act, the act in regard to income tax, and all other acts of
                        Congress must have their warrant in the Constitution of the United States,
                        or they are absolutely void, because "this Constitution, and the laws of the
                        United States <emph rend="italic">which shall be made in pursuance
                        thereof</emph>, and all treaties made, or which shall be made, under the
                        authority of the United States, <emph rend="italic">shall be the supreme law
                            of the land</emph>."</p>
                    <p>This Constitution is the work of the people. Its preamble runs thus: "We,
                            <emph rend="italic">the people</emph> of the United States, in order to
                        &amp;c., &amp;c., do ordain and establish this Constitution for the
                        United States of America." The members of the Legislative Department hold
                        their commissions under this Constitution. To say now, that Congress may
                        legislate according to its notions, or interpretation of the Constitution,
                        and then prevent any power from sitting in judgment upon that legislation,
                        is to say that these representatives of the people, elected for a brief
                        term, shall set at naught the will of the people who are their masters. The
                        stream can never rise higher than its fountain.</p>
                    <p>As this subject is of vital importance to the people, it may be interesting,
                        in this connection, to reproduce the language of one greater than any of
                        those who occupy seats in the American Congress at the present time, one
                        also who aided in framing the Constitution, helped to discuss it in all its
                        parts, and whose opinions upon that instrument have been received with the
                        highest respect ever since. We refer to Alexander Hamilton. In the 78th
                        number of the <emph rend="italic">Federalist</emph> (pages 577-9 of Mr. J.
                        C. Hamilton's edition) this great man writes as follows: "Some perplexity
                        respecting the right of the courts to pronounce legislative acts void,
                        because contrary to the Constitution, has arisen from an imagination that
                        the doctrine would imply a superiority of the judiciary to the legislative
                        power. It is urged that the authority which can declare the acts of another
                        void, must necessarily be superior to the one whose acts may be declared
                        void. As this doctrine is of great importance in all the American
                        constitutions, a brief discussion of the grounds on which it rests cannot be
                        unacceptable.</p>
                    <p>There is no position which depends on clearer principles, than that every act
                        of a delegated authority, contrary to the tenor of the commission under
                        which it is exercised, is void. No legislative act, therefore, contrary to
                        the Constitution can be valid. To deny this, would be to affirm, that the
                        deputy is greater than his principal; that the servant is above his master;
                        that the representatives of the people are superior to the people
                        themselves; that men, acting by virtue of powers, may do not only what their
                        powers do not authorize, but what they forbid.</p>
                    <p>"If it is said that the legislative body are themselves the constitutional
                        judges of their own powers, and that the construction they put upon them is
                        conclusive upon the other departments, it may be answered, that this can not
                        be the natural presumption where it is not to be collected from any
                        particular provisions in the Constitution. It is not otherwise to be
                        supposed, that the Constitution could intend to enable the representatives
                        of the people to substitute their <emph rend="italic">will</emph> to that of
                        their constituents. It is far more rational to suppose, that the Courts were
                        designed to be an intermediate body between the people and the legislature,
                        in order, among other things to keep the latter within the limits assigned
                        to their authority. The interpretation of the laws is the proper and
                        peculiar province of the Courts. A constitution is, in fact, and must be,
                        regarded by the judges as a fundamental law. It must therefore belong to
                        them to ascertain its meaning as well as the meaning of any particular act
                        proceeding from the legislative body. If there should happen to be an
                        irreconcilable variance between the two, that which has the superior
                        obligation and validity ought, of course, to be preferred; in other words,
                        the Constitution ought to be preferred to the statute, the intention of the
                        people to the intention of their agents.</p>
                    <p>"Nor does the conclusion by any means suppose a superiority of the judicial
                        to the legislative power. It only supposes that the power of the people is
                        superior to both; and that where the will of the legislature declared in its
                        statutes, stands in opposition to that of the people declared in the
                        Constitution, the judges ought to be governed by the latter, rather than the
                        former. They ought to regulate their decision by the fundamental laws,
                        rather than by those which are not fundamental.</p>
                    <p>"This exercise of judicial discretion, in determining between two
                        contradictory laws, is exemplified in a familiar instance. It not uncommonly
                        happens, that there are two statutes existing at one time, clashing in whole
                        or in part with each other, and neither of them containing any repealing
                        clause or expression. In such a case, it is the province of the Courts to
                        liquidate and fix their meaning and operation: So far as they can, by any
                        fair construction be reconciled to each other, reason and law conspire to
                        dictate that this should be done: Where this is impracticable, it becomes a
                        matter of necessity to give effect to one, in exclusion of the other. The
                        rule which has obtained in the Courts for determining their relative
                        validity is, that the last in order of time shall be preferred to the first.
                        But this is a mere rule of construction, not derived from any positive law,
                        but from the nature and reason of the thing. It is a rule not enjoined upon
                        the Courts by legislative provision, but adopted by themselves, as consonant
                        to truth and propriety, for the direction of their conduct as interpreters
                        of the law. They thought it reasonable, that between the interfering acts of
                        an <emph rend="italic">equal</emph> authority, that which was the last
                        indication of its will, should have the preference.</p>
                    <p>"But in regard to the interfering acts of a superior and subordinate
                        authority, of an original and derivative power, the nature and reason of the
                        thing indicate the converse of that rule as proper to be followed. They
                        teach us, that the prior act of a superior, ought to be preferred to the
                        subsequent act of an inferior and subordinate authority; and that,
                        accordingly, whenever a particular statute contravenes the constitution, it
                        will be the duty of the judicial tribunals to adhere to the latter, and
                        disregard the former.</p>
                    <p>"It can be of no weight to say, that the courts, on the pretence of a
                        repugnancy, may substitute their own pleasure to the constitutional
                        intentions of the legislature. This might as well happen in the case of two
                        contradictory statutes; or it might as well happen in every adjudication
                        upon any single statute. <emph rend="italic">The Courts must declare the
                            sense of the law:</emph> and if they should be disposed to exercise WILL
                        instead of JUDGMENT, the consequence would equally be the substitution of
                        their pleasure to that of the legislative body. The observation, if it
                        proved any thing, would prove that there ought to be no judges distinct from
                        that body."</p>
                    <p>This then, is the view which the authors of the constitution entertained of
                        the power of the judiciary when they framed it. These papers were written by
                        Hamilton and others for the purpose of acquainting the people with the tenor
                        and scope of the provisions of that instrument. The people then adopted it,
                        and it is reasonable to infer that they accepted and adopted it with this
                        idea of the power that belonged to the judicial department.</p>
                    <p>Montesquieu said that "<emph rend="italic">there is not liberty, if the power
                            of judging be not separated from the legislative and executive
                        powers.</emph>" Hamilton concurred in this and held that so long as the
                        judiciary remains truly distinct from both the legislatures and executive,
                        the general liberty of the people can never be endangered from courts of
                        justice. By giving <emph rend="italic">permanency</emph> in office to the
                        judges, he believed that the judiciary would be "the citadel of the public
                        justice and the public security." Indeed he drew his very strongest argument
                        for the permanence of the judges from the fact that the courts of justice
                        would be "the bulwarks of a limited constitution against legislative
                        encroachments."</p>
                    <p>Surely it becomes the American people to awaken from their apathy and say, in
                        authoritative tones, to their representatives, that they will not tolerate
                        this infringement upon their rights and liberties. Let Congress content
                        itself with the exercise of power within its proper sphere. Let this
                        encroachment be rebuked, and they may fear to awaken the indignation of the
                        people by the perpetration of still further outrages. But if this movement
                        be suffered to become a success, there is no security for the people against
                        further encroachments. The constitution will then indeed be but a rope of
                        sand, and the American people will live under the shadow of a despotism
                        worse than that which caused our forefathers to rebel against the authority
                        of the British Crown.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reacts with alarm to Congressional moves toward limiting the power of the
                    Supreme Court in interpreting laws. Forcefully comes out in support of
                    separation of powers and the right of the Supreme Court to declare laws void if
                    necessary. Quotes extensively from the Federalist Papers and other sources to
                    back up the argument.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.12.22.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Criswell</ln>
                        <fn>A. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wallace</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ditslear</ln>
                        <fn>C. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Solenberger</ln>
                        <fn>D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoover</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maclay</ln>
                        <fn>D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ott</ln>
                        <fn>Jere</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Greenvillage Lyceum elected officers for the coming year.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Sunday School of the Trinity Episcopal Church will hold a concert and
                    festival in Repository Hall on Christmas Eve.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Masonic</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoner</ln>
                        <fn>H. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Diehl</ln>
                        <fn>D. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Welsh</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wunderlich</ln>
                        <fn>D. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGrath</ln>
                        <fn>Allen C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George Washington Lodge, No. 143, A. Y. M., elected officers for the coming
                    year.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Bishop Simpson of the Methodist Episcopal Church will deliver a lecture on
                    "The Future of Our Country" in the Chambersburg Methodist Church on January 3rd.
                    The lecture comes with very high reviews.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Court Proceedings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Dr. Maxwell Kennedy, Committee of Sally Mason, vs. George Johnston. Action of
                        Dower. Verdict for Defendant.</p>
                    <p>John Dunceberger vs. Philip Florich. Slander. Judgment confessed for
                        Plaintiff for $10 and costs.</p>
                    <p>John Johnston vs. Daniel S. Reisher. <emph rend="italic">Scire Facis
                        sur</emph> Mechanics' Lien. Verdict for Plaintiff, $81.09.</p>
                    <p>The Chambersburg Woolen Manufacturing Company vs. John Miller. Trover and
                        Conversion. Verdict for Defendant.</p>
                    <p>Malachi Broudle Sr.'s Executor vs. Amos Detrich. Summons in Ejectment.
                        Verdict for Plaintiff.</p>
                    <p>Cyrus H. McCormick &amp; Bro. vs. Leander Wilkeson. Summons in Assumpsit,
                        Settled by the parties.</p>
                    <p>J. B. Levering vs. William Reber. Summons in Debt on an Exemplification of a
                        record from Knox county, Ohio. Verdict for Defendant.</p>
                    <p>Levering &amp; Wright vs. William Reber. Summons in Debt on an
                        Exemplification of a record from Knox county, Ohio. Verdict for Defendant.</p>
                    <p>John Bromley vs. J.D. Jacobs and Brother. Summons in Assumpsit. Plaintiff
                        enters a non-suit.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>Maxwell</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mahon</ln>
                        <fn>Sally</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnston</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dunceberger</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Florich</ln>
                        <fn>Philip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnston</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reisher</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brondle</ln>
                        <fn>Malachi</fn>
                        <sf>Sr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Detrich</ln>
                        <fn>Amos</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCormick</ln>
                        <fn>Cyrus H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilkeson</ln>
                        <fn>Leander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Levering</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reber</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bromley</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jacobs</ln>
                        <fn>J. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Gives very brief summaries of cases in the county court and verdicts. Most
                    seem to be low profile cases concerning debts, slander, etc.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Lecture</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Raffensperger</ln>
                        <fn>E. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Rev. E. B. Raffensperger, financial agent of the Wilson Female College,
                    will lecture in Repository Hall on December 23rd for the benefit of the Ladies'
                    Mite Society of the Falling Spring Presbyterian Church. His topic is "The Humors
                    of the Pulpit and the Pew." The lecture has received rave reviews every time it
                    has been delivered.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Literary Entertainment at Mercersburg College</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Voigt</ln>
                        <fn>Charles H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Geissinger</ln>
                        <fn>Luther S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitmore</ln>
                        <fn>Anderson J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heyser</ln>
                        <fn>W. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunting</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hatnich</ln>
                        <fn>H. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keller</ln>
                        <fn>F. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Apple</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Marshall Society of Mercersburg College gave an entertainment in the
                    Mercersburg Reformed Church. Religious services as well as orations and a poem
                    made up the evening's activities.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baltimore</ln>
                        <fn>Bernard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carl</ln>
                        <fn>Catherine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>P. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Bernard Baltimore and Catherine Carl were married in Chambersburg on
                    December 6th by the Rev. P. S. Davis.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Luschbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGrath</ln>
                        <fn>Kate</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>P. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John H. Luschbaugh of Hagerstown and Miss Kate McGrath, daughter of
                    ex-sheriff McGrath, were married in Chambersburg on December 7th by the Rev. P.
                    S. Davis.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parrott</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grant</ln>
                        <fn>Eliza</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>P. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Benjamin Parrott and Miss Eliza Grant were married on December 9th by the
                    Rev. P. S. Davis.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reinhardt</ln>
                        <fn>Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roths</ln>
                        <fn>G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jacob Myers and Miss Ann Reinhardt, both of Green, were married on October
                    6th by the Rev. G. Roths.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wells</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scraffirt</ln>
                        <fn>Eve Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roths</ln>
                        <fn>G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Wells and Miss Eve Elizabeth Scraffirt, both of Chambersburg, were
                    married on December 12th by the Rev. G. Roths.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gibbons</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clugston</ln>
                        <fn>Annie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roths</ln>
                        <fn>G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Robert Gibbons and Miss Annie Clugston, both of Chambersburg, were married
                    on December 19th by the Rev. G. Roths.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hughes</ln>
                        <fn>William D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pry</ln>
                        <fn>Barbara A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gring</ln>
                        <fn>H. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William D. Hughes of Franklin and Miss Barbara A. Pry of Maryland were
                    married on December 7th at the residence of the bride's father by the Rev. H. A.
                    Gring.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kadle</ln>
                        <fn>Peter M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richter</ln>
                        <fn>Mollie E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gotwald</ln>
                        <fn>L. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Peter M. Kadle and Miss Mollie E. Richter, both of Chambersburg, were
                    married on December 16th by the Rev. L. A. Gotwald.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.12.22.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
