<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1869/pa.fr.vs.1869.05.19">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/24/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1869-05-19">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day norm="">19</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.05.19.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.05.19.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Conservative citizens of "the Old Dominion" are about to make one grand
                        rally to save their State from the ignominious rule of carpet-baggers. The
                        most exciting feature of the election will be the contest for the
                        Governorship. The Democrats have no candidate, strictly speaking. But the
                        Conservative people of the State are supporting the candidate of the
                        moderate Republicans. His name is Gilbert C. Walker. To give our readers an
                        idea of what manner of man he is, we quote the following from an exceedingly
                        able speech of Mr. John E. Edmunds, made on the 28th ultimo, before the
                        Conservative State Convention of Virginia. Said Mr. Edmunds:</p>
                    <p>"Gilbert C. Walker is a gentleman who sought his residence among us after the
                        close of the war and invested his substance in our midst. During his sojourn
                        in Virginia he has won the confidence and esteem of those among whom he has
                        cast his lot. He favors the removal of all political disabilities. He has
                        called with those who urged upon Congress to strike from the Constitution
                        those most iniquitous provisions before it was submitted for ratification or
                        rejection. He accords to each race the rights and privileges now extended by
                        the reconstruction laws; and would extend to the white race all the rights
                        and privileges now secured to the other race. He would give to Huster,
                        Stuart and others the same right to vote and hold office which exists by the
                        reconstruction laws with their old servants. He strives earnestly to bring
                        peace and prosperity once more to our borders, and to cultivate harmony
                        between the races.</p>
                    <p>This candidate is supported by such men as Franklin Stearns, William L. Owens
                        and others, true to the best interests of Virginia, who may be safely
                        treated in counsel, or to execute the duties of any office. With such men it
                        is no dishonor to co-operate, and no humiliation to affiliate politically or
                        socially. They are united with respectable Republicans, native and Northern
                        born, who have deeply at heart the peace and prosperity of our State, the
                        harmony and welfare of the two races. They would mete out even-handed
                        justice in protecting the political and civil rights of all citizens.</p>
                    <p>To such a candidate, backed by such supporters as his <sic>counsellers</sic>
                        and advisers, you may safely trust the veto power and the control of the
                        military power of the State. Rally around him in the full strength of the
                        Conservative vote as a unit. He is bound to have due regard to the party
                        which elects him; and he will have arrayed around him the <del/> and
                            <unclear>trust</unclear> of all our population, native or adopted. His
                            <sic>counsellers</sic>, advisers, friends and associates will be
                        Conservative and true, from whatever quarter they may come. The history of
                        all political contests will but repeat itself in this. Many of us here are
                        old enough to have witnessed many such splits in parties and know full well
                        the consequences. Elect Walker by the united vote of the Conservative party,
                        and you may trust him as safely for fair and impartial justice as you can
                        trust any man in this convention."</p>
                    <p>Such is the man whom the moderate Republicans have chosen as their
                        standard-bearer, and it is earnestly hoped and expected that he will receive
                        the united support of the Democrats.</p>
                    <p>On the other hand, Mr. Edmunds portrays the character of the present occupant
                        of the Gubernatorial chair, who is the candidate of the Radicals of the
                        State for re-election, in the following words:</p>
                    <p>In contrast, let us turn to the other candidate. Wells can be elected in no
                        possible contingency, except by the union of nineteen-twentieths of the
                        negro vote with those venal and mercenary carpet-baggers who have been the
                        fomenters of discord and strife between the two races. He, too, must shape
                        the policy of his administration and accord with the views of the party
                        which elects and surrounds him. Those principles and that policy are plainly
                        written in the infamous clauses of the State Constitution, which he has
                        persistently maintained and supported. In public speeches in our State, at
                        all times and under all circumstances, he has denounced the Confederate as
                        disloyal and unworthy of political trust, or equality with the negro. He
                        would exclude him from office, from the polls, from the jury. He would
                        degrade him in political and civil rights far beneath the negro. From the
                        great commander to the humblest private he says you are unfit, and cannot be
                        treated to hold a petty office, vote along side your former slaves, nor sit
                        on the jury with him. Before the Reconstruction Committee of Congress, he is
                        reported as urging the Constitution as a whole, without modification. He has
                        exhibited a spirit of vindictiveness and prescription towards the white race
                        of this State, more befitting the cruelties of a Spanish Inquisition than
                        the impartial conduct of a Governor of Virginia in the Christian
                        civilization of the 19th century. He occupies the office and unworthily
                        wears the robe, once filled by some of Virginia's most illustrious sons, by
                        military appointment--and upon such a platform, and the open avowal of such
                        principles, he appeals to the citizens of Virginia, with vindictiveness in
                        his heart, and proscription on his banner, against the best and purest, to
                        elect him to the Executive office in the civil government. He cannot be
                        safely trusted with the veto power, nor with the command of the military
                        forces of the Commonwealth under a civil government--and on that issue, I
                        appeal to every true-hearted Virginian."</p>
                    <p>And then, in tones of stirring eloquence that remind one of the earnest
                        appeals made in days of yore by Virginia's great statesmen and orators, he
                        makes this earnest appeal:</p>
                    <p>"Summon the candidates with their supporters, <sic>counsellers</sic> and
                        advisers to meet upon the Capitol Square around the monument of Washington,
                        beneath the statue of the Father of His Country, and in the full gaze of the
                        sages and heroes of the first revolution. Place Wells on one pedestal
                        surrounded by his black cohorts and vocal carpet-baggers. Let him announce
                        his platform, breathing vindictiveness and prescription against the young
                        Confederate, the gray haired statesman, and the best and purest of
                        Virginia's sons, in the hearing and sight of all Conservative voters.</p>
                    <p>Place Walker on the opposite pedestal, surrounded by the Conservatives of all
                        parties, and sustained by this convention; and let him announce in the
                        hearing and sight of all voters his platform.</p>
                    <p>Mr. President, the hearts of the people of Virginia are mightily stirred up,
                        and they are determined to save the State from the fate foreshadowed by
                        Wells. In such a crisis, and in sight of such a spectacle, the voice of the
                        people will proclaim in the tones of thunder to every voter, "choose ye
                        between them." Woe to the man who falters or hesitates. Let him, like Felix,
                        hear and tremble, but not postpone. If in that hour he fails to discharge
                        his whole duty, or leaves <sic>aught</sic> undone, he will hear that voice
                        again in tones of fearful wrath pronouncing the doom--"Anathema--Maranatha."
                        In the hour of her severest trial, you have proven yourself a traitor to
                        your State, and a doubly accursed traitor to your race."</p>
                    <p>Between two such men, it ought not to be difficult for good men to choose.
                        And in addition, when it is considered to what an extreme depth of infamy
                        Wells has since gone, in order to obtain the negro vote, there is little
                        doubt but that the native white men of Virginia will vote against him, and
                        that the more respectable portion of the negroes will have become too much
                        disgusted with him to give him their support. The infamous Underwood
                        released Ceasar Griffin, a negro convicted of the unlawful shooting of a son
                        of Judge Brockenbrough and sentenced to two years imprisonment in the
                        Penitentiary, on the ground that the Judge before whom he had been tried and
                        convicted was not a legally constituted Judge. Chief Justice Chase, in an
                        able opinion, hooted at this idea and remanded Griffin to the custody of the
                        State authorities. <emph rend="italic">And now, this delectable Governor has
                            pardoned the would-be murderer</emph>.</p>
                    <p>The President has fixed the 6th day of July next for the election in
                        Virginia. The Underwood constitution will then be submitted to the people
                        for ratification. Two articles the President has directed the vote to be
                        taken separately upon. These are specially objectionable to old Virginians.
                        If they could be defeated, the constitution would not be so unpalatable and
                        objectionable as it is with these included. If Mr. Walker can be elected, as
                        we have the utmost hope and confidence he will be, the harsher features of
                        the constitution may be modified by his administration of it. If he should
                        be defeated and the present Governor continued in office, the danger is that
                        negroes and a few unprincipled carpet-baggers will control the destinies of
                        the State. All the odious features of the constitution will be made doubly
                        severe by the fiendish disposition of this man who cherishes the most
                        intense hatred towards native Virginians and the people of the South
                        generally.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on the upcoming elections in Virginia, heavily supports the
                    moderate Republican candidate versus the sitting Radical. Quotes liberally from
                    one John Edmunds, who cites the pros of moderates and cons of Radicals (main
                    difference being their treatment of whites in the state). Hopes and prays for
                    the election of moderates in the approaching elections.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>More Rascality</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Radicals seem to be equal to any degree of measures in order to carry
                        their schemes. The fifteenth amendment is a measure which they have resolved
                        to engraft upon the constitution, by fair means if they can, but by foul
                        means if necessary. The Democrats of Indiana have stood in the way of the
                        ratification of this amendment.--Although a majority of the Legislature of
                        that State are Radicals, it became an impossibility to get a vote on the
                        amendment, for the reason that the Democratic members would not consent to
                        be present on such an occasion, and in their absence, there was not a quorum
                        present for the transaction of business. Indeed, so persistently did the
                        Radicals press this measure last Winter that the Democrats found it
                        necessary to resign their seats in order to defeat their iniquitous purpose.
                        This they did without hesitation when no other course would avail. The
                        Governor ordered a new election to fill the vacancies. Nearly all the men
                        who resigned were renominated, and were re-elected by increased majorities,
                        thus establishing the fact that so far as the people were allowed an
                        expression of opinion on the subject, they were in hearty sympathy with the
                        men who were striving to maintain the dignity of the white race.</p>
                    <p>But the men thus re-elected were fearful that some trick might be practiced
                        upon them by which a vote would be taken on the amendment. They, therefore,
                        refused to qualify as members. In this strait, with the other business
                        before the Legislature undisposed of, the Radical members pledged themselves
                        not to press the amendment to a vote during this session. Under this pledge,
                        the Democrats consented to qualify as members.</p>
                    <p>Considerable juggling on this subject was noticed immediately afterwards, and
                        it being feared that the pledge was about to be violated, the Democrats
                        again threatened to resign. Finding them thus determined, the Radicals then
                        agreed not to press for a vote until the 13th day of the present month.--On
                        that day, seeing that no other course was left open to them and the Radical
                        members still persisting in this obnoxious measure the Democrats again
                        resigned. And then came the most rascally proceeding that has ever disgraced
                        the halls of legislation.</p>
                    <p>An understanding had been previously entered into between the Governor and
                        the presiding officers of the two Houses, by which it was agreed that no
                        note should be taken and no account kept of these resignations until after
                        the amendment had been rushed through. Accordingly, the doors were locked so
                        as to prevent the Democrats from leaving the Chambers, the amendment was
                        called up, and, <emph rend="italic">notwithstanding the fact that the
                            Democrats declared that their resignations had been sent in and that
                            they were no longer members of the Legislature</emph>, the vote was
                        taken and the amendment declared ratified.</p>
                    <p>Thus have the Radicals of Indiana, by the most shameful and undisguised
                        fraud, forced upon the people of that State this accursed doctrine of negro
                        equality. Why have they done it? Why this unseemly haste and resort to such
                        low trickery?--Simply because they believed the people of Indiana to be
                        bitterly opposed to the measure, and feared that if another election were
                        allowed to intervene, the next Legislature would be Democratic and all hope
                        of the adoption of the amendment be forever gone.</p>
                    <p>Will not the people of the country open their eyes to the enormity of an
                        offence like this? It strikes at the very roots of free government. If
                        measures as important and far-reaching, and involving such a fundamental
                        change as this one, can thus be wickedly forced upon an unwilling people,
                        what safety is there for the people of any State? What security is there
                        against any iniquitous legislation that unprincipled schemers may devise for
                        the furtherance of their own selfish purposes?</p>
                    <p>And what respect can men entertain for the laws of the land if they are to be
                        enacted by the perpetration of such an high-handed outrage as this? If such
                        conduct continues, Grant's "let us have peace" will not be worth shucks.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes the ratification of the 15th amendment in Indiana as an example
                    of how Republicans will use any means to pass it. Calls their actions fraudulent
                    and evil, signalling the end of free government. Praises Democrats who tried to
                    resign to prevent the measure from being voted on.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Union Pacific Railroad Finished</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports completion of the Union Pacific Railroad.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>What has been done by the National Life</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper extols the benefits of holding a policy with the National Life
                    Insurance Company.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Letter From Louisiana</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>BASTROP, MOREHOUSE PARISH, LA.,<lb/> April 30th, 1869.</p>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">Editors of the Valley Spirit.</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Gentlemen:</emph>--Through your paper I wish to address
                        those of my friends and acquaintances who reside in Path Valley, Amberson's
                        Valley, and about Bossart's Mill. Although there is no election pending, yet
                        I feel anxious to impress upon their minds, and the minds of all your
                        readers, the great political outrage that has been perpetrated on the South
                        by giving the right of suffrage to negroes, and withholding it from white
                        men.</p>
                    <p>I see that the people of Franklin county, and especially in the vicinity of
                        Chambersburg, have had a very impressive lesson given them on the unfitness
                        of negroes for civil society and freedom by the exploits of Cain Norris, as
                        detailed in a late number of the <emph rend="italic">Valley Spirit</emph>.
                        The radicals of the north admit that negro slaves are an evil to society,
                        but they insist that as a freedman he is capable of being a good member of
                        the body politic.</p>
                    <p>The outrages of Cain Norris on females in your vicinity should be sufficient
                        to convince the most obtuse mind that the negro is more sensual in his
                        nature than the white race--that he has all the fierceness and brutality of
                        low animal passion. In the South the negro will not as a general rule be
                        confined to one wife, nor the wife to one man. Not one-half of them are
                        faithful to their marriage vows. Many of them have a plurality of wives.
                        They do not provide for a family, nor indeed for themselves individually, as
                        white men do. As a general rule they will gratify their present wants and
                        passions at the expense of any future good. When clothed with authority they
                        are proverbially arbitrary and cruel. During the last Presidential canvass,
                        the Democratic negroes of our town were about to take a Radical negro from
                        the country and hang him for being a Radical, but were prevented by the
                        white people. And on the other hand, the Radical negroes on a certain
                        plantation would have cut a Democratic negro to pieces but for the
                        intervention of some other negroes. Throughout the South, and in some
                        instances in the North, as at Chambersburg, negro men commit the most brutal
                        outrages on unprotected females. Almost every paper gives the horrid details
                        of instances of this kind. In Arkansas, recently, because some of the
                        desperate negro criminals were confined in jail, their accomplices entered
                        into a plot to burn the town and murder all the whites in it. When hired as
                        laborers, as a general rule they don't fulfill their contracts through any
                        sense of its obligation. True, they generally stay on the plantations during
                        the year, but it is when they have no motive to go elsewhere. But if they
                        become dissatisfied with the place for want of company, or because they are
                        separated from companions or relations; or if they think they can get higher
                        wages or easier employment, their contract, as a general rule, does not
                        retain them from pursuing their inclinations, because, phrenologically
                        speaking, their animal preponderates over their intellectual and moral
                        nature. For the same reason the least temptation impels them to steal. When
                        they get some money they have no prudence in the use of it. They will
                        generally linger in town, or about a grocery or a store until it is all
                        gone. They are not adapted to the cultivation of letters. Negro children are
                        generally stolid; the apparent exceptions are cases of the Moorish race or
                        of admixture of white blood. In my family we tried a whole summer to teach a
                        negro boy to read, but it was impossible; he never did learn to distinguish
                        some of the letters from the rest. Negroes, by nature, are even more
                        superstitious than even ignorant white people; and they exhibit it on all
                        occasions. Although they are imitative by nature, (In this respect
                        approximating the monkey), yet a whole life in association with white
                        society will not eradicate this vice of superstition which seems inherent in
                        their nature and which demonstrates their inferior intellectual capacity. In
                        the South, since the restraint of slavery has been removed, they return to
                        their ancient superstitious African rites, whenever there are any native
                        Africans old enough to recollect them. The American born negroes who are
                        members of christian churches are constantly engrafting on their worship
                        some absurd practice or superstition, showing a natural tendency to
                        barbarism.</p>
                    <p>As voters they are mere tools of white men. Their first vote here was given
                        according to the dictation of carpet bagger statesmen from the North, under
                        the false promise of a gift of a mule and forty acres of land. But at the
                        last election, the white citizens got up clubs, and processions, and music
                        and speeches, by which means the former Radical negro voters all turned
                        Democrats and voted for Seymour and Blair. When a Democratic negro
                        procession would pass a plantation with music and flags, the Radical negroes
                        would drop their work and run and join the procession, and exclaim that the
                        Radicals might go to h--ll; they were going with that crowd, that is the
                        Democrats and the music. And yet these are the people whom the Radicals, in
                        violation of the rights of the people of the South, in violation of the
                        Constitution of their country, and merely for party purposes, invest with
                        the right of suffrage. At the same time they divest the intelligent, capable
                        white man of the right to vote, under the pretenses that the white man is
                        disloyal; which, if true, would justify their acts, but which is false in
                        fact and they know it. Claiming to be the peculiar friends of popular
                        government, they endeavor to engraft negro equality in the Constitution, in
                        opposition and defiance of the known popular votes of the whole country.
                        Professing to be the friends of law and order, they have endeavored to
                        over-awe and suppress the action and independence of the Supreme Court; and
                        while they are loud in their condemnation of disloyalty, they are themselves
                        notoriously disloyal to the principles of free government, as shown in their
                        flagrant violation of the Constitution, which is the best safeguard of
                        American liberty.</p>
                    <p>J.B. MATTHEWS.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Another letter from J.B. Matthews denouncing Republicans and blacks in the
                    harshest terms. Goes out of his way to portray blacks as ignorant savages and
                    Republicans as enemies of liberty. Trying to stoke up support among Northerners
                    for the overthrow of Reconstruction.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>The Will of the People is not John Cessna's Law</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We cannot understand how a man can ask the people to be allowed to represent
                        them, and <emph rend="italic">promise to represent</emph> them, and then
                        turn around and <emph rend="italic">misrepresent</emph> them. It has become
                        too common within the last few years, for our Senators and Representatives
                        after election, to entirely ignore their constituents, and engineer in their
                        own interests, for a <emph rend="italic">renomination</emph>. In fact it is
                        becoming <emph rend="italic">unbearable</emph> and the only way to put an
                        end to the evil, is, for the organs of the party to denounce such outrages.
                        This matter has been brought home to us in our own district. In the town of
                        BEDFORD, the citizens balloted for the postmastership of that place, and
                        decided in favor of Mr. Russell. We know nothing personally of Mr. Russell,
                        but take it for <emph rend="italic">granted</emph> that he is a gentleman
                        well <emph rend="italic">qualified</emph> for the position, or the citizens
                        would not have selected him; but what was the result of the peoples'
                        expression. In place of carrying out the will of the citizens of Bedford,
                        our Representative, Hon. John Cessna, had MAJOR WASHABAUGH appointed
                        postmaster, and Mr. Russell set aside. This we deem an outrage that admits
                        of no palliation. Who is Major Washabaugh, that he must be forced upon the
                        citizens of Bedford, to the exclusion of Mr. Russell? Why sir, he is a
                        worn-out politician, who has had an eye open for office ever since he came
                        to majority, and who has never had sufficiently the confidence of the people
                        but once, to secure their support. What was the object of Mr. Cessna, in
                            <emph rend="italic">misrepresenting</emph> the people of Bedford, by the
                        appointment of Washabaugh? It is well known that Major Washabaugh heretofore
                        has been the inveterate <emph rend="italic">political enemy</emph> of John
                        Cessna. Mr. Washabaugh therefore became Mr. Cessna's supporter last fall
                        because he thought he might be fed from the crumbs that fall from the "rich
                        man's table." Major Washabaugh no doubt was promised Mr. Cessna's support
                        for the State Senate, but not succeeding it became necessary for John Cessna
                        to give him this office to keep him in trim for 1870. If Hon. John Cessna
                        expects to pave the way for his <emph rend="italic">re-nomination</emph> and
                        election by putting men in positions against the will of the people,--men
                        who do not retain the confidence of the Republican party, he will find that
                        he has made a great mistake.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Cessna should remember that he was <emph rend="italic">barely</emph>
                        elected after great efforts by those who were his <emph rend="italic"
                        >first</emph> supporters, and that he was expected to make a <emph
                            rend="italic">faithful</emph> representative and would carry out the
                        will of his constituents. Thus far he has entirely failed, and unless his
                        conduct hereafter comports more with the will of the people, those who were
                        his strongest supporters, will entirely ignore him. One of the strongest
                        supporters Mr. Cessna had last fall was Jere. Cook of the <emph
                            rend="italic">Repository</emph>, and his strongest foe previous to his
                        nomination was Ed. Scull, of Somerset. Yet the other day, Ed. Scull was
                        supplied with a <emph rend="italic">good, fat office, if he should support
                            him in 1870, we suppose</emph>, and Mr. Cook was left out in the "cold."
                        We do not know that Mr. Cook was an applicant, but he should have received
                        the appointment without asking for it.</p>
                    <p>If Mr. Cessna desires a <emph rend="italic">re-nomination</emph> we know of
                        no better way of <emph rend="italic">getting</emph> it than carrying out the
                            <emph rend="italic">expressed will of the people</emph>, but if he
                        thinks he can do it by any other course he is perfectly welcome to try
                            it.--<emph rend="italic">Fulton Republican</emph>.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Russell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cessna</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Washabaugh</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Major</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Unleashes an attack on Representative Cessna, details his recent action of
                    appointing his own crony for a local postmaster job over someone who was elected
                    by the people of the town. Warns Cessna not to ignore the people too much, or he
                    will never get renominated.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Mission of the Republican Party</head>
                <origin>Baltimore Statesman</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper argues that the mission of the Republican Party is to "attend to
                    other people's business, repent of other people's sins, and reward itself by
                    drawing indefinitely upon the public crib." They will not stop with the 15th
                    amendment, but will continue with radical reforms.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.05.19.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Dead</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lindsay</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Robert Lindsay, "an old and respected citizen of Montgomery township," died
                    suddenly on May 11th. He was 70 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Young Men's Christian Association will hold a special business meeting
                    in their office on Thursday evening. They will discuss whether to continue or
                    disband.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Internal Revenue</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Balsley</ln>
                        <fn>George J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George J. Balsley, Deputy Collector of Internal Revenue for Franklin, will
                    be collecting annual income taxes during the first week of June.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Too Hasty</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houser</ln>
                        <fn>Michael W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper defends Chief of Police Michael W. Houser against accusations
                    that his negligence led to the escape from prison of Andrew J. Baker, alias
                    Horst.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Nunnery Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Snow Hill Society held their annual meeting one mile south of Quincy.
                    Large crowds attended the meeting, especially residents of the area.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Decoration Day</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On Monday evening last, a number of the honorably discharged soldiers of
                        Chambersburg met in the Court House, for the purpose of arranging some plans
                        for the decoration of the graves of soldiers who are buried in the Cemetery,
                        and different grave-yards of our town.</p>
                    <p>The meeting was organized by electing Col. Theodore McGowan, President, and
                        Lieut. S. W. Hays, Secretary. After considerable discussion, it was resolved
                        that Saturday the 29th day of May be observed as the occasion for strewing
                        flowers on the graves of our dead heroes.</p>
                    <p>Col. Rider was unanimously elected Marshal for the occasion, with authority
                        to appoint his assistants.</p>
                    <p>On motion, the "Housum Zouaves" were invited to assist in the duties of the
                        day.</p>
                    <p>On motion, the citizens of Chambersburg and vicinity were invited to join in
                        the procession.</p>
                    <p>On motion, a Committee of Arrangements was appointment to solicit bouquets
                        and flowers from the ladies, see to the marking of soldiers' graves, and
                        assist the Marshal in carrying out his programme. The Committee consists of
                        the following soldiers:--Col. Theo. McGowan, Sergt. Thaddeus M. Mahon,
                        Lieut. Geo. Platt, Lieut. Jas. Aughinbaugh, Sergt. John A. Selders, Sergt.
                        Thos. J. Grimeson, Maj. John Deebler, Sergt. J. Strickler, Sergt. Thos.
                        Donavan, Sergt. David Leshur.</p>
                    <p>Repository Hall was offered as a place in which to deposit boquets of
                        flowers. A vote of acceptance and thanks, was tendered Messrs Cook &amp;
                        Hays for their offer. It was further resolved, that the proceedings of this
                        meeting be published in the <emph rend="italic">Franklin Repository</emph>
                        and <emph rend="italic">Valley Spirit</emph>. The meeting adjourned to meet
                        at the call of the President.</p>
                    <p>We are informed that 3 o'clock P.M., on the 29th of May, will be the hour for
                        forming the procession.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGowan</ln>
                        <fn>Theodore</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>S. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rider</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mahon</ln>
                        <fn>Thaddeus M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Platt</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Aughinbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Selders</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sgt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grimsson</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sgt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doebler</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strickler</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sgt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donavan</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sgt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lesher</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sgt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports on a meeting of veterans who set up a time and place to honor their
                    fallen comrades. Lists the committeemen and officers selected and motions
                    passed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>New Appointments</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scull</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Detrich</ln>
                        <fn>J. L. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moore</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blair</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn>A. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>Jeremiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grimeson</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keefer</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoner</ln>
                        <fn>Henry X.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper criticizes John Cessna's appointments to county office. Jeremiah
                    Cook, Thomas J. Grimeson, Daniel Keefer, and Henry X. Stoner have replaced J. L.
                    P. Detrich, Robert Moore, William H. Blair, and A. H. Gordon.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moore</ln>
                        <fn>Robert C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carlisle</ln>
                        <fn>Ellie M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carlisle</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Robert C. Moore of Pittsburgh and Miss Ellie M. Carlisle of Chambersburg
                    were married on May 13th by the Rev. William Carlile.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>Rachel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Rachel Fisher, wife of Major Samuel Fisher, died in Shady Grove on May
                    2nd. She was 68 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Auld</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Elmira</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Auld</ln>
                        <fn>William W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Auld</ln>
                        <fn>Susan J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary Elmira Auld, infant daughter of William W. and Susan J. Auld, died at
                    Camp Hill, Franklin County, on May 10th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.05.19.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
