<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1869/pa.fr.vs.1869.07.14">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/26/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1869-07-14">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day norm="">14</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.07.14.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.07.14.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>"The Colored Troops Fought Bravely"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Our Radical friends do not believe it. They shake their heads and say, "there
                        must be some mistake about it. If they fought bravely, they would know how
                        to vote. The Virginia election shows that they <emph rend="italic"
                        >don't</emph> know how to vote. They must have been cowards during the war."</p>
                    <p>The Radical idea has always been that no man could be a brave and gallant
                        soldier and vote against the Radical party. But it seems that "the wards of
                        the nation," their own pet black lambs, have actually done it. Nurtured
                        under the fostering care of African-loving leaders, educated to despise and
                        hate the men who were their former masters, the negroes have "gone back" on
                        their saviors and teachers, and allied themselves with the odious Democracy.
                        They have returned evil for good. They have rejected the hand that struck
                        off their chains and fed them. They have refused to acknowledge the
                        leadership of their Freedmen's Bureau protectors. And what "weeping and
                        wailing and gnashing of teeth" there is in the Radical camp on this account.
                        Ingratitude! Who can realize the sharpness of thy thorn but the Radical
                        whose soul was set on the negro vote? And yet, "the colored troops fought
                        bravely."</p>
                    <p>We rejoice at the result of the election in Virginia first, because the
                        Radicals have been very justly punished for the infliction of negro suffrage
                        upon the South. They are now "hoist with their own petard." They introduced
                        this element into politics, not from any love for the negro, but for the
                        sole purpose of strengthening their own hands and procuring a new lease of
                        power. It "serves them right" to be disappointed, and hence, "the colored
                        troops fought bravely."</p>
                    <p>Second, We rejoice because the reign of the carpet-bagger is now at an end.
                        This result is a "ticket-of-leave" for all vermin of that species. Wells has
                        played the role of a Governor long enough. He can pack his one dirty shirt
                        into his carpet-bag and "make tracks." And so with all carpet-baggers South.
                        The Virginia election is but the beginning of the end. The negroes will
                        learn a lesson from their brethren in Virginia and, recognizing the true
                        motives and purposes which actuated Radical adventurers from the North, will
                        discard them as leaders and put their trust in men whose integrity and honor
                        have been known to them all their lives. To effect his end, "the colored
                        troops fought bravely."</p>
                    <p>Third, We rejoice because this result has given a deadly blow to the
                        disfranchisement project of the Radicals. That clause has been rejected by
                        an overwhelming vote and the Constitution, while it grants negro suffrage,
                        holds out universal amnesty and extends the ballot to thousands of whites
                        hitherto disfranchised. In consequence of this wise action, old Virginia
                        will speedily take an honored position among the States of the Union,
                        governed as she will be, before many years, by men who have been "to the
                        manor born." Feeling this, "the colored troops fought bravely."</p>
                    <p>Fourth, We rejoice because the people have spoken against the infamous
                        Radical policy and practice of exacting iron-clad test oaths. The test-oath
                        clause has been defeated and thank God for it! The oath to support the
                        Constitution of the United States, and the Constitutions of the several
                        States, is all that the Democracy ask, and anything more than this they
                        consider degrading. It was for Radicalism to devise and frame this horrid
                        system of oaths which have been administered since the close of the war.
                        Being averse to swearing, "the colored troops fought bravely."</p>
                    <p>We regard the Virginia election as a triumph of Conservative principles.
                        Radicalism has received its most effective stab on the soil of the State
                        which was the chief theatre of the late war. The noble old "Mother of
                        Presidents" has uttered her condemnation of the party which made partition
                        of her own soil against her will, and which has since sought to hold her
                        people in a state of subjection more degrading and dishonorable than the
                        slavery in which the negro was held before the rebellion. "The colored
                        troops fought bravely."</p>
                    <p>This result, however, has not changed our opinion of negro suffrage and negro
                        equality. We are not pleased because the negro voted in Virginia, but
                        because, having been clothed with the right to vote by Radicals, he <emph
                            rend="italic">has voted against them</emph>. The investiture of the
                        negro with this right can not add any intelligence and, certainly, not any
                        permanency to this government. He will be influenced always by the stronger
                        intellects of the whites. He can not think for himself. He will not act for
                        himself. Hence, we are opposed to him voting and trust that our Democratic
                        friends will remit none of their vigilance to keep the ballot box in the
                        hands of the whites exclusively in the North.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Rejoices at the Radical defeat in the recent Virginia elections. Especially
                    glad that many blacks voted for the Democrats in that election, thus turning the
                    tables on Radicals. However, still comes out against black suffrage, and hopes
                    to see it defeated in the North.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Registry Law</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Judge Sharswood's decision declaring the Registry Law unconstitutional was
                    overturned on appeal to the full bench. "The Registry act, odious, unjust and
                    unequal as it is, is now the law of the State and must be observed as such until
                    repealed. As soon as a Democratic Legislature is elected it will undoubtedly be
                    wiped out of existence. The simple qualifications of an elector prescribed by
                    our State constitution are all that should be required. But this decision has
                    been rendered in the interest of the Radical party."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.07.14.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>A Fatal Accident</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ely</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Abraham Ely died after falling off a ladder and landing on an iron hook
                    while picking cherries. He was 80 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Progressing Finely</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reside</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lull</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The construction of the Central Presbyterian Church is progressing nicely.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Borough Finances</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Borough Auditors make the following statement of the receipts and
                        expenditures of the Borough of Chambersburg from May 1st, 1868, to June 5th,
                        1869:</p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>DR.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>To bal. in hands of Treas. at last settlement</cell>
                            <cell>$1,762.53</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Cash received from sundry persons, damages</cell>
                            <cell>166.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Cash received for Licenses</cell>
                            <cell>31.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Cash borrowed</cell>
                            <cell>5,006.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Collections on Implicates of 1866-67</cell>
                            <cell>1,072.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Collections on Implicates of 1868</cell>
                            <cell>4,021.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Total</cell>
                            <cell>$12,098.53</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>CR.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>By Cash paid Outstanding Drafts</cell>
                            <cell>11.66</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>By Cash Paid Burgess, Att'ys. and Office Rents</cell>
                            <cell>90.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>By Cash Paid Council</cell>
                            <cell>200.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>By Cash Paid Treasurer</cell>
                            <cell>100.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>By Cash Paid Secretary</cell>
                            <cell>150.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>By Cash Paid Miscellaneous</cell>
                            <cell>120.39</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>By Cash Paid for Repairing Streets</cell>
                            <cell>4,257.63</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>By Cash Paid High Constable, 13 mos.</cell>
                            <cell>520.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>By Cash Paid for Gas, Lighting and Rep'g Posts</cell>
                            <cell>1,215.15</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>By Cash Paid for Repairing Bridges</cell>
                            <cell>208.03</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>By Cash Paid on Bonds and Interest</cell>
                            <cell>1,064.15</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>By Cash Paid for Printing</cell>
                            <cell>32.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>By Cash Paid Fire Department</cell>
                            <cell>228.55</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>By Cash Paid Election Expenses</cell>
                            <cell>26.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>By Cash Paid Extra Police</cell>
                            <cell>106.75</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>By Cash Paid Damages for Opening Alleys</cell>
                            <cell>244.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Total</cell>
                            <cell>$8,677.31</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>By balance in hands of Treasurer</cell>
                            <cell>3,421.22</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Total</cell>
                            <cell>$12,098.53</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>List of Chambersburg's finances.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Medical Society</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rankin</ln>
                        <fn>E. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lane</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Franklin County Medical Society met in Chambersburg. Resolutions of
                    sorrow were passed regarding the deaths of Dr. E. D. Rankin of Greencastle and
                    Dr. J. S. King of Mercersburg. Dr. Samuel Lane was requested to present an essay
                    at the next meeting.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Haefner</ln>
                        <fn>Amos S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Katie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Amos S. Haefner of Quincy and Miss Katie Miller, daughter of the Rev. J. C.
                    Miller, were married at the residence of the bride's parents in Iowa on July 4th
                    by the Rev. Snyder.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Austin</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Catharine Elizabeth Austin, wife of Richard Austin, died at Austin's
                    Tannery on July 9th. She was 43 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clippinger</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George Clippinger died in Greencastle on June 22nd. He was 77 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weagley</ln>
                        <fn>Laura</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Laura Weagley, daughter of Isaac Weagley, died near Upton. She was 23.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.07.14.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
