<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1869/pa.fr.vs.1869.02.24">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/15/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1869-02-24">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day norm="">24</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.02.24.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.02.24.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Toeing the Mark</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Our neighbors of the <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph> have at last
                        screwed their courage up to the sticking point. They have been beating
                        around the bush for a long time. They have, occasionally, taken "a sly
                        glance" at the monster, but have always heretofore been afraid to look him
                        squarely in the face. In their last issue however, they have "made a clean
                        breast" of it and declared boldly in favor of negro suffrage. We
                        congratulate them upon having reached the point at which they have been
                        aiming so long. With an ingenuity worthy of a better cause, they have kept
                        dodging this issue all through the war. At times, they have hooted at the
                        idea of our people being brought to look with favor upon this doctrine. At
                        other times, they have adroitly managed to ward off the attacks which we
                        have made upon them in regard to this issue. They have, time and again,
                        deceived their patrons with the statement that this hubbub about the negroes
                        voting was a lie gotten up by the Democrats for electioneering purposes.
                        Afterwards, when the Chicago platform declared for negro suffrage in the
                        South, they apologized for this position by stating that this step was
                        necessary in order to keep the government of the Southern States in the
                        hands of loyal men. And in order to conciliate that portion of their party
                        who were hostile to this measure, they published the most horrible tales of
                        Southern outrages, thinking thereby to so embitter the "loyal" people
                        against the people of the South that they would readily accept the idea that
                        negro suffrage in the South was an absolute necessity. All this time, they
                        kept loudly reiterating the statement of the Chicago platform that <emph
                            rend="italic">the question of suffrage in the loyal States properly
                            belongs to the people of those States</emph>. The Conservative
                        Republicans who voted for Grant on the Chicago platform, did so under the
                        belief that if ever the Radical portion of the party would attempt to force
                        negro suffrage upon the North, they would have an opportunity to vote upon
                        the question at the ballot box. The purpose of the Radical party however, is
                        to clothe the negro with the right of suffrage by having <emph rend="italic"
                            >the Legislatures</emph> of three-fourths of the States to ratify the
                        amendment about to be submitted to them by Congress. <emph rend="italic">The
                            people are not to vote upon the question at all</emph>. And the <emph
                            rend="italic">Repository</emph> has the audacity to say, that "the
                        proposition to confer suffrage upon the black citizens of the republic,
                            <emph rend="italic">is a measure of justice due to that recently
                            enfranchized class</emph> and a most natural result of our recent civil
                        war."</p>
                    <p>And, although the last campaign was fought, upon the Radical side, on the
                        basis of Grant's exclamation, "let us have peace," it admits that "until the
                        decree (of negro suffrage) shall in some manner have gone forth, there
                        remains for the American people <emph rend="italic">a period of trouble and
                            unrest</emph>." The peace which Radicalism promised us, if we would only
                        elect Grant, is still in the dim distance. Before the quiet can be hoped
                        for, we must secede to this proposition to make the negro our political
                        equal. Unless we agree in this, the Almighty will "convulse us as with the
                        thunders of Sinai, or confuse us as at Babel, or overwhelm us as at the Red
                        Sea." Why didn't Grant think of this when he wrote, "let us have peace?"</p>
                    <p>The <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph> seriously goes on to argue that the
                        black man has earned his right to the enjoyment of the elective franchise,
                        and gives its readers a lot of stuff about the loyalty of the negroes of the
                        South during the war. Whereas the truth is, that the vast majority of the
                        blacks in the South obeyed the behests of their masters, during the
                        rebellion, not from necessity but from choice. Many of them attended them as
                        servants in the camp. Others remained on the plantations to raise the crops
                        to supply armies. Others took the spade and mattock and worked on the
                        fortifications. And others still shouldered their muskets and shot down our
                        men from the trenches. The Southern negroes, as a rule, were loyal to their
                        masters, and deserve no favors on account of their loyalty.</p>
                    <p>But the strong argument which the <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph> urges
                        for negro suffrage is the same that Senator Sumner, with unblushing
                        effrontery, announced in the Senate of the United States. This argument is
                        that the negroes <emph rend="italic">will vote with the Radical
                        party</emph>. They claim that the adoption of the proposed amendment would
                        add seventeen thousand voters to the ranks of the Radical party in
                        Pennsylvania. This may be true. We do not know. We can not tell. But what a
                        selfish argument is this to address to the intelligent white voters of the
                        Keystone State! Call upon your members in the Legislature to vote for negro
                        suffrage because the negroes can be manipulated by Republican politicians
                        and will keep the Republican party in power. This is the argument.</p>
                    <p>It is high time that the people would arouse themselves to the importance of
                        this measure which the Radical leaders are seeking to force upon the
                        country. Let an earnest, vigorous protest go up from the Conservative
                        masses, both Democrats and Republicans, so that it may reach the ears of our
                        representatives in the General Assembly of this Commonwealth, informing them
                        that the white people of Pennsylvania desire to keep the suffrage entirely
                        in their own hands, and that they will brand with the seal of their
                        condemnation the men who shall dare to infringe upon their rights by
                        extending the elective franchise to those whom they regard as their
                        inferiors, both politically and socially.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Traces how the Radical press of Pennsylvania went from opposing black
                    suffrage to glorifying it. Vigorously condemns black suffrage and urges all
                    conservative men to thwart Radicals intent on "forcing" it upon the country.
                    Also claims most blacks in the South willingly served their masters in the war
                    and so do not deserve anything like suffrage.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Virginia and the Carolinas--No. 8</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Ongoing account of a trip through Virginia and the Carolinas.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.02.24.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Episcopal Services</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Rev. Robert J. Keeling of Harrisburg will preach in Chambersburg's
                    Episcopal Church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Guilford Township</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Democrats of Guilford are called to meet to select delegates to the
                    township convention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A large crowd attended the meeting on war damage claims. The paper supports
                    petitioning to be sure county citizens are paid in full for any damage
                    sustained.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Colored Entertainments</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Some of the colored folks of our Borough, assisted by one or two importations
                        from Greencastle, gave two entertainments in Repository Hall, on Tuesday and
                        Wednesday nights of last week. The exercises were a reproduction of the
                        performances in the African Church some weeks ago, and consisted of vocal
                        music and dramatic pieces, interspersed with music on the violin and guitar.
                        Several of the performers have excellent voices, but they all sang in a
                        listless, indifferent sort of manner. There was no animation, no life in the
                        music. The great trouble was that there was an effort made to act as white
                        folks would act, to the spoiling of the whole performance. There seemed to
                        be an effort to keep the negro character entirely out of sight. Of course a
                        negro entertainment is worth nothing without the natural negro in it. We
                        understand that the proceeds are to be used in repairing the Church, and
                        that the net receipts were seventy-two dollars and eighty cents.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Account and review of a concert held by Franklin African Americans.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Washington's Birthday</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miles</ln>
                        <fn>George L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Aughinbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elliott</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gerbig</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Loudensinger</ln>
                        <fn>Philip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donavin</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilmore</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper reports that most of Chambersburg failed to observe Washington's
                    birthday. Business and retail went on in town as usual. The lone exceptions were
                    the Friendship Fire Company and the Housum Zouaves who marched in the streets.
                    The Housum militia also gave a military drill demonstration on the Diamond.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Meeting of Damage Claimants</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In pursuance of a call published in the <emph rend="italic">Valley
                        Spirit</emph> and the <emph rend="italic">Franklin Repository</emph>, a
                        meeting of citizens of Franklin county who sustained damages at the hands of
                        Union and Rebel troops was held in the Court House, in the borough of
                        Chambersburg, on Thursday last, the 18th of February. Wm. C. McKnight, Esq.,
                        was chosen President, and Wm. B. Gabby, Esq., Secretary.</p>
                    <p>The object of the meeting having been stated by the President, on motion of
                        J. R. Smith, of Antrim, a committee of three from the borough of
                        Chambersburg and from each township was appointed to collect funds to defray
                        necessary expenses. The following are the committees:</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Antrim</emph>,--Joseph Hade, Capt. James M. Brown, Jacob
                        Grove.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Guilford</emph>--Henry Hoge, William Vanderan, Pharez
                        Duffield.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Green</emph>.--John W. Barr, Luther Garver, John Monn.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Quincy</emph>.--George W. McCleary, David Lowry, Eli
                        Winger.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Washington</emph>.--John Funk, of H., Henry X. Stoner,
                        Jacob Carbaugh.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Welsh Run</emph>.--William Reed, Samuel Shartle, George
                        Mowry.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Peters</emph>.--Seth Dickey, Leonard Jordan, R. P.
                        McFarland.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">St. Thomas</emph>.--William D. Dixon, George Coble,
                        Joseph Strock.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Hamilton</emph>.--William Bossert, Jonas Palmer,
                        Frederick Mish.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Southampton</emph>.--Simon Bittner, Clark Johnston,
                        William Blair, Esq.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Metal</emph>.--James Witherow, John McAllen, William
                        Noonan.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Fannett</emph>.--Samuel Holliday, Wm. Johnston, William
                        Mackey.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Letterkenny</emph>.--William McClelland, Peter Besore,
                        Henry H. Rite.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Chambersburg</emph>.--John Huber, Geo. Ludwig, J. S.
                        Nixon.</p>
                    <p>On motion, B. F. Nead, Jacob R. Smith and John Huber were appointed Executive
                        and Corresponding Committee, to correspond with persons in other counties
                        who sustained losses, in order to secure concert of action.</p>
                    <p>On motion it was resolved that claimants be requested to contribute
                        one-fourth of one per cent. (or 25 cents on $100,) of the amount of their
                        respective claims, to defray expenses.</p>
                    <p>The chairman of the Executive Committee (B. F. Nead) was requested to act as
                        Treasurer and receive such funds as might be raised.</p>
                    <p>The Township Committees were directed to report at a meeting to be held in
                        Chambersburg on the first Monday in June, and the President was directed to
                        issue a call for said meeting at such period prior to the time appointed for
                        its assembling as he might judge proper.</p>
                    <p>The Executive Committee was directed to prepare petitions to the Legislature
                        and furnish the same to the Township Committees for circulation among the
                        people.</p>
                    <p>As adjournment having been proposed, the President suggested that the meeting
                        ought to contribute sufficient funds to pay for the publication of its
                        proceedings.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Cooper, of the <emph rend="italic">Valley Spirit</emph>, stated that the
                        paper with which he was connected would publish the proceedings without
                        charge, and he was authorized by Mr. Hays to say that the <emph
                            rend="italic">Franklin Repository</emph> would do the same.</p>
                    <p>On motion, it was resolved "that the thanks of this meeting be tendered to
                        the editors of the <emph rend="italic">Valley Spirit</emph> and the <emph
                            rend="italic">Franklin Repository</emph> for their generous offer to
                        publish its proceedings free of charge."</p>
                    <p>The meeting then adjourned.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McNight</ln>
                        <fn>William G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gabby</ln>
                        <fn>William B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hade</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>James M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoge</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vanderan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duffield</ln>
                        <fn>Pharez</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barr</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garver</ln>
                        <fn>Luther</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Monn</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCleary</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lowry</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Winger</ln>
                        <fn>Eli</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Funk</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoner</ln>
                        <fn>Henry X.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shartle</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mowry</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dickey</ln>
                        <fn>Seth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jordan</ln>
                        <fn>Leonard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McFarland</ln>
                        <fn>R. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dixon</ln>
                        <fn>William D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coble</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strock</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bossert</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palmer</ln>
                        <fn>Jonas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mish</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bittner</ln>
                        <fn>Simon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnston</ln>
                        <fn>Clark</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blair</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Witherow</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McAllen</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Noonan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Holliday</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnston</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mackey</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClelland</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Besore</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rite</ln>
                        <fn>Henry H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huber</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ludwig</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nixon</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nead</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Prints the proceedings of a meeting held by Franklin county residents to
                    gain support for payment of damages sustained in the war. Lists the committees
                    and members of committees appointed, and the bipartisan support generated for
                    the effort in the county.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Our Common Schools</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We extract the following from the last annual report of P. M. Shoemaker,
                        Superintendent of Common Schools in Franklin County:</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">School Houses</emph>.--I am happy to report that our
                        directors and citizens are beginning to see the necessity of better school
                        houses. During the past year fourteen of our worst old school houses were
                        torn down, and good new ones erected in their places. Eleven new houses were
                        built since my last report. Three in Greene; one in Guilford; two in
                        Hamilton; one in Letterkenny; one in Montgomery; one in St. Thomas, and one
                        in Washington. Of these houses, three are two stories high; one in Greene,
                        one in Metal, and one in St. Thomas. All the houses built are good
                        substantial brick buildings; generally larger, have higher ceilings, are
                        better ventilated, better arranged, better supplied with seats, desks,
                        &amp;c., than those built a few years ago. They are generally well
                        supplied with blackboard surface. The directors of Greene, Metal and St.
                        Thomas, are certainly entitled to credit for the fine buildings they have
                        put up in their respective districts; and I think all the directors who have
                        built new houses, within the past two years, deserve praise for the spirit
                        of improvement manifested in this particular. I cannot help mentioning one
                        instance of liberality. The directors of Washington agreed to give Mr. J. J.
                        Miller a certain amount to put up a school house in the district in which he
                        lives, according to certain specifications. But Mr. Miller believing that
                        the times demanded better school houses than the board had agreed to build,
                        went on and put up one among the best single school houses in the county. It
                        is well arranged, with vestibule, clothes-room, seats, desks, &amp;c.,
                        and is, in almost every respect, a first class house. I understand that this
                        house cost Mr. Miller several hundred dollars more than he received from the
                        board. There were more new school houses built in this county during the
                        past year than in any previous one for years, and there will be more built
                        this year than there were last. Besides the new houses built, some of the
                        old ones have been so repaired as to make them tolerably comfortable. I am
                        however compelled to report thirty-three as unfit for use: but I think in a
                        few years they will be replaced by good ones. Last year I reported one
                        hundred and forty-two as having no out-houses; this year one hundred and
                        twelve. Thirty were built during the year. Should we succeed in getting as
                        many built each year as the last, in four years we will have an out-house to
                        every school house in the county.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Schools</emph>.--There are two hundred and twenty-eight
                        schools in this county; fifty-four graded, and one hundred and seventy-four
                        ungraded. Eight were graded at the commencement of the last school term; two
                        in Greene; two in Metal; two in Quincy, and two in St. Thomas. There is now
                        a commendable disposition among directors and citizens to grade the schools
                        wherever it can be conveniently done. One hundred and eighty-eight schools
                        were as well classified as could be expected, considering the irregularity
                        of attendance. These schools were generally well taught, and the teachers
                        gave general satisfaction. The remaining forty were not well classified, and
                        consequently not well taught; but still, but few of them could be called
                        total failures.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Teachers</emph>.--Of the two hundred and twenty-eight
                        teachers employed during the past year, one hundred and sixty-five were
                        males and sixty-three females. Thirty-nine hold professional certificates,
                        and one hundred and eighty-nine provisional. Thirty-five had no experience
                        in teaching; twenty-two taught less than one year; seventy-eight between one
                        and five years, and ninety-three over five years. Only twenty-one of the
                        whole number have attended a Normal school; one hundred and sixty-three have
                        read works on the theory of teaching. It will be seen by reference to the
                        statistical table, that the average grade of provisional certificates is but
                        little better than last year. This may be explained as follows: First, the
                        standard is somewhat higher, and second, they had never before been examined
                        on U.S. history, and many of them being deficient in this branch got low
                        marks on it, which makes the grade lower than it otherwise would have been.
                        Besides, this estimate is made on the whole number examined; last year it
                        was made out on the number employed, and about thirty of those having the
                        worst certificates were not employed. Our teachers, as a general thing, are
                        making praiseworthy efforts to improve themselves, not only in the branches
                        required to be taught, but in the manner of teaching them, and their schools
                        show it plainly.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Apparatus</emph>.--191 of our schools are supplied with
                        outline maps and elementary charts, and about 50 with astronomical charts.
                        Near the close of the term about one-half of the schools were supplied with
                        globes, but I am unable to state the exact number.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shoemaker</ln>
                        <fn>P. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Prints a report from a Superintendent of Franklin County Schools. Reports
                    on the increase in school construction, better quality of the buildings, status
                    of the teachers, and numbers of maps and globes in the schools. On the whole, a
                    positive report but says work still needs to be done.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rook</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Oyler</ln>
                        <fn>Susan Emma</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J. Keller</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Joseph Rook and Miss Susan Emma Oyler, both of Funkstown, were married at
                    the parsonage on February 18th by the Rev. J. Keller Miller.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strock</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coble</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J. Keller</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Daniel Strock of Sterling and Mrs. Susan Coble of Chambersburg were married
                    at the residence of the bride on February 23rd by the Rev. J. Keller Miller.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingert</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Etter</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneck</ln>
                        <fn>B. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John M. Wingert and Maggie A. Etter, both of Franklin, were married on
                    February 18th by the Rev. B. S. Schneck.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crouse</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boggs</ln>
                        <fn>Lizzie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boggs</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>West</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Isaac R. Crouse and Miss Lizzie Boggs, daughter of James Boggs, all from
                    near Spring Run, were married on February 11th by the Rev. William A. West.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carper</ln>
                        <fn>Minnie Myrtle</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Minnie Myrtle Carper died on February 14th at age 3.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.02.24.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
