<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1869/pa.fr.vs.1869.06.02">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/25/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1869-06-02">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="06">June</month>
            <day norm="">2</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.06.02.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.06.02.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>A Word About Candidates</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The time is rapidly approaching for the nomination of candidates of the
                        Democratic party for Governor and Judge of the Supreme Court. The persons
                        thus far named for Governor are, as far as we have noticed, Hon. Isaac E.
                        Hiester, General W. S. Hancock, George W. Cass, Hon. Asa Packer and John H.
                        Brinton.</p>
                    <p>All our exchanges seem to have their favorites for Supreme Judge just as we
                        have ours.</p>
                    <p>One thing is noticeable, however, and highly encouraging. The best of feeling
                        prevails and there is a universal disposition to go into the fight on the
                        principle that "in union there is strength." There is no dissension in the
                        Democratic camp. The nominees of the convention, whoever they may be, can
                        rely upon the earnest and enthusiastic support of the entire party. There
                        will be no stragglers. The Democracy are more than ever determined to make a
                        strong fight, for the reason that the oft-repeated prophecies as to the
                        intentions of their opponents have been literally fulfilled and all the
                        dangers that they foretold are now upon us.--They feel that, to save the
                        white race from the degradation to which the Radicals are laboring to bring
                        it, all who are proud of their Anglo-Saxon blood must join hands and make
                        one overwhelming effort to drive Radical office-holders from power.</p>
                    <p>The Radical party, on the other hand, is threatened with disintegration.
                        Geary will be renominated. He is exceedingly obnoxious to a large portion of
                        the Radical organization. Their hatred of him is so intense that it will be
                        with great difficulty they can be induced to support him. In the City of
                        Philadelphia, he will run behind his ticket to an amazing extent. The
                        leading papers of the Radical party in Philadelphia are now engaged in a
                        bitter wrangle which grows out of animosity to Geary. It is not at all
                        likely that the difficulties can be adjusted so as to insure unity of
                        action. The brethren do not dwell together in harmony.</p>
                    <p>Let our Convention, therefore, when it meets, act with deliberation. Let it
                        take up the different gentlemen named and select the most available among
                        them. We use the word <emph rend="italic">available</emph> advisedly. Our
                        purpose is to win. It may be that the man who has the most brains will be
                        the most available candidate. We have been giving our nominations recently
                        on the score of merit. But we have seen the ablest men in the State on the
                        Democratic ticket defeated by narrow-minded blockheads and
                        <unclear>gores</unclear> (we quote from the <emph rend="italic"
                        >Repository</emph>) on the Radical ticket, so that we have come to the
                        conclusion that availability must be our watchword, even if it does oblige
                        some of our best men to wait until a Democratic victory becomes a certainty.
                        There is one consolation to us in this thought, namely, that, inasmuch as
                        Geary is to be renominated by the Radicals, it will be utterly impossible
                        for us to find a man of less brains than the Radical nominee. No matter who
                        is nominated the people will be safe in voting the Democratic ticket.</p>
                    <p>We go for the most <emph rend="italic">available</emph> man, therefore,
                        whoever he may be, without regard to the question of brains. If he has a
                        superfinity of brains, well and good. If not, he can't be below Geary, for
                        his cranium comes as near a perfect vacuum as anything can be. Let the aim
                        of the Convention be to find the man who can command the largest number of
                        votes.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges Democratic leaders in the upcoming convention to select men who can
                    garner the most support among the people. Is willing to set aside ability for
                    the moment in favor of availability, which has worked for the Republicans in the
                    past. Claims Democrats will stand united this time while Republicans will be
                    torn by factionalism.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Our County Ticket</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>There is every reason for encouragement as to the prospects of the Democracy
                        in Franklin county this fall. The nomination of a good, strong ticket will
                        be followed by its triumphant election. An excellent ticket can be formed
                        out of the material already before the people and we do not doubt that,
                        before the time for holding the Convention, there will be other candidates
                        announced for some of the offices. There will be no excuse for the formation
                        of a bad ticket. The Democracy have any number of good and competent men in
                        the County. Those who have been named are all worthy and should the choice
                        be limited to them, the Convention will be able to select a ticket that will
                        command success.</p>
                    <p>We are no man's man. We have no personal wishes to gratify and no personal
                        interests to serve. We intend to do all in our power to elect the men whom
                        the Convention shall nominate.</p>
                    <p>We only ask that the delegates to the Convention shall come here determined
                            <emph rend="italic">to form the strongest possible ticket</emph>. Let
                        personal preferences be sunk and personal prejudices be overcome so as to
                        nominate men who can obtain the greatest number of votes. It is of the
                        utmost importance that we should carry the county, and if Democrats display
                        their usual earnestness and energy, the result will be favorable.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Proclaims confidence in a Democratic victory in Franklin county as long as
                    Democrats stand united and select the strongest candidates. Calls for burying
                    personal prejudices in order to secure election.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.06.02.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Orphan's Court</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rowe</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armstrong</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ferguson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A session of orphans' court met, Judge Rowe presiding with Judges Armstrong
                    and Ferguson on the bench.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Fair Grounds</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The county is improving the stock stalls at the fairgrounds.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Decoration Day</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On Saturday last, according to previous announcement, the ceremony of
                        decorating the graves of Union soldiers was performed. The procession was
                        formed on the Court House pavement at 3 1/2 o'clock, P.M., by Col. James G.
                        Elder. The Silver Cornet Band took the lead. Then came the Ministers of the
                        town, among whom was Rev. Samuel Barnes, the Orator of the day. Immediately
                        behind them, were the "Boys in Blue," then the members of the Friendship
                        Fire Company, and following them came the "Housum Zouaves" under the command
                        of Lieut. Geo. Miles, Capt. Skinner being in Path Valley attending to his
                        duties as Treasurer. A large number of citizens joined in the procession.
                        Nearly all carried boquets of beautiful flowers. The procession followed
                        strictly the route announced in our last issue.</p>
                    <p>Rev. Mr. Barnes delivered a very beautiful and appropriate address at the
                        Cedar Grove Cemetery, about fifteen minutes in length. About six o'clock,
                        the procession returned to the Court House pavement and dispersed.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elder</ln>
                        <fn>James G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnes</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miles</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Gives details of the Decoration Day ceremony held a few days earlier.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Internal Revenue</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Balaley</ln>
                        <fn>George J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George J. Balaley, Deputy Collector of Internal Revenue for Franklin, will
                    be collecting income taxes, business taxes, and license fees at the Washington
                    House in Chambersburg during the first week of June.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Border Counties' Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKnight</ln>
                        <fn>William C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Chairman William C. McKnight announces that a meeting of the war damage
                    claimants from Pennsylvania Border Counties will be held in Chambersburg on June
                    7th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>A May Party</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hayman</ln>
                        <fn>Anna B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chambers</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Washington</ln>
                        <fn>Jennie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richards</ln>
                        <fn>Daisy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Lellan</ln>
                        <fn>Nannie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kimmell</ln>
                        <fn>Beckie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Jennie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Anna B. Hayman's school held a May party in the woods of Benjamin Chambers.
                    Miss Jennie Washington was chosen May Queen.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Improvements at the Poor House</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brandt</ln>
                        <fn>Sam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The poor house received a new roof and coat of paint in compliance with
                    recommendations from the Grand Jury. Steward Sam Brandt is displaying great
                    energy in improving the grounds. "The poor of Franklin county who have become a
                    charge upon the public are well provided for."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Drunkards and Vagrants</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"Justice" writes the editors of the Spirit to criticize the Chambersburg
                    police for failing to arrest a drunken vagrant loitering on the diamond and to
                    attack the Repository for defending them.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>07</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Arpleby</ln>
                        <fn>D. C. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Montague</ln>
                        <fn>M. Alice</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Montague</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baird</ln>
                        <fn>James H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>D. C. M. Arpleby and Miss M. Alice Montague, daughter of Thomas Montague,
                    all of Shade Gap, were married on May 25th by the Rev. James H. Baird.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.06.02.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
