<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1868/pa.fr.vs.1868.05.20">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/01/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1868-05-20">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day norm="">20</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.05.20.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.05.20.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Failure of Impeachment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We are disappointed--most <emph rend="italic">agreeably</emph> disappointed.
                        There is more honesty among the Radical leaders than we gave them credit
                        for, or had any idea of. A few upright men there are in the Senate who have
                        refused to commit the crime of perjury in order to promote the interests of
                        their party. Honestly convinced that Andrew Johnson has done nothing as far
                        as the testimony goes, worthy of impeachment, they have had the courage to
                        say so by their votes. They have not shrunk from the performance of a great
                        public duty. Without "fear, favor, or affection," they have acted, and in
                        the long future their names will be held in highest honor as the names of
                        those who, under the most trying circumstances, were possessed of sufficient
                        force of character to say to their tempters, "get ye behind me."</p>
                    <p>And yet, strange as it may seem, what we call honesty, the radical press
                        calls rascality. They refuse to take the credit which we are heartily
                        willing to give them. They denounce in measured terms, all who struck hands
                        with the Democrats of the Senate to pronounce Andrew Johnson not guilty.
                        Many years of faithful service to their party--the most exalted
                        talents--hitherto undoubted purity of character--not all of them can avail
                        to shield these men from the calumnies of the scribblers for Radical
                        newspapers. The moment the vote was announced last Saturday, they rushed
                        from the Senate Chamber to prepare and transmit their dispatches and
                        letters, filled with all the opprobrious epithets and false insinuations and
                        statements that disappointed place hunters could furnish. They did not
                        hesitate to charge such men as Fessenden, Trumbull, and Grimes with
                        bribery--men who have been the shining lights of the Republican party for
                        years--men to whom the proud Radical always pointed whenever he was
                        challenged to a comparison of the leading intellects of his party with those
                        of the Democracy. If it be true that such men have bartered their
                        votes--that they have "sold out" their principles, their party, and
                        themselves for money--what a putrid mass of corruption the Radical party
                        must be! If the men occupying the highest places have become so
                        disgracefully corrupt, what is to be said of the honesty of the lesser
                        lights who claim to represent "the party of great moral ideas?"</p>
                    <p>The fact is, that the undue influence used to sway the votes of Senators came
                        from the Radicals themselves. From the moment that Grimes and Fessenden
                        announced in secret session their intention to vote for acquittal, the
                        Radicals became alarmed. They refused to take the vote on the day fixed, and
                        adjourned until Saturday. During the interval, every possible influence was
                        brought to bear upon Senators in order to convict the President. State
                        Central Committees, State Conventions, and irresponsible Governors sent
                        dispatches to Washington urging conviction in the name of the people. Town
                        meetings were called, at which strong impeachment resolutions were passed,
                        and the next morning these resolutions were published in every Radical daily
                        in the country. Members of the House of Representatives from Missouri had
                        the impudence to request Senator Henderson to withhold <emph rend="italic"
                            >his</emph> vote because <emph rend="italic">they</emph> believed that
                        the President's conviction was a necessity. Forney, in his "two papers, both
                        daily" called again and again, for the pressure of public opinion. With a
                        shamelessness characteristic of himself, he boldly proposed to admit the
                        Senators from certain Southern States for the purpose of voting against the
                        President. Finding himself foiled, seeing that "the great culprits" would
                        escape uncondemned, he became desperate and reckless. And thousands there
                        were in the Radical party, so utterly lost to all shame as to declare
                        themselves ready to approve of the adoption of this course suggested by
                        Forney.--What a "party of great moral ideas!"</p>
                    <p>Such hounds as Forney can not appreciate the moral worth of men like
                        Fessenden, Trumbull and Grimes. He has no admiration for the pure minds
                        which recognize the binding obligation of an oath. He expects every other
                        person to be ready at any time, as he would be, to "throw conscience to the
                        Devil" for the sake of party. Always cringing at the feet of power in order
                        to obtain favors, or crouching under cover of an assumed name to escape
                        public condemnation, he can not rise to an appreciation of the majesty and
                        dignity of our humanity as exemplified in Senator Fessenden when he uttered
                        these bold, noble words: "I should consider myself undeserving the
                        confidence that the just and intelligent people imposed upon me in this
                        great responsibility, and unworthy a place among honorable men, if for any
                        fear of public reprobation, and for the sake of securing popular favor, I
                        should disregard the convictions of my judgement and conscience."</p>
                    <p>So too, Forney and his crew are strangers to the feeling which prompted these
                        no less noble words of Senator Grimes. "Nor can I suffer my judgement of the
                        law governing this case to be influenced by <emph rend="italic"
                        >political</emph> considerations. I can not agree to destroy the harmonious
                        working of the Constitution for the sake of getting rid of an unacceptable
                        President. Whatever may be my opinion of the incumbent, I can not consent to
                            <emph rend="italic">trifle with the high office he holds</emph>. I can
                        do nothing which by implication, may be construed <emph rend="italic">into
                            an approval of impeachment as a part of future political
                        machinery</emph>."</p>
                    <p>These Senators felt the pressure upon them. They were asked to assist in
                        convicting the President as a political, or rather, a partisan necessity.
                        All the noble instincts of their natures rose up in rebellion against such
                        an idea. They refused to be slaves. They were unwilling to be regarded by
                        coming generations as men who were only fit to obey the commands of Thaddeus
                        Stevens. All honor to these men! They have subordinated party interests to
                        the promptings of duty. Conscience has been their guide, and however
                        fiercely the storm of party hate may rage around them--however bitterly they
                        may be traduced--a sense of duty performed will be ever with them, and that
                        consolation will be theirs which they only experience whose actions spring
                        from conscientious convictions.</p>
                    <p>But what demoralization will run through the Radical ranks! What weeping and
                        wailing and gnashing of teeth there must be at Chicago this very day. We
                        hope that there will be no copy of last weeks' <emph rend="italic"
                            >Repository</emph> there to dampen Col. McClure's spirits as he ponders
                        upon the fact that the writer over the initials A.K.M., is neither a
                        prophet, nor the son of a prophet.</p>
                    <p>Let the Chicago Convention take up the case of President Johnson. Inasmuch as
                        the majority in the Senate of the United States are Radicals, do they not
                        owe their positions to the Radical party? And is not the Chicago Convention
                        the mouth-piece of the Radical party? Surely its right to substitute itself
                        for the Senate can not be questioned. Let it vote on the articles of
                        impeachment.--Let it convict and remove Andrew Johnson. Forney will endorse
                        it. The people will sustain it provided the elections are held as in the
                        South. Let it be done by all means.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Expresses reluctant but high praise upon the Republican Senators who voted
                    against impeachment. Contrasts the "noble" efforts of these men(Fessenden,
                    Grimes, and Trumbull especially) with the actions of Radicals who did everything
                    in their power to convict Johnson. Gloats at their failure and mocks the
                    Radicals at the Republican Convention in Chicago.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Hon. Asa Packer</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper endorses calls for nominating Asa Packer as Democratic candidate
                    for vice president.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Malignant Impudence</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Impeachment Managers of the House met several days last week and examined
                        witnesses, with a view to discover what attempts have been made to influence
                        or procure the votes of Senators in favor of the acquittal of the President!
                        Was there ever a more disgusting exhibition of malignant impudence? These
                        Managers and their accomplices in the great crime they have committed have
                        used every effort both proper and improper, to influence Senators. Thad.
                        Stevens, in the bitter tirade he got off in lieu of an argument before the
                        Impeachment Court, threatened them with the gibbit, for which the impudent
                        and malignant old scoundrel should have been ordered into the custody of the
                        Sergeant-at-Arms. The whole Radical press of the country has been actively
                        engaged in improper attempts to influence Senators to vote in favor of
                        impeachment. Radical meetings have been held at numerous points, and
                        speeches made and resolutions passed, demanding the votes of Republican
                        Senators in favor of conviction. Delegations have waited upon Senators and
                        urged them to vote for conviction, or, if their conscience forbade that, to
                        withhold their votes and permit the matter to be decided by those who were
                        willing to act upon Thad. Stevens' advice and "throw conscience to the
                        devil."</p>
                    <p>In view of the notorious efforts that impeachers of all classes have made and
                        are still making <emph rend="italic">to force</emph> the Senate to convict
                        the President, it is as sublimely impudent for the House Managers to
                        "investigate" the motives which prompted certain Republican Senators to vote
                        against conviction, as it would be for a committee of harlots to inquire why
                        respectable women refused to associate with them. How long will the American
                        people tolerate the brazen-faced impudence of such men as Stevens, Butler
                        and Logan?</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Editor is disgusted at the efforts of Radicals to investigate attempts made
                    to influence Senators to vote against impeachment. Notes the efforts by Radicals
                    to get a conviction and thus finds their current investigations hypocritical.
                    Has particular venom for Thaddeus Stevens.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>An Expensive Law</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>If the Radicals are not soon put out of power, there will not be money enough
                        in the country to pay the expenses of our State and National Governments.
                        They are constantly inventing new ways to spend the people's money. The
                        Registry Law passed at the last session of our Legislature turns out to be
                        an expensive thing. The City Commissioners of Philadelphia have made
                        application to the Councils for an extra appropriation of <emph
                            rend="italic">eighty-one thousand dollars</emph> to carry out the law in
                        that city. At this rate it will take <emph rend="italic">half a million
                            dollars</emph> to execute it throughout the State! Thus while trade in
                        all its branches is languishing and business men have hard work to keep
                        their heads above water, our Radical Congress spends millions on the
                        Freedmen's Bureau and our Radical State Legislature spends half a million to
                        put in execution an unnecessary and vexatious Registry Law. Is it not time
                        to have a change?</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Condemns the wastefulness of Republican state and national governments.
                    Cites the Freedmen's Bureau and the new state Registry Law as examples of
                    Republicans throwing taxpayers' money down the drain. Urges voters to throw them
                    out of power.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Letter From Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter from Virginia commenting on the heavy immigration into the state
                    from the North.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Impeachment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on the excitement in Washington surrounding the culmination of the
                    impeachment trial.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.05.20.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Admitted</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eby</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCauley</ln>
                        <fn>I. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jacob S. Eby of the Chambersburg Bar was admitted to practice in the
                    Pennsylvania Supreme Court on motion of I. H. McCauley.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maclay</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. J. A. Maclay is practicing at Greenvillage.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Mercersburg College</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harbaugh</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bokum</ln>
                        <fn>Hermann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letter complimenting Mercersburg college.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Teachers' Examinations</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article announces that teachers holding a professional certificate
                    previously rendering them exempt from the yearly exam must take one this year.
                    The paper applauds the move, arguing it will ensure the quality of the county's
                    teachers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houchtelin</ln>
                        <fn>William H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McFetridge</ln>
                        <fn>Jennie L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McFetridge</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William H. H. Houchtelin of Chambersburg and Jennie L. McFetridge, daughter
                    of Samuel L. McFetridge of Philadelphia, were married on May 7th in the
                    residence of the bride's parents.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Speilman</ln>
                        <fn>Clinton D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henderson</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnes</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Clinton D. Speilman and Miss Sarah Jane Henderson, both of Chambersburg,
                    were married on May 5th by the Rev. S. Barnes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Updyke</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Buchanan</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnes</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Updyke of Philadelphia and Miss Sarah Jane Buchanan of Franklin were
                    married on May 12th at the American Hotel by the Rev. S. Barnes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Millhouse</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Martha Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnes</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Henry Millhouse and Miss Martha Jane Stumbaugh, both of Franklin, were
                    married at the Methodist Parsonage on May 14th by the Rev. S. Barnes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sleichter</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fortna</ln>
                        <fn>Fana</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bigham</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Daniel Sleichter and Miss Fana Fortna, both of Franklin, were married in
                    Orrstown on April 30th by the Rev. S. Bigham.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eakle</ln>
                        <fn>Christian</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Christian Eakle died in Chambersburg on May 10th. He was 55 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingert</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brechbill</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Mary Wingert died at the Green Township residence of Jacob Brechbill
                    on May 12th. She was 23 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.05.20.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
