<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1868/pa.fr.vs.1868.12.16">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/15/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1868-12-16">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="12">December</month>
            <day norm="">16</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.12.16.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.12.16.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The President's Message</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The last annual message of President Johnson, which we publish to-day, will
                        of course receive an attentive perusal from all our readers. The first part
                        of it gave so much offence to the dignified statesmen who compose the
                        Radical majority in the United States Senate, that one of them moved to
                        dispense with the further reading of it, and pending this motion the Senate
                        adjourned. In the House a bitter discussion followed its reading, the
                        Radicals denouncing it savagely. Its offence is that it shows up in strong
                        colors the iniquities of Radical legislation. It insults the wise men in
                        Congress by telling them the most unpalatable truths. The language is
                        strong--unusually so for a President's message--but it ill becomes the
                        Radicals in Congress to complain of it, or to pretend that it is offensive
                        to their dignity since every one of them has often used language far more
                        insulting to the President.</p>
                    <p>That portion of the message which is devoted to the public debt will be read
                        with the greatest interest. All will agree with the President that "the idea
                        that such a debt is to become permanent should be at all times discarded,"
                        but all will not agree to the mode he suggests for getting rid of it.</p>
                    <p>We do not think it worth while to go over the message in detail. Every man
                        will read it for himself, and approve or condemn as his judgment may
                        dictate. Upon such points of it as may give rise to controversy, we may
                        hereafter have occasion to express our views.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces the publication of President Johnson's last annual message.
                    Doesn't quote it but does note with amusement that Radicals took great offense
                    at the message's language even though they had used similar language against
                    Johnson earlier.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Female Suffrage</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A lady of our acquaintance remarked to us a few days ago, "whenever a
                        majority of the women of this country <emph rend="italic">wish</emph> to
                        vote, they <emph rend="italic">will</emph> vote." We imagine that there is a
                        great deal of truth in this remark. Since the day when Eve tempted Adam and
                        prevailed upon him to eat of the forbidden fruit, women's influence over the
                        sterner sex has been wonderful. She has ruled him, either with a rod of iron
                        or with the voice of tender entreaty. And she has always been conscious of
                        her power. She has measured her strength and is perfectly acquainted with
                        the extent of her influence. What she wills to do, she does. What she wills
                        to have done, is done. Boast as the lord of creation may and does, of his
                        superior wisdom and sounder judgment, still he finds himself ruled by a
                        woman. Delilah wrung from a reluctant Samson the secret of his great
                        strength and he soon awoke to find himself shorn of his power. Antony gave
                        up a kingdom on account of his fatal attachment to Cleopatra.</p>
                    <p>The strong-minded women of our day have mistaken the way to advance the cause
                        of woman's rights.</p>
                    <p>They are all, or nearly all, old maids. They claim great credit for
                        themselves because they have never yielded to the emotion which, they
                        allege, makes woman a slave. Those of them who have been joined in the hands
                        of matrimony are the wives of hen-pecked husbands who have never dared to
                        assert their marital rights. These women mount the rostrum and loudly and
                        eloquently attempt to persuade men of the right of women to take part in the
                        administration of government.</p>
                    <p>A more efficient mode of proceeding would be for them all to get married and
                        each one undertake to convince her own husband or, if they will not do that,
                        they ought to spend their time in convincing those of their own sex of the
                        justice and propriety of their proposition, and whenever they secure a
                        majority there, then "advance the whole line" upon their pliable partners of
                        the masculine gender. An effort of this kind would be sure to result in
                        victory because <emph rend="italic">there is scarcely any woman who does not
                            have her own way</emph>. Imagine a devoted wife throwing her arms around
                        her admiring husband's neck and exclaiming "dear husband, won't you vote to
                        allow me to vote"? Why, it would be irresistible. Female suffrage would soon
                        be an accomplished fact.</p>
                    <p>Let the New England strongminded woman, therefore, change their base and
                        begin to fight on another line. They have made no progress, and will make
                        none as long as they only use weapons drawn from the armory of the
                        intellect. They must have recourse to those more effective weapons by which
                        hearts are stirred. They must enlist in their behalf the sympathies of all
                        womankind and then arrange for a united attack.</p>
                    <p>The Democrats would very quickly come to the conclusion that if the negroes
                        must vote, it would be better by far to have women vote also, for the reason
                        that the good influence of the latter might counteract the evil influence of
                        the former. They would vote therefore for female suffrage at once.--The
                        wives of Radical husbands would be expected to make a vigorous effort to
                        control their votes. They could say to them with striking effect, "my dear,
                        you have just sided in giving the negro the right of suffrage. Don't you
                        consider <emph rend="italic">me</emph> as capable and as much entitled to
                        vote as he is"? They could point to Kansas and say, "your party is a
                        disgrace to the nation. It has shown to the world that it places a higher
                        estimate upon the negro than upon woman. Whilst the majority there against
                        negro suffrage was 8938, the majority against female suffrage was 10,787."
                        How could their Radical husbands hold out against such an argument as this?</p>
                    <p>If women wish to vote, that is the majority of them, let them fix the time
                        when they desire to begin and they can easily secure the right. If the
                        husbands are mulish and will not be convinced, let the dear creatures hint
                        at a dissolution of the bonds of matrimony, and they will soon see the
                        enemy's flag hauled down in token of surrender.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Comments on the likelihood of women's suffrage. Insists women always get
                    their way, especially over their husbands. Says if the majority of women want
                    the vote, it will happen one way or another. Claims Democrats, in order to
                    counterbalance black voting, will readily support women's suffrage if only the
                    majority of women call for it.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.12.16.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Lecture</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shumaker</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Prof. J. H. Shumaker will deliver a lecture in Greenvillage on "Manliness."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Horticultural Society</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A group of Franklin citizens is working on establishing a Horticultural
                    Society.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Installation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>J. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mitchell</ln>
                        <fn>S. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Creigh</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wightman</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. J. N. Hays was installed as Pastor of Chambersburg's Central
                    Presbyterian Church. The Rev. S. S. Mitchell, Dr. Creigh, and the Rev. J. W.
                    Wightman all spoke.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>A Musical Entertainment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Noftaker</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A concert will be held by the Ladies' Mite Society of the M. E. Church.
                    Prof. Noftaker will direct the music. The admission fees of 30 cents for adults
                    and 15 cents for children will be used to re-furnish the church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Court Proceedings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rowe</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Oliver S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Henderson M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hess</ln>
                        <fn>Jeremiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCauley</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kyner</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Judge Rowe presided over the opening of the Special Court for the trial of
                    civil causes. In the case of John W. Skinner vs. Oliver S. Brown, Summons in
                    Covenant upon articles of agreement for $500, the parties settled, the defendant
                    paying the plaintiff $120 and each paying costs. The parties settled in the
                    slander case of Henderson M. Myers vs. Dr. Jeremiah Hess. In McCauley &amp;
                    Hays vs. Alexander W. Kyner the defendant confessed judgement for $120 and
                    costs.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hassler</ln>
                        <fn>M. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Byers</ln>
                        <fn>Lizzie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J. Keller</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>M. B. Hassler and Miss Lizzie Byers, both of St. Thomas, were married on
                    December 6th by the Rev. J. Keller Miller.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walter</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walter</ln>
                        <fn>Jennie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J. Keller</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel Walter of Adams County and Miss Jennie Walter of St. Thomas were
                    married on December 10th at the residence of, and by, the Rev. J. Keller Miller.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gelwix</ln>
                        <fn>James M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zollinger</ln>
                        <fn>Jennie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James M. Gelwix and Miss Jennie Zollinger, both of Strasburg, Franklin
                    County, were married on December 3rd at the residence of the bride's father.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jarrett</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jacob Jarrett died in Harrisburg on December 4th. He was 50 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shields</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Catharine Shields died on December 8th in Lurgan township. She was 79
                    years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.12.16.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote>Advertisements appear on this page.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
