<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1868/pa.fr.vs.1868.03.11">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/17/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1868-03-11">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day norm="">11</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.03.11.01" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>07</column>
                <head>A Talk With The Confederate Vice-President</head>
                <origin>Philadelphia Inquirer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An interview with Alexander Stephens on the state of Georgia and the South.
                    "Everything there is wretched. We are ruined or next to ruined. The negroes are
                    compactly organized, their leagues reaching to every corner of the State." He
                    opposes citizenship for blacks, as it would leave whites in a "minority."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.03.11.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Judge Them By Their Fruits</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>As the people of the United States are about to enter upon a political
                        campaign of the highest importance, this would seem to be a proper time for
                        reflecting men to glance at the history of the past and judge the two
                        parties now struggling for supremacy by what they have done for the country.
                        If it shall appear, upon investigation, that one of these parties, when in
                        power, enlarged the boundaries of the Republic, promoted the general
                        welfare, caused our name to be respected abroad, and made us the happiest
                        and the lightest taxed people in the world, whilst the other has done just
                        the reverse of all this, can there be a doubt about which of them the reins
                        of government should hereafter be entrusted to?</p>
                    <p>The Democratic party came into power with Thomas Jefferson in 1801, and it
                        administered the government from that period down to 1861 with the exception
                        of the four years of John Quincy Adams, the four years of Harrison and
                        Tyler, and the four years of Taylor and Fillmore. The administration of Mr.
                        Tyler cannot be wholly excluded from the period of Democratic rule, for many
                        of his leading measures received the support of the Democratic party.</p>
                    <p>When Mr. Jefferson assumed the Presidential chair, our boundaries in the West
                        reached no farther than the Mississippi, whilst in the South west they did
                        not extend to that stream. France owned Louisiana, which comprised not only
                        the territory now embraced within the limits of that State, but the vast
                        region beyond the Mississippi. This the Democratic party under Jefferson
                        acquired and added to the Union, carrying its boundaries, at a single leap,
                        from the Mississippi to the Pacific Ocean. Subsequently Florida was
                        acquired, giving us a large addition of valuable territory on the gulf,
                        affording many fine harbors and strong naval stations.</p>
                    <p>The annexation of Texas, negotiated by Mr. Tyler near the close of his
                        administration, with the approbation of the Democracy and against the
                        violent protest of the opposite party, was consummated by the Democratic
                        administration of Mr. Polk. War with Mexico followed, but so economically
                        was it conducted that the country never felt the least financial pressure on
                        account of it. No shoddy contractors preyed upon the treasury. No bloated
                        bond aristocracy grew up like mushrooms. No government shinplasters flooded
                        the country. No provost marshal demanded of every citizen his money or his
                        life. Tax-gatherers did not stand at every cross-roads. Gold and silver were
                        abundant, and both the necessaries and luxuries of life could be bought at
                        the cheapest rates. Being conducted for the honor of the country and not for
                        the benefit of a party, this war neither lasted long nor cost much; and at
                        its conclusion we were left in possession not only of Texas but of Upper
                        California, with its golden treasures, its marvelously fertile soil, and its
                        magnificent harbor, where the united navies of the world could ride
                        uncrowded and in safety. Thus our boundaries at the south-west were pushed
                        out to the Rio Grande and the Pacific.</p>
                    <p>These various acquisitions more than doubled our territory, and opened up
                        vast fields of enterprise to our people. Our population rose from four
                        millions to thirty. No other country ever improved as rapidly as did ours.
                        Our growth in all the elements of material greatness was the wonder of the
                        world. We were everywhere regarded as the most prosperous, the most happy
                        and the best governed people on the face of the earth. Cities and towns grew
                        up as if by magic. Commerce and manufactures flourished. The face of the
                        country smiled under the labors of the husbandman, and the farmers of the
                        United States were the envy of mankind. The blessings of good government
                        were dispensed alike upon the rich and the poor, and government burdens were
                        totally unknown. Plenty blessed every industrious household, and happiness
                        and prosperity rewarded the deserving throughout the length and breadth of
                        the land. We enjoyed tranquility at home and were respected abroad. Honesty
                        was the rule with men to public life. Servants of the people did not
                        suddenly amass fortunes, and in fact most of them went out of office poorer
                        than they went in.</p>
                    <p>These were the fruits of Democratic administrations of the government, and
                        upon them the Democratic party rests its claim to the confidence of the
                        people.</p>
                    <p>The Radical party which now governs the country was formed in 1856, but it
                        did not come into power till 1861. Its nucleus was the little band of
                        envenomed Abolitionists who used to meet annually at Boston and denounce the
                        Constitution as "a league with death and a covenant with hell," and whose
                        petition for a dissolution of the Union used to be presented at every
                        session of Congress by John Quincy Adams. So long as the Whig party held
                        together these treasonable agitators were powerless,; but its disintegration
                        furnished them the opportunity to form a new party with sectional
                        principles, and they availed themselves of the chance.--Knowing that men in
                        their sober senses could not be won over to their support, they
                        systematically went to work to lash the public mind into a state of furious
                        excitement. From that day to this there has been no peace in the country.
                        They sent armed bands of agitators from New England to Kansas, headed by
                        such miscreants as old John Brown. Under their manipulation that territory
                        became a seething caldron of crime. Themselves the authors of all its woes,
                        they so perverted the facts as to "fire the Northern heart" with indignation
                        against the whole South.</p>
                    <p>Under pressure of the excitement thus created, they carried the Presidential
                        election of 1860 and assumed the administration of the government in 1861.
                        The storm they had raised was still raging, but they took no steps to allay
                        it. They had started out to subvert the Constitution and dissolve the Union,
                        and they knew that it was only in the white heat of civil war that this
                        result could be hammered out. War came because the Radicals would not hear
                        of Peace. The country was deluged with blood because the Radicals thought "a
                        little bloodletting" desirable. A mountain load of debt was piled up, which
                        unborn generations will have to pay off with the sweat of their brow. Free
                        men, accustomed to go and come when they pleased, were driven into pens like
                        sheep at the point of the bayonet, and thrust into blue clothes, and led out
                        to be slaughtered, while their wives and children were left unprotected and
                        starving at home. Myriads of graves yawned, and myriads of men in the prime
                        of life lay down and filled them. Hundreds of prison doors swung open and
                        thousands of innocent victims walked in to their doom.--Cities and towns
                        were burned and large districts of country plundered and laid waste. The
                        foundations of order were unsettled and crime held high carnival throughout
                        the land. Honest men were deprived of the fruits of their industry, whilst
                        every community had its scoundrels who grew rich.</p>
                    <p>While all this was taking place at home, the national character was sinking
                        abroad, and the national credit was brought so low that our obligations
                        commanded no more than forty cents on the dollar in the markets of the
                        world. The flood of gold and silver that followed the acquisition of
                        California by a Democratic administration suddenly receded, and in its stead
                        there came a deluge of shinplasters of all denominations. The inflation of
                        the currency produced a rage for speculation that proved the ruin of tens of
                        thousands. To the horrors of war were added the miseries of a mania for
                        riches which only left its victims poorer.</p>
                    <p>What has this great Radical upheaval ended in? Practically--for the present
                        at least--it has ended in a curtailment of the boundaries of the Union. Call
                        the Roll of the Union in Congress and no voice will be found to answer for
                        Virginia, for North Carolina, for South Carolina, for Georgia, for Florida,
                        for Alabama, for Mississippi, for Louisiana, for Arkansas, or for Texas.</p>
                    <p>Instead of the peace and prosperity we enjoyed before the advent of the
                        Radical party, we have excitement, angry discussion and stagnation in
                        business. The abolition of slavery, so far from removing a dangerous bone of
                        contention, has brought up new questions of the most exciting character. We
                        have been disgraced by the assassination of one President, and now our
                        Radical Congress, emulous of the fame of John Wilkes Booth, proposes to rid
                        us of another, and he of their own choosing.</p>
                    <p>Now, after contrasting the condition of the country under Radical rule with
                        what it was under Democratic rule, is there an honest, reflecting man who
                        will not admit that the change made in 1860 was <emph rend="italic">for the
                            worse?</emph> There stand the facts. Look at them. They cannot be
                        denied. They are plain as the sun at noonday. They vindicate the Democracy.
                        They condemn the Radicals. And they call upon the people of the United
                        States, by all that they hold dear on earth, to restore the Democratic party
                        to power, so that under its guidance this great country may be restored to
                        its former prosperity and happiness.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Pro-Democratic article contrasting the actions of the Democratic and
                    Republican parties. Pays special attention to the differences between the
                    Mexican War and the Civil War. Blames the Radicals for starting the war and all
                    the financial trouble of the country, and urges people to vote for Democrats.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Progress of Impeachment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Senate of the United States has, at length, organized itself into a high
                        Court of Impeachment. It has issued its summons to the President, returnable
                        on Friday of this week. The Chief Justice presides. Benjamin Wade is one of
                        the judges. In the event of the removal of the President from his office,
                        Senator Wade will take his place. Senator Hendricks objected to the oath
                        being administered to Mr. Wade, but subsequently withdrew the objection. It
                        will undoubtedly be renewed at some further stage of the proceedings. The
                        impropriety, indelicacy and injustice of allowing Mr. Wade to vote in a
                        trial in which he has such a gigantic personal interest are apparent to
                        everyone. Human nature can not be trusted to do justice where immense
                        personal interests are at stake. Men generally look to their own elevation
                        without entertaining conscientious scruples as to the manner in which that
                        elevation is to be attained. Hence, however high Mr. Wade's personal
                        character might be, it would be exceedingly dangerous to put into his hands
                        the power to dispossess Andrew Johnson, when Mr. Wade himself would
                        immediately step into the most honorable position in the world. The honor,
                        high social advantages, and large salary of the Presidential office might
                        well tempt him to stifle the voice of conscience.</p>
                    <p>We believe that the Chief Justice is animated by an eager desire to do what
                        is right. His judgement will not be influenced by partisan considerations.
                        No Chief Justice has ever presided at a trial so important as this. Mr.
                        Chase's legal reputation is not alone at stake. It is his also to preserve
                        the purity of the judicial ermine. He can not allow the breath of suspicion
                        to touch his hitherto fair name. Far better for his reputation in after
                        ages, that Mr. Johnson, even though he were guilty, should go free, than
                        that the pen of the historian should write that the President was convicted
                        and removed from his office, in obedience to the demand of a party operating
                        upon the mind of the Chief Justice and inducing him to prostitute his high
                        position for partisan purposes. What an enviable renown Mr. Chase might
                        achieve for himself, were he, in the course of the trial, to shake off the
                        shackles of party, and give to the high Court of Impeachment that
                        construction of the Tenure-of-office Bill which, we feel assured, he as a
                        lawyer and judge, must put upon it. Let him decide the matter in the forum
                        of conscience and give the Court his decision. He will make a record during
                        the progress of this trial which will be read by Americans as long as this
                        country has an existence. The applause of a listening Senate is, doubtless,
                        music to the ear, but it will die away. The men who surround him today will
                        ere long, like himself, sleep beneath the earth. But this trial will live in
                        history long after the actors in it have passed away. Truth and justice are
                        eternal. By them, will posterity judge of the utterances and conduct of the
                        President's judges. Passion may override sober judgement and achieve a
                        temporary triumph, but injustice, practiced now, will damn to everlasting
                        infamy in the long future, the men, who through its instrumentality, seek to
                        satisfy their political enmity and wreak their personal vengeance. The
                        people expect of the Chief Justice that he will not be-draggle the robes of
                        his high office in the mire of politics, but that by courtesy, moderation,
                        and impartiality, he will set a lofty example to the Senators sitting in
                        judgement.</p>
                    <p>They greatly need such an example. Men who have unhesitatingly expressed an
                        opinion upon the matters in controversy--men who sent words of encouragement
                        to the occupant of the War Office, advising him to "stick"--men who hurried
                        to the War Department and to the Head-Quarters of the General of the army,
                        to concert measures of resistance to the President--surely such men might be
                        taken to have incapacitated themselves as judges between the President and
                        Stanton. They can scarcely be expected to act impartially. There is a
                        partisan bias in their minds which no argument, however forcible, can be
                        expected to change. We have no doubt, therefore, as to what will be the
                        verdict of the "Senate sitting as a High Court of Impeachment," if it ever
                        reaches a verdict.</p>
                    <p>Andrew Johnson owes it to himself and the country, to prolong this trial to
                        the utmost possible limit. Let him summon all the witnesses necessary for
                        his defence, even though the number should be greater than the sands upon
                        the sea shore. The trial of Warren Hastings lasted seven years. Why should
                        not the trial of an American President require one year? He owes it to
                        himself in order to give opportunity to the Supreme Court to deliver
                        opinions which will show the wisdom of his individual action. He owes it to
                        the country, in order that the highest judicial tribunal in the land may
                        settle the principle for all time to come, that one Department of the
                        Government may not, and dare not, strip a coordinate and co-equal Department
                        of its constitutional function.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Charts the progress of the impeachment proceedings against Johnson. Has
                    harsh words for Ben Wade but pleads with Chief Justice Chase to put justice over
                    partisan feeling. Also says Johnson owes it to himself and the country to put up
                    a vigorous defense.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Democratic State Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Democratic State Convention which met at Harrisburg last week, was one of
                        the most respectable bodies that ever assembled at the capital of
                        Pennsylvania. It was presided over by the Hon. William Hopkins, of
                        Washington, one of the best and purest of our public men, and on its floor
                        were such distinguished and able gentlemen as Hon. John L. Dawson of
                        Fayette, Joh. Gaylord Church of Crawford, Hon. S.E. Ancona, of Berks, Hon.
                        R.F. Monaghan, of Chester, Hon. A.B. Longaker, of Montgomery, Gen.
                        McCandless, of Philadelphia, and Col. Sweitzer, of Pittsburgh.</p>
                    <p>The resolutions adopted by the Convention are sound and conservative. They
                        declare for the Constitution and the Union.--They arraign the Radicals in
                        Congress for violating the supreme law of the land; for squandering enormous
                        sums of money, which have been wrung from the people; for delaying the
                        restoration of the Southern States in their just relations to the Union, and
                        for attempting to perpetuate their power through the votes of illiterate
                        negroes. They declare that questions of law upon which the different
                        branches of the government may be at variance should be decided by the
                        Supreme Court; that the pending impeachment of the President is a gross
                        abuse of power and intended to effect partisan purposes; that the best
                        interests of the country demand an early return to a specie basis; that the
                        national debt should be liquidated as rapidly as possible, and that the five
                        twenty bonds should be paid in legal tenders till the government is able to
                        redeem its notes in coin. Some of the more ardent members of our party may
                        perhaps hold that the language of some of the resolutions should have been
                        stronger. But the sentiments of the resolutions will command the approbation
                        of all conservative men, whilst their phraseology involves merely a question
                        of taste.</p>
                    <p>The Convention was fortunate in its selection of candidates. We know Hon.
                        Charles E. Boyle quite intimately, and we do not hesitate to pronounce him
                        one of the best men in the State for the position of Auditor General.
                        Talented, vigilant, energetic, sagacious, and honest as the day is long, he
                        would guard the public interests with as sleepless an eye as ever watched
                        over them. With Gen. W.H. Ent,our nominee for Surveyor General, we have not
                        the pleasure of a personal acquaintance, but reliable gentlemen who live in
                        his section of the State and known him well, assure us that he is all we
                        could desire a candidate to be. We do not doubt it, and we call upon the
                        Democracy of Franklin to prepare to make good the assurance we now give to
                        Gen. Ent, that, glorious as was the result in this county last fall, his
                        majority shall exceed that given to Sharswood.</p>
                    <p>For Delegates to the National Convention the most judicious selections were
                        made. The Delegates at large are Hon. Geo. W. Woodward, of Luzerne, Hon. Wm.
                        Bigier, of Clearfield, Hon. Asa Packer, of Carbon, and Hon. Isaac E.
                        Hiester, of Lancaster, four of the best men in the State; whilst among the
                        District Delegates are Col. W.C. Patterson, of Philadelphia, Hon. John D.
                        Stiles, of Lehigh, Hon. John H. Brinton, of Chester, Hon. Hiester Clymer, of
                        Berks, Hon. F.W. Hughes, of Schuylkill, Hon. Wm. H. Miller, of Dauphin, Hon.
                        Geo. W. Brewer, of Franklin, Hon. Gaylord Church, of Crawford, Hon. John L.
                        Dawson, of Fayette, and Hon. A.A. Purman, of Greene. With such a galaxy of
                        able men to represent her, we may confidently expect Pennsylvania to
                        exercise a full share of influence in the National Convention.</p>
                    <p>Our Delegates were wisely left uninstructed. There was no clearly defined
                        feeling in favor of any particular candidate. All seemed to agree that the
                        wisest course was to select a Delegation of our best and purest public men,
                        and trust them to do what in their <sic>judgment</sic> the interests of the
                        party and the country should demand when the time came for the National
                        Convention to assemble.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewer</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lists the names of men nominated as delegates to the Democratic National
                    Convention for state offices. Gives high praise for every man chosen. Also
                    details the platform of the Pennsylvania Democratic Party.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Attention Democrats</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Our Spring elections are close at hand. Their importance can not be
                        overrated. They are preliminary skirmishes to the grand engagement which is
                        to take place next Fall. It is of the utmost moment that Democratic Judges
                        of Election should be chosen. Stir yourselves, Democrats. The enemy is
                        organizing. They are predicting apathy in our ranks. They hope to win
                        through our sluggishness. Buckle on the armor. Go into the fight determined
                        to win. You have everything to encourage you to action. Everywhere the
                        people are rising against the corrupt Radical party. Its doom is sealed. Put
                        good men in nomination, and you must win. White men will vote for white men.
                        The intelligent masses are against negro suffrage, negro equality and negro
                        supremacy. "Up, and at them."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper calls for Democrats to prepare for vigorous efforts in the Spring
                    political campaigns.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Honor to Whom Honor is Due</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Winger</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McConaughy</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letter stating that Col. B. F. Winger, not Senator McConaughy, should
                    receive credit for introducing the Border Relief Bill in the legislature.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Another Letter From Robert Criswell</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Criswell</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letter from Robert Criswell criticizing Thaddeus Stevens' Reconstruction
                    policies.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>08</column>
                <head>Glorious News! The Radicals Impeached by the People!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports victories for Democrats in city and town elections in several
                    northern states.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.03.11.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>North Ward Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>North Ward Democrats will meet in the Montgomery House to nominate a ticket
                    for spring elections.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>South Ward Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyd</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>South Ward Democrats will meet at the public house of Samuel R. Boyd to
                    nominate a ticket for the spring elections.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Young Men's Christian Association</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>S. H. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gaff</ln>
                        <fn>J. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A meeting was held to discuss organizing a Young Men's Christian
                    Association in Chambersburg. The Rev. S. H. C. Smith chaired the meeting and J.
                    R. Gaff was elected Secretary. The paper endorses the plan to promote
                    intellectual and religious development in the town's young men. A reading room
                    is also proposed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>New Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Douglas</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Amberson</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wertz</ln>
                        <fn>H. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Good</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Small</ln>
                        <fn>E. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Winger</ln>
                        <fn>E. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heller</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Knepper</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wertz</ln>
                        <fn>H. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Philips</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Saunders</ln>
                        <fn>Levi</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Geiser</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bear</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Muler</ln>
                        <fn>J. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Funk</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A meeting was held to discuss building a railroad from Scotland to
                    Waynesboro. The people of Quincy and Washington are especially excited about the
                    plan. A committee was appointed to open banks and receive subscriptions of stock
                    for the project. The paper suggests that people of the area should agitate to
                    have the connection of that road with the Cumberland Valley Road located at
                    Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Land and Labor in South-West Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A letter from Abingdon describing labor conditions, land values, and
                    productivity in South-West Virginia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Draper</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bitinger</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stonehouse</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John W. Draper and Miss Sarah E. Bitinger of Fayetteville, were married on
                    March 3rd by the Rev. H. Stonehouse.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ranger</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewer</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewer</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Startzman</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Henry Ranger of Sharpsburg, MD, and Miss Mary Brewer, daughter of the late
                    Joseph Brewer of Welsh Run, were married by the Rev. C. Startzman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.03.11.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote>Advertisements and agricultural advice appear on this page.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
