<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1868/pa.fr.vs.1868.09.02">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/11/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1868-09-02">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day norm="">2</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.09.02.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.09.02.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>What They Talk About</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It must be amusing to listen to a Radical speak in the present campaign. It
                        has been our privilege to read one or two, and to be informed of the style
                        and matter of a few others. From our information thus gathered, we are led
                        to the conclusion that the Radical speakers are frightened at the issues
                        that have grown out of the war.--They are afraid to discuss them. They are
                        still harping upon the disloyalty of the Democratic party during the
                        rebellion. They are still bandying the words, Copperhead, traitor, rebel
                        sympathizer. They are busily engaged in <del/> the Democracy for gross
                        <del/> five or six years ago, seemingly oblivious of the fact that the
                        people are calling them to account for their own terrible misrule during the
                        last three years. With great <unclear>atrocity</unclear> they go before an
                        audience of American citizens--longing for relief from the burdens under
                        which the nation is staggering--earnestly desirous to ascertain the
                            <unclear>avenue</unclear> of escape from the evils into which Radicalism
                        has plunged the country and discuss the <emph rend="italic">Slavery</emph>
                        question. They know well that slavery is "dead as
                        <unclear>Garrick</unclear>," and that there are no mourners at its tomb. And
                        yet they would persuade the people that it is the purpose of the Democratic
                        party to resurrect that forever buried institution.</p>
                    <p>With equal seriousness, they talk about the secession question. They occupy
                        their time in attempting to convince the masses that a State has not the
                        right to secede from the Union. They seem to think that the people are too
                        ignorant to know that this question has been finally settled by the bloody
                        arbitrament of the sword, and that the settlement has been accepted, and
                        acquiesced in, by the citizens of the Northern and Southern states alike.</p>
                    <p>Another favorite hobby, is the old, oft repeated charge of Democratic
                        opposition to the war for the preservation of the Union. They deny that
                        Democrats took part in the struggle in any considerable numbers, and
                        appropriate to themselves the honor of all the victories won by the Union
                        forces. They forget that during the war, more than three million,(3,000,000)
                        of men enlisted in the Union armies, and that the whole number of votes for
                        Mr. Lincoln was one million eight hundred and fifty eight thousand, two
                        hundred and fifty.(1,858,250) Even granting that every man who voted for
                        Lincoln went to the war, where did the excess of men come from? And when the
                        fact is taken into account that a great many of those who voted for Lincoln
                        did <emph rend="italic">not</emph> go to the war, it seems to us to be made
                        out very clearly that our armies were nearly equally divided in political
                        sentiment.</p>
                    <p>Now, what has all this kind of talk to do with the great questions that now
                        divide the political parties of the country? What light will it throw upon
                        the Congressional Reconstruction policy which has been so signally condemned
                        by the people wherever elections have been held? How will it explain the
                        startling extravagance and unprecedented corruption which have
                            <unclear>marked</unclear> the Radical administration in a time of
                        profound peace? How will it justify the usurpation by the Legislative
                        Department of the rights granted by the Constitution to the Executive and
                        the Judiciary? What satisfaction does it give the people in relation to the
                        military governments which have been established in the South without any
                        warrant, or shadow of right? How will it excuse the degradation of the
                        native white population of the South and the elevation to political power of
                        ignorant negroes and unprincipled carpet-baggers? What mode of payment does
                        it suggest of the heavy debt which hangs like a horrid nightmare upon the
                        bosom of the nation? What assurance does it give to the laborer that better
                        times are coming? What information does it furnish the bondholder as to the
                        payment of his bonds?</p>
                    <p>These are the questions in which the people take an interest now. The public
                        mind is agitated upon these issues. The people are tired of the cant which
                        has been drummed into their ears by the Radicals ever since the close of the
                        war. They ask for a fish, and the Radicals give them a serpent. They ask for
                        bread, and the Radicals give them a stone.</p>
                    <p>The Democratic party addresses itself to the solution of the difficult
                        problems presented by the present condition of the country. It leaves behind
                        it all <emph rend="italic">decided</emph> questions, and busies itself only
                        about those which concern the people now. It regards Slavery as dead,
                        Secession as dead, and dead forever, and it leaves the efforts of the
                        patriotic Democracy in behalf of the Union to the judgment of impartial
                        history. Had the Democratic party clung to the dead bodies of exploded
                        doctrines in the past, instead of meeting every issue as it arose, it would
                        indeed have been buried long since beyond the hope of resurrection. The
                        funeral orations pronounced at its grave, and the epitaphs written upon its
                        tombstone, might then <sic>have have</sic> had something of truth in them.
                        But it is because of its ability to adapt itself to the ever changing wants
                        and circumstances of <emph rend="italic">the people</emph> that it is, in
                        truth, the <emph rend="italic">Democratic</emph> party, and that it is now,
                        in reality, in full life and in most excellent trim for the contest.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Contrasts the issues addressed by the Democrats versus those addressed by
                    the Republicans. Claims the latter only talk about dead issues like slavery and
                    secession while the former discuss real issues like the economy and
                    reconstruction. Proclaims the Democratic party as alive and well and ready for
                    the election.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>For State Senator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duncan</ln>
                        <fn>Calvin M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McConaughy</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Editorial endorsing Calvin M. Duncan for State Senate. In the last
                    election, it appeared Duncan had won a close contest with the Republican
                    McConaughy. The Republican party challenged the results, however, and succeeded
                    in having a number of votes thrown out, giving McConaughy the office. Democrats
                    hope to gain revenge this year.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>For Congress</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kimmell</ln>
                        <fn>Francis M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cessna</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Editorial endorsing Francis M. Kimmell for Congress. Judge Kimmell will
                    challenge the Republican candidate, John Cessna.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Action! Action!! Action!!!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors urge the people of Franklin County to go to work for the
                    Democratic ticket. They instruct supporters to form township clubs to support
                    candidates. The paper argues that the "signs of the times" point to Democratic
                    victory.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Life Insurance and Banking</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article explaining the benefits and importance of Life Insurance.
                    Directions on how to purchase it are included.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Address of the Democratic State Committee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>DEMOCRATIC STATE COM. ROOMS,<lb/> 901 Arch street,<lb/> PHILADELPHIA, Aug.
                        24, 1868.</p>
                    <p>TO THE PEOPLE OF PENNSYLVANIA.</p>
                    <p>The Radicals re-produce the stale slanders of the past, and try to ignore the
                        grave questions of the present.</p>
                    <p>They prate of their loyalty and make it the excuse for their corruption,
                        their extravagance and their misrule.</p>
                    <p>They imagine that you have slept during three years of their iniquitous
                        misgovernment, and that you will forget that taxation oppresses you, that
                        your commerce languishes, and that your business is broken up.</p>
                    <p>They have proven themselves powerful to destroy and powerless to restore.</p>
                    <p>Their only policy is hate, and upon this they ask a new lease of power,
                        forgetful that a thinking and a practical people require them to answer:</p>
                    <p>Why is the national debt greater now than when Lee surrendered, and why does
                        it still increase?</p>
                    <p>What has become of the fifteen hundred millions of dollars they have wrung
                        from the comforts and necessities of the people since June, 1865?</p>
                    <p>Why are more than one hundred millions of dollars annually wasted on the
                        unreconstructed South, and why is it not made to yield us as much, to
                        relieve us from taxation, and aid in paying our debt?</p>
                    <p>Why is the white man made the inferior of the negro in every Southern State?</p>
                    <p>Why is one class of men totally exempt from taxation whilst all others groan
                        beneath the load they should aid in bearing?</p>
                    <p>Why shall the 5-20 bonds be paid in gold when by express terms of the
                        contract they were made payable in legal tender notes?</p>
                    <p>Why is the Constitution violated and the Union not restored, and why are our
                        resources wasted, and the people oppressed, the cost of living trebled and
                        our trade destroyed?</p>
                    <p>DEMOCRATS OF PENNSYLVANIA: AROUSE THE PEOPLE.</p>
                    <p>Organize a speaking canvass in every locality. Go into the strongholds of
                        Radicalism, and</p>
                    <p>TEACH THE PEOPLE.</p>
                    <p>Direct your arguments to reason and not to the passions. Confine them to the
                        living issues of the present and of the immediate future.</p>
                    <p>PURSUE THE ENEMY</p>
                    <p>Our grand old State moves steadily into her true place in the Democratic
                        line.</p>
                    <p>From every section comes the glad news of a defiant and united Democracy, and
                        of a torpid and dispirited foe.</p>
                    <p>Organization, energy and united effort will bring you a glorious victory.</p>
                    <p>AROUSE THE PEOPLE.<lb/> TEACH THE PEOPLE.<lb/> PURSUE THE ENEMY</p>
                    <p>By order of the Democratic State Committee, WM. A. WALLACE, <emph
                            rend="italic">Chairman.</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Accuses the Republicans of dodging the important issues. Addresses problems
                    like debt, reconstruction governments, taxes, etc. Tells Democrats what they can
                    do to get our the vote and bring about a Democratic triumph.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.09.02.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Gone to California</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Senseny</ln>
                        <fn>B. Rush</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. B. Rush Senseny has left Franklin for relocation in California.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Camp Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mentzer</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The African American congregation of the Wesleyan M. E. church plan to hold
                    a camp meeting on the grounds of Henry Mentzer near Fayetteville.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Seymour and Blair Club</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seymour</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blair</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gelwicks</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burkhart</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A Seymour and Blair Club meeting will be held in the third story of the
                    building occupied by the grocers Gelwicks and Burkhart.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>United Brethren Camp Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dickson</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The United Brethren Church's camp meeting began last week in Yaukey's Woods
                    near Funkstown. A large number of people assembled to hear the Sunday sermon
                    delivered by the Rev. John Dickson who was once pastor of Chambersburg's United
                    Brethren Church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Agricultural Fair</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The people of Franklin are beginning to take a great interest in the
                    ongoing preparations for the fair. The attractions will include an "immense
                    exhibition of stock and goods. The premium list embraces horses, cattle, sheep,
                    swine, poultry, and everything in the mechanical and industrial line."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Record Your Discharges</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strickler</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Register and Recorder Henry Strickler will record the honorable discharges
                    of Franklin's soldiers. The paper urges all veterans to see Mr. Strickler and
                    make their discharge part of the county record, since discharge papers can
                    easily be lost.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Extension of the Franklin Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Watts</ln>
                        <fn>Edward</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The project of extending the Franklin Railroad from Hagerstown to the
                    Chesapeake and Ohio Canal at Williamsport will soon be under contract. Those
                    wishing to bid for work may see Edward Watts, the chief engineer, at Hagerstown.
                    Grading and masonry are scheduled for completion by May.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Meeting at Waynesboro'</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kimmell</ln>
                        <fn>F. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stenger</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A Democratic meeting was held at Waynesboro' in which "no personal
                    vituperation was indulged in." The speakers "appealed to the reason, and not to
                    the passions of their hearers. The Conservative citizens of Washington township
                    are wide awake. The Radicals will steal no march on us there."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Congressional Conference</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewer</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kimmell</ln>
                        <fn>F. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Conferees from the counties making up the 16th Congressional District,
                    including Franklin, met in Bedford. George W. Brewer of Franklin was elected
                    President of the conference.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>A Joint Discussion</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamilton</ln>
                        <fn>Alex</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elden</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Besore</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Washabaugh</ln>
                        <fn>E. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Amberson</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blair</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Philips</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reid</ln>
                        <fn>W. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tritle</ln>
                        <fn>W. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoner</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mickley</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elden</ln>
                        <fn>Ezekiel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nevin</ln>
                        <fn>A. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rogers</ln>
                        <fn>Volney</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Long</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Russell</ln>
                        <fn>D. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bender</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Welsh</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coon</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cooper</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Douglas</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brackbill</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lecrone</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mullan</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fitz</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Besore</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lecron</ln>
                        <fn>Simon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>French</ln>
                        <fn>T. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Republicans and Democrats of Washington Township, Franklin County,
                    invite Congressional candidates John Cessna and F. M. Kimmell to hold a joint
                    discussion on the political issues of the contest. The following Republican
                    signed the appeal: Alex Hamilton, Joseph Elden, George Besore, E. W. Washabaugh,
                    W. S. Amberson, William Blair, John Philips, W. A. Reed, W. A. Tritle, Samuel P.
                    Stoner, Daniel Mickley, Ezekiel Elden, A. G. Nevin, Volney Rogers, J. C. Long.
                    The following Democrats signed: D. B. Russell, Joseph W. Miller, George Bender,
                    George W. Welsh, J. W. Coon, J. Cooper, Joseph Douglas, J. C. Brackbill, Samuel
                    Lecrone, Jacob J. Miller, John Mullan, Jacob Fitz, Henry Besore, Simon Lecron,
                    T. D. French.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Senatorial Conference</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>Maxwell</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Welsh</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duncan</ln>
                        <fn>Calvin M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Conferees of the 17th Senatorial District that includes Franklin met at
                    Graeffenberg Springs. Dr. Maxwell Kennedy of Franklin was chosen president. C.
                    M. Duncan received a majority of votes on the third ballot and was declared the
                    nominee. Resolutions were passed denouncing the unfairness of the last election
                    in which it appeared Duncan had won only to loose his seat after a challenge by
                    the Republican, McConaughy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Fayetteville Democratic Club</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Holland</ln>
                        <fn>A. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lochbaum</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>George</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shearman</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shively</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Colby</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Democrats of Green and Guilford met at the hotel of A. N. Holland in
                    Fayetteville to organize a Democratic club. John Lochbaum was chosen president.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Waynesboro' Democratic Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Douglas</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stiffy</ln>
                        <fn>J. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nicodemus</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McIntyre</ln>
                        <fn>C. J. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stenger</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kimmell</ln>
                        <fn>F. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>French</ln>
                        <fn>T. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>T. D. French, Secretary of the Waynesboro' Democratic Meeting, writes to
                    the Spirit to describe the recent gathering. French asserts that several hundred
                    citizens, at least four times as many as turned out for the Republican meeting,
                    assembled to hear the Democratic speakers. The Waynesboro' Brass Band provided
                    entertainment. The speakers denounced the "political and financial disorder of
                    the country" occasioned by Republican rule. Officials argued that "if we wished
                    to save the nation from bankruptcy and ruin--if we wished to have a free
                    country--that the Radical element now in power should be routed by the people at
                    the coming elections."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fahnestock</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Elizabeth L. Fahnestock died in Chambersburg on August 8th. She was 76
                    years old. "She was one of those who had her full share of earthly trials and
                    crosses, but she bore them as becomes the devoted Christian. She was a worthy
                    member of the German Reformed Church, and died a calm and peaceful death."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shaffer</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Margaret Shaffer died near Mercersburg on August 15th. She was 54
                    years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.09.02.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote>Advertisements and agricultural information appear on this page.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
