<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1868/pa.fr.vs.1868.04.22">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/30/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1868-04-22">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day norm="">22</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.04.22.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.04.22.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Impeachment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that the counsel for President Johnson has rested its
                    case. The editors refuse to speculate, but reiterate their conviction that
                    Johnson has done nothing to warrant conviction. The paper claims that the public
                    is much troubled and worried by the suspense.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Pompey Smash--X--His Mark</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper ridicules the African Americans who participated in the Virginia
                    Constitutional Convention. The editors assert that only the president and
                    secretary of the convention had to sign the document because "very few of the
                    niggers who helped to make that instrument were able to sign it, because very
                    few of them knew how to write their names."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Getting Scared</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper asserts that the Radicals fear the outcome of the impeachment
                    trial.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Sambo Puts Down his Heel</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Gen. Schofield can do pretty much as he pleases with the white men of
                        "District Number One," formerly known as Virginia, but he can't make headway
                        against the niggers. He says to Gov. Pierpoint, "go, and he goeth;" but when
                        he says the same thing to a nigger, the "American citizen of African
                        descent" puts down his heel and refuses to move a peg.</p>
                    <p>The General addressed the Virginia Convention on Friday last in opposition to
                        the "iron clad oath." He said his experience had taught him that it would be
                        impossible to carry on the State Government with such a test, and he thought
                        that as a party measure it would be fatal to the new Constitution. When he
                        left the Convention, an effort was made to reconsider the oath, but this was
                        refused by a vote of 32 against 26.</p>
                    <p>If this were a body of white men, we have no doubt that Gen. Schofield would
                        send a squad of soldiers into the hall in which it sits and disperse it for
                        venturing to disregard his wishes. But Sambo, like Dan Rice's "Sacred Cow,"
                        is altogether too sacred or too dangerous an animal to be trifled with. The
                        "Sacred Cow," it will be remembered, deeming her sacred character insulted
                        by something that Dan did or said on one occasion, elevated her tail and
                        lowered her horns, and then quickly reversing the position of both, tossed
                        Dan out of the ring, doing considerable damage to his "tights."--If Gen.
                        Schofield should undertake to treat this Convention as he treated the white
                        Governor, Sambo would <emph rend="italic">butt</emph> him out of "District
                        Number One" before the sun had time to go down on his wrath.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A racist article on General Schofield's supposed preferable treatment
                    towards blacks over whites in Virginia. Tells about the Virginia Convention,
                    Schofield's recommendation against an iron clad oath, and his inactivity after
                    the Convention passes an iron clad oath. Also tells the tale of Dan Rice's
                    "Sacred Cow" as a metaphor for the situation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.04.22.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Temperance Lecture</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pratt</ln>
                        <fn>N. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>N. W. Pratt of Philadelphia, Grand Worthy Patriarch of the Sons of
                    Temperance, will deliver a lecture at the Court House.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Bible Society</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>J. Agnew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Presbyterian Church will host the anniversary celebration of the
                    Franklin County Bible Society. The Rev. J. Agnew Crawford will give the address.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>A Rail Road Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wiestling</ln>
                        <fn>George P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A meeting will be held to discuss connecting Chambersburg and Waynesboro by
                    rail. The paper urges all businessmen to attend, and stresses the importance of
                    securing Chambersburg as the hub. "The section of country which it is proposed
                    to thus open for our benefit is exceedingly fertile and productive. It is the
                    richest portion of our country." Failure would risk cutting Chambersburg off
                    from the lower portion of Franklin County. Col. George P. Wiestling will address
                    the meeting.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Court Proceedings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Court is still in session, Judge Rowe presiding since Wednesday last, owing
                        to the absence of Judge King, who is expected to resume his seat on the
                        Bench to-day. The following cases have been disposed of since our last
                        report:</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Irving McDowell. Disturbing Singing School. Daniel Raffensberger
                        Prosecutor. Verdict Guilty--Motion for a new trial filed. Stenger and
                        Kimmell for Com; Sharpe for Def't.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. P. D. Ostrander. Passing counterfeit money. David Hoover Prosecutor.
                        Verdict Not Guilty. Stenger for Com; Duncan for Def't. The Dist. Att'y asked
                        the Court to recommit this Defendant for trial at the next term, upon
                        another bill found by the Grand Jury, charging him with having a large
                        quantity of counterfeit money in his possession with intent to pass the
                        same. In default of $600 bail, the Defendant was recommitted.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Isaac Wright. The indictment contains three counts--the first
                        charging Def't with setting fire to a Stable on the "Poor House Farm"--the
                        second with <emph rend="italic">attempting</emph> to set fire to said
                        Stable--the third with setting fire to a wood-pile on the same premises.
                        Verdict Not Guilty on all three counts, but Guilty of an <emph rend="italic"
                            >attempt</emph> to set fire to the wood pile. Sentenced 6 months to
                        county jail. Stenger for Com; Stewart for Def't.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Patrick Conner. Larceny of a suit of clothing, the property of
                        Charles Wright. Defendant pleaded guilty. Sentenced to 2 months imprisonment
                        in the county jail. Stenger for Com.; Sharpe and Brewer for Defendant.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. James Turpin. Surety of the Peace. Mary Beasly, Pros'x. Case
                        dismissed and the Prosecutrix sentenced to pay the costs. Stenger for Com.;
                        Eyster for Defendant.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. John Lane. Surety of the Peace. Jacob Myers Prosecutor. Case
                        dismissed and Defendant sentenced to pay costs. Stenger for Com.; McCauley
                        for Defendant.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. William Furley, Susannah Furley, Caroline Furley, and Virginia
                        Shatzer. Assault and Battery on Rebecca Grove, Daughter of Lydia Grove the
                        Prosecutrix. Verdict not guilty but Susannah Furley and Caroline Furley to
                        pay one-half the costs and the Prosecutrix the other half. Stenger for Com.;
                        Kimmell for Defendant.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs Allen Ward, Upton Ward and Jane Dunesson. Disturbing Singing School
                        at Pine Grove School House in Hamilton Township. Michael L. Diehl
                        Prosecutor. Verdict not guilty, but Upton Ward to pay one-half the costs,
                        and the Prosecutor the other half. Stenger and Sharpe for Com.; Kimmell for
                        Defendants.</p>
                    <p>Bills Ignored</p>
                    <p>Com. vs John Schlosser; Com. vs Francis Bowden; Com. vs Samuel C. Seylar;
                        Com. vs S. D. Kell; Com. vs William Weicht; Com. vs William Flory; Com. vs
                        Cornelius Vincent; Com. vs David Snyder.</p>
                    <p>Cases in which a <emph rend="italic">nolle prosequi</emph> was entered.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs Hanson Horner; Com. vs Michael Cressler; Com. vs George L. Maxwell;
                        Com. vs Jacob Spoonhour; Com. vs Peter Sewell and Elizabeth Sewell; Com. vs
                        Elias Brumbaugh and Samuel Berger; Com. vs David Smith; Com. vs John Bray;
                        Com. vs Thomas Attlesperger; Com. vs Henry Bartle; Com. vs Lewis Etter; Com.
                        vs Josephine Franklin; Com. vs Joseph Miller; Com. vs R. W. Ramsay; Com. vs
                        Caroline Stoops; Com. vs John Lane; Com. vs James R. Kaufman; Com. vs Jacob
                        Streely; Com. vs E. J. Wallace; Com. vs Caroline Jackson; Com. vs David
                        Bergenstock, et al.; Com. vs A. J. Sultzer; Com. vs Jacob Flory.</p>
                    <p>In the case of the Com. vs Samuel Ellis, the Defendant was discharged after
                        bill found, owing to the Prosecutor not appearing. Several cases were
                        continued to the August Sessions. The Court finished the criminal business
                        on Thursday at noon, and in the afternoon began the trial of civil causes.</p>
                    <p>Common Pleas, First Week.</p>
                    <p>Samuel Frederick's Executor vs. Chas. W. Eyster and Christian S. Eyster,
                        Executors of Jacob Oyster, dec'd., with notice to the widow, and Heirs and
                        Legatees of said deceased, and also notice to Chambersburg Woolen
                        Manufacturing Co., James L. Black, Christian Stouffer, terre tenants.--Scire
                        Facias Sur judgement No. 210, August Term 1867. Verdict for Plff. for
                        $1188.08 with int. from Nov. 9, 1867. Eyster and Bonbrake for Plff.;
                        Kimmell, Sharpe, Douglas and McCaulay for Defendants.</p>
                    <p>William McNulty, use of Benjamin Bert, vs James Anderson. Appeal by Def't
                        from judgement of J. Kauffman, Justices.--Judgement confessed by Def't in
                        favor of Plff. for $28 and costs. Kimmell for Plff.; M'Gowan for Deft.</p>
                    <p>Levi Young vs. Isaac Miller. Foreign Attachment. Judgement confessed by Deft.
                        in favor of Plff. for $35 and costs. Joseph Douglas for Plff.; Reily for
                        Deft.</p>
                    <p>James H. M'Gaughey vs Nancy J. Horner, Ext'rx of R. C. Horner. Summons in
                        assumpsit. Verdict for Plff. for $235. Kimmell for Plff.; Stenger for Deft.</p>
                    <p>L. B. Kurtz, now for the use of D. O. Gehr, vs Levi Sanders. Summons in
                        Assumpsit. Verdict for Plaintiff for $2756.25.</p>
                    <p>Rutledge, Perry &amp; Co. vs Wm. C. McNulty. Appeal by Deft. from
                        judgement of A. McElwain, Justice. Judgement confessed for $62.11. McGowan
                        for Plff.; Douglas for Defendant.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rowe</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDowell</ln>
                        <fn>Irving</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Raffensberger</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kimmell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharpe</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stenger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ostrander</ln>
                        <fn>P. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duncan</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stewart</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Conner</ln>
                        <fn>Patrick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewer</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turpin</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beasly</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lane</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCauley</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Furley</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Furley</ln>
                        <fn>Susannah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Furley</ln>
                        <fn>Caroline</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shatzer</ln>
                        <fn>Virginia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn>Lydia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ward</ln>
                        <fn>Allen</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ward</ln>
                        <fn>Upton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duncason</ln>
                        <fn>Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Diehl</ln>
                        <fn>Michael L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schlosser</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowden</ln>
                        <fn>Francis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seylar</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kell</ln>
                        <fn>S. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weicht</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flory</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vincent</ln>
                        <fn>Cornelius</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Horner</ln>
                        <fn>Hanson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cressler</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maxwell</ln>
                        <fn>George L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spoonhour</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sewell</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sewell</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Elias</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Berger</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bray</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Attlesperger</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bartle</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Etter</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Franklin</ln>
                        <fn>Josephine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ramsay</ln>
                        <fn>R. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoops</ln>
                        <fn>Caroline</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lane</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kaufman</ln>
                        <fn>James H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strealy</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wallace</ln>
                        <fn>E. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jackson</ln>
                        <fn>Caroline</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bergenstock</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sultzer</ln>
                        <fn>A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flory</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ellis</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Frederick</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>Charles W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>Christian S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Oyster</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Black</ln>
                        <fn>James L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stouffer</ln>
                        <fn>Christian</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bonbrake</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Douglas</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCaulay</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McNulty</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bert</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kauffman</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Gowan</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>Levi</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Gaughey</ln>
                        <fn>James H. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Horner</ln>
                        <fn>Nancy J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Horner</ln>
                        <fn>R. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kurtz</ln>
                        <fn>L. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gehr</ln>
                        <fn>D. O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sanders</ln>
                        <fn>Levi</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rutledge</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Perry</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McNulty</ln>
                        <fn>William C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McElwain</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Summary of county court proceedings.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bleske</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kendig</ln>
                        <fn>Mary A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>W. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Elder</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Bleske, of Cumberland County, and Miss Mary A. Kendig, of Orrstown,
                    were married on April 6th by Elder W. L. Jones.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barney</ln>
                        <fn>Nathaniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Nathaniel Barney died in Letterkenny on February 25th. He was 77 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.04.22.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote>Advertisements and agricultural advice appear on this page.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
