<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1868/pa.fr.vs.1868.01.29">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/14/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1868-01-29">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day norm="">29</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.01.29.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.01.29.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Negro Suffrage and Negro Equality</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Thaddeus Stevens has offered in the lower House of Congress a bill to
                        establish universal suffrage throughout the United States, and John Hickman
                        has offered in the lower House of our State Legislature an amendment to the
                        Constitution conferring the elective franchise upon every male freeman over
                        twenty-one years of age who is able to read the said Constitution. Thus we
                        find the leading Radical in the House of Representatives at Washington and
                        the leading Radical in the House of Representatives at Harrisburg both
                        moving to fasten Negro Suffrage upon Pennsylvania. One of them proposes to
                        do this by an act of the Congress of the United States--the other by an
                        amendment of the Constitution of the State.</p>
                    <p>After the verdict pronounced upon this question last fall, wherever the
                        People had an opportunity to express their sentiments upon it either
                        directly or indirectly, it might not unreasonably have been expected that
                        the Radicals would desist from making any further attempts to force the
                        Negro up to the political and social level of Whites. A few of the Radical
                        leaders, though none of the more conspicuous among them, have shown some
                        little disposition to back out of the Negro business; but the ruling spirits
                        of that party are determined to go on with it, and they will force their
                        weaker-kneed brethren to stand up to the work, whether they like it or not.</p>
                    <p>This question of Negro Suffrage will have to be settled by the People, and it
                        is for them to determine <emph rend="italic">how</emph> it shall be settled.
                        The triumph of the Radical party would settle it one way. The triumph of the
                        Democratic party would settle it another way. If Stevens' bill should be
                        rejected by Congress and Hickman's amendment meet the same fate in our State
                        Legislatures, this would not settle the question. It would merely postpone
                        it. Some Radicals in Congress, and some in our Legislature, who are really
                        in favor of conferring upon the Negro the right to vote, may possibly vote
                        against the Stevens bill or the Hickman amendment, (as the case may be) on
                        the ground of <emph rend="italic">expediency.</emph> They may not be
                        disposed, on the eve of a great Presidential election, to incur the heavy
                        risk of attempting to force the Negro down the unwilling throat of White
                        people. But let them carry the next President and the next Congress, and
                        just as surely as the sun rises in the East and sets in the West, so surely
                        will Stevens' bill or another of the same tenor be passed and approved. Or
                        let them carry the next Legislature of Pennsylvania, and with equal
                        certainty will the Hickman negro amendment to the Constitution be adopted by
                        that body.</p>
                    <p>Let no White man flatter himself that the adoption of a bill like Stevens' or
                        an amendment like Hickman's would confer upon the Negro the right to vote
                            <emph rend="italic">only.</emph> Along with this right will go the right
                        to sit on juries and to fill offices; and when the Negro becomes <emph
                            rend="italic">your equal</emph> in the jury box and in the halls of
                        legislation, where will he not be your equal? Accustom yourselves to
                        association with him on terms of equality in public and will not this
                        inevitably lead to association with him on terms of equality in private? And
                        would not such association, continued through a few generations, break down
                        the repugnance of one race to the other and bring about their intermarriage,
                        finally resulting in a nation of people as streaked and speckled as Jacob's
                        cattle, or as many-colored as Joseph's coat?</p>
                    <p>We find ourselves supported in these views by a very distinguished member of
                        the Republican party, who is also a prominent member of the Presbyterian
                        church--Hon. David Agnew, one of the Judges of the Supreme Court of
                        Pennsylvania. In delivering the opinion of the Court in the case of Mary E.
                        Miles, a colored woman, against the Philadelphia and Westchester Railroad
                        Company, in November last, speaking of the two races, Judge Agnew said:</p>
                    <p>Why the Creator made one black and the other white we know not; but the fact
                        is apparent, and the races distinct, each producing its own kind, and
                        following the peculiar law of its constitution. Conceding equality, with
                        natures as perfect and rights as sacred, yet God has made them dissimilar,
                        with those natural instincts and feelings which He always imparts to his
                        creatures when He intends that they shall not overstep the natural
                        boundaries He has assigned to them. The natural law which forbids their
                        intermarriage and that social amalgamation which leads to a corruption of
                        races, is as clearly divine as that which imparted to them different
                        natures. <emph rend="italic">The tendency of intimate social intermixture is
                            to amalgamation, contrary to the law of races.</emph> The separation of
                        the white and black races upon the surface of the globe is a fact equally
                        apparent. Why this is so, it is not necessary to speculate, but the fact of
                        a distribution of men by race and color is as visible in the providential
                        arrangement of the earth as that of heat and cold. The natural separation of
                        the races is therefore an undeniable fact, and social organizations which
                        lead to their amalgamation are repugnant to the law of nature. <emph
                            rend="italic">From social amalgamation it is but a step to illicit
                            intercourse, and but another to intermarriage.</emph></p>
                    <p>The Radicals constantly appeal to the soldiers for support. We appeal not
                        only to those who have been soldiers, but to all who are liable to do
                        military duty, to consider well the consequences before they aid in
                        conferring the right of suffrage upon the Negro. When the Negro votes he
                        will hold office. He will go to Congress. Congressmen have the appointment
                        of Cadets to the Military Academy at West Point, from which Officers for the
                        Army are furnished. Negro Congressmen would appoint Negro Cadets, and these
                        in due time would receive their commissions and be assigned to the command
                        of companies and regiments of White men. Then we should see Black Captains
                        of Cavalry galloping about, with White Orderlies riding behind them at
                        "regular" distance, and holding their horses when it pleased their Sable
                        Highnesses to dismount!</p>
                    <p>We are certain to be engaged in war at some future period, and we may be so
                        engaged before many years. There are questions pending between us and our
                        old enemy Great Britain which might lead to hostilities, before they can be
                        settled. Many of our own soldiers in the late war, and still more of our
                        voters who have not been soldiers, may be called upon to take the field at
                        the next summons to arms. <emph rend="italic">Could they endure to have
                            Negro Officers set over them?</emph> If not, let them remember that the
                        only way to insure themselves against such degradation is to aid in
                        defeating the Radical party.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Comes out against the proposed amendments by Pennsylvania Radicals to grant
                    blacks voting rights. Implicitly calls on voters to vote for Democrats to
                    prevent such measures from passing. Also plays on racial fears by claiming black
                    voting would lead to intermarriage and black officers commanding white regiments
                    in future wars.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Judge Black for President</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spirit endorses the idea of Judge Jeremiah S. Black running for
                    president.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Startling Declaration</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spirit takes as confirmation of their own fears the statement of a
                    Republican Senator that financial ruin is "staring the country in the face."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Losses of the Border Counties</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Winger</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Col. B. F. Winger, representative from Franklin County, introduced a bill
                    in the House of Representatives providing for payment for citizens who had
                    property destroyed during the war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Radical Repudiation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spirit denounces a Republican proposal to pay government obligations in
                    bonds bearing 3% interest in gold. The move, the paper asserts, would destroy
                    the public credit.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>General Garfield</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reprints a letter from James A. Garfield urging the Republican
                    Party to honor its obligations to African Americans. The Spirit retorts: "Any
                    white man who thinks he can't die happy without dying in bed with a negro, ought
                    to join the radical party at once, if he does not already belong to it. And any
                    white man who entertains a preference for company of his own color, living or
                    dying, ought to be a Democrat."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.01.29.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Meeting of the Democratic County Committee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamsher</ln>
                        <fn>B. Y.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Democratic County Committee will meet in the offices of the Valley
                    Spirit to select delegates to the State Convention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Lecture</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunter</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. J. Hunter of the Baptist Church will deliver a lecture at Repository
                    Hall to raise funds to benefit the poor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Fire</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foreman</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Frants's Mill on Conococheague Creek burned to the ground. Owner Frederick
                    Foreman sustained $15,000 in damage.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Missionary Anniversary</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carroll</ln>
                        <fn>D. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Magee</ln>
                        <fn>Irving</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. D. H. Carroll will preside at the meeting of the Missionary Society of
                    the M. E. Church. He will also join Rev. Irving Magee at the Sabbath School
                    Anniversary.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Lecture Last Week</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCauley</ln>
                        <fn>I. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Magee</ln>
                        <fn>Irving</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>I. H. McCauley filled in for Rev. Irving Magee and delivered a lecture at
                    the Court House on "The Moors of Spain." $57.47 were raised for the benefit of
                    the poor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Chambersburg Academy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A businessman is planning to complete construction of Chambersburg's old
                    Academy building, bringing a "first-class Academy" to the town.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Court Proceedings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoner</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Montgomery</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stenger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duncan</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharpe</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewer</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shank</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hollingsworth</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharpe</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kimmell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hollingsworth</ln>
                        <fn>Franklin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walter</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ackerman</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ackerman</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCauley</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hiesy</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wallach</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rowe</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Plowden</ln>
                        <fn>Calvin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Plowden</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dailey</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chambers</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Butler</ln>
                        <fn>Elias</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunter</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Douglass</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doyle</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lane</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rockwell</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Latus</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Plowden</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gehr</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gates</ln>
                        <fn>Eli</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reisher</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Renfrew</ln>
                        <fn>Lindsay</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>West</ln>
                        <fn>Simon P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hollingsworth</ln>
                        <fn>Franklin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rock</ln>
                        <fn>Albert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rock</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Meyers</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKinley</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brady</ln>
                        <fn>Alfred</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heminger</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heminger</ln>
                        <fn>Warren</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Williams</ln>
                        <fn>Jarret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Plowden</ln>
                        <fn>Wilson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Norris</ln>
                        <fn>Cain</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Singleton</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Verner</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tate</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jimason</ln>
                        <fn>Lazarus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lane</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newcomer</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Grath</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stirling</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyd</ln>
                        <fn>S. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sellers</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rupert</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Letoriere</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harper</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Court met and resolved several cases. William Stoner was found guilty
                    of assault and battery with intent to kill David Montgomery. He was sentenced to
                    6 years, 8 months in jail. Stenger and Duncan served for the prosecution; Sharpe
                    and Brewer for the defense. John Shank was found guilty of fornication and
                    bastardy on charge of Mary E. Hollingsworth. Sharpe and Stenger for prosecution;
                    Kimmell for defense. Franklin Hollingsworth was found guilty of perjury and
                    sentenced to 6 months in jail and payment of a $5 fine with costs. Stenger for
                    prosecution; Kimmell and Sharpe for defense. William Ackerman and Peter Ackerman
                    were found guilty of conspiracy and false pretense. Peter received one day in
                    jail and a one dollar fine plus costs. William received one year in jail and a
                    one dollar fine plus costs. Stenger and McCauley for prosecution; Kimmell and
                    Sharpe for defense. Jacob Hiesy acquitted of larceny on charges brought by
                    Joseph S. Wallach. Stenger and Duncan for prosecution; Rowe, Sharpe, and Kimmell
                    for defense. Daniel Daily charged $100 as surety of peace with Calvin Plowden.
                    Stenger, Sharpe, Duncan for prosecution; Chambers for defense. Elias Butler
                    found guilty of keeping a Disorderly House on charge of James Hunter. Butler
                    sentenced to 10 days in jail and a $10 fine plus costs. Stenger and Kimmell for
                    prosecution; Douglass for defense. James Hunter ordered to pay costs in surety
                    of peace case brought by Elias Butler. Stenger and Douglas for prosecution;
                    Kimmell for defense. William Doyle and James Lane found guilty of riot and
                    assault and battery on charges brought by Michael Fallon. Sentenced to 1 year, 2
                    months in jail and a $5 fine plus costs. Stenger and Stewart for prosecution,
                    Kimmell and Sharpe for defense. James Lane pleaded guilty to assault and battery
                    charges brought by Jacob Rockwell. Fined one dollar and costs. Stenger and
                    Stewart for prosecution; Kimmell and Sharpe for defense. Lewis Anderson plead
                    guilty to larceny of a silver watch. Brought by Michael Latus. Sentenced to 1
                    year, three months in jail, and a $1 fine plus costs. John Plowden found guilty
                    of assault. Prosecutor Daniel Daily. Sentenced to one dollar fine and costs.
                    Stenger and Chambers for prosecution; Stumbaugh, Gehr and Orr for defense.
                    Calvin Plowden found guilty of larceny of a pocket book. Prosecutor Eli Gates.
                    Sentenced to one year, one month in prison, $1 fine and costs. Stenger for
                    prosecution; Sharpe and Duncan for defense. The following cases entered nolle
                    prosequi: com vs William Ackerman; com vs Samuel Reisher; Com vs Lindsay
                    Renfrew; Com vs Simon P. West; Com vs Franklin Hollingsworth; com vs Albert
                    Rock; com vs John Rock; com vs Charles Meyers; com vs William H. McKinley; com
                    vs Alfred Brady; com vs John Heminger; com vs Warren Heminger; com vs Jarret
                    Williams. The following were ignored: com vs Wilson Plowden and Cain Norris; com
                    vs James Singleton; com vs John Verner; com vs Thomas Tate; com vs Lazarus
                    Jimason; com vs Robert Lane. The following licenses were not granted: Jacob
                    Newcomer; James Snyder. The following licenses were transferred: M'Grath and
                    Stirling to S. R. Boyd; Jacob Sellers to William Rupert; Charles Letoriere to
                    David Harper.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Franklin Railroad</head>
                <origin>N. Y. Evening Mail</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports plans to extend the Franklin Railroad from Hagerstown to the
                    Potomac, a move important in linking New York commerce to the South and West.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Open Wide the Doors</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In this letter to the editor, "Tax Payer" advocates opening Town Council
                    meetings to the general public. Chambersburg's citizens, he argues, "cheerfully
                    and promptly pay their taxes, with the expectation that their money will be put
                    to its best use, and feel at all times a deep interest in the progress of the
                    town."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fields</ln>
                        <fn>Russell</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guyer</ln>
                        <fn>Emma R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dyson</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Russell Fields and Miss Emma R. Guyer, both of Horse Valley, were married
                    on January 16th by the Rev. F. Dyson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Neff</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rinehart</ln>
                        <fn>Charlotte C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dyson</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel J. Neff and Miss Charlotte C. Rinehart were married on January 24 by
                    the Rev. F. Dyson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>Elvina</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Elvina Eyster, wife of Lewis B. Eyster, died in Chambersburg of consumption
                    on January 12th. She was 42 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Cook died on January 21st in Quincy Township. He was 82 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.01.29.04.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote>Advertisements and agricultural advice appear on this page.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
