<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1868/pa.fr.vs.1868.08.26">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/08/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1868-08-26">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="08">August</month>
            <day norm="">26</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.08.26.01" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>The Ball Still Rolling! More Desertions from the Radical Ranks!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article asserting that the Democrat's presidential ticket of Horatio
                    Seymour and Frank Blair is attracting large numbers of Republicans.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.08.26.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Let Us Alone</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The thief who has appropriated stolen property to his own use, thinks it a
                        terrible outrage that the law requires him to make restitution to the owner,
                        and in addition punishes him for his crime. All that he asks is, <emph
                            rend="italic">to be let alone</emph>.</p>
                    <p>The assassin who, through greed of gain, or long cherished hatred, has
                        plunged his dagger into the heart of his victim, deems it the height of
                        cruelty that outraged justice never leaves his track, but follows him with
                        relentless purpose to the bar, and from the bar to the gibbet. All he
                        desires is, <emph rend="italic">to be let alone</emph>. And so with
                        criminals of every kind and every grade. They always seek to awaken the
                        sympathies of the human heart for what they call their misfortunes. They
                        argue that their severe punishment will not give back to the owner his
                        stolen property--that their ignominious death upon the gallows can not
                        restore the murdered citizen to life--and that punishment never places the
                        wrong doers and the wronged in the same relative positions that they
                        occupied before the wrong was committed. The point which they wish to make
                        is that the wrong having been done--the evil having been accomplished, the
                        perpetrators of both <emph rend="italic">might as well be let alone</emph>.</p>
                    <p>Jefferson Davis, after he had become the head and front of the
                        rebellion--after eleven States had severed the ties that bound them in the
                        Union--after the Confederate flag had been "set upon the perilous ridge of
                        battle" as a sign round which the best and bravest of the South were to
                        rally for the purpose of maintaining their separate existence against the
                        authority of the National Government--thought that, inasmuch as all this had
                        been accomplished, and it might be a little inconvenient to disarrange
                        matters by bringing back the States to their former relations, it would be
                        far better <emph rend="italic">to let them alone</emph>.</p>
                    <p>Such is the logic which the Radical party has recently adopted in relation to
                        their iniquitous measures of reconstruction. They are appealing to the
                        intelligent people of the Union to vote for Grant and Colfax because the
                        mischief has been perpetrated by the Radical Congress, and it might cause a
                        little commotion to unsettle it--therefore they only ask, <emph
                            rend="italic">to be let alone</emph>. They are denouncing Seymour and
                        Blair and the whole Democratic party because they are proclaiming it as
                        their intention, on their accession to power, to undo, as far as possible,
                        the mischievous work which Radicalism has performed--because they intend to
                        repeal the unconstitutional acts with which Radical Congresses have
                        disgraced our statute books--because they intend to institute a thorough
                        investigation into the expenditure of the tremendous sums of money which
                        have been wrung from the tax-payers of the country--because they intend to
                        equalize taxation so that it shall fall in just proportions upon the rich
                        bondholder and the poor day-laborer--because they intend to strike the
                        manacles from the hands, and the shackles from the feet of <emph
                            rend="italic">white men</emph> all over the Union--because they intend
                        to battle, by all honorable and constitutional means, against the accursed
                        doctrines of negro suffrage and negro equality--because they intend to
                        assert the independence and maintain the rights of the Executive and
                        Judicial Departments of the Government against the encroachments of the
                        Legislative Department--because they intend to preserve to the nation its
                        Constitution, to the citizen his liberties, and to the white race the
                        administration of the government. They know well that if the Democracy
                        accomplish all this, their lease of power is ended. Place-hunters in their
                        ranks will be doomed to perpetual disappointment. Opportunities will be gone
                        for appropriating the people's money to the furtherance of partisan
                        interests. The leeches that have been sucking out the life-blood of the
                        nation will be torn from its body, and the wheels of government will begin
                        to run again in the old grooves of rigid economy and honest
                        conservatism.--Hence the cry which is going up so vigorously from loyal
                            throats--<emph rend="italic">let us alone</emph>.</p>
                    <p>"What!" they say, "repeal the reconstruction act! Why that would be
                        revolution! And is the nation ready for another civil war?" Why should there
                        be a revolution? Have laws never been repealed before?--Have unjust measures
                        never received the condemnation of the people before? Have parties never
                        been turned out of office before? Have cormorants who have fastened upon the
                        public treasury never before been forced to let go their hold?
                        Certainly.--And when all this has been done, has it been considered a just
                        cause for revolution? Certainly not. This cry of revolution has been started
                        for the purpose of frightening timid men into the support of the Radical
                        candidates. It is the last wail of despairing men who see inevitable defeat
                        staring them in the face.</p>
                    <p>Of one thing the Radicals may rest assured--this cry of revolution will
                        strike no terror to Democratic hearts. We propose to move upon the Radical
                        works. We intend to smash them into smithers. We intend to stop the leaks in
                        the Treasury, to unfetter the Judiciary, to restore to the President his
                        constitutional rights, to upset the carpet-bag State governments of the
                        South, to abolish the Freedmens Bureau entirely and forever, to equalize
                        taxation, to pay the bonds in greenbacks that are not expressly made payable
                        in gold, to put a stop to military establishments and their ruinous expenses
                        in time of peace, in short to govern the country according to the
                        Constitution. To the accomplishment of these objects, our candidates stand
                        pledged, and if the sovereign people of the United States so order in
                        November, it shall be done. If this be revolution, the Radicals may make the
                        most of it. The people want a change, and they have no disposition to
                        tolerate Radical iniquitous proceedings with their terrible consequences,
                        simply because that party might get excited over its defeat and feel like
                        originating another war. The Conservative hosts of the country are not
                        inclined to let the Radical party alone until they have given it a sound
                        drubbing at the polls, nor will they let their unconstitutional acts alone
                        until they have blotted them from our statute books.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Again bashes the Republican party and its policies while pumping up the
                    virtues of Democrats. Likens Republicans to criminals who say they should be let
                    off because you can't reverse the crime, gives some examples. Outlines what
                    Democrats will do if elected, namely end all Republican Reconstruction policies
                    and strictly follow the Constitution.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Military Clap-Trap</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The editors of the <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph> think that the only
                        qualification a man needs for the discharge of the duties of certain
                        offices, is the record of his <sic>enrolment</sic> among the soldiers of the
                        Union army. To enumerate--military experience is absolutely requisite to fit
                        men for the positions of Additional Law Judge, State Senator, Member of the
                        Assembly, Sheriff, District Attorney, Commissioner and County Auditor. It is
                        an impossibility for men to get along decently in those several official
                        positions without being versed in military tactics, to some little extent at
                        least.</p>
                    <p>To fit a man for Congress in Radical estimation, he must not necessarily have
                        bared his breast to the foe, but he must have been on both sides during the
                        war--he must be one of that class which had "<emph rend="italic">determined
                            to be on the winning side, even if that should be Jeff Davis'
                        side.</emph>" And after he was sharp enough to see which side was bound to
                        win, he must have suddenly become "trooly loil," screamed himself hoarse
                        denouncing Copperheads, and endeavored to show that the Democratic party had
                        left him, and not he the Democratic party.</p>
                    <p>The County Surveyor and Director of the Poor are the only officers, besides
                        who do not require military skill and experience, and hence, Kuhn and
                        Bowman, especially as they are both <emph rend="italic">experts</emph>, were
                        allowed to carry off these nominations.</p>
                    <p>Now, it matters not to these martial Editors how long a man may have served
                        in the army, or with what courage and distinction, or in what manner he may
                        have made his exit from the tented field. Just let it be ascertained that
                        his name is on the muster roll--either as an honorably discharged soldier or
                        as a deserter--and their hearts swell with gratitude to "the brave
                        defenders," and their voices become eloquent in pronouncing their panegyrics
                        over "the loyal millions," and their pens trace the paper with the rapidity
                        of lightning in writing their eulogiums of the "great and good men" who,
                        like themselves, have marched "into the mouth of cannon" and "into the jaws
                        of death," and snatched victory from the grasp of the enemy. They care
                        nothing for the soldier as a soldier. They only care for him as a <emph
                            rend="italic">voter</emph>. They imagine that he can be tickled, and
                        flattered, and cozened into the support of Radical men and measures by loud
                        professions of attachment to his interests and admiration of his
                        achievements.</p>
                    <p>They serve up for us a dish of refreshments in the shape of services rendered
                        and wounds received by very estimable gentlemen of this County. It is not
                        our purpose, or inclination, to disparage the military record of these men
                        or to underestimate their services. We have gallant men in our own ranks
                        whose records will compare favorably with those of the persons named. True,
                        the majority of the Democratic soldiers belonged to the rank and file, for
                        it required loyalty to Radicalism to gain promotion in the army. But their
                        scars are none the less honorable, or their services none the less valuable
                            <emph rend="italic">because they were privates, serving their country
                            for small pay</emph>. But we will not make invidious comparisons. Let
                        the soldier enjoy the honors which he has won, but let him take care not to
                        attempt to make himself a hero out of fictitious capital.</p>
                    <p>The editors of the <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph> however, must remain
                        content to shine with borrowed splendor. Neither of them has so
                        distinguished himself by honorable service as to commend him specially to
                        the gratitude of his countrymen. And yet we consider the clap-trap of last
                        week as only preparatory to some stuff of the same sort in praise of these
                        fighting Editors. It would not surprise us if the <emph rend="italic"
                            >Repository</emph> would soon regale us with some Munchausen stories in
                        relation to the military career of the Radical candidate for District
                        Attorney. Just on what particular picket line he stood as a mark for Rebel
                        sharpshooters, or in what unrecorded skirmish he performed astounding feats
                        of valor, or in what recorded battle he led the forlorn hope, we confess
                        that we have not yet been informed, but we are prepared for anything,
                        gentlemen. Hairbreadth escapes on the field of battle--hand to hand
                        encounters with the enemy--screaming bullets, gleaming sabres, thundering
                        cannon, ghastly wounds--captured by a barbarous foe--starved to death in the
                        dungeons of Libby Prison--murdered by Captain Wirz at Andersonville--escaped
                        only to be hunted down and torn to pieces by bloodhounds--again in the
                        custody of heartless traitors, and only rescued from their clutches by his
                        gallant partner, who alone, unaided, scaled the walls of his gloomy prison
                        and with his glittering sword hewed their way through thousands of
                        bloodthirsty guerrillas, among whom was Stenger shouting loudest of them
                        all--are there no such little incidents in the military career of Lieut.
                        Hays? If not, <emph rend="italic">make</emph> them. Our people are very
                        gullible. It would be no trouble to get them to swallow something like this.
                        They are passionate admirers of the kind of military stuff of which a
                        portion of your ticket is composed, and they will gulp down anything in
                        honor of your distinguished heroes.</p>
                    <p>The people of this country have ceased to be influenced by "fuss and
                        feathers." Their eyes are no longer dazzled by military splendors, however
                        bright. Whilst they hold in highest honor the heroic dead who laid down
                        their lives as so many sacrifices upon the altar of their country, and
                        whilst they appreciate fully the services of the living men who were in
                        reality the defenders of their country, they are not so blind as to be
                        unable to see the breakers towards which military men are now steering the
                        old ship of State. The Editors of the <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph>
                        forget that the war is over--that the people are not only saying, "let us
                        have peace," but inquiring why we have not had peace during the last three
                        years. They forget that the passions excited by the war have been supplanted
                        by ideas--that principles have taken the place of prejudices, and that no
                        man can hope for success politically, who, however distinguished his
                        military services, now seeks to subordinate the civil to the military power,
                        and bring the proud Anglo-Saxon race under the heel of the untutored
                        African. The question is, under which flag <emph rend="italic">now</emph>.
                        Bezonian? Black, or white, which?</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Finds fault with the Republicans who only nominate soldiers for office.
                    Does not criticize the soldiers themselves but hates the idea that only people
                    with military records should hold public office. Also accuses Republicans of
                    inventing war stories to make their candidates more appealing.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>An Oath-Bound Organization</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The members of the Grand Army of the Republic have always insisted to
                        outsiders that it was not a political organization. They make the same
                        statement to those whom they endeavor to entrap into the order. "The Post"
                        is the first degree. "Upon initiation, the novice is simply obligated to
                        vote for a soldier as against a civilian unless otherwise instructed by the
                        order, which means that in case a Radical civilian is a candidate for office
                        against a Democratic soldier, the order will instruct its members to vote
                        for the civilian." The horrid oaths which the members of the higher degrees
                        are obliged to take are not disclosed to the masses of "The Post." They are
                        required <emph rend="italic">to do military duty</emph> under the orders of
                        the Supreme Commander, and can thus be ignorantly used to carry out the
                        purposes of wicked, unpatriotic men.</p>
                    <p>We append the oath administered to those who take the highest degree, and
                        none lower than the grade of Brigadier General can take it. Our readers can
                        rest assured that this is no fiction.</p>
                    <p>"I, --------------, in the presence of Almighty God and upon his Holy
                        Evangely, do solemnly swear that I will bear true allegiance to the American
                        Nation, <emph rend="italic">that I will recognize all men without
                            distinction of race or color as my political equals, and that I will
                            oppose and stand ready, at all hazards, to assist in abrogating, or if
                            need be, in overturning, all laws, under whatever name, not in harmony
                            with this doctrine of equality; and I furthermore swear that I will, at
                            all times and under all circumstances, favor the concentration of power
                            in the Federal Government and oppose the idea of reserved rights
                            residing in the States, or in the people; and I furthermore swear that I
                            will resist, to the extent of my power, even if it should require the
                            sacrifice of life itself, the continuance of the States Rights theory in
                            the policy of the Government of the United States;</emph> and in token
                        of my sincerity, I hereby announce my willingness to submit to the extreme
                        penalty, even death, which this order may choose to inflict upon me, if at
                        any time I should prove unfaithful to this my oath of loyalty. So help me
                        God and keep me true."</p>
                    <p>What say you, honest men? Will you allow yourselves to be identified with
                        such an organization? Are you to be held as mere tools to be blindly used by
                        designing men for such unlawful purposes? Come out from among these foul
                        conspirators. Let no such nefarious plots, alongside of which that of
                        Cataline was respectable, be carried on with your apparent influence. Break
                        the fetters which bind you. Throw off your chains and be free men. Let Know
                        Nothingism and the Grand Army of the Republic stand as remembrancers of the
                        folly and impotence of misguided men who have sought to destroy the
                        allegiance of the American people to their written constitution by means of
                        secret meetings and revolting oaths. Come out from among them.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Attacks the Grand Army of the Republic as vile conspirators in league with
                    the Radicals. Quotes what the editor says is the oath of loyalty to the
                    organization, which includes pledges for racial equality and a powerful federal
                    government. Calls on its readers not to be fooled and see them for what they
                    are.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Who Went to the War?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that large numbers of Democrats fought for the Union, and criticizes
                    Republicans for claiming to hold a monopoly on loyalty.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>A Radical Lie Nailed</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Greencastle, Aug. 20, 1868.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Messrs. Editors</emph>:--No doubt you have heard the
                        Radical report that several of the most influential Democrats of Greencastle
                        have enlisted under the Radical banner of More Tax and Negro Equality. Let
                        me assure you that the report is false. Several boys--two, as far as I know,
                        neither has a vote this fall--have been persuaded into their Club with the
                        promise of a Cap, Cape and torch to carry during the procession, during the
                        campaign. Very influential Democrats indeed. I was told to-day by a
                        gentleman, that a Radical, under the influence of King Alcohol, reported in
                        his hearing in Mercersburg, that our respected and highly esteemed townsman,
                        John Goetz, had left the Democratic party, and joined in with the Radicals.
                        The Leopard is more likely to change his spots, or the Ethiopean his skin,
                        than for John Goetz to join that party. He is still the unflinching,
                        uncompromising Democrat he always has been. Let me assure you Messrs.
                        Editors, where one doubtful Democrat has joined in with the Radicals, two
                        from their ranks have seen the error of their ways and joined the Democratic
                        Club. Old Antrim has always held her own at the Ballot-Box, and will do her
                        duty at the polls this fall effectually, John Cessna's speech to the
                        contrary notwithstanding. Our motto is, the whole Democratic ticket, the
                        Constitution, and the Union one and inseparable. ANTRIM</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Goetz</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>"Antrim" writes to denounce Republican claims that many Democrats in Antrim
                    are defecting to their party.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.08.26.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Daily Prayer Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Daily prayer meetings continue at the Young Men's Christian Association
                    office.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Seymour and Blair Club</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyd</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewer</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wunderlich</ln>
                        <fn>D. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilmore</ln>
                        <fn>B. Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cormany</ln>
                        <fn>B. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamsher</ln>
                        <fn>B. Y.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Seymour and Blair club elected officers at their meeting at the hotel
                    of Samuel R. Boyd. According to the paper, the club is growing, and "will soon
                    be one of the largest and most effective in the State."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Our Agricultural Fair</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper praises preparations for the fair. The editors support
                    constructing ampitheatre seating for 1,000 to 1,500. A "Grand Tournament" with
                    jousting is planned.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Colored Troops Fought Nobly</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Our "colored men and brothers" turned out last Thursday to celebrate some
                        event, but what it was, neither we, nor they could tell. Eight men in ranks
                        in various styles of uniform, one Captain on foot with cavalry sabre, one
                        color bearer and two drummers made up the party. The rain came down in
                        torrents and drenched their clothing and quenched their ardor. Does the
                        Grand Army of the Republic furnish the muskets?</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Gives a brief and belittling description of a reunion of black soldiers in
                    the city.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>An Old Citizen Gone</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Watson</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf>Sr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James Watson, Sr., "one of our oldest and most highly respected citizens"
                    died at his Chambersburg residence after a short illness. "He had almost
                    attained the age of fourscore years. For twenty three years he has been a
                    resident of Chambersburg. He was known to our entire community and respected by
                    everybody."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Federal Hill Seminary</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foster</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper announces that the Federal Hill Seminary for Ladies will open on
                    September 2nd. The editors endorse the principal, Mr. Foster, and his planned
                    course of study. An omnibus will run to the school in bad weather.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Senatorial Conference</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>Maxwell</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Welsh</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duncan</ln>
                        <fn>C. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Democratic conferees from Franklin and Adams met to nominate a
                    candidate for State Senate. The race between Franklin's C. M. Duncan and Adams's
                    Joseph McDovitt was deadlocked at the end of the day and the meeting was forced
                    to adjourn.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Claims for Damages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article tabulating the damage claims for various southern Pennsylvania
                    counties. Franklin has submitted 460 claims totalling $237,325.74.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Open Air Concert</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Open Air Concert held on last Saturday evening under the auspices of the
                        Franklin County Monumental Association was a very <emph rend="italic"
                            >recherche</emph> affair. If anything was needed to make the handsome
                        grounds of Mr. Chambers present a rare and beautiful appearance, it was the
                        brilliant display of lights and transparencies so <sic>skilfully</sic> added
                        by the hands of the Managers of the Association. According to our estimates,
                        fully six hundred persons were present within the enclosure while as many
                        more gazed upon the bright panorama from without. We noticed conspicuous
                        among those having the affair in charge, and who labored assiduously to
                        supply patrons with the refreshments of the evening, a class of our ladies
                        whose faces have become familiar to us in connection with many such laudable
                        and patriotic enterprises during a number of years. Both of our bands were
                        present and seemed to vie with each other in discoursing some of their best
                        airs. The thought occurred to us amidst the cheer and gaiety of the evening,
                        that a monument was even then and there being erected to the memory of our
                        fallen braves. If not in cold marble, at least to the warm hearts of those
                        present. For what one, knowing the object for which the entertainment had
                        been provided, did not find his or her thoughts reverting to those who had
                        gone out from amongst us at their country's call, and who sleep in unknown
                        and unmarked graves on some one of the many battle fields of the war? While
                        inscribed marble may be needed to perpetuate the memory of these through
                        future generations, no more graceful tribute could be paid them by the
                        present, than the endeavors of those, who seek to provide against their
                        oblivion when their surviving comrades shall no longer live to rehearse the
                        story of their deeds. The zeal manifested by this association of our country
                        should entitle it to every encouragement. We favor the policy of raising
                        funds by such entertainments and can say for Saturday evening's Concert that
                        we went, through a desire to further the object in view, and came away
                        feeling ourselves more than repaid for the enjoyment afforded.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Talks about a concert given by the Franklin County Monumental Association
                    to raise funds for war monuments. Highly praises the concert and the motives for
                    it. Says monuments are needed to remember the fallen soldiers when surviving
                    veterans are no longer around to tell their stories.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bradley</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bradley</ln>
                        <fn>Horace</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bradley</ln>
                        <fn>Marian</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary Bradley, infant daughter of Horace and Marian Bradley, died in
                    Chambersburg on August 8th. She was 5 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.08.26.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote>Advertisements and agricultural advice appear on this page.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
