<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1868/pa.fr.vs.1868.09.30">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/12/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1868-09-30">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day norm="">30</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.09.30.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.09.30.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Negro and the Riots</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The recent riots in Georgia and Louisiana are simply the natural results of
                        the policy which the Radical party has adopted in the South. The election in
                        the Northern States last year convinced Congress that Radicalism was waning
                        in the North, and it consequently resolved to better its chances at the
                        Presidential election by a system of legislation which would give it the
                        electoral vote of the South. To do this, it became necessary to put the
                        ballot in the hands of the Southern negro. By an assumption of power not
                        contemplated by the Constitution, Congress undertook to regulate the right
                        of suffrage in the States that had attempted to secede. Men were sent down
                        from the North whose business it was to persuade the negro that his only
                        friends are to be found in the ranks of the Radical party. These men went to
                        work diligently and were glad to find that the job was an easy one. They
                        inflamed the passion of the blacks. They stimulated their hatred of the
                        whites. They tempted them with the promise of money land, and offices. When
                        the blacks were reported to be properly educated to carry out the designs of
                        the Radicals, Congress invested them with the right of suffrage. They were
                        led up to the polls and voted. Enormous frauds were perpetrated.
                        Double-breasted ballot boxes were manufactured. By means of most flagrant
                        outrages, conservative men were driven from the polls and the elections were
                        carried by the negroes. Once clothed with the right to vote, the negroes
                        aspired to hold office. They became candidates for the legislature and were
                        elected. In Louisiana, a negro was elected Lieutenant Governor and, by
                        virtue of his office, became Speaker of the Senate. They soon stepped into
                        the jury box. In an incredibly short time, not only was the machinery of the
                        State governments under their control, but they were sitting also as judges
                        to try the cases of the whites.</p>
                    <p>All this naturally gave rise to hard feelings between whites and blacks. Men
                        of intelligence, refinement and wealth saw the protection of the law taken
                        away from them, and found themselves at the mercy of ignorant, unscrupulous
                        negroes. The more they protested against this condition of affairs, the
                        harder did the negroes clamor for power. Not satisfied with the exercise of
                        the power granted by Congress, they are now seeking to inaugurate and
                        establish a reign of terror in the south by constantly carrying fire arms
                        and using them whenever they feel so inclined. They respect neither sex nor
                        age. They fire indiscriminately upon men, women and children. The fearful
                        riots, chronicled recently in the papers, were caused by negroes undertaking
                        to hold political meetings with arms in their hands.</p>
                    <p>Men of Pennsylvania! We appeal to you. What security would you feel for your
                        lives, or your property, if bands of armed negroes were allowed to assemble
                        night after night in your public places, there to be harangued by men whose
                        object would be to excite and exhort them to deadly hatred of you, and your
                        wives, and your children? Think of it seriously. The Congress that has
                        inaugurated this state of affairs in the South may, <sic>afterwhile</sic>,
                        undertake to do the same thing in the North. "Do unto others as you would
                        have others do to you." Save the white men of the South from anarchy,
                        bloodshed, and desolation. Give to the negro ample protection as to his
                        rights of life, liberty and property, but let white men rule America.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Blames recent riots in the South on Radical policies which allow blacks to
                    vote and hold office. Claims blacks carry weapons and go around shooting whites
                    at will. Urges voters to overturn this state of affairs and bring political
                    control back to whites.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Col. M'Clure On Hand With Money</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper announces that Col. McClure, the man "who has done more to
                    debauch the politics of Pennsylvania than any other," has been named to handle
                    disbursement of $115,000 in campaign funds to Republican candidates in Franklin
                    County. The paper calls it a "corruption fund."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Radical Mass Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Our Radical friends held their mass meeting in this Borough last Friday. We
                        chronicle the fact inasmuch as it will, doubtless, be an item of news to
                        many portions of the county from which nobody was present. Extensive
                        preparations were made for a grand demonstration. Numerous Marshals were
                        appointed. The houses of our Radical citizens were tastefully decorated.
                        There were flags and banners in abundance. The <emph rend="italic"
                            >Repository</emph> and <emph rend="italic">Country Merchant</emph>
                        printing offices, for days beforehand, were engaged in printing mottoes upon
                        muslin to give expression to the sharp, spicy and witty thoughts that were
                        floating through Radical brains. The leaders, and enthusiastic young men
                        known as the "Boys in Blue," busied themselves, night and day, in arranging
                        everything "in apple-pie order," so as to fill the minds of their country
                        friends with admiration and wonder. Our Radical lady friends brought out
                        their whitest and most handsomely embroidered handkerchiefs to wave their
                        welcome to the thousands who were expected to throng our town. The Bands
                        were engaged. The New Fair Ground was procured to accommodate the immense
                        crowd that was to hang upon the lips of the speakers. A special train of
                        seven cars was sent up to Greencastle to bring down as many hundreds of
                        people from Antrim township</p>
                    <p>Five new carriages, each drawn by two beautiful horses, were driven to the
                        depot to receive the distinguished speakers and their accompanying friends.
                        But alas for the apathy of the Radical rank and file. For days before, rain
                        had fallen. The morning was cloudy. There was not a Radical farmer in the
                        county who worked on that day, because the ground was too wet for him to do
                        any effective work. But the trouble was that there was no disposition to
                        come.</p>
                    <p>The train came down from Hagerstown and Greencastle carrying about one
                        hundred men. They did not fill <emph rend="italic">two</emph> of the <emph
                            rend="italic">seven</emph> cars that were sent up.</p>
                    <p>When the speakers arrived, they and the committee entered one carriage, a few
                        of our prominent citizens filled another, and the other three drove up from
                        the depot <emph rend="italic">empty</emph>. The band discoursed their
                        sweetest music. The Marshals rode gaily, with their beautiful sashes
                        streaming in the air, in search of delegations that ought to have come, but
                        did not. At last the grand procession was formed and marched down Main
                        Street. It numbered <emph rend="italic">one hundred and seven horsemen, and
                            forty-eight wagons, buggies and other machines</emph>. Not more than
                        four hundred voters were in the whole procession. Candidates looked
                        blue--the leaders hung their heads--the ladies looked upon the small show
                        with contempt. Everybody felt that it was a huge disgraceful fizzle.</p>
                    <p>Going to the Fair Ground was out of the question--the crowd was too small. A
                        stand was hurriedly erected in front of the Court House, and at two o'clock,
                        Senator Wilson was introduced to the mixed crowd of negroes and whites,
                        after some scalawag hanger on had sung a song. For two hours, Senator Wilson
                        harangued his audience giving him his strongest and most savory dish of
                        negro suffrage and negro equality.</p>
                    <p>Hon. Ed. M'Pherson followed him and said nothing, except to make the
                        ridiculous prediction that the Radicals in Adams county will elect part of
                        their County Ticket. The crowd then dispersed, and went sadly to their
                        homes, evidently wondering how the Radical ticket is to be elected in
                        Franklin County if the Grant and Colfax men can not make a better turn-out
                        than this was.</p>
                    <p>In the evening a meeting was held in Repository Hall, at which a speech was
                        made by a gentleman named Burleigh and where John Cesson indulged in some
                        more of his gasconade. It gives us pleasure to say that our recent lessons
                        seem to have taught the little fellow some manners and to have lashed him
                        into a small exhibition of decency. The "Boys in Blue" figured during the
                        day but <emph rend="italic">the Grant and Colfax Club was not
                        discernible</emph>. What has become of it?</p>
                    <p>On Saturday morning, the same attention was not shown the speakers as that
                        which marked their reception. Senator Wilson was allowed to go to the depot
                        to get on the five o'clock train, carrying his own carpet bag, accompanied
                        by a single Radical, <emph rend="italic">pay for his own ticket</emph>, and
                        leave with feelings as despondent as those which dwelt in the breasts of the
                        sleeping Radicals whom he left behind him.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes a Republican gathering in the worst possible terms. Says the
                    preparations were excellent but the turnout was poor and everyone was
                    despondent. Tries to put the worst spin on the occasion to promote the idea that
                    the Radicals can never win.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>"Mint-Stick" Geary</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>During the recent visit of our Governor to the peach and pear trees in the
                        vicinity of Mercersburg, he tried to make "a ten strike" among the Germans
                        of that section. He went into a candy shop and bought twenty-five cents
                        worth of "mint-sticks." Said he to the man behind the counter, "you are a
                        German, I believe." "Yes sir," was the reply. "Well," said the Governor,
                        'the loyal Germans of the Keystone State are coming up nobly to the support
                        of Grant, and I should like to see you do it also. And my dear fellow,"
                        tapping him familiarly on the shoulder, "if you do it, <emph rend="italic">I
                            will remember you</emph>." Citizens of Franklin county, think of the
                        Governor of our grand old commonwealth descending to such a contemptible
                        little act as this. The honest German, it gives us pleasure to say, <emph
                            rend="italic">saw through</emph> the little arrangement and is laboring
                        with renewed zeal for Seymour and Blair.</p>
                    <p>We suspect that a certain very astute politician of that Borough was anxious
                        to secure the influence of that very German, and, having gauged Geary and
                        found him sufficiently small for his purpose, sent him on this errand, which
                        no amount of money would have induced him to undertake himself. We hope that
                        the Governor enjoyed his "mintsticks."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes a scene where Governor Geary buys mint sticks from a German candy
                    store owner and tries to influence him to vote Republican. Mocks the move, says
                    the German is working for the Democrats, and accuses Geary of being a tool for
                    an unnamed unscrupulous local Radical politician.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Our Redemption Draweth Nigh</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We observed the above inscription on a banner carried in the Radical
                        procession on Friday last. Did some waggish "Copperhead" climb up on a wagon
                        and raise that banner, or was it carried by some repentant Radical who reads
                        aright the signs of the times and looks forward to the election of Seymour
                        and Blair for redemption from the evils with which Radical rule has
                        afflicted this nation?</p>
                    <p>We are glad to believe that "our redemption draweth nigh." For eight years we
                        have suffered from Radical tyranny, corruption, extravagance and misrule,
                        and it is not possible for the country to endure four years more of grinding
                        taxation and lavish expenditure. If the time of our redemption is not very
                        near at hand, poor people will starve and our paper money will be worth
                        nothing. The election of Seymour will redeem the country and put gold and
                        silver once more in circulation.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Saw the above quotation on a Republican banner, spins it into a cry for
                    Democrats to elect Seymour and end Republican rule.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Our "Loil" Governor</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>That beautiful specimen of humanity who disgraces the Gubernatorial Chair of
                        the Keystone State delivered a violent partisan harangue at Mercersburg a
                        short time ago. He made a flying visit to that borough under the pretence of
                        wishing to ascertain the condition of the grounds and fruit trees belonging
                        to the Association of which Mr. Tobias Martin is the Superintendent. In the
                        evening he addressed his fellow citizens from the residence of Hon. James O.
                        Carson. He indulged in the grossest misstatements, and the most incendiary
                        and revolutionary appeals to the passions of his hearers. He predicted
                        another war in case Seymour and Blair are elected. He expressed his
                        willingness to lead, with match in hand, the loyal Pennsylvanians through
                        the city of Baltimore, and if they could not pass through it, he declared
                        that they would pass <emph rend="italic">over</emph> it.</p>
                    <p>He said it was true that in 1863 Governor Seymour did send thirteen regiments
                        into Pennsylvania, <emph rend="italic">but it was with the understanding and
                            expectation that Lee would whip the Union Army, and that, then, these
                            thirteen regiments were to swell the Rebel leader's forces and march
                            triumphantly upon Baltimore and Washington</emph>. To what degree of
                        infamy would not this man descend who could thus willfully and deliberately,
                        by a statement which he knew to be an unmitigated falsehood, seek to cast
                        odium upon the man to whom Lincoln, Stanton and Curtin each expressed his
                        warmest thanks.</p>
                    <p>Thaddeus Stevens pronounced Geary a "lamentable failure," and the people of
                        this State have long since been thoroughly disgusted with his inordinate
                        vanity and intolerable egotism, but we doubt whether his bitterest personal
                        enemy ever charged him with such moral turpitude as this reckless
                        declaration discloses.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Viciously attacks Governor Geary for making incendiary remarks about
                    Seymour. Declares that even Radicals call Geary "a failure" and that he should
                    not remain governor much longer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Lord How This World is Given to Lying</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph> gives evidence of great alarm about
                        the result of the election in this county. It has taken to downright lying
                        in dead earnest. Its notice of the Democratic meeting at Greencastle
                        contains seven sentences and seven falsehoods. Each sentence is a falsehood.
                        Let every man who can lay his hand on a copy of the paper take it up and
                        read the article we allude to, and see whether he will not lay it down
                        convinced that every sentence in it is a deliberate falsehood.</p>
                    <p>The <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph> could not even notice the accident
                        that happened to the train returning from the Democratic meeting at
                        Greencastle, without indulging in a deliberate falsehood, the eighth it has
                        told in connection with this one meeting. It will be remembered the train
                        ran over some horses, killing one and badly injuring one or two others. The
                            <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph> says:</p>
                    <p>Previous to the starting of the train, one of the joyful Cops amputated the
                        head of the dead horse and carried it through the cars, to the great
                        enjoyment of his comrades.</p>
                    <p>The head of the horse that was killed outright was amputated by the engine
                        and not by any person on the train. One foolish fellow, who was in the same
                        condition that some of our Radical friends found themselves in before they
                        got entirely through with their meeting in this place on Friday last, lifted
                        the head of the horse up on the platform, but was not permitted to carry it
                        "through the cars," if such was his intention. His offence against good
                        behaviour was very trifling compared with the <emph rend="italic"
                            >Repository's</emph> offence against truth and fairness.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Takes severe offense at a Republican paper's reporting of a Democratic
                    meeting at Greencastle. Claims the entire article was a lie through and through,
                    and gives a particularly gory example.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Attacks John Cessna for sitting with 19 African Americans at the Chicago
                    Convention, and asserts that if elected he would vote to allow blacks the right
                    to sit in Congress.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Greencastle Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>GREENCASTLE, Sept. 25.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Messrs. Editors:</emph>--As there was no account
                        published in this week's <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> of the grand
                        Democratic meeting held in Greencastle on Saturday, the 19th inst., we will
                        send you a short sketch of it for your next issue.</p>
                    <p>This meeting, it is conceded on all sides, was the largest ever convened for
                        any political purposes in this section of the county, it having numbered
                        perhaps, not less than fifteen hundred, including about one hundred and
                        fifty ladies, whose presence was very acceptable, and undoubtedly a check to
                        many useless exhibitions by Young Americans, for the order was quite good
                        considering the vast multitude in attendance.--Chambersburg sent about three
                        hundred men, and the surrounding villages and neighborhoods were represented
                        in full.--There were nearly as many torch lights and transparencies as men,
                        and these, as they danced above the heads of the procession moving along
                        through the various streets, were beautiful to look upon. The banners
                        present "showed which way the wind blowed," as the bondholder and Sambo
                        received about an equal share of attention from them, and formed the
                        principal texts from which the almost matchless eloquence and power of
                        argument displayed by the speakers, Messrs. Sharpe, Stenger and Brewer, laid
                        bare to the bone the sophistries of modern Radicalism.</p>
                    <p>The Radical meeting in Waynesboro' on the same evening drew from Greencastle
                        and vicinity nearly every thing of that color, so that ours was almost
                        entirely composed of Democrats, and but for the barbarous, utterly
                        inexcusable shooting that occurred on the pike just below Shady Grove, by
                        which an innocent and worthy young man, returning from meeting, was brutally
                        murdered, the pleasure, satisfaction and benefit afforded to all present by
                        the occasion would have been lasting and complete.<lb/> SELFPROTECTION.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharpe</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stenger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewer</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Prints a contributory article from an anonymous source describing a
                    Democratic meeting held the week before. Might be included here to counter any
                    Republican bashing of the rally and contrast it with the low attendance of
                    Republican rallies.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Letter from Louisiana</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>BASTROP, MOREHOUSE PARISH, LA.<lb/> Sept. 16, 1868.</p>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">Messrs. J.M. Cooper &amp; Co:--Gentlemen:</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>Having lately seen a copy of the "Valley Spirit," sent me by a friend, I was
                        reminded by it of the home of my childhood. In almost every column, I see
                        the names of persons and places which were familiar to me in my youth and
                        which I have long desired to see again, and especially I desired this summer
                        to re-visit my friends and acquaintances in Franklin Co., and speak to those
                        who were my school mates, and to those who were my pupils, on the subject of
                        the bad affects of the radical measures of reconstruction of the South--of
                        the wickedness, selfishness and cupidity of the radical emissaries sent down
                        here, and of the wrongs that they inflict on us. But the poverty in which
                        the war has left me, prevents me from accomplishing an object which I have
                        long contemplated. I avail myself therefore of your excellent paper, to give
                        a true statement of the facts as regards the people of the South and as to
                        the radical policy of reconstruction.</p>
                    <p>I desire to address those who knew me, or who can be certified as to who and
                        what I am--to those who were my school mates at the school house near
                        Bossarts' Mill. The Pattons--the Weists--the Bolmers, Eastons, Keefers,
                        Shearers, Titewilers and Longneckers, and to William Bossart, my cousin at
                        Bossart's Mill. I address myself also to my friends and companions and
                        acquaintances in Path Valley and in Amberson's Valley. To Elias and George
                        Shearer--to the Alexanders, the Campbells, the Gambles, the Clippingers, the
                        Flickingers, the Bears, the Hammonds, the Pipers, the Harveys, the Kaseys,
                        Filsons, M'Curdys, and the Wolfs, the Varners, the Culbertson's and M'Vittys
                        and M'Gees of Amberson's Valley, and all whom it may concern. It is now
                        almost if not quite a half a century since some of the above parties knew
                        me, and as many of them have no doubt passed away, I refer to William
                        Bossart, at Bossarts' Mill and to Elias Shearer, in Path Valley.</p>
                    <p>I will not presume to inform you as to the facts which you must know as well,
                        if not better, than myself. There never was such a contrast in the
                        characters and merits of two candidates for the Presidency as that between
                        Grant and Seymour. Even the radicals admit that Seymour is a gentleman of
                        irreproachable manners, habits and character, while Grant is admitted to be
                        a man of vulgar tastes and habits, being notoriously a sot and a sensualist.
                        Seymour is a civilian by education, habits and pursuits, and therefore
                        eminently fitted for the office of President of the United States: Grant, on
                        the other hand, is a mere military character with no fitness whatever for
                        any civil office. Seymour wished under all circumstances to preserve the
                        constitution which is the real life of the nation. Grant is said at the
                        commencement of the war, to have tendered his services to the Confederate
                        States. Seymour is a man of honor and truth; Grant stands contradicted by
                        Johnson and his cabinet in a question of veracity and fact. Seymour is the
                        candidate because of his preeminent fitness for the office. Grant was
                        selected on account of his supposed availability. Seymour is a positive man;
                        Grant is a negative man politically. Seymour is explicit and out-spoken as
                        to his political principles. Grant's great talent is silence. Seymour speaks
                        and acts for himself. Grant must have Sherman as a guardian to speak for him
                        in political affairs. In Seymour's case, "the office seeks the man," but in
                        Grant's case, the "man seeks the office." It is a very strong presumption
                        therefore that Seymour will be elected; for as the election depends mainly
                        on the vote of the North, it is hard to conceive it possible that an
                        enlightened and christian people will prefer a man for the highest office in
                        the nation who is every way so unfit, to one so well qualified for the
                        station. But I proposed to write concerning what is under my own
                        observation--the effects of the radical policy of reconstruction.</p>
                    <p>After the close of the war the South needed no political reconstruction,
                        except to legalize the emancipation of the slaves by the vote of the people.
                        This was done by the vote of the South. It is true President Johnson
                        demanded this as a condition precedent to our restoration to the Union; but
                        the South freely did it, as much from a conviction of the future inutility
                        of slavery under the circumstances as to comply with the Executive policy.
                        Therefore the only reconstruction needed in the South was, the rebuilding of
                        our homes which had been given to the flames, and the repairing of our
                        desolated plantations, where fences were dilapidated, or burnt, and the
                        fields overgrown by weeds and brambles, and had we been let alone, we might
                        in a great measure by this time have reconstructed our dwellings and
                        repaired our farms; but the negroes (who are our only laborers) have been
                        rendered idle or worth but little for plantation service, by being flattered
                        with false ideas of their liberty, and by the demoralizing and mischievous
                        influence of the mongrel party agents. Had we been let alone we would
                        probably, by this time, have had a tide of emigration from the North, and
                        from Europe, to replenish our thinned laboring population. As it is,
                        thousands of the best citizens of the South have left their country in
                        despair and disgust, and gone to Brazil, Honduras, California, or the
                        northwest to escape the bad effects of the reconstruction policy.</p>
                    <p>Had not the natural laziness and improvidence of the negro race, and their
                        antagonism to the white people, been stirred up and cherished by political
                        agents we would have had capital seeking investment here where improved
                        land, the richest in the world, finds no purchasers at one dollar and
                        twenty-five cents per acre. <sic>Haviving</sic> prosperity would have
                        enabled us by this time to help pay the national taxes, whereas an increased
                        burden now falls on the industry of the north. Had we been let alone the
                        negroes would be self supporting, and the one hundred millions of dollars
                        expended annually to support the freedmen's bureau, and military government
                        would have been saved to the taxpayers.</p>
                    <p>Unity of feeling and interest (which is the only true and safe bond of union)
                        would have been pretty well restored; and the bitterness of conquest would
                        have been compensated in the prospective power and glory of the government
                        created by the wisdom and blood of our fathers.</p>
                    <p>Why then were the reconstruction laws adopted? It was not necessary, in order
                        to put down the "so called" slave aristocracy, because, the emancipation of
                        the slaves by their own vote, effectually prevented any future "slave
                        aristocracy."</p>
                    <p>It was not necessary to prevent another attempt at secession and war. No sane
                        man could think so, after the leaders of the South were paroled prisoners or
                        in exile, all of whom counseled the South to submit to the United States
                        Government,--after nearly all the fighting men were either <sic>kiled</sic>,
                        wounded, or tired of the war--after all the wealth and resources of the
                        South were exhausted--after so disastrous a failure under the most favorable
                        circumstances--after voluntarily abandoning slavery (which was the occasion
                        of the war) it seems to be a moral impossibility for any intelligent man to
                        believe there existed the remotest probability of a renewal of secession or
                        of war.</p>
                    <p>Reconstruction was not necessary in order to protect the negroes. The
                        meddling interference of bureau and other agents, by inspiring the negroes
                        with ideas which foster laziness, and arrogance among them has been the
                        cause of the death or punishment of scores of negroes to one whose life or
                        rights have been vindicated by such agents. Most assuredly the pecuniary
                        rights of the negroes have been more violated by the government agents, than
                        any other class of men. In many instances when pretending to settle disputes
                        between the planter and the negro, the bureau agent would assume control of
                        the crop in dispute and swindle the negro out of his share of it wholly or
                        in part. The truth is, the reconstruction laws are in violation of the
                        policy avowed by the republicans during the war, and in violation of the
                        rights and interests not only of the Southern people (including the
                        negroes), but in violation of the interests of the whole north; and were an
                        afterthought of vindictive unprincipled politicians (Stevens, Sumner,
                        Beecher, &amp;c.) to <emph rend="italic">keep the South out of the
                            Union:</emph> because they saw that the South would be a large element
                        of political power against them, therefore they devised the reconstruction
                        laws as a means of keeping the South out of the Union (<emph rend="italic"
                            >not to restore them to it</emph>) unless they could, by excluding the
                        intelligent influential citizens from voting and making the negroes voters,
                        and exciting antipathy between the races, manage to keep their party in
                        power.<lb/> JACOB B MATTHEWS.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Another letter from one Jacob Matthews of Louisiana, formerly a
                    Pennsylvania native, lamenting the burdens of the South. Explains why Seymour is
                    better than Grant, and then delves into a detailed critique of reconstruction
                    policies and shows how they are detrimental to everyone in the South and the
                    North. Pays particular attention to policies concerning African Americans and
                    the economy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>07</column>
                <head>Kimmell vs. Cessna</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">Little Johnny laid out Flat!--He blows and squeals and
                            snorts, but can't argue!--He gets mad and deals in abuse!--Poor Little
                            Turncoat John!</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>On Friday and Saturday last, Judge Kimmell and John Cessna met at Schelisburg
                        and Bloody Run, to discuss the questions involved in the Platforms of the
                        two political parties. Judge Kimmell did discuss those issues and discussed
                        them with great ability. J. Cessna did <emph rend="italic">not</emph>
                        discuss them. He went off at a tangent and ranted about the late war, in
                        which he took no part, except in speaking at Democratic meetings. He did not
                        dare to touch the financial questions and evaded the greater part of the
                        "Reconstruction" issue. His speeches were the "old two-and-six pence" over
                        again, which he repeated during the last three years. Judge Kimmell fairly
                        flayed him alive, and at Bloody Run the little fellow could stand it no
                        longer. He got mad. He reared, and pitched, and picked his lips and pulled
                        at the seat of his unmentionables, until his own friends became disgusted
                        with him. A pretty specimen he would be to send to Congress! We would like
                        it if he and Judge Kimmell could discuss jointly before the people of every
                        township in this Congressional district. Such a course would elect Judge
                        Kimmell by 1,000 majority.--<emph rend="italic">Bedford Gazette</emph>.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprints an article discussing a debate between two candidates for
                    Congress. Praises Kimmel but accuses Cessna(a well known radical) of ignoring
                    key issues and basically ranting and raving the whole time.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.09.30.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Theatre</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Sherry's New York Theatre will perform in Chambersburg during the fair
                    offering "persons from remote parts of the county, who seldom see anything of
                    the kind" the opportunity to enjoy a play.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Call Extended</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hayes</ln>
                        <fn>I. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Second Presbyterian Church of Chambersburg issued a call to the Rev. I.
                    M. Hayes to serve as pastor. The congregation has been meeting in the Court
                    House and is currently looking for a lot on which to build a church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Mr. Foster's Seminary</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foster</ln>
                        <fn>A. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Rev. A. S. Foster, principal of the Federal Hill Seminary for Young
                    Ladies, has transferred his school rooms from Federal Hill to Mrs. Bard's
                    building opposite the Court House. This will make it much easier for students to
                    get to school, especially during bad weather. The paper urges parents interested
                    in educating their daughters to look into Foster's school.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Democratic Meetings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The meetings of the Democracy in this county have been attended with unusual
                        success. The first regular meeting of the campaign was held at Greencastle
                        last Saturday night a week. A special train from this place took three
                        hundred men to the meeting. The largest crowd was assembled that ever
                        attended a political meeting there at night. The meeting was addressed by
                        Hon Geo. W. Brewer and J. McDowell Sharpe and W.S. Stenger Esqs. On Monday
                        night of last week, two meetings were held--one at Mercersburg which was
                        addressed by J. McDowell Sharpe and W.S. Stenger Esqs., and the other at
                        Fayetteville which was addressed by Hon. F.M. Kimmell and Hon. Geo. W.
                        Brewer. On Tuesday night meetings were to be held at Loudon and Sharpe's
                        School House, but owing to the heavy rain, were postponed. The meeting at
                        Loudon will be held on the evening of Tuesday Oct. 6th. On Wednesday
                        evening, a meeting was held at Fannettsburg addressed by Capt. Geo. W.
                        Skinner, Lieut. M.D. Reymer and Mr. B. Rush Hollar. A meeting was held on
                        the same night at New Franklin and was addressed by Hon. G. W. Brewer and J.
                        McDowell Sharpe Esq.</p>
                    <p>On Thursday evening a meeting was held at the School House in Dry Run at
                        which addresses were delivered by J. McDowell Sharpe Esq. Capt. Geo. W
                        Skinner, Lieut. M. D. Reymer and Jas. P McClintock Esq. The meeting
                        appointed for Strasburg was postponed on account of the inclemency of the
                        weather.</p>
                    <p>On Friday evening a meeting was held at Greenwood and addressed by C.M.
                        Duncan Esq. Same night, another at Concord addressed by Capt. Geo. W.
                        Skinner, Lieut. M. D. Raymer and Mr. Goshom.</p>
                    <p>In the afternoon of Saturday these same gentlemen addressed a meeting in
                        Amberson's Valley. On Saturday evening a meeting was held at Marion which
                        was addressed by J. McDowell Sharpe and James P. McClintock Esqs. There was
                        also a meeting, the same night, at the Hotel of Mr. M. Gable in Hamilton
                        township which was addressed by Wm. McLellan, C.M. Duncan and John R. Orr,
                        Esqs.</p>
                    <p>On Monday evening of this week two meetings were held, one at the Forge
                        School House in Warren township, addressed by J. McDowell Sharpe Esq., and
                        the other at Upton addressed by Wm. M'Lellan, Capt. Geo. W. Skinner, Lieut.
                        M.D. Raymer and Col. B.F. Winger.</p>
                    <p>All these meetings have been marked with the greatest enthusiasm and
                        interest. The speakers indulged in no personal abuse but dealt in argument
                        and facts exclusively. Men went to hear a discussion of the living issues of
                        the present and did not go away disappointed. We have never seen the
                        Democracy of Franklin county more fully alive to the importance of energetic
                        action and we can assure our friends throughout the State that they will
                        hear a good report from us next month.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewer</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharpe</ln>
                        <fn>J. McDowell</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stenger</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kimmell</ln>
                        <fn>F. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewer</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reymer</ln>
                        <fn>M. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hollar</ln>
                        <fn>B. Rush</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClintock</ln>
                        <fn>James P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duncan</ln>
                        <fn>C. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Goshom</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gable</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLellan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn>John R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Winger</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Gives a very detailed description of Democratic meetings held throughout
                    the State and who spoke at each. Is pleased with the turnout and enthusiasm at
                    all of them.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilbert</ln>
                        <fn>Calvin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Franklin County Fair will be held next week, and the paper anticipates
                    large attendance from neighboring counties will supplement the citizens of
                    Franklin. The editors reiterate that there are no entry fees except for speed
                    trials and tournaments. Entries are still being accepted by the Secretary,
                    Calvin Gilbert.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Sands is Coming</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prof. Sands, a "magician, ventriloquist, and exposer of spiritualism," will
                    perform at Repository Hall. "His exhibitions are instructive and amusing, at the
                    same time wonderful and mysterious." Admission is 25 cents, 15 cents for
                    children.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Who Wants the Banner</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Seymour and Blair club of Chambersburg will present a banner to the
                    election district that produces the largest increase in Democratic votes over
                    the 1867 results.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greenhalgh</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walt</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hawkins</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Peter Greenhalgh and Miss Elizabeth Walt, both of Chambersburg, were
                    married on August 27th by the Rev. William George Hawkins.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLucas</ln>
                        <fn>Solomon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Erisman</ln>
                        <fn>Maria</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>J. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Solomon McLucas and Miss Maria Erisman, both of Warren, were married on
                    September 3rd by the Rev. J. G. Brown.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zeigler</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rhodes</ln>
                        <fn>Hetty</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nimmon</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Zeigler of Spring Run and Miss Hetty Rhodes of Fannettsburg were
                    married at the Fannettsburg residence of Maj. J. S. Nimmon on September 15th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Warnick</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parks</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hollar</ln>
                        <fn>Solomon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mowers</ln>
                        <fn>S. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Peter Warnick and Mrs. Rebecca Parks, both of Franklin, were married at the
                    St. Thomas residence of Solomon Hollar on September 22nd. The Rev. S. A. Mowers
                    presided.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fautz</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Andrews</ln>
                        <fn>Jane Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Isaac Fautz and Jane Elizabeth Andrews, all of Franklin, were married on
                    September 17th by the Rev. J. A. Crawford.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.09.30.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
