<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1868/pa.fr.vs.1868.05.27">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/01/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1868-05-27">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day norm="">27</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.05.27.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.05.27.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Conservative Soldiers' and Sailors' National Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper announces a national convention of conservative soldiers and
                    sailors.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Radical National Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on the Republican National Convention, including the part played by
                    A. K. McClure. The paper declares the ticket of Grant and Colfax a poor one,
                    both men of "limited intellectual capacity."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Union Pacific Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on the construction of the Union Pacific.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Read Them Out!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper gloats that Judge Chase and Senators Fessenden, Trumbull,
                    Henderson, and Ross have been "read out" of the Republican Party, a move sure to
                    strengthen the Democracy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Candidates Serenaded</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Grant and Colfax were serenaded in Washington, D. C. last Friday evening.
                    The paper mocks Colfax for pointing to the Republican achievement of freeing the
                    slaves, and asserts that he favors black suffrage rights.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Soldiers' Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Calls for the "conservative soldiers of Franklin County" to select
                    delegates to attend the national convention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.05.27.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Readings and Recitations</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Howard</ln>
                        <fn>C. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>C. B. Howard will give readings from works by American and English authors
                    before an audience in Repository Hall. His repertoire includes the trial scene
                    from Merchant of Venice, scenes from Pickwick, Poe's Raven, The Lay of the
                    Madman, Candle Lecture, Scene from the Lady of Lyons, Sheridan's Ride, and Comic
                    Sketch and the Delirium Scene from "The Drunkard."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Building Association</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Record of the Chambersburg Building Association's receipts and expenses for
                    last 6 months. They took in $9499.97 and paid out the same. They hold $9411.80
                    in assets over liabilities.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Honor to Our Dead</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Next Saturday, as will be seen by the notice in another column, it is
                        proposed to strew the graves of our dead soldiers with flowers. We are glad
                        that this is to be done. It will be an appropriate tribute to the memory of
                        our citizens who fell upon the field of battle, or who died of disease in
                        the camp.</p>
                    <p>This custom was inaugurated in this country by the Rebels, who each year
                        decorate their cemeteries and the resting-places of their dead with
                        evergreens and flowers.--They thus strive to keep alive the recollections of
                        their former comrades and friends. And if they are to be admired for thus
                        casting their offerings of affection upon the graves of those who fell in
                        rebellion against the National Government, how much more ought we to emulate
                        each other in doing honor to those who sacrificed their lives in defence of
                        the Constitution and the Union!</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Favors the proposal to place flowers on the graves of soldiers who died in
                    the war. Notes how former rebels do it and so the North should do it as well.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Supreme Court</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Helser</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGrath</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ritter</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Downey</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wickey</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hetrick</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hughes</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Oaks</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Lanahan</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schlosser</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sollenberger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Knepper</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kurtz</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The following Franklin County cases were decided in state supreme court.
                    Helser vs McGrath, judgement affirmed; Ritter vs Downey, judgement affirmed;
                    Wickey vs Eyster, judgement affirmed; Hetrick vs Smith, judgement affirmed;
                    Hughes vs Oaks, judgement affirmed; Cumberland Valley Railroad Company vs
                    M'Lanahan, judgement reversed; Schlosser vs Sollenberger, judgement reversed;
                    Knepper vs Kurtz, judgement affirmed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>To Farmers and Horse Dealers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Balaley</ln>
                        <fn>G. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snesserott</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper extols the benefits of insuring farm animals. Frank Miller, the
                    Chambersburg agent for Great Western Insurance, can handle inquiries. G. J.
                    Balaley can also issue policies. Dr. Snesserott recently received a payout after
                    the death of one of his horses.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carson</ln>
                        <fn>J. O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKinstry</ln>
                        <fn>W. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Winger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dougherty</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A railroad meeting was held at Mercersburg to discuss the incorporation of
                    the Huntingdon, Fulton, and Franklin and the Fort Loudon Railroad companies. J.
                    O. Carson presided with W. D. McKinstry as Secretary.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Attention Comrades!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Saturday, the 30th day of May, 1868, having been designated for the purpose
                        of strewing with flowers or otherwise decorating the graves of comrades who
                        died in the defence of their Country during the late Rebellion, all Soldiers
                        and Sailors in the borough of Chambersburg and the surrounding country are
                        cordially and earnestly invited to attend and participate in this patriotic
                        ceremony, and also to attend a meeting of Soldiers and Sailors, to be held
                        in the Court House, on Wednesday evening the 27th inst., at 7 1/2 o'clock,
                        for the purpose of making arrangements for such fitting services and
                        testimonials of respect for our heroic dead as may be deemed proper.</p>
                    <p>On Saturday the 30th inst. at 7 o'clock A.M. all Soldiers and Sailors
                        desiring to participate will meet at the Court House, where they will be
                        immediately formed, and headed by a band will proceed to the Cemetery and
                        other grave yards where the ceremonies will be had. And may we not hope that
                        our patriotic ladies, whoso constantly cheered the braves while in the field
                        to greater deeds of valor will now lend a helping hand to garland the
                        passionless mounds above our deceased comrades with the choicest flowers of
                        Spring-time. Join us then Soldiers, Sailors, and Ladies, in doing homage to
                        those of the Nation's defenders who are no more. F.S. Stumbaugh P.C.</p>
                    <p>P.S.--Sheriff Doebler has kindly tendered his office room in the Court House,
                        to be used as a depository for such bouquets and flowers as the ladies may
                        see proper to furnish. F.S.S</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter from one F.S. Stumbaugh urging all army and navy veterans and ladies
                    to participate in the honor ceremony for fallen soldiers in the late war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Death of Dr. W. H. Watson</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Watson</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. W. H. Watson died in his residence at Bedford.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Death of Mrs. W. P. Schell</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schell</ln>
                        <fn>W. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. W. P. Schell died in Bedford after a "lingering illness."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stahl</ln>
                        <fn>Anna Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stahl</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heintzelman</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Anna Mary Stahl, wife of Joseph Stahl, died at the Guilford residence of
                    Andrew Heintzelman. She was 72 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.05.27.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote>Advertisements and agricultural advice appear on this page.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
