<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1868/pa.fr.vs.1868.06.24">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/04/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1868-06-24">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="06">June</month>
            <day norm="">24</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.06.24.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.06.24.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Party of Fanaticism</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Fanaticism never reasons. It drives headlong to the accomplishment of its
                        object. It is born of the passions and it is as uncontrollable as they. It
                        is hemmed in by no laws. It holds itself accountable to nobody. It is the
                        stuff of which mobs are made.--It never consults conscience. It allows
                        nothing to hinder its progress. It sweeps from its path everything which
                        seeks to stay its march. Never reasoning, lawless, irresponsible and without
                        principle, it grapples one idea alone, and pushes it with astounding vigor
                        and energy.</p>
                    <p>This fact has been strikingly exemplified in the history of the Radical
                        party. In its inception, it grappled to its soul as if with hooks of steel,
                        the negro. The burden of its cry ever since 1856, has been the terrible
                        wrong done to the African in this country. At first it inveighed against
                        slavery and slaveholders. It lit the fires of civil war in Kansas and
                        crimsoned the soil of that fair territory with blood. It appealed to every
                        passion of the human heart in order to excite the hatred of the North
                        against the South. It counseled resistance to the fugitive slave law. Armed
                        mobs rescued the fugitive from the hands of the officers of the law and
                        conveyed him beyond their reach. Terrible riots grew out of these lawless
                        proceedings.</p>
                    <p>It put pike and rifle into the hands of the infamous John Brown and his
                        deluded associates to make war upon the unarmed men, women, and children of
                        Virginia. And when he expiated the horrible crime upon the scaffold, it
                        canonized him as a martyr, sung paeans to his memory, and is to-day keeping
                        his soul on a perpetual march for the benefit of its type of perfection, the
                        negro.</p>
                    <p>It refused to entertain any terms of compromise between the Northern and
                        Southern States in 1861, and so fired the Northern heart by appeals for
                        revenge by means of blood-letting, that reason was dethroned, and the nation
                        was precipitated into a civil war in which hundreds of thousands of its
                        bravest and best went down to bloody graves, and almost every Northern home
                        has been draped in mourning. Indeed, so ferocious did this fell spirit of
                        fanaticism become that, during the pendency of that terrible struggle, while
                        our soldiers were famishing in Southern prisons and dying by thousands, the
                        voice of humanity was stifled in the North and they were left to their sad,
                        bitter fate, because it was inexpedient, forsooth, to exchange healthy men
                        for sick men. It is, alas, too true that a vast deal of the responsibility
                        for the sufferings of Union men in Rebel prisons lies at the door of the
                        National Government. Let those who are unwilling to accept our statement as
                        true upon this point, refer to the correspondence of General Benjamin F.
                        Butler with General Hiram Ulysses Grant, and they will discover that this
                        policy in relation to the exchange of prisoners, by the adoption of which so
                        many of our soldiers went down to premature graves, was adopted by the
                        present standard bearer of the Radical party, General Grant himself, and
                        that he is responsible for the consequences.</p>
                    <p>It struck the shackles from the feet of the negro and yet it was not
                        satisfied. Its war cry was freedom for the slave, but when that was won, it
                        refused to rest. The rebellion was crushed. The insurgent armies surrendered
                        and acknowledged the authority of the National Government. The shadow of
                        slavery had been lifted from every negro hovel in the land. Everything
                        looked propitious. It seemed as though a happy era of peace and good-will
                        was about to be ushered in. But not so. Fanaticism again blew its bugle
                        blast and negro equality and equal rights became the watchwords of the
                        Radical party. The Constitution and laws and the multifarious interests of
                        the nation were all disregarded and treated as of no account in its blind
                        zeal for the success of this new doctrine. For three years the
                        representatives of the States of the South have been denied admission to the
                        halls of Congress except upon the extension of equal rights to the negro as
                        a <emph rend="italic">sine qua non</emph> to the enjoyment of the right of
                        representation and the privilege of participating in the administration of
                        the government. During all this time, business interests have suffered every
                        where. Trade has languished. Embarrassments in financial matters confront
                        nearly all, while total ruin has been the lot of many. The expenses of the
                        National Government, as the result of this Radical, fanatical policy, are
                        frightful. And whilst business is so dull that men find it difficult to make
                        a bare living, taxation is growing heavier and heavier and grinding harder
                        and harder. The expenses of negro conventions must be supplied with food,
                        and the Freedmens' Bureau furnishes it at the cost of Northern capital
                        labor. Large sums of money have been appropriated for the purpose of
                        maintaining the soldiers who are kept in the South in order to insure the
                        ascendancy of the negroes, and the State governments have been handed over
                        to their management.</p>
                    <p>But fanaticism does not stop here. The purpose of the Radical party is to
                        force negro suffrage upon the North. It is earnestly at work to educate the
                        Northern mind to accept that doctrine. Seeing political power slipping from
                        its hands, it imagines that the way to retain it is to place the negro upon
                        the same footing with the whites, and it then expects to secure his vote for
                        Radical measures. All this it seeks to do "outside the Constitution." It
                        despises the forms of law. It repudiates the authority of the constitution.
                        It laughs at the teachings of the Fathers. It overleaps all legal barriers,
                        and flies in the face of musty precedents. It has determined not to
                        relinquish the management of governmental affairs even though to retain
                        power it becomes necessary to erect a military despotism upon the ruins of
                        the American Republic.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Seeks to blame the Republicans for all ills past and present. Blames the
                    Republicans for Kansas, the Civil War, prison deaths, and reconstruction woes.
                    For the latter, stresses the financial burdens put on Northerners because of
                    Radical policies. Claims Radicals only care about blacks and disregard the law
                    whenever it sees fit.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>A. K. M.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper ridicules Alexander K. McClure for his erroneous predictions that
                    Johnson would be convicted and removed from office.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Democratic Candidates</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper asserts that, to the chagrin of the Radicals, the Democrats will
                    select candidates true to party principles. They will not seek compromise
                    candidates as some have speculated.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>How About the Soldiers?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper defends itself against the assertions of the Repository that only
                    26 men joined the Conservative Soldiers' Convention. The editors ask how many
                    veterans participated in the Radical Convention, and point with pride to the 107
                    soldiers from the "old Radical borough of Chambersburg" who joined the
                    Conservative Soldiers' Club. "The 'White Boys in Blue' are going for the
                    Constitution and the Union and the Democratic nominees, as against Negro
                    Equality, military despotism, and Grant and Colfax."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.06.24.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Fair Held on Friday</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The fair held by Chambersburg's Catholic Church was a notable success. The
                    parish raised money to liquidate Church debts.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Scotland and Mont Alto Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Only $42,000 of a needed $300,000 remain to be raised to construct the new
                    railroad. The paper predicts this goal will be easily met, as meetings are
                    planned up and down the proposed route. The route will be planned after the
                    grain harvest.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Licensed to Preach</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Croft</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel Croft of St. Thomas completed his theological course at the
                    Missionary Institute, Selinsgrove, Pa. He is now licensed to preach and has
                    already received an invitation from a Lutheran Church in Perry County. The paper
                    wishes him well.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Radical Forgetfulness</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper complains that the "Radical" janitor at the Court House went home
                    for lunch and conveniently forgot to ring the one o'clock bell on the day that
                    the Conservative Soldiers' Convention planned to use it to announce a
                    re-convening. The paper suspects political motives, since this was the only day
                    all year that the janitor had been so remiss in his duties. The editors call for
                    his replacement in the event of a Democratic victory in the fall elections. "We
                    must have a man there who will attend to his business regardless of party ties."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>A Novel Wager</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We learn that a wager of rather novel character will be decided in this place
                        on Friday next. Mr. W. W. Crooks and J. A. S. Cramer are the parties
                        interested. The wager was made on the result of the impeachment trial. Mr.
                        Crooks, a staunch Republican, believing in Mr. Johnson's guilt, and that his
                        removal would certainly occur, agreed to wheel a wheel-barrow from the front
                        of Washington House, through Market street, to the front of the Gordon
                        Stand, West of town, in case of his acquittal--in case of conviction Mr.
                        Cramer, who is a staunch Democrat and believing in his innocence, felt
                        confident of his acquittal, was to wheel the same vehicle over the same
                        route, with a placard attached bearing the following
                        inscription;--"Impeachment a success!" The placard for the loser of the
                        wager is:--"Impeachment a failure!" A Band of Music will be in attendance
                        and the procession will be headed by the winning party carrying a flag. The
                        wheeling will take place between the hours of 10 A. M. and 3 P. M.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crooks</ln>
                        <fn>W. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cramer</ln>
                        <fn>J. A. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Description of a political wager between two partisan residents of
                    Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Time for Holding County Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Lellan</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kimmell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Democratic County Executive Committee decided at their recent meeting
                    in the offices of M'Lellan and Kimmell to hold the County Nominating Convention
                    the first week in August. This is much earlier than usual, but the committee
                    decided it was essential to give the candidates enough time to canvass their
                    districts.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Conservative Soldier's Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Detrich</ln>
                        <fn>J. L. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Winger</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reymer</ln>
                        <fn>M. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brand</ln>
                        <fn>A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>D. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lochbaum</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coble</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>West</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pugh</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swanger</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nimmon</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Embick</ln>
                        <fn>M. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jarrott</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clem</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Powders</ln>
                        <fn>D. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kuhn</ln>
                        <fn>N. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>French</ln>
                        <fn>T. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Conservative Soldiers' Convention elected officers and delegates to the
                    National Convention in New York. Col. B. F. Winger and Capt. George Skinner
                    addressed the meeting. The Silver Cornet Band and the Citizen's Band provided
                    musical entertainment. The paper predicts that most of Franklin's soldiers will
                    side with the Democrats in the coming elections.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Our Town Fathers have had the Receipts and Expenditures of the Borough, for
                        the year ending April 30, 1868, printed on slips and circulated for the
                        information of all concerned. The Auditors certify to the following
                        statement of D. S. Fahnestock, Treasurer:</p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>To bal. in hands of Treas. at last settlem't</cell>
                            <cell>$2,323.78</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Borrowed Money</cell>
                            <cell>9,765.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Amount received from old Factory Bridge</cell>
                            <cell>25.15</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Amount received from W. S. Everett</cell>
                            <cell>23.60</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Amount collected on Duplicate of 1866</cell>
                            <cell>2,294.32</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Amount collected on Duplicate of 1867</cell>
                            <cell>6,402.87</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Total</cell>
                            <cell>$20,835.62</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Balance on Duplicate, for 1866</cell>
                            <cell>4,204.41</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Amount of Duplicate, 1867</cell>
                            <cell>9,639.50</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Total</cell>
                            <cell>$13,843.71</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Am't coll'd on Dup., 1866</cell>
                            <cell>$2,294.32</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Am't coll'd on Dup., 1867</cell>
                            <cell>6,402.87</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Exonerations</cell>
                            <cell>1,711.56</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Comm'n allowed Collector</cell>
                            <cell>641.80</cell>
                            <cell>11,030.55</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Balance due on Duplicate, subject to Exonerations and Commissions</cell>
                            <cell>2,793.16</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>By am't of Council and Burgess' salary</cell>
                            <cell>$313.40</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>am't of Clerk's salary</cell>
                            <cell>162.50</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>am't of Treasurer's salary</cell>
                            <cell>206.48</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>am't paid Attorneys</cell>
                            <cell>200.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>am't paid on Bonds and Interest</cell>
                            <cell>8,200.90</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>am't paid Street Commissioner</cell>
                            <cell>500.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>am't paid for Repairing Streets</cell>
                            <cell>3,452.34</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>am't paid Fire Department</cell>
                            <cell>819.97</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>am't paid for Gas, Lamp Lighting, Rep'rs</cell>
                            <cell>1,372.76</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Miscellaneous</cell>
                            <cell>192.83</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>am't paid for Bridges</cell>
                            <cell>668.77</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>am't paid Market House</cell>
                            <cell>109.85</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>am't paid for Printing</cell>
                            <cell>166.89</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>am't paid High Constable</cell>
                            <cell>480.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>am't paid Watchmen</cell>
                            <cell>44.50</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>am't paid Academy</cell>
                            <cell>2,000.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Balance in hands of Treasurer</cell>
                            <cell>1,782.53</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Total</cell>
                            <cell>$20,853.62</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <p>This statement shows an expenditure of nearly one thousand dollars more than
                        this Borough ought to pay in the shape of salaries. We make no special
                        objection to the salaries paid to the Clerk and Treasurer, though possibly
                        these might be put somewhat lower and still afford a fair compensation for
                        the services rendered. But we do object to the "Council and Burgess" eating
                        up $313.40, when less than one-third this amount used to be sufficient. We
                        also object to the payment of $200 to Attorneys, when more than one good
                        Attorney would be willing to transact all the legal business of the Borough
                        for $50 per annum. We particularly object to the payment of $500 to a Street
                        Commissioner, for whom there is not the slightest need. At this time, when
                        our property holders and business men are heavily in debt, our Borough taxes
                        should be kept down to the lowest possible point. There should not be a
                        dollar expended unnecessarily. Salaries should not be raised. A citizen who
                        feels that he cannot afford to serve as Burgess or Councilman at the salary
                        paid ten years ago, ought to decline. Plenty of good men can be got to serve
                        at the old price. And if the salaries of old offices should not be raised,
                        much less should new and unnecessary offices be created, with high salaries
                        attached to them.</p>
                    <p>We invite the attention of taxpayers of all shades of political opinion to
                        the foregoing statement, and we submit to them the question whether one
                        thousand dollars of the expenditures should not have been saved.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fahnestock</ln>
                        <fn>D. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>List and discussion of expenditures of the borough of Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Refreshing Coolness</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph> says in relation to the Grant and
                        Colfax meeting held on Saturday night, the 13th inst., "as business was the
                        only object that called this body together, there were no speeches made."</p>
                    <p>It won't do, neighbors. Always look to the record before you venture on
                        apologies. The call for this meeting, whose only object was business, as
                        placarded upon our street corners, reads as follows:</p>
                    <p>"Attention! All loyal citizens are invited to meet at the Court House, this
                        evening, Saturday, June 13th, to organize a Grant and Colfax club. <emph
                            rend="italic">Good speakers will be in attendance</emph>. Let every
                        Republican be present. (Signed) Many Citizens." It seems queer that the
                        "many citizens" who are responsible for the call, and who were so earnest in
                        urging others to attend, did not attend themselves. Perhaps "many" does not
                        mean more than <emph rend="italic">thirty-six</emph>. The fact is their
                        meeting was a perfect fizzle, and that the able speakers, who were to be in
                        attendance, came to the conclusion that Radicalism in this Borough is
                        "whittled down to the little end of nothing," and refused to waste any
                        breath on that little band of <emph rend="italic">thirty-six</emph>.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper mocks the small turnout for a Grant and Colfax meeting.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Boys in Blue</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A meeting was held on Monday night in the Court House to organize a Soldiers'
                        Club for the support of Grant and Colfax. Col. A.K. McClure and John
                        Stewart, Esq. were announced to speak. The former was not present at the
                        meeting, not being in town. After two weeks of arduous labor, the Radicals
                        succeeded in getting together about fifty soldiers, from the Brevet Brig.
                        General down to the drummer boy of a recruiting office. Some citizens were
                        present, both Democrats and Radicals, but the Court Room was by no means
                        full.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Stewart addressed the meeting for about one hour. He labored hard to
                        convince his audience that the Democratic party is the Rebel party, by
                        rehashing all the stale charge <sic>sabout</sic> sympathy with rebellion
                        &amp;c. He then endeavored to establish his assertion that the Radical
                        party is par excellence the union party. He asserted that it is now
                        endeavoring to model this government after the idea of its founders, and
                        charged the Democratic party with being in favor of an aristocracy founded
                        on caste. He argued that the question of suffrage in the South is a settled
                        fact--that this right has been conferred upon the negro there by Congress in
                        all due solemnity of the law. He insisted that when the Democratic party
                        regains power, it intends to repudiate this action--that he had heard one of
                        its orators in that room, during the convention of soldiers the other day,
                        declare that he was in favor of such repudiation. The speaker's reference
                        here was to the speech of one of the editors of this paper, who did say most
                        unqualifiedly that whenever the whites get control of the Southern State
                        Governments, he hoped that they would strip the negro of this privilege
                        which has been conferred <sic>up-</sic> him without any Constitutional
                        authority whatever.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Stewart declared that to repudiate negro suffrage was to repudiate every
                        victory of union soldiers in the late war--that it was a necessity to the
                        Radical party to keep the government in the South from falling into the
                        hands of the Rebels. He said that just here he differed with his party--that
                        while they have given the negro the privilege of voting as a necessity, he
                        held that <emph rend="italic">it was due to him as a right</emph>. We
                        thought that it was impossible for the gentleman to allow himself to be held
                        by the leading strings of his party. He closed by assuring his audience that
                        Grant will prove just as invincible in the Presidential contest as on the
                        field of battle.</p>
                    <p>The committee on organization and resolutions then reported Col. J.G. Elder
                        President; Grimason and Strike Vice Pres; Stumbaugh Chief Marshal. A
                        constitution containing twelve articles was submitted by Col. Theo. McGowan
                        and adopted--ayes 6; nays, none.</p>
                    <p>The President then hurriedly called up the members of the club to sign the
                        constitution. A few advanced, while almost the entire audience left the
                        room. This action of the President was intended to crowd off a certain
                        General and Lieutenant who seemed very anxious to deliver themselves of some
                        happy thoughts.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>A. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stewart</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elder</ln>
                        <fn>J. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grimason</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strike</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGowan</ln>
                        <fn>Theodore</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports on a Republican soldiers' meeting held in the Court House.
                    Summarized the speeches of the speakers, namely John Stewart, who reiterated the
                    themes of the Republican platform, especially about black voting. Ends by
                    claiming that when a constitution was written up and adopted, only a few in the
                    audience actually went up to sign it.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Mercersburg College</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The article calls attention to Mercersburg College that offers examinations
                    in Classics, Mathematics, History, and Geography. The school maintains a
                    relationship with the Mercersburg Theological Seminary with which it holds joint
                    services for a congregation of 50 or 60. John Bowman, Jr., of Chambersburg gave
                    the most recent valedictory address.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Important Railroad Movement</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Helster</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKinstry</ln>
                        <fn>William D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Winger</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carson</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carson</ln>
                        <fn>James O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A meeting was held in Maryland to discuss a railroad line from Mercersburg
                    to Hagerstown. The citizens of Mercersburg proposed to raise $150,000 to
                    construct the line. The paper applauds the energy and determination of the
                    people of that part of the county, and chastises Chambersburg for acting as if
                    they lived in the "days of stage-coaches."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sherman</ln>
                        <fn>L. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Behm</ln>
                        <fn>Carrie M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnes</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>L. G. Sherman of Newville and Miss Carrie M. Behm of St. Thomas were
                    married on June 18th in the Chambersburg Methodist Parsonage by the Rev. S.
                    Barnes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>Isabella M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kope</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>West</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Kope of Juniata County and Isabella M. Walker of Dry Run were married
                    on June 18th by the Rev. William A. West.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Jane Stuart died in her residence on South Front Street in
                    Chambersburg on June 10th. She was 68 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Byers</ln>
                        <fn>Louisa Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Byers</ln>
                        <fn>Emanuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Louisa Jane Byers, wife of Emanuel Byers, died on June 7th in
                    Guilford. She was 35 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.06.24.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote>Advertisements and agricultural advice appear on this page.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
