<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1868/pa.fr.vs.1868.12.23">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/15/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1868-12-23">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="12">December</month>
            <day norm="">23</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.12.23.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.12.23.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Virginia and the Carolinas</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Detailed account of a trip by a group of Pennsylvanians and Marylanders
                    through Virginia and the Carolinas.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>The Democratic State Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Since the November election there has been a lull in politics. The excitement
                        that preceded it has entirely subsided and in its place we have an
                        extraordinary indifference to political questions. This may be partly owing
                        to the financial troubles in which the country finds itself. But it is also
                        attributable, in some degree, to the fact that the Conservative portion of
                        the people have resolved to be quiet for awhile and watch the course of the
                        Radical leaders. They believe that "their strength is to sit still." This
                        determination is likely to continue for some time to come. Not that the
                        Democratic organization is to be broken up or not to be kept up. Not that
                        the Democracy intend to make an inglorious retreat from the face of the foe.
                        On the contrary, there never was a stronger determination on the part of the
                        Conservative hosts to rally for another effort in behalf of Constitutional
                        liberty, than there is now.</p>
                    <p>As firm believers in the success of Democratic principles and measures if
                        affairs are properly managed, we can not see the propriety of holding the
                        next Democratic State Convention at such an early date as the fourth of
                        March. On the other hand we believe that such an early meeting will ruin our
                        chance of success.</p>
                    <p>There is no <emph rend="italic">necessity</emph> for disclosing our position
                        on questions that will enter into the <unclear>canvass</unclear> so long
                        before the election is to take place. We will have sufficient time, if the
                        Convention is held in July, or August, or even the first week in September,
                        to discuss the positions of the two parties and the qualifications of the
                        respective nominees.</p>
                    <p>Nor is there any <emph rend="italic">wisdom</emph> in holding the Convention
                        in March. It is true that Congress will adjourn on the fourth of March, but
                        the effects of their legislation will not have been seen. The evils that
                        will grow out of it will not have assumed such a shape as to admit of being
                        pressed home upon the people with most telling effect. Our Convention ought
                        to know <emph rend="italic">where</emph> to strike before it attempts to
                        strike at all.</p>
                    <p>And then, too, General Grant will just enter upon his administration. How is
                        the Convention to speak intelligently to the people of Pennsylvania in
                        regard to the next President's course if it is obliged to present its
                        platform before the inaugural address has reached it?</p>
                    <p>Let us take all the time we possibly can. And when the people of the State
                        meet in their respective districts to select delegates, let them be careful
                        to select men of intelligence and sound Democratic principles.--Last March
                        the Convention suffered itself to be dragooned into the nomination of a
                        certain candidate by a loud-mouthed military hero who went over to the enemy
                        before the election came on. Let us be spared such mortification as this in
                        the future.--Let the Convention be composed of men who will stand by their
                        guns.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Let the Convention be postponed. We call upon the press
                            of the State to consider this matter and cry aloud for a postponement of
                            the Convention.</emph> Let us enter the next canvass with a thorough
                        knowledge of the situation and we can elect a Democratic Governor.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Calls on the Democratic state party to postpone its scheduled convention
                    date from March 4th to a later date. Gives its reasons why, mainly because
                    Radical legislation and Grant's policies will not have had any negative effect
                    by March. Plus, political activity is waning and so the editors want to wait for
                    a time when it can be reinvigorated.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.12.23.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Border Damages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The damage commissioners announce that all damage claims must be filed with
                    the clerk at Harrisburg before January 15th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Appointment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Balsley</ln>
                        <fn>George S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ashcom</ln>
                        <fn>C. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George S. Balsley has been appointed by C. W. Ashcom to the position of
                    Deputy Collector of Internal Revenue for the County. "George is a clever fellow
                    and will make an obliging and competent officer."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Admitted to the Bar</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hyssong</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewer</ln>
                        <fn>William U.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Hyssong and William U. Brewer were admitted to the Franklin County
                    Bar.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Episcopal Services</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A children's Christmas Eve service will be held in the lower hall of the
                    Masonic building.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Lecture</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shumaker</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Prof. Shumaker delivered a "highly instructive and entertaining" lecture on
                    "Manliness" at Greenvillage. He has been asked to repeat it by the Young Men's
                    Christian Association.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Musical Concert</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The M. E. Church is planning to follow up last year's success by holding
                    another Christmas night concert.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Gough's Lecture on Temperance in the M. E. Church</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>Corwin V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Prof. Corwin V. Wilson will recite at the M. E. Church John Gough's
                    temperance speech delivered in Exeter Hall, London. The proceeds will go to the
                    church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Monumental Fair</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Fair for the benefit of the Monumental Association opens tonight. The
                    paper predicts that the extensive preparations and time of year augur well for
                    success.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Obituary</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wagoner</ln>
                        <fn>David C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Powders</ln>
                        <fn>David L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClelland</ln>
                        <fn>William C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn>D. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Orrstown Literary Society published resolutions of sympathy and respect
                    upon the death of David C. Wagoner.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rots</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kochenour</ln>
                        <fn>Josephene</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Thomas J. Rots of Lock Haven and Miss Josephene Kochenour of Franklin were
                    married on December 8th by the Rev. J. A. Crawford.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flickinger</ln>
                        <fn>Edgar M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elder</ln>
                        <fn>Ada C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>West</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Edgar M. Flickinger of Metal and Miss Ada C. Elder of Dry Run were married
                    on December 9th by the Rev. William A. West.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Avery</ln>
                        <fn>Ella</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Avery</ln>
                        <fn>John R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Ella Avery, beloved wife of John R. Avery, died near Mont Alto on December
                    13th. She was 26 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bough</ln>
                        <fn>Emma M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Emma M. Bough died near Fayetteville on December 18th. She was 15
                    years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mentzer</ln>
                        <fn>Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Ann Mentzer died near Fayetteville on December 7th. She was 75 years
                    old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.12.23.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote>Advertisements and agricultural advice appear on this page.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
