<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1864/pa.fr.vs.1864.05.04">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Amy Murrell</taggerName>
            <tagDate>10/21/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 4/2/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1864-05-04">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day>4</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.05.04.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Freedom of Speech: Speech of Mr. Vorhees of Indiana</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"I am discussing now not merely the right of a Democrat on this floor; I am
                    discussing the right of every Republican on this floor. I go further. I am
                    discussing the right of the humblest citizen of America, the right to escape the
                    galling yoke of tyranny and oppression."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Transcript of a speech given by a member of the US House of Representatives
                    that condemns attempts by his colleagues to expel a congressman who expressed
                    conciliatory sentiments toward the South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Speech covers the entire page.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.05.04.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Mixing the Races</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"When the President proclaimed emancipation, he proclaimed also the
                    mingling of the races."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Says that the abolitionist doctrine is nothing more than support for the
                    mixing of the races.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Is the Vice President a Myth</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We have a dim recollection that some three or four years ago, a gentleman
                    named Hamlin, belonging to the State of Maine, was placed on the Republican
                    ticket as a candidate for Vice President, and was believed to have been elected.
                    But whether he was or was not, or what became of him, is a mystery: for the
                    public has never heard of him from that day to this."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Wonders if the Vice President is still around, and if so, where.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Sublime Mingling of the Races</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Says new information shows that rebel soldiers were not responsible for the
                    massacre of black soldiers in Vicksburg. Instead, this information suggests, an
                    Indian regiment killed the soldiers after finding they had "committed the
                    grossest possible outrages" on white women in a Vicksburg hotel.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Fiction and poetry, columns 1-5, classified ads, column 6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.05.04.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Rotation of Crops</head>
                <origin>Wisconsin Farmer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges farmers to remember to rotate their crops in order to preserve the
                    soil.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 2-6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.05.04.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Democratic Party and Slavery</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"They [Democrats] have always deplored the existence of slavery, but a
                    sacred regard for the compromises of the Constitution has ever induced them to
                    oppose all attempts of the general government to interfere with it in States
                    where it existed."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that the Democratic Party is in sympathy with the Constitution and
                    not with the institution of slavery, as opponents have charged.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Fate of the Claim Bill</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"What do the sufferers by Stuart's raid, in Franklin county, think of the
                    course pursued by Republican members of the House, in relation to this bill?
                    These claims so just, so equitable, and which the State, in justice to our
                    citizens, despoiled of their property through her neglect, was bound in good
                    faith to pay, have been bandied about from Harrisburg to Washington back again;
                    payment being at last refused by the votes of representatives, every one of whom
                    is a Republican."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Expresses disgust with the defeat of amendments in the US Congress that
                    would ensure that civilians received payment for property damaged in the war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Abolition State Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The convention was presided over by Ex-Speaker Lawrence, who, on taking
                    the chair, delivered a speech eulogizing the Union party as being the only one
                    able to save the country (God save the country!)."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the Republican State Convention met and voted to support
                    Abraham Lincoln in the next election.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Judiciary</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt> "A party that has lived by assailing the Judiciary should be the last to
                    charge it upon others as a fault. Assaults on the Judiciary have been and still
                    are its principal stock in trade, of which the files of the <emph rend="italic"
                        >Repository</emph> afford ample proof. In the language of scripture we would
                    say to our neighbor: 'Physician heal thyself.'" </excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We have no desire to get into a controversy with the <emph rend="italic"
                            >Repository</emph> about the Court. What we have said on the subject,
                        was dictated by an honest desire to promote the attainment of the ends of
                        justice. This was our sole purpose, and this we regarded as a solemn duty
                        which we owed to the law, to the Court, and to the people. We made no
                        assault on the Judiciary and sincerely trust it may never become necessary
                        for us to do so. If the <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph> wishes to
                        become the special defender of Judge Nill, and the Judge is satisfied, we
                        certainly have no objection. We have only this to say, however, that if we
                        are reluctantly drawn into a discussion against our wishes, we may have to
                        say <emph rend="italic">some</emph> things not too palatable to the editor
                        of the <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph> himself, and which he might
                        wish to have remained <emph rend="italic">unsaid</emph>.</p>
                    <p>To say the least of it, it comes with a bad grace for a Republican journal to
                        talk about "assaults on the Judiciary." A party that has lived by assailing
                        the Judiciary should be the last to charge it upon others as a fault.
                        Assaults on the Judiciary have been and still are its principal stock in
                        trade, of which the files of the <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph>
                        afford ample proof. In the language of scripture we would say to our
                        neighbor: "Physician heal thyself."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Explains that the Valley Spirit's expressed concern about the impartiality
                    of judges was not meant to be an attack on the judiciary, as the Franklin
                    Repository suggested.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that an election will take place on the first Tuesday in August
                    during which the people will decide whether soldiers should be able to vote.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Off With Their Heads</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that yet another officeholder--a postmaster--has been removed for
                    speaking disrespectfully of Lincoln.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Says that Lincoln is pleased with the defeat of General Banks in Louisiana
                    because it takes away a presidential competitor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Our Washington Letter</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Conococheague</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Valley Spirit's Washington, D.C. correspondent returns with an overview
                    of the "patriotism, corruption, and rascality" in that city.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Classified ads, column 6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.05.04.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Coming Draft</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The Board of Enrollment of the 16th Congressional District have completed
                    all the preliminary business and are ready to make a draft, under the last call
                    for troops, at any time."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Board of Enrollment of the 16th Congressional District have completed all
                        the preliminary business and are ready to make a draft, under the last call
                        for troops, at any time. The draft had been postponed temporarily by the War
                        Department but may be ordered to take place very soon.</p>
                    <p>We give below the official quota of each sub-district in the country,
                        carefully adjusted, and embracing all credits up to the 15th of April; from
                        which it would appear that the only subdistricts having their quotas filled,
                        are Greencastle and the South Ward of the borough of Chambersburg; the North
                        Ward has yet one man to furnish, but it is expected that our wide-awake
                        council will succeed in securing a "colored cuss" or some other man in time
                        to fill the deficiency.</p>
                    <p>Our readers can on this table as entirely correct, and we would advise
                        sub-districts not yet filled, to offer liberal bounties to volunteers and
                        make a vigorous effort to complete their quotas before the wheel at the
                        Masonic Hall commences its revolution.</p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Sub. Districts</cell>
                            <cell>Townships</cell>
                            <cell>No. Subject to Draft</cell>
                            <cell>Quotas</cell>
                            <cell>Total credited</cell>
                            <cell>Total to be furnished</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>41</cell>
                            <cell>Antrim township</cell>
                            <cell>433</cell>
                            <cell>129</cell>
                            <cell>82</cell>
                            <cell>47</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>41 1/2</cell>
                            <cell>Greencastle borough</cell>
                            <cell>196</cell>
                            <cell>50</cell>
                            <cell>61</cell>
                            <cell>-</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>42</cell>
                            <cell>Chambersburg N.W.</cell>
                            <cell>356</cell>
                            <cell>106</cell>
                            <cell>105</cell>
                            <cell>1</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>43</cell>
                            <cell>Chambersburg S.W.</cell>
                            <cell>292</cell>
                            <cell>87</cell>
                            <cell>87</cell>
                            <cell>-</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>44</cell>
                            <cell>Fannett township</cell>
                            <cell>257</cell>
                            <cell>77</cell>
                            <cell>17</cell>
                            <cell>60</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>45</cell>
                            <cell>Greene township</cell>
                            <cell>320</cell>
                            <cell>95</cell>
                            <cell>79</cell>
                            <cell>16</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>46</cell>
                            <cell>Guilford township</cell>
                            <cell>287</cell>
                            <cell>86</cell>
                            <cell>31</cell>
                            <cell>55</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>47</cell>
                            <cell>Hamilton township</cell>
                            <cell>145</cell>
                            <cell>43</cell>
                            <cell>23</cell>
                            <cell>20</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>48</cell>
                            <cell>Letterkenny township</cell>
                            <cell>220</cell>
                            <cell>66</cell>
                            <cell>40</cell>
                            <cell>26</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>49</cell>
                            <cell>Lurgan township</cell>
                            <cell>126</cell>
                            <cell>38</cell>
                            <cell>31</cell>
                            <cell>7</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>50</cell>
                            <cell>Metal township</cell>
                            <cell>140</cell>
                            <cell>42</cell>
                            <cell>20</cell>
                            <cell>22</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>51</cell>
                            <cell>Montgomery township</cell>
                            <cell>358</cell>
                            <cell>107</cell>
                            <cell>51</cell>
                            <cell>56</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>51 1/2</cell>
                            <cell>Mercersburg borough</cell>
                            <cell>116</cell>
                            <cell>35</cell>
                            <cell>32</cell>
                            <cell>3</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>52</cell>
                            <cell>Peters township</cell>
                            <cell>271</cell>
                            <cell>71</cell>
                            <cell>44</cell>
                            <cell>37</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>53</cell>
                            <cell>Quincy township</cell>
                            <cell>304</cell>
                            <cell>91</cell>
                            <cell>66</cell>
                            <cell>25</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>54</cell>
                            <cell>St. Thomas township</cell>
                            <cell>181</cell>
                            <cell>54</cell>
                            <cell>50</cell>
                            <cell>4</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>55</cell>
                            <cell>Southampton township</cell>
                            <cell>198</cell>
                            <cell>59</cell>
                            <cell>43</cell>
                            <cell>16</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>56</cell>
                            <cell>Warren township</cell>
                            <cell>78</cell>
                            <cell>23</cell>
                            <cell>9</cell>
                            <cell>14</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>57</cell>
                            <cell>Washington township</cell>
                            <cell>281</cell>
                            <cell>84</cell>
                            <cell>61</cell>
                            <cell>23</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>57 1/2</cell>
                            <cell>Waynesboro borough</cell>
                            <cell>159</cell>
                            <cell>47</cell>
                            <cell>31</cell>
                            <cell>16</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>____</cell>
                            <cell>____</cell>
                            <cell>____</cell>
                            <cell>____</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>4720</cell>
                            <cell>1400</cell>
                            <cell>953</cell>
                            <cell>458</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Provides official quotas of how many soldiers must be drafted from each
                    township in the 16th Congressional District.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Fair</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Mrs. D. N. Couch, Pres., Miss M. E. McCulloh, Secy.</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nixon</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Niccolls</ln>
                        <fn>S. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dyson</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCulloh</ln>
                        <fn>Mollie E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Couch</ln>
                        <fn>D. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLlellan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dechert</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clark</ln>
                        <fn>Lyman S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shryock</ln>
                        <fn>John K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armstrong</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoner</ln>
                        <fn>H. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mitchell</ln>
                        <fn>W. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fellows</ln>
                        <fn>B. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoskinson</ln>
                        <fn>J. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>A. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lane</ln>
                        <fn>S. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Raynolds</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seibert</ln>
                        <fn>Helen</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stevenson</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>Ellen</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilt</ln>
                        <fn>Kate</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Glosser</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that the ladies of Chambersburg met at the residence of Mr. J. S.
                    Nixon on April 26 in order to organize a fair to benefit the Christian
                    Commission. Rev. S. J. Niccolls gave a short address. Rev. F. Dyson was called
                    to the chair, and Mollie E. McCulloh was appointed secretary. Other appointments
                    made were: Mrs. D. N. Couch, president; Mrs. William McLlellan, vice president;
                    Mrs. J. L. Dechert, treasurer; and managers: Mrs. Lyman S. Clark, Mrs. John K.
                    Shryock, Mrs. John Armstrong, Mrs. H. S. Stoner, Mrs. W. G. Mitchell, Mrs. B. T.
                    Fellows, Mrs. J. T. Hoskinson, Mrs. A. K. McClure, Mrs. S. G. Lane, Miss Sarah
                    Raynolds, Miss Helen Seibert, Miss Sarah Wright, Miss Maggie Stevenson, Miss
                    Ellen Cook, Miss Kate Wilt, and Miss Maggie Glosser.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Borough Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Aughinbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deal</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stewart</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>C.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dubler</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wallace</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huber</ln>
                        <fn>Solomon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lane</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henninger</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Haslet</ln>
                        <fn>K. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Provides results of the borough election held last Monday. The only contest
                    was between R. Aughinbaugh and J. W. Deal for town council, in which the former
                    won by about eighty votes. The other positions filled were: burgess, John
                    Stewart; town council, C. S. Eyster, John Dubler, William Wallace, Samuel Myers,
                    and Solomon Huber; school directors, Samuel G. Lane, Jacob Henninger; auditor,
                    K. P. Haslet; and high constable, John [?].</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Communicated</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Weare [sic] all interested in this movement, hundreds of our young men,
                    our fathers, husbands and brothers are girding on their swords for the battle,
                    before whose significance the past withers into forgetfulness, no human sagacity
                    can tell when or where the blow may be struck, but we all know that in that
                    fatal field many a womanly form in our midst, will be widowed and broken
                    hearted, the refluent tide of war may bring the thunder of artillery in our very
                    midst, and our fields may be crimsoned with the blood of our brothers."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>At a meeting of the ladies of Chambersburg, interested in the Christian
                        Commission (which has for its object the supply of materials for the sick
                        and wounded of our army, more especially after a battle) it was unanimously
                        agreed to hold a fair on the 13th of June, for the purpose of raising funds
                        towards the benevolent association above mentioned. It is thought advisable
                        to interest the people of Franklin county in this laudable enterprise, so
                        that a united effort on the part of the citizens of one of the richest and
                        most populous counties in the State may be successful and worthy of the
                        cause and the people. In furtherance of this object, it is suggested, that
                        the prominent ladies of the large towns of Waynesboro, Greencastle,
                        Mercersburg, London, Orrstown and Fannettsburg, with all the villages of the
                        county, should confer among themselves and act with our citizens in this
                        undertaking. Each of these places could be separately represented at the
                        fair and have their own table, superintended by a committee from amongst
                        themselves. Mrs. General Couch is President of the ladies association in
                        this place, Mrs. William McLellan Vice President and Miss. Mary McCullough
                        Secretary from whom any information desired, can be had by addressing her.
                        Weare [sic] all interested in this movement, hundreds of our young men, our
                        fathers, husbands and brothers are girding on their swords for the battle,
                        before whose significance the past withers into forgetfulness, no human
                        sagacity can tell when or where the blow may be struck, but we all know that
                        in that fatal field many a womanly form in our midst, will be widowed and
                        broken hearted, the refluent tide of war may bring the thunder of artillery
                        in our very midst, and our fields may be crimsoned with the blood of our
                        brothers. It is the part of wisdom to prepare <emph rend="italic">now</emph>
                        to alleviate the pain and suffering of the wounded. In this Gospel of
                        Charity the ministry is given unto woman, for many reasons, she may not go
                        in the field, but what more cheering thought could sooth[e] the brow of
                        pain, than to know that a mother, wife or sister's hand had sent these
                        comforts to the stricken soldier. But I merely meant to suggest the plan of
                            <emph rend="italic">united</emph> action, all over our county, to the
                        ladies, knowing full well, that the fair hands, that roused them into the
                        field, will also alleviate their sufferings.</p>
                    <p>Delta.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Delta</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCullough</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf>Secretary</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Couch</ln>
                        <fn>General</fn>
                        <sf>President</sf>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLellan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf>Vice President</sf>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Encourages women of Franklin County to get involved in the work of the
                    Christian Commission.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Sad Accident</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shuman</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shuman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ward</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that Private James Shuman, son of Mr. John Shuman and member of
                    Captain Ward's Company of the 11th Pennsylvania Cavalry, was killed by the kick
                    of a horse on April 25. He is the second son of Mr. Shuman to have died in the
                    army in the last few months.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Arresting Deserters</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the practice of arresting deserters has become dangerous and
                    life-threatening.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Pennsylvania Reserves</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lists the expiration dates for the terms of service of various Pennsylvania
                    reserve regiments: 1st Regiment, August 1; 3rd Regiment, July 28; 4th Regiment,
                    July 17; 5th Regiment, June 21; 6th Regiment, July 27; 7th Regiment, July 27;
                    8th Regiment, July 29; 9th Regiment, July 29; 10th Regiment, July 21; 11th
                    Regiment, July 29; 12th Regiment, August 10; 13th Regiment, June 11.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Robbery</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cresler</ln>
                        <fn>Henry H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that while Henry H. Cresler and his family, of Southampton
                    Township, were at church on April 23, their house was robbed. A revolver is
                    among the missing items.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Spirit of Speculation</head>
                <origin>N. Y. Express</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Condemns speculators and urges government officials to do more to stop
                    them.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orth</ln>
                        <fn>Emma</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>L. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On April 31, Rev. L. G. Brown married Emma Orth and William Thompson, of
                    Altoona.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnhart</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Connor</ln>
                        <fn>Eleanor Francie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ware</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. Thomas Barnhart married Eleanor Francie Connor and Daniel Ware on
                    April 28.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maurer</ln>
                        <fn>Carrie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maurer</ln>
                        <fn>B. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maurer</ln>
                        <fn>Annie C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On May 3, Carrie Maurer, daughter of B. L. and Annie C. Maurer, died at age
                    18 months.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Alexander</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Alexander</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel Alexander, son of John Alexander, died on April 18 at age 13 months.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCune</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCune</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jacob McCune, son of Jacob McCune, died on April 25 at age 13 years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Domish</ln>
                        <fn>John Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Domish</ln>
                        <fn>Nathan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Domish</ln>
                        <fn>Catherine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Michael Domish, infant son of Nathan and Catherine Domish, died on
                    April 9.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clark</ln>
                        <fn>Charles Calvin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clark</ln>
                        <fn>Charles A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clark</ln>
                        <fn>Barbara</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Charles Calvin Clark, son of Charles A. and Barbara Clark, died on April 18
                    at age 8.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cromer</ln>
                        <fn>Maria</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Maria Cromer died on April 19 at age 46.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houser</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Jacob Houser died on April 26 at age 68.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kindline</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On April 17, Margaret Kindline died at age 65.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClintick</ln>
                        <fn>J. Sloan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. Sloan McClintick died on May 2 at age 44.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grible</ln>
                        <fn>John Ellsworth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Ellsworth Grible died on April 13 at age 3.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 3-6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.05.04.06">
            <pageNote>Reports of troop movement in North Carolina and Alabama, column 1, classified
                ads, columns 2-6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.05.04.07">
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 1-6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.05.04.08">
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 1-6</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
