<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1864/pa.fr.vs.1864.10.05">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Amy Murrell</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/05/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 4/24/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1864-10-05">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="10">October</month>
            <day>5</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.10.05.01">
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>To Brig. Gen. W. H. Koontz</head>
                <origin>Somerset Democrat</origin>
                <commentary>"We had no idea that such a blatant war man as General Koontz was, after
                    all, but a dunghill fowl, until we saw this article in the Democrat. Read it."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>H. G. &amp; G. F. Baer, late editors of Somerset Democrat</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Chastizes Brigadier General W. H. Koontz, Republican candidate for
                    Congress, for suggesting that Democratic newspapers celebrated when the Union
                    army was defeated in the First Battle of Bull Run.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Lesson it Teaches</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"In this day of national tribulation when the people have for four years
                    been watching the administration struggle in their feeble way to keep the rebels
                    out of Washington and out of the Northern States it will be refreshing, and will
                    be accepted as promising in the future, when the Democratic party, by unanimous
                    vote, proclaims that there can and shall be no peace save on the basis of the
                    federal union of States."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Suggests that Republicans who are frustrated that there is nothing in the
                    Democratic platform to render it offensive should recognize that there is no
                    viable option except the one provided by the Democrats.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Another Letter from Hon. Reverdy Johnson of Maryland</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"His [McClellan's] perfect devotion to the Union and his expressed
                    determination to make its restoration the 'one condition of peace'--the purity
                    of his character, his demonstrated ability, and his military attainments--
                    furnish guarantees, that in his hands the executive power will not be abused but
                    be directed in strict subordination to the Constitution, to the sole end of
                    restoring the Union."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Reverdy Johnson</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Senator Johnson, a Republican, explains why he will be voting for McClellan
                    in November.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>"Striking at the Cause"</head>
                <origin>Age</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that Lincoln's present policy is similar to what John C.
                    Breckinridge would have done had been elected president in 1860. Suggests that
                    Breckinridge would have forced the North into submission by making slavery a
                    national institution, using the sort of coercion that Lincoln is currently
                    relying on.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 1-4</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.10.05.02">
            <pageNote>Page 2 is missing.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.10.05.03">
            <pageNote>Page 3 is missing.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.10.05.04">
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 1-7</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
