<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1864/pa.fr.vs.1864.06.29">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Amy Murrell</taggerName>
            <tagDate>10/21/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 4/2/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1864-06-29">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="06">June</month>
            <day>29</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.06.29.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Dedication of the Site for the Battle Monument at West Point: Speech of
                    General McClellan</head>
                <origin>New York Tribune</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"At such a time as this, and in such a struggle, political partisanship
                    should be merged in a true and a brave patriotism, which thinks only of the good
                    of the whole country. It was in this cause and with these motives that so many
                    of our comrades have given their lives, and to this we are all personally
                    pledged in all honor and fidelity."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prints General McClellan's speech from a ceremony to dedicate a monument to
                    West Point graduates who have fallen in the war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Article covers the entire page.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.06.29.02">
            <pageNote>Fiction, columns 1-3, classified ads, columns 4-6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.06.29.03">
            <pageNote>Agricultural hints, column 1; classified ads, columns 2-6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.06.29.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Valley Spirit: For the Campaign</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We hope our Democratic friends will use their best exertions in furthering
                    the circulation of the paper by getting up clubs, thus aiding in the
                    dissemination of political truth among the people."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that the Valley Spirit will be furnished in folio form beginning
                    on August 3 through the Presidential election so that readers in remote areas
                    can be sure to have Democratic news.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Military Situation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The only real good news at hand is that the road south from Petersburg is
                    securely in possession of our army. This is no doubt an inconvenience to the
                    rebels, but that is all. It of itself effects no important object. We wish we
                    could write in a more hopeful strain; but the people are entitled to know the
                    truth."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The news from the front is not as encouraging as we could wish. Secretary
                        Stanton has ceased issuing war bulletins for the reason that our military
                        operations recently have been a series of defeats and disappoin[t]ments. The
                        disaster to a portion of our left wing on Wednesday last must have been a
                        severe mortification to the whole army. It seems the rebels succeeded in
                        capturing an entire brigade of Union troops. General Hunter's movement
                        against Lynchburg has also proved a failure. He was repulsed in the direct
                        attack upon that city, and now it is semi-officially announced that he is in
                        retreat to West Virginia. Thus ends the second combined movement against the
                        rebel capital. The first failed when Sigel was beaten in the Valley and
                        Butler failed in his assault upon Fort Darling. The second great combined
                        movement was to isolate the rebel capital by cutting off its communications
                        on every side. Grant himself was to capture Petersburg, Hunter Lynchburg,
                        and Sheridan was to destroy the Gordonsville Railroad. Each of these
                        movements has resulted in a failure, and General Grant must now form new
                        combinations. It is idle any longer to talk of starving out the rebels. The
                        roads northwest and southwest from Richmond are no longer even menaced. The
                        only real good news at hand is that the road south from Petersburg is
                        securely in possession of our army. This is no doubt an inconvenience to the
                        rebels, but that is all. It of itself effects no important object. We wish
                        we could write in a more hopeful strain; but the people are entitled to know
                        the truth.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Laments that Union forces have suffered a series of defeats in Virginia
                    recently.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The $300 Commutation Clause</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the US Senate voted to repeal the commutation clause of the
                    enrollment bill. The Spirit suggests that the substitute clause be repealed too.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"A rails-plitter [sic], having opportunities of culture and improving them,
                    may become a learned and able statesman; and a tailor by the same means, may
                    attain an exalted position and occupy it worthily; but a rail-splitting
                    'buffoon' is scarcely the man to whom the helm of a great nation should be
                    confided in the hour of its most imminent peril; nor is a 'boorish' tailor, best
                    fitted to preside in the most dignified body of the world."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph> seems to have been much exercised
                        by an article in a recent issue of our paper, copied as an editorial from
                        the New York <emph rend="italic">World</emph>, in which "Old Abe" is
                        denominated "a rail-splitting buffoon," and Andy Johnston "a boorish
                        tailor." The deduction by the <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph>
                        therefrom that "it (the SPIRIT) revolts at the propositions to elect a
                        laborer and a mechanic to the first offices of the nation" is, to say the
                        least of it, disingenuous, and as refreshing a specimen of claptrap as has
                        lately come under our notice. A rails-plitter [sic], having opportunities of
                        culture and improving them, may become a learned and able statesman; and a
                        tailor by the same means, may attain an exalted position and occupy it
                        worthily; but a rail-splitting "buffoon" is scarcely the man to whom the
                        helm of a great nation should be confided in the hour of its most imminent
                        peril; nor is a "boorish" tailor, best fitted to preside in the most
                        dignified body of the world. It is not only buffoons who are
                        "rail-splitters," and tailors who are "boors," that are unfitted for such
                        exalted positions as the presidency and Vice Presidency, in times like the
                        present. We would make the same objection to buffoons and boors from any
                        other station in life, whether lawyers, doctors, clergymen, or even
                        newspaper editors. If President Lincoln has shaken off his buffoonery and
                        risen up to the full standard of statesmanship required in his position by
                        the perils which environ the country, and if Andy Johnston has acquired, by
                        culture, sufficient knowledge to entitle him to respect in the sphere to
                        which he aspires, the fact that the one was a rail-splitter, and the other a
                        tailor, would not, in our opinion, unfit them for the highest positions ever
                        attained by mortal men; but if "Abe," when he ceased splitting rails, still
                        remained a buffoon, and "Andy," when he relinquished an honest calling to
                        play demagogue, still remained a boor--as we have good reason to believe is
                        the case--we have nothing to take back, and are free to say that this
                        precious pair of worthies are not the men to manage with credit to
                        themselves, or profit to the country, the affairs of this great Republic in
                        a contest, which, if controlled much longer by unskilled hands, may prove
                        its death struggle.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Authors defend themselves against criticism from the Repository about the
                    Valley Spirit's language in a recent article about Lincoln's and Johnson's
                    renominations.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>General McClellan's Oration</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Calls General McClellan's speech at West Point "one of the finest
                    productions of modern times."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Suggests that rather than criticizing General McClellan for leaving
                    Washington exposed, Republican papers should turn their attention to Lincoln's
                    "broken pledge" to provide McClellan with assistance.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Rejection of Hamlin</head>
                <origin>Johnstown Democrat</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Hamlin has always been a violent advocate of negro emancipation,
                    miscegenation, &amp;c., and has never raised his voice in denunciation of
                    the rascalities and corruptions of his party."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Supports the decision of delegates to the Baltimore Republican Convention
                    to keep Hannibal Hamlin's name off the ticket for Vice President.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Abraham's Pets</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"This is how the negroes stay in the South, as we were told they would by
                    our Abolition friends. This is how they are taken care of and feasted on the fat
                    of the land while soldiers families are suffering the pangs of want--not to
                    mention the fact that poor white Union refugees are daily starving for food and
                    perishing of hardships."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Says the N.Y. <emph rend="italic">Herald's</emph> Washington correspondent:
                        "Over a thousand contrabands arrived here to-day from the White House, and
                        were sent to Colonel Green's Freedman's Colony. All the men able to work are
                        employed in the Quarter master's Department. The Colony is in a most
                        thriving condition, having three thousand acres under a high state of
                        cultivation, and crops of wheat and rye that promise a harvest valued at ten
                        thousand dollars." This is how the negroes stay in the South, as we were
                        told they would by our Abolition friends. This is how they are taken care of
                        and feasted on the fat of the land while soldiers families are suffering the
                        pangs of want--not to mention the fact that poor white Union refugees are
                        daily starving for food and perishing of hardships.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Opposes the good conditions in which blacks live at a Freedman's Colony in
                    New York.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Another Convict Pardoned</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the Pennsylvania Governor has pardoned a black soldier who
                    shot and killed a white man at Camp William Penn last fall.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Fourth of July</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We are sorry to observe of late years, a decreasing interest, on the part
                    of our citizens in properly celebrating the nation's birth-day and would be
                    pleased to again participate in an old-fashioned celebration, Spread-Eagle
                    'oration,' 'regular toasts,' 'volunteer toasts' and all."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The an[n]iversary of our National Independence is fast approaching, but as
                        yet we have heard of no arrangement being in progress, in our midst, for its
                        proper observance. We are sorry to observe of late years, a decreasing
                        interest, on the part of our citizens in properly celebrating the nation's
                        birth-day and would be pleased to again participate in an old-fashioned
                        celebration, Spread-Eagle "oration," "regular toasts," "volunteer toasts"
                        and all. For upwards of eighty years our country has been blessed beyond all
                        the nations of the earth, enjoying a degree of happiness and prosperity
                        without a parallel, all resulting from the actions of our fathers on the 4th
                        day of July 1776. This accursed rebellion now afflicting our beloved
                        country, fostered and kept alive as it is, by the mistaken policy of those
                        who are charged with its suppression must end sometime, and prosperity and
                        peace once more bless us with their smiles. Let us, then, keep up the usual
                        celebration of the day, even during the present troubles of the country:
                        hoping that in the end we may have another day on which to celebrate the
                        re-union of these states under the constitution our fathers gave us, and
                        under the folds of that Star Spangled flag, which for eig[h]ty-eight years,
                        has been as a beacon to the oppressed of all nations, and the pride and
                        glory of a free people.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges readers to celebrate the Fourth of July in spite of the present
                    sectional hostilities.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Haying</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that because this region has been spared from troops moving through
                    in recent months, this year's hay crop is an excellent one.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Wounded</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mathews</ln>
                        <fn>D.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Williams</ln>
                        <fn>John S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sonem</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Iser</ln>
                        <fn>Wesley</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Conner</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Polk</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lists injuries received recently by members of the 107th Pennsylvania
                    Volunteers: Capt. D. S. Mathews, Company I, leg, severe; Lieut. John S.
                    Williams, Company F, abdomen, severe; Private Daniel Sonem, Company I, shoulder,
                    slight; Private S. Jones, Company K, ankle, severe; Private Wesley Iser, Company
                    B, neck, severe; Private John Campbell, Company C, toe, slight; Private James
                    Conner, Company H, thigh, severe; Private Thomas Polk, Company I, knee, slight.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.06.29.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Terrible Accident</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that David Holler was involved in an accident with his mower that
                    resulted in the amputation of his leg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>21st Penna Cavalry</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyd</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mosham</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lt. Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillis</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Major</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Major</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes that since the 21st Pennsylvania Cavalry has been moved to the front,
                    three officers have been injured and only one--Major Bell--is left to take
                    command.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Colored Substitutes</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It is said that Provost Marshal General Fry has issued instructions to the
                        various Provost Marshals that, under existing laws, they can receive or
                        accept colored substitutes for white persons. The decision will naturally
                        cause a great reduction of the rates demanded for white substitutes.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the Provost Marshal has authorized the enlistment of black
                    substitutes for white persons.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Vocal and Instrumental Concert</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that the Young Ladies of the Seminary will be giving a concert
                    next Thursday evening at 8 o'clock in Franklin Hall. Proceeds will go to the
                    Christian Commission.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McHenry</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henry</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peifer</ln>
                        <fn>Lizzie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On June 16, Rev. S. McHenry married Andrew Henry and Lizzie Peifer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coble</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coble</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clugston</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clugston</ln>
                        <fn>Caroline</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On June 2, Rebecca Susan Coble, wife of George Coble, Jr., and daughter of
                    Robert and Caroline Clugston, died at age 26 years, 5 months and 3 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burkholder</ln>
                        <fn>Christian</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Christian Burkholder died on June 22 at age 63 years, 6 months and 17
                    days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shank</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On June 16, the infant child of Isaac Shank died at age 28 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoeppler</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoeppler</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoeppler</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Stoeppler, son of Andrew and Mary Stoeppler, died on June 26 at age
                    2 years, 1 month and 11 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 2-6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.06.29.06">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Congress</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Summarizes recent proceedings of the US Congress, including a successful
                    vote in the Senate to eliminate the commutation clause of the enrollment act.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Bill Increasing the Pay of Soldiers is Now a Law</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the President has approved legislation that will increase the
                    pay of soldiers in the US army.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Dispatches describing troop movement near Petersburg, Virginia, columns 1-2,
                classified ads, columns 3-6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.06.29.07">
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 1-6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.06.29.08">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Latest Telegraphic News!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"On Saturday night the rebels made an attack on our pickets about the
                    centre of our line as they were being relieved but were repulsed with little or
                    no loss to our troops."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>[By the Atlantic and Ohio Telegraph Line--Office in Shryock's Book Store and
                        at the Depot.]</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Reported Expressly for</emph> THE VALLEY SPIRIT.</p>
                    <p>Latest from the Army of the Potomac.</p>
                    <p>Washington, June 27.</p>
                    <p>The steamer Highland Light, arrived here at 11 o'clock from City Point which
                        place she left at 11 o'clo[c]k yesterday morning.</p>
                    <p>The Highland Light brought up the 8th Ohio volunteers, 151 officers and men.</p>
                    <p>There has been no very heavy firing within the last few days, but skirmishing
                        is kept up all along the line. The cannonading at times is heard. Firing was
                        heard about 5 miles from Bermuda Hundred on Saturday, where General Butler
                        is entrenched.</p>
                    <p>The enemy made an attack upon Butler's entrenchments but did not succeed in
                        effecting anything and were driven off. On Saturday the rebels attacked
                        Sheridan's rear at Wilcox's landing, and captured a few of his men.</p>
                    <p>A brigade of Infantry was at once despatched to protect Sheridan's rear, and
                        the enemy was kept back till Sheridan had succeeded in crossing the river
                        with the entire train.</p>
                    <p>The Railroad is advanced five miles from City Point toward Petersburg.</p>
                    <p>Yesterday, just before the Highland Light left, heavy firing was heard in the
                        direction of Petersburg. On Saturday night the rebels made an attack on our
                        pickets about the centre of our line as they were being relieved but were
                        repulsed with little or no loss to our troops.</p>
                    <p>On the Heights beyond Petersburg the rebels have an 18 gun battery bearing
                        upon the centre of our line in front of that place. This battery has been
                        very troublesome and so far has proved too heavy for any artillery that we
                        have brought against it.</p>
                    <p>Wilson has gone on another cavalry expedition and good news from him may be
                        expected soon.</p>
                    <p>A rebel Captain and four privates came into Butler's lines on Friday and took
                        the oath of allegiance.</p>
                    <p>Two hundred rebel prisoners were at City Point yesterday morning.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes skirmishing around Petersburg and unsuccessful Confederate
                    charges on Union entrenchments.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Latest News By the Mails!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The War Department today received information from Gen. Hunter's command,
                    which, having fulfilled the mission on which it was sent, (the destruction of
                    the Central railroad in the vicinity of Stanton, and the Gordonville and
                    Lynchburg railroad and an important portion of the James River canal.) is
                    successfully pressing forward to the point in Western Virginia, to which it was
                    ordered."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>General Grant's Army. <lb/>Wilson's Cavalry Destroying the Track of the
                        Weldon Railroad--The Second and Sixth Corps Moved Toward the Railroad Lee
                        Attempts to Turn our Right Flank--The Second Corps Meets H-- Corps--An
                        Engagement Ensues--The Twelfth New York Artillery Loses Four Guns Heavy
                        Firing in front of the Nineth Corps--Return of the Third Excelsior Regiment.</p>
                    <p>H.Q. Army of the Potomac, <lb/>June 23--6, A.M.</p>
                    <p>Wilson's division of cavalry have moved off in the direction of the Weldon
                        Railroad. When last heard from they had reached Reim's Station, and were
                        tearing up the track.</p>
                    <p>The Second and Sixth Corps moved from their old position on the right toward
                        the Weldon Railroad.</p>
                    <p>Lee seems to have anticipated a movement by our left, and determined to turn
                        our right flank.</p>
                    <p>When near the Jerusalem Plank Road, the Second Corps was confronted by Gen.
                        Hill's Corps, and a smart engagement ensued.</p>
                    <p>A battery of the Twelfth New York Artillery was annoying the Rebels, who
                        succeeded in getting round in the flank, and charged it.</p>
                    <p>The infantry support being surprised, retired, leaving four guns in the hands
                        of the enemy; but our line of battle was soon reformed.</p>
                    <p>The men had become accustomed to Lee's new practice of acting entirely on the
                        defensive, and must have been confused by his bold assault.</p>
                    <p>Two divisions of the Fifth Corps were within easy supporting distance on the
                        right, and the Sixth was ready for any hostilities on the left.</p>
                    <p>Several charges were made by the Rebels, who suffered severely.</p>
                    <p>There was heavy firing in front of the Ninth Corps about midnight. At times
                        the musketry broke out into regular volleys. The firing lasted all night.</p>
                    <p>H.Q. Army of the Potomac, June 24.</p>
                    <p>Maj. Holt, of the First Massachusetts, is slightly wounded.</p>
                    <p>It is reported that the Seventeenth New York battery has lost four guns by
                        being surprised.</p>
                    <p>Skirmishing was continued all last night on our left, but with what result is
                        not yet known.</p>
                    <p>The Third Excelsior Regiment, Lieut. Col. Leonard Commanding, will leave
                        here, to morrow, for home, their term of service having expired. This
                        regiment participated in all the battles of the Peninsula, under Gen.
                        McClellan,a nd with the exception of Antietam, all those in which the Army
                        of the Potomac have been engaged.</p>
                    <p>Fortress Monroe, <lb/>June 28--5 P.M.</p>
                    <p>The mail steamer <emph rend="italic">Charles Vandebilt</emph>, from Bermuda
                        Hundred, reports no fighting up to 10 o'clock this morning.</p>
                    <p>There is nothing later from the Whtie House, and no particulars from Sheridan
                        since his arrival there.</p>
                    <p>General Grant's Army. <lb/>Details of Wednesday's Right on the Weldon
                        Railroad From Gen. Hunter.</p>
                    <p>H.Q. Army of the Potomac, June 23.</p>
                    <p>The attack upon the Second corps on Wednesday, near the Weldon railroad, did
                        not result so disastrously as was at first supposed.</p>
                    <p>The line was formed by Barlow's division being on the left, Birney's (Gen.
                        Mott in command) on the centre, and Gibbons on the right.</p>
                    <p>It was expected that the Sixth Corps would have connected on the left with
                        Burlow, but it seems quite a gap was left, into which A.P. Hill's corps
                        entered, and before our men were aware of it they had received a volley from
                        the rear which created a panic in the ranks and caused a rapid retreat to
                        the woods in the rear of the third division.</p>
                    <p>This left the flank of the third division unprotected, and the enemy, taking
                        advantage of it, charged through and fairly late the rifle pits, ordering
                        our men to surrender.</p>
                    <p>The troops, however, left the trenches and fell back rapidly, but many of
                        them were captured and quite a number killed and wounded.</p>
                    <p>Our loss in prisoners is reported at about 1,000 while some make the figure
                        higher. Our loss in killed and wounded is probably 1,500.</p>
                    <p>Four officers engaged in this fight had just joined their commands after
                        being exchanged, and when surrounded and ordered to surrender replied,
                        "Never! death rather than Libby!" and fighting their way as best they could,
                        several of them got back safe.</p>
                    <p>At 8 p.m., a change was made by the 2d corps and the line of works from which
                        they had been forced in the afternoon recovered.</p>
                    <p>We lost scarcely a man in this advance, as the enemy fired too high and the
                        balls all passed over the heads of our men.</p>
                    <p>A number of prisoners were taken.</p>
                    <p>Skirmishing was kept up all night along the line, the pickets being at some
                        points not more than 50 yards apart.</p>
                    <p>At daylight this morning an advance of the entire line was made, when it was
                        found the enemy had taken a new position, some distance further back, where
                        they had thrown up strong entrenchments during the night, which they still
                        hold.</p>
                    <p>Col. Blaisdell, 11th Mass., was killed today by a sharpshooter while visiting
                        the skirmish line.</p>
                    <p>W. H. Child of the 45th Pennsylvania regiment, who was but a few days ago
                        promoted from Sergeant Major of the regiment, to Lieutenant of Co. F. of the
                        same, was shot dead by a rebel sharpshooter on Tuesday evening.</p>
                    <p>The 6th Corps moved towards the railroad this morning, driving the enemy
                        before them and during the afternoon reported that they were in possession
                        of the road, and arrangements were at once made to destroy it.</p>
                    <p>At 5 p.m., a large force of the enemy were seen moving towards the the [sic]
                        front as if to resist the advance of the 6th corps. An engagement in that
                        direction is expected tonight.</p>
                    <p>June 24--5 P.M.--Nothing but picket firing took place during the evening or
                        night, and very little is going on this morning.</p>
                    <p>From Gen. Hunter's Command.</p>
                    <p>The War Department today received information from Gen. Hunter's command,
                        which, having fulfilled the mission on which it was sent, (the destruction
                        of the Central railroad in the vicinity of Stanton, and the Gordonville and
                        Lynchburg railroad and an important portion of the James River canal.) is
                        successfully pressing forward to the point in Western Virginia, to which it
                        was ordered.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the President has approved legislation that will increase the
                    pay of soldiers in the US army.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 1-6</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
