<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1864/pa.fr.vs.1864.01.06">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andrew Morris, first pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 3/3/98</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1864-01-06">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day>6</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.01.06.01">
            <div type="l">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Our Washington Letter</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Conococheague</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>A correspondent to the Spirit and Times writes of an anecdote regarding a
                    Treasury Department official whose responsibility it was to burn old demand
                    notes. In fact, he had been discovered hoarding the notes for his own use. The
                    writer uses this as an illustration of the general corruption of the
                    administration, claiming "that there has never been an administration in
                    Washington under which fraud was carried on as openly and boldly as now." He
                    goes on to add that the exchange of prisoners with the Confederates has broken
                    down because of the dispute over the status of black soldiers. An order was also
                    issued prohibiting the recruitment of black soldiers in Washington by agents
                    from the Northern states.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Includes a list of advertisers in the issue, and an indictment of Charles
                Sumner and Massachusetts for being hypocritical on the slavery issue, in view of
                that state's record with Indian tribes.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.01.06.02">
            <pageNote>Fiction and classified advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.01.06.03">
            <pageNote>Poetry and four columns of classified advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.01.06.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Mr. Niccolls on the War</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Whatever we may say will be said in kindness and respect, for we entertain
                    the deepest regard for the gentleman. We shall not assail him, but confine
                    ourselves to refuting his fallacies."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Niccolls</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The editors attempt to refute, point by point, a sermon given by Rev.
                    Samuel J. Niccolls, "the zealous and eloquent pastor" of the Chambersburg
                    Presbyterian Church, which was published in the Repository on December 23.
                    First, they argue, the law has not retained its supremacy in the country, as
                    evidenced by the suspension of habeas corpus. Second, the country is not in a
                    state of prosperity, as Niccolls would like to claim. Third, Niccolls' assertion
                    that slavery is a crime contradicts both the intention of the framers of the
                    Constitution and Biblical law. The editors argue that slavery for blacks is set
                    out in the Bible. If Niccolls chooses to preach against it, he is no longer
                    preaching the Gospel.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>The rebuttal to Niccolls takes up five out of six columns.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.01.06.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>New Year's Eve</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"This shooting away of the old year is a relic of barbarism, which we think
                    it is about time to do away with. Nobody enjoys it except for the little urchins
                    who participate, and it is seven day's wonder some of them hadn't their heads
                    blown off. Boys, better save your powder for the rebels."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors condemn the practice of firing off weapons on New Year's Eve.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Death of Archbishop Hughes</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hughes</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Archbishop</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hughes</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Archbishop Hughes of the Catholic Church of New York died recently. He was
                    a native of Ireland and a former resident of Chambersburg. His brother Michael
                    still lives in Franklin County. Hughes was appointed Archbishop in 1850.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>House Burned</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guyer</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The house of John B. Guyer in Mount Pleasant caught fire from the chimney
                    on Thursday, December 24, and was entirely consumed. The family was absent at
                    the time, and nothing was rescued from the house.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Another Fire</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The old distillery on the farm of Joseph C. Kennedy, southwest of town,
                    burned last Monday from some coal tar being heated on the stove. Word was sent
                    at once to town, but it was difficult to get the fire engines across the
                    Conococheague. The building was almost entirely consumed by the time the engines
                    arrived. It is understood that most of the valuable machinery had been removed
                    prior to the fire.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Sudden Death</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"He was sitting, as we are informed, in his own house in the enjoyment of
                    his usual health, when he suddenly fell from his chair a corpse."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Over</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>David Over of Strasburg died suddenly on Tuesday, December 29 of heart
                    disease. He was a "highly respected and useful citizen," and will be missed. He
                    was 58.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Another Death</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGrath</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGrath</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sheriff</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Thomas McGrath died suddenly at the home of his brother, the sheriff, on
                    Friday afternoon. He went to his room in his usual health and was found a few
                    minutes later, face down on his bed, dead. "He was an industrious and worthy
                    man," conclude the editors.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Sunday School Festival</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wightman</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Niccolls</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The children of the Presbyterian Sunday School were treated to a festival
                    on New Year's Eve. Rev. J. W. Wightman of Greencastle and Rev. Niccolls
                    addressed the scholars. The scholars then sang several pieces of sacred music,
                    and were then each given a present of a package of sweetmeats. The church was
                    beautifully decorated, and the exercises "were of a peculiarly interesting
                    character."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>A Rebel Raid</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We have come to believe that speculation upon army movements amounts to
                    very little, and have concluded patiently to wait the upshot of events . . . "</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>There are indications that the rebel General Early comtemplates [sic] a
                        movement up the Valley of Virginia, and perhaps on this side of the Potomac.
                        He has been hovering, with a considerable force, about Strasburg: and the
                        last advices [sic] from Winchester state that our pickets have been driven
                        in. We have come to believe that speculation upon army movements amounts to
                        very little, and have concluded patiently to wait the upshot of events; we
                        advise our readers to "Keep their powder dry" and follow the same
                    course.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>There are rumors that General Early is contemplating a raid up the Valley
                    of Virginia, though the editors do not put much stock in it.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Banner Town</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors print a report from Greencastle which informs them that that
                    town has filled its quota of volunteers with a subscription drive for bounties.
                    The editors ask, "Is there any valid reason why Chambersburg should not be the
                    second on the list?"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Recruiting Station</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ward</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strickler</ln>
                        <fn>Snively</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Captain Ward of Company D, 11th Pennsylvania Cavalry, has been detailed to
                    open a recruiting office in Chambersburg. His office is in the room lately
                    occupied by Snively Strickler, Esq., and any patriotic citizens who "wish to
                    accept the large bounties now offered by the Government and the Borough of
                    Chambersburg" should go see him.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Re-enlistments Credited on Quota</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The War Department has decided to credit the states with the men who have
                    re-enlisted, as part of their quota of 300,000. It is expected that 75,000 men
                    will be obtained in that way; 120,000 more are expected to volunteer, leaving
                    about 100,000 to be drafted.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>A Large Porker</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Berger</ln>
                        <fn>Lawrence</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lawrence Berger of Hamilton Township recently slaughtered a two-year-old
                    hog which yielded over 600 pounds of clean meat.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>From the Valley of Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A report of a skirmish between the 21st Penn. Cavalry and a Confederate
                    party near Winchester. General Early is reportedly in Middletown with 5,000 men.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnhart</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Metcalf</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paxton</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paxton</ln>
                        <fn>W. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Thomas Metcalf and Sarah Paxton (daughter of Hon. W. W. Paxton), of
                    Chambersburg, were married on January 5.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rider</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fritz</ln>
                        <fn>Jinnie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnhart</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Michael Rider of Peters Township, and Jinnie Fritz of Warren Township, were
                    married on December 29.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deatrich</ln>
                        <fn>W. R. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davison</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>Martha A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John B. Davison and Martha A. Young (eldest daughter of Jacob Young, Esq.)
                    of Antrim Township were married on December 29 at the residence of the bride's
                    parents.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Over</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>David Over died on December 29 at age 59.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Goldsmith</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Private W. H. Goldsmith of Company L, 21st Penn. Cavalry, died on January 3
                    in Fayetteville, aged 18 years, 10 months and 3 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Includes war news from Charleston and classified advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.01.06.06">
            <pageNote>Classified advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.01.06.07">
            <pageNote>Agricultural advice and classified advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.01.06.08">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Next President--Who Shall He be</head>
                <origin>Journal of Commerce</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Already the idiosyncrasies of the present administration, its peculiar
                    ways of doing things, its assumption of authority without limit, and looking to
                    no end all begin to seem historic . . ."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The writers suggest that the next president should be a man from outside
                    Washington, youthful, with military experience--strong, skillful, and free of
                    the influences of "old political bonds."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Four columns of classified advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
