<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1864/pa.fr.vs.1864.01.13">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andrew Morris, first pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 3/4/98</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1864-01-13">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day>13</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.01.13.01">
            <div type="l">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Correspondence--Our Washington Letter</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Conococheague</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>This correspondent to the Spirit and Times begins by criticizing the lavish
                    entertainments of Mrs. Lincoln and the reported exclusion of people who are not
                    well dressed from the Presidential home. In other news, he reports work on
                    amendments to the conscription bill, a proposal to extend the payment of
                    bounties until March 5, and discussion of a direct rail line between Washington
                    and New York that could possibly run through the Cumberland Valley.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Includes reprints of letters from General McClellan to Lincoln during 1862 on
                the larger political character of the rebellion.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.01.13.02">
            <pageNote>Fiction, anecdotes, and classified advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.01.13.03">
            <pageNote>Agricultural advice and classified advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.01.13.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Let us Go to Work</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"But what are we doing? Has our patriotism expended itself in noisy
                    declamation and vain boasting? If the rebellion is to be suppressed, our armies
                    must be recruited up to the old standard, before the opening of the next
                    campaign; and Chambersburg and Franklin county must do their share."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We people of Chambersburg and Franklin county, of whatever political party,
                        profess to be heartily in favor of suppressing the rebellion, and of giving
                        all the money and men necessary to accomplish that end. Whatever be our
                        differences of political belief, we all think alike on this one question.
                        But what are we doing? Has our patriotism expended itself in noisy
                        declamation and vain boasting? If the rebellion is to be suppressed, our
                        armies must be recruited up to the old standard, before the opening of the
                        next campaign; and Chambersburg and Franklin county must do their share.
                        Congress is about to continue the time for recruiting one or two months
                        longer; and during that period we will either have to fill our quota by
                        volunteering, or be subject to another draft. Drafts, as we all know, are
                        not very pleasant things; and self-interest, as well as town and county
                        pride, should prompt us to lend our whole energies to the work of filling
                        our quota. Let us lay aside crimination and recrimination, and prove the
                        sincerity of our professions. It is not enough simply to offer large
                        bounties; what we need is systematic, personal exertion--the exertion of men
                        of influence and property. Whatever opinions we may entertain of the policy
                        of the administration, however much we may disapprove of the reckless
                        fanaticism of the party in power, we are still bound to aid in sustaining
                        the majesty of the law, in suppressing revolt and insurrection, and in
                        restoring the fabric of our once glorious Union. To this noble purpose let
                        us, one and all, consecrate the honest labor of a few brief weeks, and
                        success will attend our efforts. The time has passed for windy patriotism
                        and vapid boasting. If we really wish to accomplish anything, we must go to
                        work heart and hand. Greencastle was the first town in the State which
                        filled its quota, let us see if Franklin cannot be the first county.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors call for community leaders to exert themselves in procuring
                    volunteers to fill up Franklin County's quota.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Inconsistency of Abolitionism</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors attack the Lincoln administration and its Congressional allies
                    for inconsistency on a number of fronts. Lincoln claimed to have the authority
                    to suspend habeas corpus on his own, but then Congress passed a bill authorizing
                    it and indemnifying those exercising that authority. If Lincoln had the power to
                    take such action in the first place, why were the bills needed? Similarly, with
                    the emancipation proclamation, Congress soon after produced a bill giving power
                    to the president's proclamation. If Lincoln had the authority to free slaves in
                    the first place, whey was this bill needed? Then, when the conscription bill was
                    passed, volunteers dropped off, and the administration turned back to
                    volunteering as if they had never advocated conscription.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>No Presidential Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors note the importance of this year's presidential election, but
                    also report rumors that Lincoln, if defeated, may try to retain power, "backed
                    by a negro army of 300,000."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Meeting of the Legislature</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Pennsylvania House of Representatives recently organized itself, with
                    Mr. Johnson, a Republican from Crawford County, as Speaker. However, the Senate,
                    with an equal number of Democrats and Republicans, remains unorganized, though
                    the Democrats proposed an alternation of the offices, with the Republicans
                    getting the Speaker and Democrats the Clerk, and so-on down.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Includes reports of cavalry skirmishes near Harper's Ferry.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.01.13.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Cumberland Valley Rail Road</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Watts</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bacon</ln>
                        <fn>Josiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Edmund</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henderson</ln>
                        <fn>W. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scott</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Biddle</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>J. Edgar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lombaert</ln>
                        <fn>H. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gehr</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hulme</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Knight</ln>
                        <fn>E. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Biddle</ln>
                        <fn>Edward M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lull</ln>
                        <fn>O. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Morris</ln>
                        <fn>Wistar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The directors of the Cumberland Valley Rail Road issued their 29th Annual
                    Report. Included were the damages caused by the Confederate raids. These
                    included: temporary construction of a bridge at Carlisle, $3,410.55; Estimate
                    for permanent structure, $3,566; first temporary construction of bridge at
                    Scotland, $727.35; second temporary construction of same bridge, $3,743.96;
                    repairs of damages on bridge, $75; reconstruction of buildings at Chambersburg,
                    $6,964.63; new T-iron, lumber, wood destroyed and stolen, $9,629--a total of
                    $6,115.49 (less $7,845 for 224 tons of T-iron left on road). Damages to the
                    Franklin Rail Road were: cost of reconstruction and estimate for completion of
                    road, water tower, etcetera: $20,084.07 (less $5,167.65 for 147 tons of T-iron
                    left on road). Officers of the company are: President, Hon. Frederick Watts;
                    Managers, Josiah Bacon, Edmund Smith, W. H. Henderson, Thomas B. Kennedy, Thomas
                    A. Scott, Thomas A. Biddle, J. Edgar Thompson, H. J. Lombaert, Daniel Gehr,
                    Wistar Morris, John Hulme, E. C. Knight; Secretary and Treasurer, Edward M.
                    Biddle; Superintendent, O. N. Lull.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>At Home</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dixon</ln>
                        <fn>William D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut. Colonel</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davison</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lieut. Colonel William D. Dixon, and Capt. Joseph A. Davison, of the 6th
                    Penn. Reserves, have been at home on a short visit. The 6th has been in almost
                    every major engagement from "Dranesville to Gettysburg," and its ranks are
                    severely depleted. However, the editors hope the unit will be refilled soon.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The "Cold Snap"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors note the severity of the cold the past week and ask people to
                    remember the troops in the field, "protected by nothing but a thin shelter tent,
                    or doing guard duty among snow and ice." They then go on to note that the
                    skating has been excellent.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Common Schools</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shoemaker</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The editors reprint extracts from the Pennsylvania School Report of 1863
                    and the report of Mr. Shoemaker, the former Superintendent. Five new school
                    houses were built in the county last year, four in the place of old ones and one
                    new one--one in Greencastle, two in Guilford, one in Montgomery, and one in
                    Washington. There are 204 school houses in the county, 50 new ones having been
                    built since 1857. The average number of scholars increased about 1200, though
                    attendance fell off last year by 500, "occasioned by Stuart's raid." One hundred
                    and thirty three of the teachers rendered general satisfaction, eighty three
                    were medium, and nine were poor. The Scriptures were "read regularly, and used
                    for purposes of moral instruction," in 193 schools. The prevailing public mood
                    is supportive, "yet there are still some who are opposed to certain features of
                    the system."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Horrible Railroad Accident</head>
                <origin>Patriot and Union</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kunkel</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reasner</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Kunkel, a shifter employed by the Pennsylvania railroad, was killed
                    near the round house by one of the trains he was separating. Kunkel was a former
                    resident of Franklin County and brother-in-law of John Reasner.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Masonic Appointments</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Robert A. Lamberton of Harrisburg was appointed Deputy G. H. P. for the
                    counties of Dauphin, Cumberland, Franklin, and Lebanon. He was also appointed
                    Deputy Grand Master of the Third Masonic District, composed of Dauphin,
                    Franklin, Cumberland, Juniata, Perry, and Lebanon.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Trains Delayed</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The delay in the passenger train on the Cumberland Valley Rail Road last
                    Thursday noon was caused by the rear car running off the track when the train
                    was backing up at Mechanicsburg. All the rumors in town about the accident
                    proved to be greatly exaggerated.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>End of the Game Season</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Sportsmen are reminded that anyone killing a partridge after the first of
                    January is liable to a five-dollar fine, and the editors add that "no true
                    sportsman will violate the law."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Look Out for Them</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Lancaster papers warn of a new counterfeit in circulation--a photograph
                    of the genuine five dollar note on the Union Bank of Philadelphia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Draft Postponed</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spirit reprints letters by President Lincoln, the Secretary of War, and
                    the Provost Marshal General to Congress that ask it to extend the deadline for
                    the federal bounty for volunteers. The letter writers state that they would
                    rather continue to encourage volunteering than have to resort to a draft.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Banker</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Banker</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary Catharine Banker, youngest daughter of Mr. Andrew Banker, died in
                    Chambersburg last Friday morning after a protracted illness, aged 16 years, 8
                    months and 2 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Money Wanted</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seilhamer</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Borough of Chambersburg desires a loan of $6,000 for the purposed of
                    furnishing a bounty to volunteers to fill the Borough's quota under the last
                    call. George Seilhamer, secretary of the Town Council, adds, "It is hoped
                    patriotic citizens will come forward at once to take the above loan."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Volunteers Wanted</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Borough of Chambersburg will pay a bounty of $200 in addition to the
                        regular Government bounties to persons desiring to volunteer under the
                        present call. An appeal is made to patriotic citizens (white or black) to
                        accept this liberal offer and thus to fill up the Armies of the Union and at
                        the same time avoid the coming draft.</p>
                    <p>By order of the Town Council, <lb/>Dec 30, '63. <lb/>E. C. Boyd.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seilhamer</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Borough of Chambersburg will pay a bounty of $200 in addition to the
                    regular government bounties to persons who will volunteer under the present
                    call. The Town Council urges "patriotic citizens" to step forward so as to avoid
                    the draft.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.01.13.06">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>News From the South</head>
                <origin>Richmond Sentinel, Macon (Georgia) Confederacy</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A collection of short articles from papers across the South. The principal
                    article notes that President Lincoln has been forced to deal with the South as a
                    belligerent nation, as humiliating as it must be to him and his supporters.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Five columns of classified advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.01.13.07">
            <pageNote>Humor and five columns of classified advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.01.13.08">
            <pageNote>Includes a list of Pennsylvania State Senators and Representatives, a list of
                advertisers, and four columns of classified advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
