<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1864/pa.fr.vs.1864.07.13">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Amy Murrell</taggerName>
            <tagDate>10/21/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 4/22/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1864-07-13">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day>13</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.07.13.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The New Enrollment Act</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Provides transcript of the most recent military enrollment act to be passed
                    by the US Congress.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Lincoln Upon the Battle-Field</head>
                <origin>Essex Statesman</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We know that this story is incredible, that it is impossible that a man
                    who could be elected President of the United States could conduct himself over
                    the fresh made graves of the heroic dead."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Tells about a rumor that President Lincoln ordered a comical song sung when
                    he recently visited places where soldiers have died.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>General Sturgis</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Accuses Republican newspapers of hypocrisy, since they have often called
                    for the removal of Democratic army officer who failed to achieve victories but
                    have not held Republican officers to the same standards.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Proclamation by Gov. Curtin</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prints a copy of a proclamation made by Pennsylvania Governor Andrew Curtin
                    that calls for 12,000 more men to volunteer for service.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Latest Telegraphic News!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The rebels attacked the train at Magnolia. They went through the train
                    after we had stopped capturing all officers and soldiers on the train, among the
                    was Maj. Gen. Franklin. They went through most of the passenger's pockets
                    capturing watches and money."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>[By the Atlantic and Ohio Telegraphic Line--Offices in Shryock's Book Store
                        and at the Depot.]<lb/></p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Reported Expressly for</emph> THE VALLEY SPIRIT. Rebels
                        at Magnolia on the Philadelphia and Baltimore R.R.<lb/> Two Trains Captured
                        and Burned. <lb/>General Franklin taken Prisoner. <lb/>Fighting Near
                        Washington. <lb/>Residence of F.P. Blair Reported Burned, &amp;c.,
                        &amp;c.</p>
                    <p>Havre de Grace, Md., July 11.</p>
                    <p>About 200 rebel cavalry under command of Harry Gilmore, appeared at Magnolia
                        Station 18 miles south of this point, on the Phila. and Balt. Railroad and
                        captured the 8:30 a.m. passenger train, from Baltimore, by firing a volley
                        into it, causing the train to stop. The 10 o'clock express train from
                        Baltimore also shared the same fate. Conductor Breyson of the express was
                        robbed of his watch and money as was Conductor Munshower of the first train.</p>
                    <p>The rebels fired the trains and also the freight house at Magnolia, which
                        were consumed. One of the engines was fired up, reversed and started towards
                        Gunpowder Bridge, for the purpose of setting fire to that structure, but it
                        is very probable that no damage resulted to the bridge from the fact that a
                        heavy guard was stationed to protect it.</p>
                    <p>Passengers were not, as far as learned, molested, except in a very few cases.</p>
                    <p>The rebels started in a southerly direction toward General Cadwalader's
                        residence, a few miles south for the purpose of destroying it, and this has
                        no doubt been accomplished.</p>
                    <p>Passengers are arriving here in every kind of vehicles and many on horseback.</p>
                    <p>A battery and a half of nine guns from the Philadelphia Navy Yard, arrived
                        here to-day and one section proceeded to near Magnolia, where the rebels
                        were discovered in force, causing the section to return.</p>
                    <p>What are the future intentions of the rebels in this vicinity, are of course
                        conjecture, but the general impression is that they will retreat under cover
                        of the darkness.</p>
                    <p>The Steam Ferry boat Maryland is safe and the town and ferry are well
                        defended by the presence of the gunboat Currituck, whose guns command all
                        the approaches. Large detachments of troops and marines from the
                        Philadelphia Navy Yard are here with other forces, and the country is
                        scoured by our scouts.</p>
                    <p>There is no truth in the reported burning of the Conowago bridge over the
                        Susquehanna ten miles north of this.</p>
                    <p>The telegraph north of this point is badly damaged, but the railroad is not
                        thought to be injured to any great extent.</p>
                    <p>Harry Gilmore avows his intention of going into Baltimore.</p>
                    <p>To-night artillery firing has been heard since 8 p.m. in a southwest
                        direction, perhaps at Beech river.</p>
                    <p>Philadelphia, July 11.</p>
                    <p>Information has been received by President Fulton, of the P.W. &amp;
                        Baltimore railroad that [sic] the gunpowder bridge has not been destroyed.
                        The rebels were attacked by a gunboat as they were about to set it on fire
                        and driven off. An engine was recaptured and is now on the way to Havre de
                        Grace. It is supposed that the rebels are retreating.</p>
                    <p>Baltimore, July 11--Evening.</p>
                    <p>The news from Washington is alarming. The <emph rend="italic">Star</emph>
                        says the skirmishing on the Rockville road had commedced [sic] at an early
                        hour this forenoon and was continued by the advance of the rebels to a point
                        about 4 miles west of Tennallytown. Their progress on that road was stopped
                        and they disappeared in some other direction. Subsequently we hear of them
                        skirmishing about noon on and around the 7th street turnpike near the
                        Claggett farm and the residence of F.P. Blair. It is reported to-day that
                        the rebels have burned the residence of Mr. Blair.</p>
                    <p>Panic stricken refugees arriving to-day from the vicinity of Edward's Ferry
                        report them crossing north at that point yesterday ad to-day in large
                        numbers, some saying 12,000 and others 30,000 strong.</p>
                    <p>Philadelphia, July 11.</p>
                    <p>The following was received by H.F. Kenney, Superintendent of the Baltimore
                        R.R:</p>
                    <p>I was conductor of train No. 17. The rebels attacked the train at Magnolia.
                        They went through the train after we had stopped capturing all officers and
                        soldiers on the train, among them was Maj. Gen. Franklin. They went through
                        most of the passenger's pockets capturing watches and money. They unloaded
                        baggage and set fire to my train, burning three first class passenger cars,
                        one second class car and baggage car and engine H. Clang, and one freight
                        car and a Northern Central engine that was on the siding.</p>
                    <p>Signed, J.R. Munshower, <lb/>Philadelphia, July 11.</p>
                    <p>It is reliably ascertained that two passenger trains which left Baltimore
                        this morning were captured and burned by the rebels at Magnolia 17 miles
                        from Baltimore. They also burned all the property of the railroad company in
                        that vicinity.</p>
                    <p>Headquarters Dep't Susquehanna, <lb/>Harrisburg, July 11.</p>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">To all Telegraph Stations on the C.V.R.R.</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>Gen. Kelley telegraphs from Cumberland that there is no truth in reports that
                        John Morgan and Imbeden are following Hunter's forces. Hunter's forces
                        occupy Martinsburg and that line of our forces occupy Hagerstown.</p>
                    <p>The enemy still occupy the South Mountain passes in Maryland and are in some
                        force at Middletown, whilst his main force is making demonstrations on
                        Baltimore and Washington.</p>
                    <p>Jno. S. Schultze,</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes how Confederate troops captured and burned two passenger trains
                    on the Philadelphia and Baltimore Railroad, taking a number of officers and
                    soldiers prisoner, including Major General Franklin.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Report on the sinking of the Confederate ship 'Alabama,' column 4; dispatches
                about skirmishing in Maryland, column 6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.07.13.02">
            <pageNote>Poetry and fiction, columns 1-5, classified ads, columns 5-6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.07.13.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Situation--Call for Troops</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"You must forget for the time being that you have been stigmatized as
                    'traitors,' 'copperheads,' 'rebel sympathizers,' &amp;c., by the men who are
                    now calling on you for help."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The military situation is alarming. The movements of the enemy along the
                        border, which for more than a week past have kept our people in dread
                        suspense, are at last being developed. It is now positively certain that the
                        enemy is in considerable force and is moving on Baltimore and Washington,
                        but whether as a real movement having for its object the capture of these
                        cities or as a feint to cover some other design we are as yet unable to
                        determine. Their advance on Sunday evening was said to be within fifteen
                        miles of Baltimore (one report says seven miles) and within thirteen miles
                        of Washington. They cut the Northern Central Railroad at Cockeysville, and a
                        late despatch says they penetrated to the Baltimore and Wilmington railroad,
                        captured two trains of cars and made prisoners of the passengers among whom
                        was Major General Franklin. Gen. Wallace, who commands at Baltimore,
                        undertook to resist their advance with about 10,000 men at Monocacy, near
                        Frederick, but was defeated and driven back in disorder. Among the prisoners
                        taken was Brig. Gen. Tyler.</p>
                    <p>We publish in another column the urgent call of Gov. Curtin for men. He tells
                        us the danger is imminent--that the authorities at Washington have
                        authorized him to muster in men by companies, which they peremptorily
                        refused just the day before. We believe the case has not been over-stated by
                        the Governor. It is the duty of patriotic citizens to respond promptly to
                        the call of the Governor in this emergency. You must forget for the time
                        being that you have been stigmatized as "traitors," "copperheads," "rebel
                        sympathizers," &amp;c., by the men who are now calling on you for help.
                        You must forget all this and rally once more in defense of your imperiled
                        country. The peril is great, and any action to be effective must be prompt
                        and decisive. As appropriate on this point we make the following extract
                        from the <emph rend="italic">Age:</emph></p>
                    <p>It seems to be well established, that the movement of the confederates is
                        made in large force, and it may become--it may already be--the duty of every
                        citizen to enter the ranks and aid in defence of his State. How well that
                        duty will be discharged by the disloyal--"the left wing of Lee's army"--is
                        abundantly shown by the action of Governor Seymour. Already eight organized
                        regiments are under orders, and, if necessary, he can in a few days send ten
                        times that number.</p>
                    <p>But while thus prompt to answer the summons which they have never failed to
                        heed, it would be idle to deny that they regard it as an onerous one. They
                        believe that the necessity which now compels them only exists because of the
                        criminal mismanagement of the war, and it will be with no alacrity or
                        enthusiasm that they will again go to the field. They are weary, very weary,
                        of this costly and ghastly war, protracted as it has been to gratify the
                        fanaticism and "avarice and passion of the men in authority." They know that
                        it might have long since been ended, or at least that it might have been so
                        conducted that no Northern State could ever be menaced with invasion. But
                        there are thousands in this city who think very differedtly [sic] from all
                        this; who are, in profession at least, thorough going war men; who believe
                        that everything has been for the best, and even rejoice that the war has not
                        been brought to a close, because its continuance seems to promise the
                        annihilation of slavery. These men, moreover, contend that one half of their
                        fellow citizens have no right even to live here in the North, and, if they
                        had had the power they would have hanged the very Commander in Chief, who is
                        now hurrying troops to their relief.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Sounds alarm about the advancement of Confederate troops toward Washington.
                    Urges all men--including critics of the Lincoln administration--to volunteer for
                    service to beat back the rebel troops.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Clergy and the Draft</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"This ministry should be exempt, they say, in order 'that it may be devoted
                    to the duties of its calling'--which duties it has neglected, and which calling
                    it has perverted, until many of the pulpits in our unhappy land have become the
                    rostrums from which political Abolition stump speeches are enunciated."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Criticizes ministers for suggesting that they should be exempt from the
                    draft. Points out that the clergy have been active in the political affairs of
                    the war since its beginning.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>"Bolstering Traitors"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We cannot see that either the requirements of patriotism or our duty as a
                    public journalist makes it obligatory upon us to publish false intelligence to
                    delude the people."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Author defends the Valley Spirit's willingness to report on Union military
                    setbacks, which the Repository has recently criticized as an act "bolstering
                    traitors."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Address to the People of Pennsylvania</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"It is my duty to state to you the fact, that your country requires your
                    immediate service, and the safety of your own soil, and of our good neighbors in
                    Maryland, may depend on your promptness."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prints copy of Governor Curtin's recent call for more volunteers for
                    service.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Here and There</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"They take every occasion, in and out of the pulpit, to excite their
                    hearers to deeds of hate and carnage, in place of preaching 'peace and good will
                    among men,' but are exceedingly careful to keep their own precious carcasses
                    clear of all danger."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>When our cavalry, on the recent raid under Wilson and Kautz, reached
                        Petersburg over Stoney creek they surprised a rebel Parson haranguing the
                        troops who, on the approach of our men, precipitously fled into the forest.
                        Just the moment he so ingloriously skedaddled he was chuck full of
                        patriotism, with the blood of revolutionary ancestors overflowing in his
                        veins, and was telling his listeners, among other things, that it was "a
                        glorious achievement to die for one's country!" The correspondent adds:</p>
                    <p>"He also told the pickets to shoot him a few Yankees so that he might have
                        the pleasure of burying them without form or prayers, and in various other
                        ways this divine individual manifested a decidedly unchristianlike
                        disposition."</p>
                    <p>We have a good many "divine individuals" in the North who manifest the same
                        "unchristianlike disposition" and are the perfect counterparts of this rebel
                        Parson. They take every occasion, in and out of the pulpit, to excite their
                        hearers to deeds of hate and carnage, in place of preaching "peace and good
                        will among men," but are exceedingly careful to keep their own precious
                        carcasses clear of all danger. If they are not of the class denounced in the
                        Scriptures as "Wolves in Sheep's Clothing" then we know of nothing to which
                        these terms can be applied with appropriateness.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Criticizes ministers for pushing men to fight but not enlisting themselves.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>More Taxes</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"This item will put $20,000,000 into the Treasury, ostensibly for the
                    purpose of paying bounties to soldiers about to be drafted; but really to
                    furnish food for the leeches that are bleeding the country to death in the
                    Treasury Department, and to support the thousands of worthless negroes now under
                    the care of the government."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Criticizes the 5 percent tax on all income from 1863 that Congress recently
                    passed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates an incident in which the new Secretary of the Treasury was the
                    subject of derogatory humor in the Senate.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Reports on the new ownership of several Pennsylvania newspapers, column 5;
                ads, column 6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.07.13.04">
            <pageNote>Page missing</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.07.13.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal: The Rebel Invasion</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The bells of the town were rung as a notification to the farmers of the
                    vicinity that the Philistines were coming, so that they might remove their stock
                    to a place of safety; when commenced a scene of the wildest confusion beggaring
                    any attempt at description. Horses, cattle, wagons and carriages, were rushed
                    through the streets in one general, confused and hurried stream; men, women and
                    children ran to and fro in every direction; the military were ordered under
                    arms, and every preparation was made for the defense of the town that the force
                    at the command of those in authority would admit of . . . "</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Since our last issue our town and surrounding country, and in fact the entire
                        valley, has again been thrown into an intense state of excitement in
                        anticipation of the advance of the rebel army, then on the Potomac, into and
                        through Cumberland Valley. At the date of our last all had become quiet,
                        business was partially resumed, and many of our farmers had returned with
                        their stock. This state of affairs was however of short duration. On
                        Wednesday evening an announcement was made by the military authorities here,
                        that the rebels had driven the Union forces from Hagerstown, and had
                        advanced to and occupied Greencastle. The bells of the town were rung as a
                        notification to the farmers of the vicinity that the Philistines were
                        coming, so that they might remove their stock to a place of safety; when
                        commenced a scene of the wildest confusion beggaring any attempt at
                        description. Horses, cattle, wagons and carriages, were rushed through the
                        streets in one general, confused and hurried stream; men, women and children
                        ran to and fro in every direction; the military were ordered under arms, and
                        every preparation was made for the defense of the town that the force at the
                        command of those in authority would admit of; batteries were placed in
                        position supported by infantry and made ready for action; barricades of a
                            <emph rend="italic">formidable</emph> character were erected to check
                        the advance of the foe, and the citizens called on to take up arms and
                        assist in the defense of the town. Things indeed began to look warlike; the
                        infernal clang of bells kept up the confusion and intensified the
                        excitement, and it seemed, for a time, as if--a nameless place had broke
                        loose. Some of our weak-nerved "loyal" leaguers, carpet bag in hand, broke
                        for the Railroad at a high rate of speed, and things for the time were
                        pretty well mixed. During the night quiet and order again resumed their
                        sway, and nothing was to be seen or heard, save the patrol pacing his beat;
                        the tired soldier rested on his arms ready and eager to meet the enemy and
                        drive him back. Nothing occurred on Thursday to cause fresh alarm, and in
                        the evening the welcome intelligence was received that the enemy were
                        withdrawing in the direction of Frederick city, and all apprehensions of an
                        attack here were dismissed; a joyful feeling of relief was felt by all, at
                        this news; countenances that had been clouded by gloom and despondency,
                        became again placid and serene, and everything assumed a bright and cheerful
                        aspect. The public serenity was again disturbed on Friday morning in
                        consequence of a despatch that the rebels had returned and were burning
                        Hagerstown, but it was soon ascertained that the burning was confined to
                        some government stores, by a small detachment sent back for that purpose.</p>
                    <p>During the entire period we managed to keep as cool as possible under the
                        circumstances, feeling very incredulous as to the intention of the raiders
                        to advance this far, and indeed, we kept our equanimity quite well until we
                        observed on the street on Wednesday, a portly gentleman with a linen coat
                        who resides in Hagerstown, his cheeks blanched with terror, fleeing in the
                        direction of the hyperborean regions. We knew him as one of the most
                        reliable "raid barometers," having observed him in our midst on every
                        previous occasion of a rebel incursion, and we must confess that we became
                        somewhat scared when we saw him, but were reassured and got our courage up
                        again on observing that our reliable local "raid barometers" indicated fair
                        weather.</p>
                    <p>We can scarcely yet estimate the force of the enemy occasioning all this
                        alarm along the border. The city dailies are failed with letters and
                        dispatches giving ridiculous reports of the enemy's movements, his strength,
                        positions and imaginary battles fought, but to the people here along the
                        border, they excite nothing but ridicule, most of them being manufactured in
                        Harrisburg by a somewhat notorious correspondent of one of the sensation
                        dailies, who never gets within fifty miles of the scene of action. All that
                        we know for certain is, that a considerable force of the enemy advanced up
                        the Shenandoah Valley, drove Gen. Sigel from Martinsburg and a portion of
                        them crossing into Maryland advanced as far as Hagerstown. Sigel is now on
                        Maryland Heights which is invested by the enemy, and it is to be hoped he
                        can maintain his position until relieved. The enemy is commanded by Early,
                        Ewell or somebody else, and is variously estimated at from 5,000 to 40,000,
                        and may be possibly the latter number as, if as we believe, his design is to
                        advance on Baltimore and Washington, he would scarcely attempt so hazardous
                        a movement with a less number.</p>
                    <p>At the present writing everything is again quiet; many of our farmers have
                        already returned and others are still returning with their stock; business
                        is being resumed and there is every indication that the war, in our midst,
                        is over for the present.</p>
                    <p>It will be seen by a reference to our news columns that the enemy is menacing
                        Baltimore with a large force, and, for the present, our valley is safe.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes the confusion in town that has greeted the news of rebel troops
                    advancing toward Greencastle.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Lost</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foreman</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes that Jacob Foreman of Waynesboro lost his pocket book and the eighty
                    dollars it contained in Shippensburg last Thursday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Letter From the 21st Pennsylvania Cavalry</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Here, too, was an ancient camp where the rebs used to teach their deluded
                    followers the art of war, that they might be effective in tearing down this
                    'temple of liberty,' which the hands of their fathers had helped to rear."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Near Petersburg, Va., <lb/></p>
                    <p>Correspondence of the Valley Spirit.</p>
                    <p>Messrs. Editors: Knowing that many of the readers of the Spirit have sons and
                        brothers in the 21st Pa. Cavalry, and knowing that others feel an interest
                        in the regiment, I propose to let you hear from us occasion[al]ly.</p>
                    <p>The regiment, though lately reorganized, has many members who are veterans in
                        the service of their country, and consequently the scenes of carnage and
                        bloody strife through which the regiment has recently passed was nothing new
                        to many, but to many of us a battle-field was a thing only of imagination.
                        The regiment was dismounted at Washington, D.C., on the 21st day of May; the
                        reason given was the great need of horses by the government to supply some
                        of the veteran cavalry regiments, who had worn their horses out by the many
                        successful raids which have distinguished that branch of the service, during
                        the present campaign. We soon came to the conclusion that the government was
                        not only in great need of horses, but also needed a regiment about the size
                        of ours, with muskets in their hands; for scarcely had we turned our horses
                        in to the Quarter Master at Washington, than we were ordered to be armed
                        with these weapons of warfare and immediately sent to the front. The men
                        were somewhat dis[s]atisfied with this order but a few words from our brave
                        Colonel soon banished all dis[s]atisfaction, and the men, like veterans, who
                        seemed to realize the crisis through which our country was passing,
                        shouldered the arms whose use they knew but little about, and took up the
                        line of March for the scene of active hostilities. We embarked at
                        Alexandria, Va., on three transports and were soon steaming down the bay as
                        merry as if going on some pleasure excursion. We soon entered the mouth of
                        the Rappahannock, whose banks being infested with guerrillas, our Captain
                        thought it best to lay to for the night. Nothing of interest occurred during
                        our trip up the river except the drowning of one man of Company H, who fell
                        overboard, and all efforts to save him proved of no avail. We landed at Port
                        Royal, a small but ancient looking town, on the southern bank of the
                        Rappahannock, on the 28th of May. Here we rested for the night, but early
                        next morning found us marching along one of the roads of the "Old Dominion"
                        in sand shoe-mouth deep. These marches over the "sacred soil" must be
                        participated in to be properly appreciated. After a long and tiresome march
                        of four days, in which we crossed the famous Mattapony, (formed by the
                        junction of four small streams bearing the names of the four syl[l]ables
                        composing the name of the river,) and Pamunkey rivers and passed over much
                        of the ground which was recently the scene of Gen. Grant's great battles and
                        brilliant victories. This has been called the sacred soil, but heretofore,
                        we, who hail from a northe[r]n clime could not see it, but now every lover
                        of his country must own that the term is applicable, for it is made so by
                        the many patriots whose blood crimsons every field and whose bones here find
                        a resting place. Worn down by long marches and short rations, we arrived at
                        Gen. Meade's headquarters and were immediately ordered out to support a
                        battery then engaged with the enemy in an artillery duel; this was on the
                        first day of June and the same night we slept on our arms; the next day we
                        rested till evening, when the 2d and 9th corps having moved farther to the
                        left, leaving our right exposed, the enemy began to press upon us when we
                        had a slight engagement with them in which Lieut. R. Waters of Company E was
                        instantly killed by a shell. When we saw this young patriot fall by our side
                        and saw his men bearing his bloody corps to the rear, we then began to
                        realize that we were at the "front." This was our only loss--the reader may
                        say it was very light, we do not think so, and to his bereaved young wife
                        the loss is irreparable. The next day we were again engaged, being under a
                        heavy fire during the entire day, in which we lost about sixty-five men in
                        killed and wounded, among the latter was our beloved leader. A full list of
                        names have already been published in the papers. The next day, being
                        relieved, we commenced marching farther to the left, and nothing occurred to
                        us of interest for several days, marching and fortifying being our constant
                        employment.</p>
                    <p>On the night of the 12th we again took up the line of march for the James
                        river, and reached that noble stream on the 16th, marching mostly at night.
                        In this march we passed the White-oak Swamp, famous for being the place
                        where John Smith was captured by the Indians, and in whose behalf the dusky
                        but noble Poccahontus so generously interposed and saved his life.</p>
                    <p>We crossed the James on a transport some distance below Harrison's Landing
                        and immediately took up the line of march for Gen. Grant's new line of
                        operations. All day and all night we march through impenetrable clouds of
                        dust and until night-fall beneath the rays of a scorching southern sun.
                        During the night we passed Prince George's C.H., and had it not been for the
                        legal pa-papers [sic] and calf-bound volumes which strewed the ground, we
                        might have mistaken it for a country [illegible]kirk," and imagined that we
                        were in the classic lowlands of Scotland. We could distinctly hear the
                        booming of cannon and the rattle of musketry which they called skirmishing
                        with the enemy, but I thought it sounded like fighting. We came up to where
                        the 2nd and 9th corps were encamped and there halted, it not yet being
                        daylight, we spread our blankets and were soon in the "arms of tired
                        nature's sweet restorer." In the morning we found ourselves in close
                        proximity to the "Johnnies," though there was some formidable works between
                        us; works of the enemy's own construction which they were generous enough to
                        abandon for his own and our safety. Here, too, was an ancient camp where the
                        rebs used to teach their deluded followers the art of war, that they might
                        be effective in tearing down this "temple of liberty," which the hands of
                        their fathers had helped to rear. Here were many huts constructed of pine
                        logs and had the appearance of being very comfortable quarters. Fighting
                        seemed to be going on all along the line, and we thought we might soon have
                        to try our hands again; accordingly on the 18th we started for the front and
                        were soon under the fire of the rebel artillery, we crossed a large field
                        which had been the scene of a bloody action the previous evening, and quite
                        a number of our dead were yet dying upon the field and seemed to be mostly
                        of the 2d Pa. heavy artillery. On a little farther in the woods the effect
                        of our own batteries was plainly visible, in the heaps of dead Johnnies
                        which covered the ground, and we, who a few weeks before, would have been
                        shocked at the sight of mangled bodies, could look upon this scene and feel
                        proud that the "Yanks" had been so successful. Very soon the enemy's shells
                        commenced exploding among us and our well filled ranks were fast depleting.
                        Our General thought that the sooner we got out of this the better; did he
                        order us to fall back, not he, this is not Gen. Griffin's style; "forward!"
                        was the command and gallantly did the 21st advance against a shower of
                        leaden hail--many of our brave comrades fell, but nothing daunted, we rushed
                        on until we reached a cut in the Petersburg and Weldon R.R., from which the
                        fr[e]ightened rebels fled in confusion before our unbroken lines; here we
                        halted some time and kept up a constant fire on the enemy who had fallen
                        back behind their works. Late in the evening we charged upon their works,
                        but owing to our not being supported on the right and left, the charge was
                        unsuccessful in the main, but we succeeded in gaining a position within two
                        hundred yards of the enemy's works, which we held until morning, when we
                        were relieved; here we were not over fifty yards from the enemy's
                        skirmishers who kept a constant fire upon us. I never felt the full force of
                        that beautiful sentiment, "The earth is my mother, I will repose on her
                        bosom," until now; indeed, we dig holes in her bosom with our bayonets that
                        we might embrace her more closely. We got some intrenching tools and before
                        morning we had a formidable line of works thrown up; at daylight we were
                        relieved and fell back to the railroad; it was here that Lieut. Lott of
                        Company B was wounded which wound has since caused his death; he was a brave
                        officer and his death is mourned by the entire regiment. In this engagement
                        we lost about one hundred and twenty-five men killed and wounded, among the
                        latter our 1st Major and Lieut. Colonel. On the evening of the 20th we left
                        here and marched to the left of our line, where the regiment again
                        distinguished itself by retaking some rifle pits, out of which our men had
                        been driven a short time previous; we occupied the ground until morning when
                        we handed the pits over to the troops who had been driven out the night
                        before. Since then we have not been engaged except in throwing up
                        fortifications; we have been resting and enjoying our newly earned
                        reputation and fresh laurels.</p>
                    <p>All correspondents should address this regiment as follows: "2d Brigade, 1st
                        Division, 5th Corps, Washington, D.C.," and they will come through all
                        right.</p>
                    <p>The glorious Fourth passed off here without any patriotic demonstration
                        except the occasional roar of a cannon. General Grant has a one hundred
                        pound "Blakely" which is known as the Petersburg Express, and threw a
                        message into Petersburg every fifteen minutes throughout the day.</p>
                    <p>It will not be expected of me to give any news of the army as the "dailies"
                        keep your readers posted and give you much more reliable information than I
                        am able to do. We have many rumors here constantly, the latest of which is
                        that there is to be a cessation of hostilities for six months; this may be
                        so, but I don't think it will take that long to starve the rebels in their
                        present condition. Many prisoners come into our lines daily and all seem to
                        think that they are pretty nearly "played out;" they said General Lee said
                        he intended astonishing the world on the 4th of July, consequently we
                        thought he was going to surrender, for certainly this would be the most
                        astonishing thing he could do at this time. We are being strongly
                        reinforced, seventy-five thousand troops having arrived here within the past
                        two weeks.</p>
                    <p>I see the Sanitary Fair has been quite successful in Chambersburg, and I am
                        convinced if the good people of the "Green Spot" could be here and see the
                        immense amount of labor that this benevolent commission is performing, they
                        would labor with increased zeal in its cause.</p>
                    <p>I will close for the present and will write you again.</p>
                    <p>Yours, P.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>P.</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waters</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lott</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Provides the latest news on the movement and activity of the 21st
                    Pennsylvania Cavalry in Virginia, including the deaths of Lieut. R. Waters of
                    Company K and Lieut. Lott of Company B.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wightman</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Price</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn>Cornelia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. J. W. Wightman married John Price and Cornelia Gordon on May 2 at the
                    home of the bride's father.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn>Naran McCann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Naran McCann Martin, daughter of Joseph Martin, died on June 21 at age 11
                    months and 8 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mahaffey</ln>
                        <fn>Emma</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Emma Mahaffey died on June 14 at age 16 years, 6 months and 8 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilman</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Gilman, formerly of Franklin County, died in Ottawa, Illinois, on
                    June 30 at age 80 years and 4 months.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 4-6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.07.13.06">
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 1-6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.07.13.07">
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 1-6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.07.13.08">
            <pageNote>Dispatches reporting on troop movement around Baltimore, columns 1-2;
                classified ads, columns 3-6</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
