<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1864/pa.fr.vs.1864.03.02">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Amy Murrell</taggerName>
            <tagDate>10/05/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1864-03-02">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day>2</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.03.02.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Enlistment Bill</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Summarizes the provisions of the recently passed enlistment bill, which
                    would allow the President to call on certain quotas of men from every county
                    when the needs of the army require it.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Other Side</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"This pamphlet is remarkable as an assertion by Republicans of all the
                    charges that the Democrats have made against Lincoln and his friends. It sneers
                    at his jocularity; it charges the ruin of the country on him; and insinuates
                    what we have always believed to be his intention, that he will perpetuate his
                    power by the bayonet. Such acknowledgments, coming from those in close
                    connection with the Administration, cannot fail to have irresistible force."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Supports the criticism of Lincoln contained in a pamphlet of the
                    Philadelphia Union League, a Republican organization that has lost confidence in
                    the President's desire to restore the Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Summary of War News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Provides overview of recent troop movement and skirmishing, including
                    General Sherman's march through Jackson, Mississippi, on his way to Mobile,
                    Alabama.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Reports on a robbery in New York City and a fire in Wilmington, Delaware,
                columns 4-6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.03.02.02">
            <pageNote>Fiction and poetry, columns 1-6, including an essay on mules</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.03.02.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Agricultural: How to Make Docile Horses</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Explains that horses may be made docile by keeping them close to the
                    owner's family.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Useful Recipes</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Offers suggestions for producing cheap household goods, including
                    substitutes for butter.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 3-6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.03.02.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Emancipation Proclamation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Explains why two prominent Republicans from Ohio and Maryland have declared
                    the Emancipation Proclamation "worthless."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that a proposal requiring men who file damage claims against the
                    government to take an oath to the Union is an intended insult toward Democrats.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Honest Old Abe</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"This famous individual is likely to have more trouble to re-elect himself,
                    or even to re-nominate himself than was at first supposed."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>This famous individual is likely to have more trouble to re-elect himself, or
                        even to re-nominate himself than was at first supposed. The movement
                        initiated in the early part of the winter, to have himself re-nominated
                        through the action of the State Legislatures has come to a sudden halt. The
                        friends of Mr. Chase, determined not to be out-generaled in this style, have
                        drawn the sword in defence of their favorite candidate. The first
                        declaration of open hostilities appeared about a week ago, in the shape of a
                        circular signed by Senator Pomerey, of Kansas, from which we make the
                        following extract:</p>
                    <p>So long as no efforts were made to forestall the political action of the
                        people, it was both wise and patriotic for all true friends of the
                        government to devote their influence to the suppression of the rebellion.
                        But when it becomes evident that party machinery and official influence are
                        being used to secure the perpetuation of the present administration, those
                        who conscientiously believe that the interests of the country and of freedom
                        demand a change in favor of vigor, and purity, and nationality, have no
                        choice but to appeal at once to the people at once to the people, before it
                        shall be too late to secure to fair discussion of principles.</p>
                    <p>Those in behalf of whom this communication is made, have thoughtfully
                        surveyed the political field, and have arrived at the following conclusions:</p>
                    <p>1. That, even were the re-election of Mr. Lincoln desirable, it is
                        practically impossible against the union of influence which will oppose him.</p>
                    <p>2. That, should he be re-elected, his manifest tendency toward compromises
                        and temporary expedients of policy will become stronger during a second term
                        than it has been in the first, and the cause of human liberty and the
                        dignity and honor of the nation, suffer proportionately; while the war may
                        continue to languish during his whole administration till the public debt
                        shall become a burden too great to be borne.</p>
                    <p>3. That the patronage of the government, through the necesities [sic] of the
                        war, has been so rapidly increased, and to such an enormous extent, and so
                        loosely placed, as to render the application of the [illegible] term
                        principle" absolutely essential to the certain safety of our republican
                        institutions.</p>
                    <p>This is pretty strong talk to come from one of the most "loyal" men in the
                        country. It would almost pass for the language of a "copperhead."</p>
                    <p>Another circular issued by the friends of Mr. Chase, has since made its
                        appearance." This circular has been circulated extensively throughout the
                        West, and animadverts still more severely on the conduct of the
                        "Government." Indeed it smacks strongly of treason according to the
                        Administration mode of defining that term. We publish an article on the
                        first page containing copious extracts from this document to which we call
                        the attention of our readers. We will simply give one short extract, in this
                        connection, to show the <emph rend="italic">animus</emph> of the document:</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">"This vacillation and indecision of the President has
                            been the real cause why our well-appointed armies have not succeeded in
                            the destruction of the rebellion.</emph> He has constantly been going
                        between these two theories, taking no positive ground for either but holding
                        on to the skirts of both.--Whether from the feebleness of his will which has
                        been unequal to the alternate pressure of the respective leaders of these
                        theories, or whether from the want of intellectual grasp, he has really been
                        unable to comprehend their philosophy, or from the want of political
                        principle and indifference to truth, he has, with that species of cunning
                        which characterizes a certain class of lawyers, sought to ride both
                        theories, for the purpose of securing his re-election. <emph rend="italic"
                            >The cant about "Honest Old Abe" was at first amusing, it then became
                            ridiculous, but now it is absolutely criminal.</emph></p>
                    <p>What think our "loyal" neighbors of this language as applied to their great
                        Master and Lawgiver? Truly, when rogues fall our honest men may expect to
                        get their rights.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Predicts that the presence of open Northern hostility toward Lincoln will
                    make it difficult for him to win renomination for president.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Damage Bill</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We are sorry to see a disposition manifested on the Republican side of the
                    House to prevent the passage of this bill. So far their opposition has been
                    shown by offering obnoxious amendments to embarrass the action of its friends.
                    But we can tell these gentlemen that they will shoulder a heavy responsibility
                    if they undertake to defeat this just and equitable measure for the relief of
                    the suffering citizens of this section of the state."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The bill introduced in the House of Representatives at Harrisburg some time
                        ago by Mr. Sharpe, to indemnify the citizens of the border counties for
                        losses sustained by rebel invasions and by our own militia, has not yet been
                        passed.--It was up for discussion on last Wednesday evening, at which time
                        Mr. Sharpe made a most masterly and unanswerable speech in favor of the
                        measure. He defended the loyalty and patriotism of his constituents, and
                        portrayed in glowing terms the hardships that have been endured by the
                        citizens of the border, and the almost perpetual annoyance and suspense to
                        which they are subject owing to their proximity to the rebel lines. He urged
                        the passage of the bill on the ground that every Government was bound to
                        protect its citizens in the enjoyment of their rights of person and
                        property, and where they suffered loss of property by reason of the invasion
                        of an enemy, every principle of justice and right demanded that they should
                        be indemnified by the State, whose duty it was to afford them protection.
                        His speech was a powerful and convincing argument and was listened to with
                        marked attention by all who heard it delivered. The citizens of the border
                        counties owe Mr. Sharpe a lasting debt of gratitude for the zeal and ability
                        with which he has defended their interests in this matter.</p>
                    <p>We are sorry to see a disposition manifested on the Republican side of the
                        House to prevent the passage of this bill. So far their opposition has been
                        shown by offering obnoxious amendments to embarrass the action of its
                        friends. But we can tell these gentlemen that they will shoulder a heavy
                        responsibility if they undertake to defeat this just and equitable measure
                        for the relief of the suffering citizens of this section of the State.
                        Before the last election, for the purpose of obtaining votes for the
                        Republican ticket, Republican stump speakers, solemnly pledged their party
                        in favor of the payment, by the State, of all the losses sustained by our
                        citizens. We ask our people now to watch the course of the Republican
                        members of the Legislature, and if the damage bill is defeated let the
                        responsibility be placed upon the right shoulders.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Criticizes the Republican members of the Pennsylvania House of
                    Representatives for opposing a bill that would provide payment to residents of
                    border counties who have sustained damages during the war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Lincoln's Administration -- Dissolution of the Republican Party</head>
                <origin>Albany Statesman</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The proud and numerous party which was represented in the Convention at
                    Chicago, no longer retains an existence. It has been dissipated by the action of
                    its chosen head. The Administration, therefore, stands in the anomalous and
                    painful position of having no organized political support outside the circle of
                    its own office-holders and retainers -- a very noisy but by no means controlling
                    faction."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Dissolution of the Republcan [sic] Party.--The Albany Statesman, the most
                        ultra of the Republican press, confesses that "the proud and numerous party
                        which was represented in the Convention at Chicago, no longer retains an
                        existence. It has been dissipated by the action of its chosen head. The
                        Administration, therefore, stands in the anomalous and painful position of
                        having no organized political support outside the circle of its own
                        office-holders and retainers--a very noisy but by no means controlling
                        faction."</p>
                    <p>Looking for the causes of this dissolution, it finds them in the falsehood of
                        the administration to its principles, and in this other fact, to which all
                        will bear witness, that--</p>
                    <p>A pack of sharks, hungry, villainous and incorrigible, have fastened upon the
                        public treasury and depleted it at the rate of millions monthly; that the
                        patronage of the Federal Government has been bestowed upon those with whom
                        the electors if allowed an exercise of choice, would have absolutely refused
                        all dealings--until high places of trust are held by known and convicted
                        cormorants, and men drive fast horses and live in freestone houses purchased
                        with the United States greenbacks, who ought to be pegging shoes in State
                        prisons.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that Republican newspapers are lamenting that that party is falling
                    apart under Lincoln's leadership.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Loyal Religion</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"It was to have been hoped that of all places desecrated by the intrudes of
                    the military power, the house of God might have been spared that infliction. . .
                    . now freedom of conscience, the liberty to worship the Creator after the
                    dictates of our own heart, is made to fall before the same engine of power."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Expresses outrage that churches in Norfolk and Portsmouth, Virginia, have
                    been placed under the control of the US Provost Marshal.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Classified ads, column 6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.03.02.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Murder</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Murders are getting to be very prevalent all over the State, and in fact,
                    all over the country. Scarcely a week passes without our having to chronicle a
                    murder or two in some part of the country."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Murders are getting to be very prevalent all over the State, and in fact, all
                        over the country. Scarcely a week passes without our having to chronicle a
                        murder or two in some part of the country. On Wednesday morning last the
                        body of an unknown man, apparently about 20 years of age, was found in a
                        lime kiln on the premises of Wm. B. Gabby Esq., near the Franklin Railroad,
                        about four miles from this place.--Various marks on the body indicated that
                        he had been foully dealt with. A wound in the neck inflicted by some sharp
                        instrument which severed the jugular vein must have occasioned his death in
                        a short time. A dislocated shoulder and a number of contusions on different
                        parts of the body induce the belief that a severe struggle occurred between
                        the deceased and his murderer. A small muslin bag was found turned inside
                        out, near the corpse, but the instrument with which the deed was committed
                        was not discovered. On Monday previous, the deceased in company with a negro
                        visited the store of Mr. H. C. McKnight in Marion and purchased some small
                        articles, and on the same evening they were seen together going in the
                        direction of the limekiln where the body was found. No marks or papers were
                        found which give any indication of the name or residence of the deceased.
                        The inquest held on the body, from the evidence before it, came to the
                        conclusion that the deceased was murdered by this unknown negro. The body
                        was brought to the county alms house and intered [sic].</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gabby</ln>
                        <fn>William B.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKnight</ln>
                        <fn>H.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Laments that murders are becoming more common in the county. Reports on the
                    latest killing, that of a twenty-year-old man who was left to die near the
                    Franklin Railroad.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>How to Send Letters to Prisoners in the Confederacy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Explains that letters sent to friends or family in Confederate prisons must
                    not be longer than one-page in length, must deal mainly with personal matters,
                    and must not be sealed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Cool Rascality</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Expresses disgust at reports of Union soldiers who robbed a black boy at a
                    local train depot.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Nigger in Cars</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"As niggers rule the roost at Washington it is no more than fair that they
                    should ride in the cars."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Agrees that a law passed allowing blacks to ride in Washington, D. C.
                    streetcars is appropriate for that city.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Prisoners Returning</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that citizens from Franklin County who are imprisoned in Salisbury,
                    North Carolina, will be paroled for sixty days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deatrich</ln>
                        <fn>W. R. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waters</ln>
                        <fn>Richard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>Gaff</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. W. R. H. Deatrich married Richard Waters, of Jennings County, to Bell
                    Gaff on February 22.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Humberger</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>How</ln>
                        <fn>Theodore</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harmon</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On February 18, Rev. Wm. Humberger married Theodore How and Sarah Harmon.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoffmeir</ln>
                        <fn>C. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cipe</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>Lydia J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. C. F. Hoffmeir married Samuel S. Cipe and Lydia J. Fisher on February
                    23 in the Fulton House at McConnellsburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bernhart</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Adams</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heck</ln>
                        <fn>Martha C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On February 25, Rev. Thomas Bernhart married William Adams, Esq., to Martha
                    C. Heck.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kramer</ln>
                        <fn>Phillip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Phillip Kramer of Groen Township died at age 56 on February 21.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>High</ln>
                        <fn>Amanda Virginia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>High</ln>
                        <fn>David V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>High</ln>
                        <fn>Susannah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Amanda Virginia High, daughter of David V. and Susannah High, died on
                    February 21 at age 1 year and 9 months.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mercey</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Catharine Mercey died at age 86 on February 12.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bear</ln>
                        <fn>J. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On February 19, Mr. J. T. Bear died at age 81.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rone</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Ellen Lavinia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On February 18, Mary Ellen Lavinia Rone died at age 2 years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Besore</ln>
                        <fn>Julia A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Besore</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Julia A. Besore, wife of the late G. W. Besore, Esq., and formerly a
                    resident of Waynesboro, died on February 3 in Mt. Carmell, Illinois.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>Albert Gregg</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Albert Gregg Taylor died on February 23 at age 6 months and 17 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Notice</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cross</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doyle</ln>
                        <fn>Edward B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Asks readers not to harbor John Cross (alias "Miles"), an apprentice who
                    ran away from Edward B. Doyle. He is 18 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 4-6, reports on the occupation of Selma, Alabama,
                column 4</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.03.02.06">
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 1-6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.03.02.07">
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 1-6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.03.02.08">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Congressional</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Summarizes recent proceedings of the US Congress, including consideration
                    of a bill to equalize the pay of all soldiers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 2-6</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
