<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1864/pa.fr.vs.1864.02.24">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andrew Morris, first pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 3/4/98</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1864-02-24">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="2">02</month>
            <day>24</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.02.24.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Republican Panegyric on the Confederate Constitution</head>
                <origin>World</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"But from a free, fair and honest election, conducted without corruption
                    and without terror, the country has nothing to fear and everything to hope."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The writer observes a recent article in the Times wherein that paper
                    examined the Confederate Constitution and found several aspects of it
                    admirable--specifically, those strengthening executive power, and those
                    providing for a longer term for the president. As the Times is a Republican
                    paper, the writer assumes that it is part of an effort to convince the public
                    that an election during the war would be dangerous. This is yet another sign
                    that Republicans hope to extend Lincoln's term by extraconstitutional means.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Miscellaneous war and Congressional news</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.02.24.02">
            <pageNote>Poetry, fiction, and anecdotes</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.02.24.03">
            <pageNote>Agricultural advice and four columns of classified advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.02.24.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Are Negroes Descendants of Ham?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt> "Yet it shall be our purpose to show that this curse was pronounced upon
                        <emph rend="italic">all the descendants of Ham</emph>, that the descendants
                    of Ham did people the continent of Africa, and that in them, and in no other
                    people on the earth, this curse has been and is being fulfilled even down to the
                    present day." </excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A correspondent, over the signature of "C," in our issue of week before last,
                        accuses us of falling into the "groundless and vulgar error" of supposing
                        the Afrcan race to be descendants of Canaan or Ham, and consequently
                        included in the prophecy of Noah, when he "awoke from his wine." The
                        argument by which he attempts to refute this "vulgar error" deserves credit
                        for its ingenuity, but beyond its ingenuity has little else to recommend it.
                        The very basis upon which it rests is fallacious. The writer asserts that,
                        "No true solution (of the question) can be attained without a careful
                        consideration of the relations of enmity existing between the people of
                        Israel and the Canaanites <emph rend="italic">when this Scripture was
                            written</emph>." What bearing the state of affairs existing at the time
                        "this Scripture was written" can have upon the interpretation of the
                        prophecy, we are unable to see. Moses merely <emph rend="italic"
                        >recorded</emph> the prophecy, which was uttered by Noah long ages before
                        the inspired writer was born. Moses is simply writing history--simply
                        recording what was said and done almost a thousand years before--and must we
                        not look for the true solution of the prophecy in the state of affairs
                        existing, not in the times in which the historian lived, but in the time
                        when the facts transpired and the prophecies were uttered which that
                        historian records? Let us illustrate our meaning by an example from profane
                        history. We find it recorded in a recently published volume of American
                        history that the Father of his Country, in his farewell address, warned his
                        fellow-citizens against the evil of sectionalism, which he predicted would
                        sever the Union. We cannot speak of the prediction as being made under the
                        facts and influences which existed when it was recorded by the
                        historian--the States discordant and belligerent--the land drenched in
                        fraternal blood. No, it stands sublimely by itself, in the mighty past, as
                        the almost prophetic utterance of the purest patriot and greatest statesman
                        of the age and nation. So does the prophecy of Noah; and it matters nothing
                        what influences may have operated upon the mind of the inspired writer when
                        he recorded it. The inimical relations between Canaan and Israel, in the
                        time of Moses, have much less to do with the interpretation of this passage,
                        than those same relations in the time of Joshua, when the Gibeonites, the
                        descendants of Canaan, were made hewers of wood and drawers of water for the
                        congregation of Israel, and thus this prophecy, to a limited extent, was
                        fulfilled in their enslavement. To approach a true solution of the prophecy
                        on this basis, we must take our stand with Noah and not with Moses--with
                        Noah as he stands in his hoary-headed majesty as the father of postdiluvian
                        man, and looks down through the vista of coming centuries, tracing the
                        development of the races sprung from his loins, through all the ceaseless
                        changes of the world's history.</p>
                    <p>In another respect the groundwork of "C"s argument is fallacious. He tells
                        us, "No interpretation (of this passage) can be admitted by reflecting men,
                        which makes the curse upon Canaan to be the immediate <emph rend="italic"
                            >consequence</emph> of the conduct of Ham." While we admit that the
                        curse is not the immediate <emph rend="italic">consequence</emph> of the
                        conduct of Ham, yet we contend that "C" entirely loses sight of the true
                        connection between the narrative and the prophecy itself. He regards the
                        events detailed as merely the <emph rend="italic">occasion</emph> on which
                        the prophecy was uttered. We maintain that there is a typical relation
                        between the narrative and the prophecy, which renders it necessary that they
                        should correspond with each other. We can illustrate our meaning by
                        reference to a similar case in the Scriptures, where King Joash smites the
                        ground with his arrows, at the bidding of the Prophet Elisha [2 Kings 13;
                        15-19]. As many times as he should thus smite the ground, so many times was
                        he to overcome the Syrians. He smote it but thrice, "and the man of God was
                        wroth with him and said thou shouldst have smitten five or six times; then
                        hadst thou smitten Syria till thou hadst consumed it." No one would pretend
                        that the future defeats of the Syrians were smitten out thrice, <emph
                            rend="italic">because the king smote but thrice</emph>. So in the case
                        under consideration. The narrative and the prophecy are so closely related
                        as to be mutually dependant [sic] upon each other. The facts recorded
                        previously just suit the prophecy; and had the prophecy been of a different
                        character, we are compelled to believe that Providence would have provided a
                        different state of facts. That this is the true theory of interpretation is
                        evident because Moses relates the facts as the introduction to the prophecy;
                        because the three sons of Noah who appear in the <emph rend="italic"
                            >narrative</emph> appear again in the <emph rend="italic"
                        >prophecy</emph>--two of them in proper person and the third in the person
                        of his son Canaan, a change which Moses leads us to expect by previously
                        announcing that Ham was "the father of Canaan" who is mentioned in the
                        prophecy; and lastly because those who behaved righteously, as recorded in
                        the <emph rend="italic">narrative</emph>, were blessed in the <emph
                            rend="italic">prophecy</emph>, and those whose sins are recorded in the
                            <emph rend="italic">narrative</emph> are cursed in the <emph
                            rend="italic">prophecy</emph>. Surely, then, though the curse of Canaan
                        is not the <emph rend="italic">immediate consequence</emph> of the conduct
                        of Ham, yet there is an inseparable connection between the narrative and the
                        prophecy, which compels us to take them together, if we would arrive at a
                        correct understanding of the whole passage. But this is just what our
                        correspondent don't [sic] wish to do, because it will not serve his purpose.
                        He must isolate Canaan from all his surroundings, and argue as if the
                        preceding verses were blotted from the Bible; though in doing so he violates
                        every known rule of interpretation in Law, Science or Scripture.</p>
                    <p>From these false premises "C" builds his argument. We might be content to
                        stop here, for when the foundation gives away the whole superstructure must
                        tumble. Yet it shall be our purpose to show that this curse was pronounced
                        upon <emph rend="italic">all the descendants of Ham</emph>, that the
                        descendants of Ham did people the continent of Africa, and that in them, and
                        in no other people on the earth, this curse has been and is being fulfilled
                        even down to the present day.</p>
                    <p>The inspired writer evidently designs to explain the occurrence of the name
                        of Canaan, by previously stating that Ham was "<emph rend="italic">the
                            father of Canaan</emph>," thus showing that he regarded the latter as
                        the representative of his father. A number of the most able commentators,
                        amongst them Hengstenberg, hold that Canaan was the eldest son of Ham,
                        though mentioned last in the list of sons, for the sake of convenience; just
                        as Japheth, the eldest son of Noah is always mentioned last, though at
                        Noah's death he became the head of the whole family, and is called Japheth
                        "the elder." So here, Canaan, the eldest son, is the representative of his
                        father. This same view is suggested by the words of the prophecy, "cursed be
                        Canaan, a servant of servants shall he be unto his brethren." Canaan's
                        brethren were Mizraim, Cush, and Phut, and it is clearly established by
                        history that neither he nor his descendants became the servants of his
                        brethren; while it is just as clearly established that the descendants of
                        Ham, including Canaan, <emph rend="italic">did</emph> become subject to the
                        descendants of <emph rend="italic">his</emph> brethren Shem and Japheth. The
                        prophecy, moreover, says, of both Shem and Japheth, "Canaan shall be his
                        servant." Both passages taken togehter would read, "cursed by Canaan, a
                        servant of servants shall he be unto his brethren Shem and Japheth." <emph
                            rend="italic">But Canaan is not the brother of Sham and Japheth</emph>,
                        and can only be considered so when standing in the place of his father. He
                        must therefore represent his father in this prophetic view of the future
                        history of the three great families of the human race, and through him the
                        curse must have passed from all the descendants of Ham. There is extant an
                        Arabic version of the Scriptures, which renders this passage "Cursed be Ham
                        the father of Canaan." Bishop Newton, in his work on the Prophecies, says
                        "If we regard the metre, this line 'cursed by Canaan' (the ancient Hebrew
                        being written in metre) is much shorter than the rest, as if something was
                        deficient. May we not suppose therefore that the copyist wrote by mistake
                        only <emph rend="italic">Canaan</emph>, instaed of <emph rend="italic">Ham
                            the father of Canaan?</emph>" There are other arguments to prove that
                        the curse was pronounced upon all the descendants of Ham, but our space will
                        not admit of them.</p>
                    <p>Having thus shown that the curse had reference to all the descendants of Ham,
                        we now proceed to prove that the Africans were the descendants of Ham, we
                        now proceed to prove that the Africans were the descendants of Ham, and that
                        the curse applies to them. The very name of Ham signifies "the blackish one"
                        and it is used in the Scriptures, a number of times, as synonymous with
                        Ethiopia. The descendants of Cush, the first mentioned son of Ham, emigrated
                        to Assyria and Arabia, and founded a kingdom in Meroe, now called Abyssinia.
                        The Rev. Dr. Alexander says the kingdom of Cush, ****</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A three-column reply to a letter written several weeks previously, by
                    correspondent "C," who argued against assertions in the Spirit and Times that
                    black people were the descendants of Ham and under the curse of Canaan. The
                    editors first question the writer's attempt to historicize the interpretation of
                    the biblical stories, and then move on to attempt to prove the connection
                    between the biblical stories and contemporary black people.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Military Damages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors note the supplement to the act passed last session in the state
                    legislature to provide compensation for damages incurred during the Confederate
                    raid in 1862. The addition, proposed by Mr. Sharpe, would include all incursions
                    of the enemy into the state, and would also cover damages sustained from the
                    occupation by state militia forces. Those who suffered losses due to occupation
                    of their land or supplying troops will be given certificates of indebtedness
                    bearing four percent interest, redeemable in twenty years or sooner at the
                    option of the state; those who lost horses or other property taken by the
                    Confederates will receive certificates of redemption that will be funded by a
                    special tax of one-fourth mil on the dollar. The editors urge representatives
                    from counties not invaded to consider the bill favorably.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Republicans, note the writer, have begun to act under the assumption
                    that the Confederates have no rights under the Constitution. Now, it would be
                    impertinent for Confederates to try to claim Constitutional rights, as they
                    reject the Constitution in other ways, but for Republicans to deny the
                    Confederates the privileges of the Constitution implies that they release them
                    from its obligations as well. The editors compare it to a Christian claiming
                    that an infidel cannot claim treatment as a Christian since he does not live by
                    those laws, but it does not mean that they would not treat this infidel without
                    Christian obligation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Includes miscellaneous news and opinion.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.02.24.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Veterans and Local Bounties</head>
                <origin>Patriot and Union</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Provost Marshal General, in reply to an inquiry from the Provost
                    Marshal in Pittsburgh, writes that unless veterans who enlist in the field
                    specifically credit their re-enlistment to the quota of a county or township,
                    they will not receive a bounty for re-enlistment. The editors find this unfair,
                    as they see no reason that veterans should be denied the "liberal local
                    bounties" being offered, and they believe the effect of the opinion will be to
                    discourage veterans from re-enlisting.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Good Chance</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dawney</ln>
                        <fn>B. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orem</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>B. C. Dawney has associated himself with Captain Orem in raising a company
                    for the 22nd Pennsylvania Cavalry. Orem has been in the service for two years,
                    and is known as an experienced and courageous officer. Dawney goes in the
                    capacity of Second Lieutenant. He was a member of the 126th Regiment, and since
                    then he has been associated with the Provost Marshal's office of this place. The
                    editors praise his military reputation and believe his connection with the
                    Provost Marshal's office will put new recruits at a great advantage.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Relief for Prisoners</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reid</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Some citizens are under the mistaken impression that, since the escape of
                    federal officers from Libby Prison, no packages can be sent to prisoners there.
                    Dr. Reid informs the editors that the express agent at Fortress Monroe says that
                    articles of food and clothing, from private parties, are still being forwarded
                    and received as usual.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Alarm of Fire</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The chimney of the Poor House caught on fire last Wednesday, setting the
                    roof on fire. It was quickly extinguished, though, and the damage was minimal.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>2d Regiment Penna. Artillery</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Winger</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>1st Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lieut. B. F. Winger writes to deny the charges against Col. A. A. Gilson,
                    who was accused of refusing to fly a Pennsylvania flag with the colors of the
                    mostly Pennsylvania regiment. The state flag, says Winger, has been flying the
                    entire time he has been with the regiment. Winger blames the accusations on
                    intrigue among the officers. He goes on to write that he hopes they will be
                    moved from garrison duty soon.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Forney</ln>
                        <fn>C. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. C. H. Forney will preach the following series of sermons in the
                    Bethel, on the corner of Queen and Water Street, on Sunday, commencing on
                    February 28. The titles are: "The duty and manner of hearing the word;" "The
                    Church of God--Her form and faith;" "Ordinances, nature and character of;"
                    "Baptism, Action of;" "Baptism, subjects of;" " Feetwashing, an ordinance;"
                    "Lord's Supper, Nature, etc."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Cavalry Camp</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"A cavalry camp has been established about four miles west of this place .
                    . . "</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A cavalry camp has been established about four miles west of this place, on
                        the Pittsburgh turnpike, where all new cavalry recruits are to be sent for
                        drill and the men put in proper condition to take the field. There are at
                        present in camp, the 20th and 21st regiments, the latter being recruited
                        mainly from this county; the former having arrived from Harrisburg on the
                        22d inst. We understand that General Stahieds to take command of the
                    camp.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A cavalry camp has been established four miles west of Chambersburg on the
                    Pittsburgh turnpike, where new cavalry recruits will be sent for drill. At
                    present, the 20th and 21st regiments are in camp, the former having arrived from
                    Harrisburg and the latter having been recruited principally in Franklin County.
                    General Stahle is to take command of the camp.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Rev. P. S. Davis</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Rev. P. S. Davis of Norristown will preach in the German Reformed Church of
                    Chambersburg next Sunday morning and evening.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Mr. Warner's Lecture</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Rev. J. R. Warner, of Gettysburg, gave a lecture last Thursday on the
                    battle of Gettysburg and drew a full house to the Methodist Church. It was a
                    graphic description of the battle, and Warner was frequently interrupted with
                    applause. The lecture produced about $75 for the Ladies' Aid Society.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Counterfeit</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A counterfeit $20 bill on the Bank of Gettysburg has just been issued. The
                    bill is of very good quality, the only distinguishing mark being that the fake
                    is signed by W. G. McPherson and R. Smith, while the genuine are signed by G.
                    Swope and T. D. Carson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Provost Marshal General</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Provost Marshal General has decided that officers do not count against
                    a state's quota and cannot be offered a bounty. Officers technically do not
                    enlist, but instead accept a commission. Bounties are considered a gratuity for
                    enlisting, not for taking a commission.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Condemned Horses at Auction</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Three-hundred horses condemned as unfit for service in the U.S. cavalry
                    will be sold at auction in Harrisburg on February 26. They will be sold singly.
                    They are recommended for farm or road work.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>New Counterfeit</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Readers are alerted to counterfeit $2 notes on the Bank of Stroudsburg
                    (Pennsylvania). The vignette is of a locomotive and cars. They first appeared on
                    Wednesday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thomas</ln>
                        <fn>R. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGowan</ln>
                        <fn>Cyrus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Meredith</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Cyrus McGowan married Maggie E. Meredith of Peters Township at the house of
                    John Miller, Esq., in Mt. Parnell, on the evening of February 11.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Howe</ln>
                        <fn>Wesly</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lindsey</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Killinger</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Thomas Lindsey and Rebecca Killinger, both of Greenvillage, were married on
                    February 18.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dickson</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stouteagle</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dansberger</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George Stouteagle and Elizabeth Dansberger, both of Chambersburg, were
                    married on February 11.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dickson</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Comfort</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mudd</ln>
                        <fn>Luaretta</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Thomas Comfort of Pottsville, Pennsylvania, married Luaretta Mudd of
                    Chambersburg on February 11.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneck</ln>
                        <fn>B. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>John J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sgt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baughman</ln>
                        <fn>Charlotte</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sgt. John J. White, Co. B, 22nd Reg't Penn. Cavalry, of Bedford County,
                    married Charlotte Baughman of Franklin County on January 28.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneck</ln>
                        <fn>B. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palmer</ln>
                        <fn>Reuben M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Withers</ln>
                        <fn>Anna E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reuben M. Palmer and Anna E. Withers, both of Franklin County, were married
                    on February 11.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneck</ln>
                        <fn>B. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Embich</ln>
                        <fn>Elijah S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kupfender</ln>
                        <fn>Dorothy A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Elijah S. Embich of Middletown, Dauphin County, married Mrs. Dorothy A.
                    Kupfender of Chambersburg on February 16.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Krebs</ln>
                        <fn>W. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cayhoe</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoves</ln>
                        <fn>Amanda Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Henry Cayhoe of Wayne County, Ohio, married Amanda Susan Hoves, of the
                    vicinity of Waynesboro, on February 11.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tritle</ln>
                        <fn>Martha Ellen</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tritle</ln>
                        <fn>John C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tritle</ln>
                        <fn>Nancy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Martha Ellen Tritle, youngest daughter of John C. and Nancy Tritle, died on
                    February 5 in Guilford Township, aged 1 year, 2 months and 14 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zimmerman</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf>Sr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingert</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>David Zimmerman, Sr., until recently a citizen of Orrstown, died at the
                    residence of his son-in-law, David Wingert, in Shippensburg, aged 82 years [no
                    date of death given].</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ludwig</ln>
                        <fn>Mary A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ludwig</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ludwig</ln>
                        <fn>Martha M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary A. Ludwig, daughter of John and Martha M. Ludwig, died on February 17,
                    aged 1 year, 6 months and 26 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Falkenstein</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Falkenstein</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Elizabeth Falkenstein, wife of George Falkenstein, died on February 18,
                    aged 42 years and 27 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Graff</ln>
                        <fn>L. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClintic</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Elizabeth McClintic, formerly of Chambersburg, died on February 19 at
                    the home of her son-in-law, L. G. Graff, in Philadelphia, aged 73 years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gamble</ln>
                        <fn>James Morton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James Morton Gamble died on January 27 near Dry Run, aged 36 years, 10
                    months and 25 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Unger</ln>
                        <fn>Emanuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Emanuel Unger died on February 15, near Welsh Run, aged 63 years, 2 months
                    and 17 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ervin</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah Rebecca</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Sarah Rebecca Ervin died on February 9 in Waynesboro, aged 41 years,
                    11 months and 18 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tracey</ln>
                        <fn>Sophia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Sophia Tracey died on February 13 near Monterey, aged 48 years, 7
                    months and 21 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vanlear</ln>
                        <fn>Sidney M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vanlear</ln>
                        <fn>Matthew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Sidney M. Vanlear, wife of Matthew Vanlear, died on February 7 near
                    Mercersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cooper</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Margaret Cooper died on February 18 in Mercersburg, aged 76 years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chambers</ln>
                        <fn>John J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. John J. Chambers died on February 12 in Mercersburg, aged 40 years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Page includes a brief summary of war news, and two columns of
            advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.02.24.06">
            <pageNote>Classified advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.02.24.07">
            <pageNote>Classified advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.02.24.08">
            <pageNote>Classified advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
