<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1864/pa.fr.vs.1864.02.03">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andrew Morris, first pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 3/4/98</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1864-02-03">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day>3</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.02.03.01">
            <pageNote>A reprint of the Constitution of the United States</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.02.03.02">
            <pageNote>Poetry, fiction, and anecdotes</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.02.03.03">
            <pageNote>Agricultural advice and four columns of classified advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.02.03.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Constitution</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The purposes it achieved with wonderful harmony and success, for the
                    period of seventy odd years, until the madness of sectional fanaticism became
                    the ruling power in the councils of the nation, tore asunder the bonds of Union,
                    struck down the scales of justice, stabbed the domestic tranquillity to the
                    heart, shivered into atoms the common defense, and debased the great privileges
                    of civil liberty to the sole purposed of liberating a few million savage and
                    untutored blacks while it would leave thirty millions of whites in chains."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors explain that they reprinted the Constitution in this issue to
                    remind readers of the clauses that they believe are being violated by the
                    Lincoln administration. Among others, the confiscation act has deprived people
                    of property without due process, the admission of West Virginia was not done
                    with the consent of Virginia, freedom of speech, freedom of the press, and
                    freedom from false imprisonment have all been violated by federal authorities,
                    the right of states to organize militias has been trumped by federal
                    conscription laws, and military authorities have interfered with free elections.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>A Bogus Senator</head>
                <origin>The Age</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>Major</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The editors protest the attempt by Republicans to file a resignation for
                    Major White, a Republican state senator who has been unable to take his seat
                    because of his commission. White's resignation has not been presented to the
                    proper authorities, claim the editors, and thus there is no legal ground on
                    which they can hold a replacement election.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Coming Financial Crash</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"[The Democratic press] showed that the vaunted prosperity of the country
                    was false and hollow, a mere bubble that must burst, sooner or later, producing
                    untold misery and ruin to the business and laboring classes of the community,
                    and that even now, while speculators and army contractors are acquiring sudden
                    wealth, the great body of the people are stinted in the common necessities of
                    life."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors cite a report by the Comptroller of the Currency that warns
                    that the end of the war may bring an end to the "apparent prosperity" of the
                    country. They accuse the Lincoln administration of misleading the country with
                    falsely optimistic statements about the future of the economy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"There is to be no way of escape to any except such as the possessors of
                    magnificent farms and stately mansions a la 'Norland.'"</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors note the call of the Repository to Congress to issue a ruthless
                    conscription bill, one that will, in the Spirit's words, "gobble up every poor
                    man as well as every man of moderate means, and force him into the army before
                    spring opens."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Includes a review of recent books and periodicals, as well as war news from
                east Tennessee.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.02.03.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>How to Avoid the Draft</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Curtain</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Governor</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hancock</ln>
                        <fn>Winfield</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Major General</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burnside</ln>
                        <fn>Ambrose</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Major General</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The editors reprint a call by Governor Curtain for volunteers to fill up
                    the 2nd and 9th Army Corps, under the command of Major Generals Winfield Hancock
                    and Ambrose Burnside. The following Pennsylvania regiments and batteries are
                    included. 2nd Army Corps: 53rd, 69th, 71st, 72nd, 81st, 106th, 116th, 140th,
                    145th, and 148th regiments, and Independent batteries C and F, and batteries F
                    and G of the 1st Pennsylvania artillery. 9th Army Corps: 45th, 48th, 50th, 51st,
                    100th regiments, and Durrell's Independent Battery D. The editors encourage
                    enlistment "thereby avoiding any necessity for another draft."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Another Draft</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lincoln</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>President</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The editors reprint an order from President Lincoln authorizing a draft for
                    500,000 men on March 10 for three years service. The editors note that this
                    follows on the October order for a draft of 300,000. This order includes the
                    300,000, and assumes a volunteer rate of 2000 per day. The order credits any men
                    who have been enlisted or drafted up to the 1st of March to the state's quota.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Nine Months' Men to be Drafted</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Senate has amended the conscription bill to exempt only those men
                    currently in the service, or who have been in the service two years and have
                    been honorably discharged, from the draft. This makes all those who served in
                    the nine months regiment subject to the draft. These veterans do receive an
                    additional bounty of $40 on top of the $362 for first-time enlistees.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Row</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Such displays of the progress of our soldiers are not at all creditable,
                    and no laurels are to be gained in such encounters, we would therefore suggest
                    that they reserve their valor for the enemies of our country 'away down South in
                    Dixie.'"</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On Friday night last, just after dark, considerable of a row was gotten up,
                        in front of the Post Office, by some of the military now stationed in and
                        near town. Several knock downs occurred; but we could not ascertain whether
                        cavalry or artillery came off second best. Our country's gallant defenders
                        appear so anxious for a fight, that, in the absence of rebels, in order to
                        keep their hands in, they occasionally pitch into each other.--Such displays
                        of the progress of our soldiers are not at all creditable, and no laurels
                        are to be gained in such encounters, we would therefore suggest that they
                        reserve their valor for the enemies of our country "away down South in
                        Dixie."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A fight among members of the troops stationed in town took place in front
                    of the Post Office last Friday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>United Brethren</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burd</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf>P. E.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dickson</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bishop</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hummelbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>H. Y.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Colestock</ln>
                        <fn>Z. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Humberger</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jackson</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The annual conference of the United Brethren in Christ took place in
                    Mechanicsburg on January 21. The following are the pastoral appointments for
                    Franklin County: Chambersburg District, J. W. Burd, P.E.; Chambersburg Station,
                    J. Dickson; Rocky Spring Station, J. M. Bishop; Orrstown Station, H. Y.
                    Hummelbaugh; Big Spring Station, Z. A. Colestock; St. Thomas Circuit, S.
                    Jackson; Greencastle and Alto Dale Circuit, J. C. Smith and W. Humberger; Path
                    Valley Station, S. Young.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Court Martial</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fishel</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>At a Court Martial held in Chambersburg last November, presided over by
                    Gen. O. S. Ferry, U.S. Volunteers, Private Isaac Fishel, 166th Reg't Penn.
                    Militia was convicted of desertion and giving intelligence to the enemy, which
                    finding was approved by the Major General commanding. Fisher was ordered to be
                    shot by musket on Friday, March 18. Joseph Fisher was tried and found guilty of
                    spying for and giving intelligence to the enemy, and was sentenced to be hanged.
                    The finding and sentence were approved, but the sentence was commuted to
                    imprisonment for 10 years in the state penitentiary.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Academy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Notwithstanding the adverse circumstances of 'wars and rumors of wars' in
                    our valley we have to congratulate Mr. Kinney not only on the rapid increase of
                    attendance at his school, but the large number of fine looking young men which
                    we daily see passing to and from the academy."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The editors call attention to the advertisement of the Chambersburg Academy
                    in this issue and praise the school and the "efficient and energetic management"
                    of its principal, Mr. Kinney.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>How to Treat Frozen Limbs</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors pass on some advice on thawing out frozen limbs. They recommend
                    encouraging internal circulation at the same time as applying external heat.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Public Lecture</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The subject, the battle of Gettysburg, is an intensely interesting one to
                    all and the well established reputation of the Rev. gentleman, who was an eye
                    witness of the battle . . . "</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Rev. John A. Warner of Gettysburg has consented to deliver a lecture in this
                        place on some evening next week in aid of the funds of the "Ladies Aid
                        Society."</p>
                    <p>The subject, the battle of Gettysburg, is an intensely interesting one to all
                        and the well established reputation of the Rev. gentleman, who was an eye
                        witness of the battle; as a speaker, in connection with the laudable object
                        in view, should, and not doubt will, attract a full house. The time of the
                        lecture will be duly announced.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Warner</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Reverend</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. John A. Warner of Gettysburg will give a lecture in Chambersburg on
                    the battle of Gettysburg, to benefit the Ladies' Aid Society. Warner was an
                    eyewitness to the battle, and he should command a full house.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The 77th Regiment Pa. Vols.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The gallant men of the 77th deserve a cordial welcome and high honors."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We understand from private sources, that the members of this gallant Regiment
                        which covered itself with laurels on the hard-fought fields of the South
                        west, have almost to a man, re-enlisted for three years, and are now on
                        their way home on a furlough of thirty days. The gallant men of the 77th
                        deserve a cordial welcome and high honors.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that nearly every member of the 77th Reg't Penn. Volunteers
                    re-enlisted for three years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>School House Burned Down</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Mount Rock School House, in Southampton Township, was entirely consumed
                    by fire last week. There is no information on the source of the fire.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolf</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harmony</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baine</ln>
                        <fn>Regina</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Harmony and Regina Baine, both of Chambersburg, were married on
                    January 28.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>I. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Starliper</ln>
                        <fn>Clarkson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Steffy</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Clarkson Starliper of Montgomery Township married Elizabeth Steffy of
                    Peters Township on January 28 at the residence of the bride's father.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>West</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Culbertson</ln>
                        <fn>James B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stewart</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stewart</ln>
                        <fn>Davis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James B. Culbertson and Margaret Stewart (daughter of Davis Stewart), of
                    Amberson's Valley, were married on January 21.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Niccolls</ln>
                        <fn>S. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Haymaker</ln>
                        <fn>James G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>Adele E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James G. Haymaker and Adele E. Skinner (daughter of William Skinner, Esq.)
                    were married near Chambersburg on January 27. A "large and delicious cake" to
                    which "all hands did ample justice" accompanied the wedding notice.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schaefer</ln>
                        <fn>George Franklin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schaefer</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schaefer</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George Franklin Schaefer, son of Jacob and Catharine Schaefer, died on
                    January 26, aged 4 years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cantner</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Michael Cantner, son of Michael Cantner, died on January 19 in Greencastle,
                    aged 4 months.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hawbecker</ln>
                        <fn>Levi</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Levi Hawbecker died on January 23 in Greencastle at age 48.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bonebrake</ln>
                        <fn>Levi</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Levi Bonebrake died on January 25 near Waynesboro of typhoid fever [age
                    obscured by tear in paper].</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hennicle</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hennicle</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Hennicle, son of Henry Hennicle, died on January 24 near Waynesboro
                    [age obscured by tear in paper].</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mullnix</ln>
                        <fn>Bartholomew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Bartholomew Mullnix died on January 23 in Chambersburg, aged 63 years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kerr</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James Kerr died on January 29 in Chambersburg, aged about 87 years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>The top portion of column five is missing; the remaining page includes three
                and a half columns of classified advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.02.03.06">
            <pageNote>Classified advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.02.03.07">
            <pageNote>Anecdotes and classified advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.02.03.08">
            <pageNote>Includes miscellaneous war news, a directory of advertisers, and four columns
                of classified advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
