<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1864/pa.fr.vs.1864.06.22">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Amy Murrell</taggerName>
            <tagDate>10/21/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 4/2/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1864-06-22">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="06">June</month>
            <day>22</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.06.22.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Union Principles</head>
                <origin>Journal of Commerce</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Accuses Republicans of "hypocrisy" for believing they are loyal when in
                    fact they are "revolutionists."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Important Revelations</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Have we not just been apprised by that despot that we can only expect his
                    gracious pardon by emancipating all our slaves, swearing allegiance, and
                    obedience to him and his proclamation, and becoming, in point of fact, the
                    slaves of our own negroes? Can there be in North Carolina one citizen so fallen
                    beneath the dignity of his ancestors as to accept, or to enter conference on the
                    basis of these terms?"</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Gov. Vance, of North Carolina, because of widespread discontent among the
                        people of his State, on the 24th ultimo addressed a letter to Jeff Davis,
                        imploring him to make overtures of some sort to our Government for the
                        cessation of hostilities, in view of bringing about a permanent peace. The
                        Governor expresses the belief, that if such a course were pursued and their
                        overture rejected, it would have the effect of crushing out all discontent
                        in his State, and of making the people a unit in the cause of Southern
                        independence.</p>
                    <p>Jeff Davis replies to the Governor at length in opposition to his
                        suggestions; but as we feet no interest in points of ettiquette [sic]
                        regarding the personal opinions of either, we confine ourself to quoting the
                        following important paragraphs from Davis' communication, he says:</p>
                    <p>We have made three distinct efforts to communicate with the authorities at
                        Washington, and have been invariably unsuccessful. Commissioners were sent
                        before hostilities were begun, and the Washington Government refused to
                        receive them or hear what they had to say.</p>
                    <p>A second time I sent a military officer, with a communication addressed by
                        myself to President Lincoln. The letter was received by Gen. Scott, who did
                        not permit the officer to see Mr. Lincoln; but promised that an answer would
                        be sent. No answer has ever been received. The third time, a few months ago,
                        a gentleman was sent, whose position, character and reputation were such as
                        to insure his reception, if the enemy were not determined to receive no
                        proposals whatever from the Government. Vice President Stephens made a
                        patriotic tender of his services in the hope of being able to promote the
                        cause of humanity, and although little belief was entertained of his
                        success, I cheerfully yielded to his suggestion, that the experiment should
                        be tried.</p>
                    <p>The enemy refused to let him pass through their lines, or to hold any
                        conference with them. He was stopped before he ever reached Fortress Monroe,
                        on his way to Washington. To attempt again, in the face of these repeated
                        rejections of all conference with us, to send commis[s]ioners or agents to
                        propose peace is to invite insult and contumely, and to subject ourselves to
                        indignity without the slightest chance of being listened to.</p>
                    <p>Our object in quoting this is to direct the reader's attention to Davis'
                        statement regarding the mission of Mr. Alexander Stephens. We all remember,
                        for it is not a year ago--when he approached Fortress Monroe, on a mission
                        to Washington, and how our authorities refused to receive him. When it was
                        hinted that he had been authorized to enter into negotiations for peace, it
                        was denied by the Administration, President Lincoln himself declaring that
                        he had no intimation whatever, from Richmond, of a desire for a cessation of
                        hostilities. At last we have the truth, however. Mr. Stephens desired a
                        conference with our a[u]thorities, but as soon as the nature of his
                        commission was ascertained, he was refused an audience. He went back to
                        Richmond, and immediately our Administration commenced lying in regard to
                        his purposes in visiting Washington. It was a fear that Stephens would offer
                        to lay down the rebel arms that denied him admission to Washington. He had
                        always been a thorough Union man, up until the opening of the rebellion, and
                        is now; and the fact of Jeff Davis sending him on a mission of peace to our
                        Government, shows how anxious they all were to lay down their arms and
                        return to their allegiance. But in order to prevent this consum[m]ation,
                        Stephens was denied an audience, and in order to prevent him or his
                        Government from ever again asking for peace, Mr. Lincoln issued his
                        proclamation, which Davis notices as follows. It will be seen how
                        successfully Lincoln has managed to prolong hostilities. Alluding to
                        Lincoln's proclamation Davis remarks:</p>
                    <p>Have we not just been apprised by that despot that we can only expect his
                        gracious pardon by emancipating all our slaves, swearing allegiance, and
                        obedience to him and his proclamation, and becoming, in point of fact, the
                        slaves of our own negroes? Can there be in North Carolina one citizen so
                        fallen beneath the dignity of his ancestors as to accept, or to enter
                        conference on the basis of these terms?</p>
                    <p>It is with Lincoln alone that we ever could confer, and his own partisans at
                        the North avow unequivocally that his purpose in his message and
                        proclamation was to shut out all hope that he could ever treat with us on
                        any terms. If we break up our Government, dissolve the Confederacy, disband
                        our armies, emancipate our slaves, take an oath of allegiance binding
                        ourselves to obedience to him and of disloyalty to our own States, he
                        proposes to pardon us and not to plunder us of anything more than the
                        property already stolen from us and such slaves as still remain. In order to
                        render his proposals so insulting as to secure their rejection he joins to
                        them a promise to support with his army one-tenth of the people of any State
                        who will attempt to set up a Government over the other nine-tenths, thus
                        seeking to sow discord and suspicion among the people of the several States,
                        and excite them to civil war in furtherance of his ends.</p>
                    <p>I know well it would be impossible to get your people, if they possessed full
                        knowledge of these facts, to consent that proposals should now be made by us
                        to those who control the Government at Washington. Your own well known
                        devotion to the great cause of liberty and independence, to which we have
                        all committed whatever we have of earthly possessions, would induce you to
                        take the lead in repelling the bare thought of abject submission to the
                        enemy.</p>
                    <p>Yet peace on other terms is now impossible. To obtain the sole terms to which
                        you or I could listen, this struggle must continue until the enemy is beaten
                        out of his vain confidence of our subjugation. Then, and not till then, will
                        it be possible to treat of peace. Till then; all tender of terms to the
                        enemy will be received as proof that we are ready for submission, and will
                        encourage him in the atrocious warfare which he is waging.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Governor Vance of North Carolina has urged Confederate
                    President Davis to cease fighting and work for peace.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Suppression of the New York World and the Journal of Commerce--Judge
                    Russell's Charge to the Grand Jury</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prints criticism from a Judge Russell about the government's suppression of
                    two newspapers for disloyal remarks.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Terrible Explosion in Washington</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on a deadly explosion at the arsenal in Washington in which
                    nineteen were killed and fifteen to twenty more were wounded.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.06.22.02">
            <pageNote>Poetry and fiction, columns 1-3, classified ads, columns 4-6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.06.22.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Crop of Roots</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges readers to diversify their harvests by planting root crops: parsnips,
                    carrots, and beets. Says this will provide employment during a time of the year
                    when jobs are usually scarce.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 2-6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.06.22.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Left-Handed Endorsement</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"And yet the President has permitted these "palpable, irreconcilable
                    dessensions" to exist for three long years, resulting in "evil only," and we are
                    nevertheless cooly asked to re-elect this same man and continue these
                    dissensions four years longer! This looks like a cruel joke on the part of our
                    neighbor."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The old maxim that there is nothing new under the sun is again at fault, as
                        seen in the amomalous [sic] position of the <emph rend="italic"
                        >Repository</emph> on the Baltimore nominee for the presidency. In one
                        column of its last issue we find an article abounding in hypocritical
                        laudations of Abraham Lincoln; in another column appears an article, under
                        the head of "Revision in the Cabinet," condemning his administration in the
                        most unequivocal terms. How the intensely "loyal" worshippers of Abraham the
                        First, will regard this disloyal assault on their great Master, is no
                        concern of ours. We hope, however, we will be pardoned for venturing to
                        advert to a single point.</p>
                    <p>The article in question is based on the assumption that the Cabinet of Mr.
                        Lincoln is divided in sentiment, and the first conclusion arrived at is,
                        that "a divided, discordant cabinet neutralizes its own influence upon the
                        policy of the country, and can be peculiarly <emph rend="italic">potent only
                            for evil</emph>." This bold charge of the <emph rend="italic"
                        >Repository</emph> against Mr. Lincoln and his cabinet will no doubt startle
                        our readers as it did us. It will not do for the <emph rend="italic"
                            >Repository</emph> to excuse itself by pretending that no part of the
                        censure was intended for Mr. Lincoln. It cannot make an exception in favor
                        of Mr. Lincoln without making itself appear ridiculous; for every tyre in
                        politics knows that the President is directly responsible to the country for
                        the conduct of his cabinet officers. He is not only responsible for the acts
                        of each individual member of the cabinet, but it is his solemn duty to
                        compel unity of purpose and harmonious action of the cabinet as a whole, if
                        the welfare of the country demands it. The <emph rend="italic"
                        >Repository</emph> says the welfare of the country <emph rend="italic"
                        >does</emph> demand unity and harmony in the cabinet of the President,
                        instead of which we have "palpable, irreconcilable dissensions" which can be
                        potent "only for evil."</p>
                    <p>Now, who is responsible for this condition of things which the <emph
                            rend="italic">Repository</emph> says is potent only for evil? There can
                        be but one answer to this question, and that is--Abraham Lincoln. He, and he
                        alone, has the power to remedy the evil. These men that are so "discordant"
                        in their views, hold their positions at his pleasure. He can remove them any
                        day; and it is his duty, whenever a member of the cabinet fails in the
                        proper discharge of his duties, to dismiss him forthwith. And yet the
                        President has permitted these "palpable, irreconcilable dessensions" to
                        exist for three long years, resulting in "evil only," and we are
                        nevertheless cooly asked to re-elect this same man and continue these
                        dissensions four years longer! This looks like a cruel joke on the part of
                        our neighbor.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Calls the Repository "hypocritical" for praising Lincoln in one column and
                    then condemning his cabinet in another.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Extraordinary Statement</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We verily believe that an investigation would show that of one hundred and
                    twenty five million dollars appropriated for recruits, at least one-half of it
                    found its way into the pockets of fellows who are now bawling for Lincoln and
                    Johnson."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Wonders where the reported 700,000 new recruits and the money appropriated
                    to pay them have gone.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Harmony of the Cabinet</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Agrees with the Repository that unity among the President's cabinet members
                    is wanting.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Chastises the Repository for not judging General Grant by the same criteria
                    that they judged (and criticized) General McClellan.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Calls the Republicans and the rebels the "twin curses of the country," and
                    suggests that electing an opposition administration would give the people back
                    their liberties.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Latest Telegraphic News!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Our forces drew out from within fifty yards of the intrenchments at Cold
                    Harbor, made a flank movement of an average of fifty miles' march, crossing the
                    Chickahominy and James River, the latter being two thousand feet wide and eight
                    and one-half feet deep at the point of crossing, and surprised the enemy's rear
                    at Petersburg."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>By the Atlantic and Ohio Telegraph Line--Offices in Shryock's Book Store and
                        at the Depot.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Reported Expressly for</emph> THE VALLEY SPIRIT.</p>
                    <p>Petersburg Not Yet Taken--The Outer Fortifications of the City
                        Carried--Official Details of the Great Flank Movement from the Chickahominy
                        to the James River.</p>
                    <p>Washington, June 18--10 P.M.</p>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">Major General Dix, New York:</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>The following despatch from Gen. Grant, dated yesterday, at 11 o'clock, A.
                        M., at City Point, has been received at this department:</p>
                    <p>The Ninth Corps this morning carried two more redoubts forming a part of the
                        defences of Petersburg, capturing 450 prisoners and 4 guns.</p>
                    <p>Our successes are being followed up.</p>
                    <p>Our forces drew out from within fifty yards of the intrenchments at Cold
                        Harbor, made a flank movement of an average of fifty miles' march, crossing
                        the Chickahominy and James River, the latter being two thousand feet wide
                        and eight and one-half feet deep at the point of crossing, and surprised the
                        enemy's rear at Petersburg.</p>
                    <p>This was done without the loss of a wagon or piece of artillery, and only
                        about one hundred fifty stragglers were picked up by the enemy.</p>
                    <p>In covering this move Warren's Corps and Wilson's cavalry had frequent
                        skirmishing with the enemy, each losing from fifty to sixty killed and
                        wounded, but inflicting an equal, if not a greater loss upon the enemy.</p>
                    <p>The Eighteenth Corps (Smith's) were transferred from White House to Bermuda
                        Hundred by water, moved out near to Petersburg on the night of their
                        arrival, and surprised, or rather captured, the very strong works northeast
                        of Petersburg before sufficient force could be got in them by the enemy to
                        hold them.</p>
                    <p>He was joined the night following this capture by the Second Corps, which in
                        turn captured more of the enemy's redoubts further south, and this corps was
                        followed by the Ninth, with the resutt [sic] above stated.</p>
                    <p>All the troops are now up except two divisions covering the wagon trains, and
                        they will be up to-night.</p>
                    <p>The enemy, in their endeavors to reinforce Petersburg, abandoned their
                        intrenchments in front of Bermuda Hundred. They no doubt expected troops
                        from the north side of James River to take their places before they were
                        discovered. Butler took advantage of this, and moved a force at once upon
                        the railroad and plank road between Richmond and Petersburg, which I hope to
                        retain possession of.</p>
                    <p>Too much credit cannot be given the troops and their commanders for the
                        energy and fortitude displayed in the last five days. Day and night has been
                        all the same, no delays being allowed on any account."</p>
                    <p>Later unofficial despatches show that at 8 o'clock this morning the enemy
                        still occupied Petersburg.</p>
                    <p>Major Morton was killed in an assault yesterday.</p>
                    <p>Nothing has been receivd to-day from Sherman or Hunter.</p>
                    <p>Our Army Within One Mile of Petersburg.<lb/> Important from General Sherman's
                        Department.</p>
                    <p>Washington June 19--9.45 P. M.</p>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">To Major Gen Dix:</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>This evening a despatch from City Point dated, 9 o'clock this morning,
                        reached the department.</p>
                    <p>It reports that our forces advanced yesterday to within about a mile in front
                        of Petersburg, where they found the enemy occupying a new line of
                        entrenchments which alter successive assaults we failed to [illegible], but
                        hold and have intrenched our position.</p>
                    <p>From the forces of the enemy within the new line it is inferred that
                        Beauregard has been reinforced from Lee's army.</p>
                    <p>No report has been received by the Department concerning the casualities
                        [sic] of our army in its operations since crossing the James River, except
                        the death of Major Morton.</p>
                    <p>General Sherman reports to-day, that the enemy gave way last night in the
                        midst of darkness and storm, and at daylight our pickets entered his line
                        from right to left. The whole army is in pursuit and is as far as the
                        Chattahouchie.</p>
                    <p>I start at once for Marietta.</p>
                    <p>No other military intelligence from any other quarter have been received
                        to-day.</p>
                    <p>E. M. Stanton, <lb/>Secretary of War.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letters from U. S. Grant and E. M. Stanton discussing the Union army's
                    advance within a mile of Petersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Ladies' Fair</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The whole enterprise was successful, even beyond the expectations of the
                    most sanguine of those engaged in it, and is a very satisfactory evidence of
                    what can be done, in this community, for the relief of the sick and wounded
                    heroes who have bared their bosoms to the bayonet and the bullet, in defense of
                    our country."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Fair held by the ladies of Chambersburg and vicinity for the benefit of
                        the U.S. Christian Commission opened in Franklin Hall, on the 13th inst. and
                        continued until Saturday evening last. The Hall and Court House were both
                        used for the display of the articles for sale, and were thronged during the
                        entire period with an interested and delighted crowd of visitors who
                        dispensed their cash with commendable liberality. The Halls were decorated
                        with much taste, and the display of articles in the various departments
                        spoke well for the industry and zeal of the ladies of our town when excited
                        into action by philanthropic and charitable objects.</p>
                    <p>The "Old Folks' Concert," on Friday and Saturday evenings, attracted immense
                        crowds from the neighboring towns and villages, and on each evening the Hall
                        was packed with a dense mass of delighted, though perspiring auditors. This
                        feature of the Fair was perhaps the most successful and yielded a
                        considerable amount of clear cash. The whole enterprise was successful, even
                        beyond the expectations of the most sanguine of those engaged in it, and is
                        a very satisfactory evidence of what can be done, in this community, for the
                        relief of the sick and wounded heroes who have bared their bosoms to the
                        bayonet and the bullet, in defense of our country.</p>
                    <p>We have been unable to procure a statement of the sum realized in each
                        department, but learn that the gross reciepts [sic] will reach the sum of
                        $4,300, and the nett [sic] profits not less than $3,200.</p>
                    <p>The ladies intend publishing a detailed statement of the receipts of each
                        department, with the nett [sic] profits realized therefrom, which we expect
                        to receive in time for publication in our next issue.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on the recent Ladies' Fair held at Franklin Hall for the benefit of
                    the Christian Commission.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Revival of the Iron Business</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The well known character of the new proprietor for energy of character of
                    and business capacity is a sufficient guaranty of their success."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hughes</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Major</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that Major Hughes has sold the Mont Alto Iron Works to a Mr. Ahl of
                    Cumberland County, who plans on erecting new furnaces.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Death of Capt. McKesson</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKesson</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that Captain Samuel R. McKesson died at age 42 after a long
                    illness.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Wounded</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greenawalt</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greenawalt</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Private John Greenawalt, son of Daniel Greenawalt and a member of the 21st
                    Pennsylvania Cavalry, died after being wounded during fighting at Cold Harbor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Dispatches reporting on troop movement around Petersburg, Virginia, column
            5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.06.22.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greenawalt</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maurer</ln>
                        <fn>B. Latrobe</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dechert</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jarrett</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fredrick</ln>
                        <fn>Christian</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Peters</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seibert</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn>Cyrus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seiders</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowman</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ludwig</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heneberger</ln>
                        <fn>Christian</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnitz</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Remp</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bert</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jacobs</ln>
                        <fn>P. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoffman</ln>
                        <fn>David S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lightcap</ln>
                        <fn>Theodore</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duke</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kunos</ln>
                        <fn>Christian</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lists the officers elected at the June 13 meeting of the Friendship Fire
                    Company: assistant engineer, Samuel Greenawalt; president, B. Latrobe Maurer;
                    vice president, John A. Seiders; treasurer, J. L. Dechert; secretary, Jacob
                    Jarrett; directors, Christian Fredrick, Peter Myers, J. W. Seibert; standing
                    committee, Cyrus Gordon, John A. Seiders, Christian Fredrick, George Stumbaugh,
                    Henry Bowman; chief pipeman, George Ludwig; assistant pipemen, Christian
                    Heneberger, John Barnitz; hose attachers, George Remp, John A. Seiders, John
                    Smith, Peter Myers, John Bert; hose guards, P. W. Jacobs, George Stumbaugh, John
                    Smith, David S. Hoffman, Theodore Lightcap; auditors, J. L. Dechert, John A.
                    Seiders, B. L. Maurer; axe men, Benjamin Duke, Christian Kunos; collector, Jacob
                    Jarrett; superintendent, Christian Heneberger.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Star Spangled Banner</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sollenberger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Praises the efforts of Capt. Sollenberger and the committee on
                    superintendence for erecting a pole from which the star spangled banner can fly.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Board of Enrollment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the Board of Enrollment is making its way through the region
                    and will eventually come to Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>77th Regiment P.V.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stark</ln>
                        <fn>Albert G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>1st Lieutenant</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Harry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sergeant</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hidler</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sergeant</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Neely</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hardsock</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cooper</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Authors</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moran</ln>
                        <fn>Francis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lists casualties among members of the 77th Pennsylvania Volunteers from
                    recent fighting in Georgia: Captain Samuel T. Davis, Company G, wounded severely
                    in the groin; 1st Lieutenant Albert G. Stark, slightly, cheek; Sergeant Harry
                    Miller, Company F, slightly, arm; Sergeant W. Hidler, Company C, slightly leg;
                    Private David Neely, mortally; Private Peter Hardsock, slightly; Private David
                    Cooper, Company D, slightly; Private Benjamin Authors, Company B, severely,
                    ankle; Private Francis Moran, Company G, slightly.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Drafted Men Cannot Enlist as Volunteers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that a government order states that drafted men cannot enlist as
                    volunteers after they have been drafted.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>U. S. Christian Commission</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the ladies of Mercersburg have collected one thousand dollars
                    for the Christian Commission.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Meyers</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Meyers</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On June 14, Rev. Samuel R. Fisher married Daniel Miller and Susan Meyers,
                    daughter of Samuel B. Meyers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Mary Kennedy died on June 9 at age 83.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bitner</ln>
                        <fn>Joshua</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bitner</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Joshua Bitner, son of Jacob Bitner, died on June 10 at age 9 years, 6
                    months and 20 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKesson</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Captain Samuel R. McKesson died on June 18 at age 42 years, 6 months and 6
                    days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>StClair</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>StClair</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary E. StClair, wife of William StClair, died on June 2 at age 19 years,
                    11 months and 3 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 3-6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.06.22.06">
            <pageNote>Dispatches reporting on troop movement and skirmishing in Arkansas, Tennessee,
                and Petersburg, Virginia, columns 1-3, classified ads, columns 3-6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.06.22.07">
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 1-6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.06.22.08">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Latest News by the Mails!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The hardest fighting was done by the colored troops. The forts they
                    stormed were the worst of all. After the affair was over General Smith went to
                    thank them and tell them he was proud of their courage and dash. He says they
                    cannot be excelled as soldiers, and that hereafter he will send them in a
                    difficult place as readily as the best white troops."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>From The Army of the Potomac. <lb/>Official Despatch--The Army Crosses the
                        James River--Gen. Grant at Bermuda Landing.</p>
                    <p>Washington, June 15, 7 A. M.</p>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">To Major General Dix, New York:</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>The movement of the Army of the Potomac to the south side of Richmond, across
                        the Chickahominy and James Rivers, has progressed far enough to admit of the
                        publication of some general facts without danger of a premature disclosure.</p>
                    <p>After several days preliminary preparations, the movement commenced on Sunday
                        night. The 18th Army Corps, under command of General Smith, marched to the
                        White House, and then embarked on transports for Bermuda Landing.</p>
                    <p>General Wright's corps and Burnside's moved to Jones' Bridge where they
                        crossed the Chickahominy and marched thence to Charles City, on the James
                        River. Hancock's and Warren's corps crossed the Chickahominy at Long Bridge,
                        and marched thence to Wilcox's, on the James River. The James River was
                        crossed by the army at Powhatan Point.</p>
                    <p>A despatch from Gen. Grant, dated Monday evening, 5 1/2 o'clock,
                        headquarters, Wilcox's Landing, states that the advance of our troops had
                        reached that place, and would commence crossing at City Point that night;
                        that no fighting was reported during the movement, except a little cavalry
                        skirmishing. Yesterday (Tuesday) afternoon at 1 o'clock, Gen. Grant was at
                        Bermuda Landing.</p>
                    <p>In a despatch from him dated there, of that date, he says, "our forces will
                        commence crossing the James River to-day. The enemy show no signs of yet
                        having brought troops to the south side of Richmond. Our movements from Coal
                        [sic] Harbor to the James River has been made with great celerity, and so
                        far without loss or accident."</p>
                    <p>An unofficial despatch dated at headquarters, 5.20 P.M., says that Smith's
                        corps was coming in, 5,000 having already landed.</p>
                    <p>A despatch from General Sherman's headquarters, dated at 3 P.M., yesterday,
                        near Kenasaw, states that the General is in front, advancing his lines on
                        Kenasaw.</p>
                    <p>Another unofficial despatch dated at 9 P.M., yesterday reports some advance
                        to-day; that Thomas had gained ground, and that one rebel brigade is nearly
                        surrounded.</p>
                    <p>It further reports that the rebel General Polk was killed to-day. His body
                        was sent to Marietta.</p>
                    <p>In another part of General Sherman's East Mississippi division, our forces
                        have not met with the success which has attended competent commanders.</p>
                    <p>Gen. Washburne, at Memphis, reports that the expedition, consisting of 3,000
                        cavalry and 5,000 infantry, and 16 pieces of artillery, sent out from there
                        a few days ago, under command of Gen. Sturgis, encountered a large rebel
                        force on the 10th inst., under command of Forrest, at Guntown, on the
                        railroad running south from Corinth, and after a severe fight, in which our
                        loss in killed and wounded was heavy, our forces were worsted; and at the
                        last accounts Sturgis was at Colliersville, retreating towards Memphis. He
                        further states that, with the troops that had lately arrived. Memphis is
                        safe.</p>
                    <p>General Sherman, having received the news of Sturgis' defeat, reports that he
                        has already made arrangement to repair the disaster, and has placed General
                        A. J. Smith in command, who will resume the offensive immediately.</p>
                    <p>No other military intelligence has been received by this Department since my
                        last telegram.</p>
                    <p>Edwin M. Stanton <lb/>Secretary of War</p>
                    <p>Reported Capture of Petersburg.</p>
                    <p>Fortress Monroe, June 16, <lb/>via Baltimote [sic], June 17.</p>
                    <p>Yesterday morning at 4 o'clock the 18th army corps, under the command of Gen.
                        W. F. Smith, left City Point and marched into Petersburg.</p>
                    <p>Gen. Kautz's cavalry, comprising the 5th and 11th Pennsylvania and District
                        of Columbia regiments, attacked the intrenchments of the rebels outside of
                        Petersburg, and at 11 A. M. succeeded in carrying them and entered the city.
                        They were supported by the advanced guard of General Smith's forces.</p>
                    <p>The troops were, at last accounts, marching in the direction of Petersburg as
                        fast as they landed.</p>
                    <p>The crossing of James River by the army is described by those who had the
                        good fortune of viewing it, as one of the most brilliant scenes of the war.</p>
                    <p>An endless stream of transports, barges and schooners have been making their
                        way up the James River to the new base of supplies all day to-day.</p>
                    <p>[Official.] <lb/>Despatch from Secretary Stanton, to General Dix.</p>
                    <p>Washington, June 17, 1864.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">To Major Gen. Dix</emph>:</p>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">The following despatches have been received by this
                            Department:</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>City Point, June 15.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">via</emph> Jamestown Island, 5.30 A. M., 16.</p>
                    <p>Smith with 15,000 men, attacked Petersburg this morning.</p>
                    <p>General Butler reports from his observatory, near Bermuda Hundred, that there
                        has been sharp fighting, and that the troops and trains of the enemy were,
                        as he writes, moving from the city across the Appomattox, as if retreating.</p>
                    <p>Hancock is not near enough to render Gen. Smith any aid.</p>
                    <p>The Richmond papers have nothing to indicate a suspicioun of our crossing the
                        James River. They expect to be attacked from the direction of Malvern Hill.</p>
                    <p>City Point, Va., 5.30 P.M. <lb/>June 15, 1864.</p>
                    <p>Our latest report from Smith was at four P.M. He had carried a line of
                        Intrenchments at Beatty's House, the colored troops assaulting and carrying
                        the rifle pits with great gallantry, but he had not yet carried the main
                        line. He describes the rebel artillery fire as very heavy.</p>
                    <p>He expected to assault this line just before dawn. Hancock is within three
                        miles of Gen. Smith.</p>
                    <p>City Point, Va., 7 A.M. June 16. <lb/>Via Jamestown Island, 11.45 A.M.</p>
                    <p>At 7.30 P.M. yesterday Smith assaulted and carried the principal line of the
                        enemy before Petersburg, taking thirteen cannon, several stands of colors,
                        and between three and four hundred prisoners. This line is two miles from
                        Petersburg. Hancock got up and took position on Smith's left at three A.M.
                        to-day. There was heavy firing in that direction from five to six o'clock.
                        No report has been received yet.</p>
                    <p>Dont Hard Landing, Va., 1 P.M. <lb/>June 15, 1864.</p>
                    <p>After sending my despatch this morning from the heights southeast of
                        Petersburg, I went over the conquered lines with Gen. Grant and the engineer
                        officers. The workers are of the very strongest kind, more difficult to take
                        than was on Missionary Ridge at Chattanooga. The hardest fighting was done
                        by the colored troops. The forts they stormed were the worst of all. After
                        the affair was over General Smith went to thank them and tell them he was
                        proud of their courage and dash. He says they cannot be excelled as
                        soldiers, and that hereafter he will send them in a difficult place as
                        readily as the best white troops. They captured six out of the sixteen
                        cannon which he took.</p>
                    <p>The prisoners he took were from Beauregard's command. Some of them said they
                        had just crossed the James River above Drury's bluff.</p>
                    <p>I do not think any of Lee's army had reached Petersburg when Smith stormed
                        it. They seem to be there this morning, however, and to be making
                        arrangements to hold the west side of the Appomattox. The town they cannot
                        think of holding, for it lies directly under our guns.</p>
                    <p>The weather continues splendid.</p>
                    <p>City Point, Va., June 16--4.15 P.M.</p>
                    <p>Gen. Butler reports from Bermuda Hundred that the enemy have abandoned the
                        works in front of that place. His troops are now engaged in tearing up the
                        railroad between Petersburg and Richmond.</p>
                    <p>The following despatch does not designate the hour, and it is supposed to be
                        later than the preceding ones:</p>
                    <p>Jamestown, Va., June 16.</p>
                    <p>I came down from the pontoon above Powhattan with despatches for Secretary
                        Stanton. Just as I left Capt. Pitkin reported to me that Petersburg was in
                        our possession.</p>
                    <p>Nothing of recent date has been heard from Gen. Sheridan, but the Richmond
                        Whig of the 15th contains a despatch from Gen. Lee, stating that Sheridan
                        had been routed in an engagement with Fitz Lee and Hampton, losing 500
                        prisoners, and leaving his dead and wounded on the field.</p>
                    <p>From General Sherman, a despatch dated last night at nine o'clock, has been
                        received. It only states the relative position of the forces. No serious
                        engagement had yet occurred.</p>
                    <p>Edwin M. Stanton <lb/>Secretary of War.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letters from Secretary of War Edwin Stanton describing the movement of the
                    Army of the Potomac south of Richmond across the Chickahominy and James Rivers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 1-6</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
