<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1864/pa.fr.vs.1864.04.20">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Amy Murrell</taggerName>
            <tagDate>10/21/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 4/2/63</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1864-04-20">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day>20</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.04.20.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Miscegenation</head>
                <origin>London Saturday Review, March 12</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Condemns several prominent abolitionist writers for reportedly supporting
                    miscegenation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Another Outrage</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges the Democratic newspaper in Monroe County to strike back against
                    Republicans in that area after a group of drunken soldiers destroyed the paper's
                    offices.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Way the Shoddyites Carry Elections</head>
                <origin>Monitor</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Accuses Republicans in Connecticut of unfairly rigging that state's recent
                    election in their favor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Congressional</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Summarizes recent proceedings of the US Congress, including consideration
                    of a bill to reduce fraud upon the Treasury.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Reports of troop movement and skirmishing in Tennessee and Louisiana, columns
                4-5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.04.20.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>From Fortress Monroe Release of all the Union Prisoners in Richmond</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that nearly a thousand Union soldiers and officers were returned to
                    the North from Richmond prisons on April 7.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Poetry and fiction, columns 1-6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.04.20.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Tomato Culture</head>
                <origin>Culturist</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Gives overview of different techniques that can be used to grow "perfect"
                    tomatoes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.04.20.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Freedom of Debate</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Condemns the Republican "demagogues" in Congress for trying to expel a
                    member who publicly suggested that the Democratic party could restore the Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Maryland Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Mourns the loss of the "freedom of the ballot" in Maryland, where no "real"
                    election has been held in the last three years. The editor says that the
                    elections that have been held have been fraudulent since voters have been
                    required to take loyalty oaths.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Personal Security</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"There is a deep sense of insecurity beginning to pervade the minds of the
                    community with regard to the protection of their persons and property.
                    Lawlessness seems to prevail everywhere, in high as well as in low places."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>There is a deep sense of insecurity beginning to pervade the minds of the
                        community with regard to the protection of their persons and property.
                        Lawlessness seems to prevail everywhere, in high as well as in low places.
                        Those charged with the high and responsible duties of executing the laws and
                        administering justice with an impartial hand, have been found shamefully
                        derelict in the performance of their duties. That strict impartiality and
                        inflexible integrity in the administration of the laws to which we were
                        formerly accustomed, is now no more to be seen. Political prejudice and
                        partisan bigotry are the influences that control the actions and decisions
                        of many of our public officers; and the fact that a man belongs to this or
                        that party, has much more to do with his obtaining justice at the hands of
                        the executors of the law, than the merits of his case.</p>
                    <p>Is it any wonder that the people are growing uneasy under this sense of
                        insecurity of their property, reputation and lives? Is it any wonder that
                        they are beginning to inquire whether there is any longer any hope left for
                        protection, save in their own ability to defend themselves? This is a
                        serious question, involving the dearest interests and rights of every man,
                        woman and child in the community, and should engage the serious attention of
                        every well-wisher of society. We may, perhaps, have more to say on this
                        subject in our next.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Accuses the public officers of Chambersburg of exercising favoritism toward
                    anyone who commits a crime but is a Republican.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Legislative</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that the state legislature has again proposed a bill to relieve
                    citizens whose property has been damaged in the war. The editor wonders whether
                    the Governor will decide to veto the bill again this year.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The State Capital</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Expresses opposition to a proposal to move the state capital from
                    Harrisburg to Philadelphia. Argues that Harrisburg is more central and equally
                    accessible to all sections of the state.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>How the Rebellion is Abetted--The Folly of the House</head>
                <origin>New York Times</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"How is it possible for true men so to misunderstand the American people,
                    as to suppose they will submit quietly to this destruction of free debate in the
                    council halls of the nation?"</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A Republican newspaper expresses outrage that members of Congress tried to
                    suppress the speech of a congressman who supported Northern copperheads.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Apportionment of the State</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that the recent apportionment of Pennsylvania House and Senate
                    districts is unfair to the Democrats. Franklin County was assigned only one
                    member of the House and, with Adams County, one member of the Senate.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.04.20.05">
            <div type="j">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Court Proceedings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bryan</ln>
                        <fn>Morgan R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flory</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Unger</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn>Cyrus H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keyser</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGowan</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heagy</ln>
                        <fn>John S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports on recent court cases. In the case of Commonwealth versus Morgan R.
                    Bryan, the defendant was found guilty of manslaughter in the death of Frank
                    Jones at the home of George Eyster, Esq. In the case of Commonwealth versus John
                    Flory, the defendant was found not guilty of murder in the death of Henry Unger,
                    a constable in Waynesboro. In the case of Commonwealth versus George W. White,
                    the defendant was found guilty of aggravated assault and battery. In
                    Commonwealth versus William Keyser, the defendant was found not guilty of
                    larceny. In Commonwealth versus James McGowan, the defendant was found guilty of
                    malicious mischief and guilty of assault and battery. In Commonwealth versus
                    John S. Heagy, the defendant was found not guilty of larceny.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Pennsylvania Reserves</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that the Pennsylvania Senate has passed a resolution asking the
                    Governor what he intends to do about reenlisting members of the Pennsylvania
                    Reserve Volunteer Corps after their terms have expired.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Information Wanted</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zink</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zink</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Porter</ln>
                        <fn>W. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Asks that any information on Andrew or Henry Zink, refugees from Virginia,
                    be sent to W. W. Porter of Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClellan</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClellan</ln>
                        <fn>James M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClellan</ln>
                        <fn>Mary A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On April 7, James McClellan, son of James M. and Mary A. McClellan, died at
                    age 10 months.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gryer</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Mary Gryer died on March 31 at age 78.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCune</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCune</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On April 1, James W. McCune, son of George McCune, died at age 1.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shook</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shorts</ln>
                        <fn>Harry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shorts</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George W. Shook, son of Harry and Margaret Shorts, died on April 10 at age
                    1.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spring</ln>
                        <fn>B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. B. Spring died on April 13 at age 79.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kershner</ln>
                        <fn>Catherine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kershner</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf>dec'd</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Catherine Kershner, widow of Joseph Kershner, dec'd, of Franklin County,
                    died on March 28 in Benson County, Illinois. She was 73 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 3-6, report of an explosion in New York harbor aboard
                the steamer Chenango, column 3</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.04.20.06">
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 1-6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.04.20.07">
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 1-6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1864.04.20.08">
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 1-6</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
