<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vr1863/pa.fr.vr.1863.06.12">
    <header>
        <title>Waynesboro Village Record</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/11</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Waynesboro</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1863-06-12">
            <year>1863</year>
            <month norm="06">June</month>
            <day>12</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr..vr.1863.06.12.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Clergy and Slavery</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Close to 2,000 clergymen in France and England have united to condemn the
                    "Slave Aristocracy," says the article. The religious leaders assert that the
                    Confederacy, based as it is on slavery, "is at war with Christianity." In fact,
                    proclaims the piece, outside of the South, with the exception of northern
                    copperheads, this sentiment "is the view of the Christian world."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Copperhead Logic</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>According to the article, it is quite easy to determine the motives
                    underlying copperheads' support for the Confederacy: naked self-interest.
                    Proponents of the southern cause in New York advocate "peace at any cost"
                    because they "lost the Southern trade" as a consequence of the war. Similarly,
                    supporters of the rebel cause in Illinois are spurred primarily by the drop in
                    the price of corn occasioned by the onset of the conflict. These malcontents,
                    the article declares, would rather "break up the nation" than sacrifice their
                    own personal economic interests.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr..vr.1863.06.12.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Address</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Gen. Stumbaugh, of Chambersburg, spoke at the Union League meeting last
                    Monday where he was greeted with an "enthusiastic" reception. The subject of his
                    speech was a "history of the Rebellion," from its commencement to the present.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>"CopperHead" Sheet</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article notes the appearance of a new copperhead journal in
                    Philadelphia, the Age. The new publication expresses sentiments so treasonable,
                    says the piece, that a man would have to be a "bold, bonified traitor" to
                    endorse such opinions.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>For Clerk of the Courts</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brotherton</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>It is reported that local Union men have convinced W. H. Brotherton to run
                    for clerk of the Courts, a decision praised by the editors of the Village
                    Record.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Newspaper Change</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>A. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoner</ln>
                        <fn>H. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A. K. McClure has purchased the Repository and Transcript and the Dispatch,
                    and plans to merge the two newspapers together. McClure and H. S. Stoner will
                    join forces to pursue the new enterprise.</summary>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Patriot</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Ridicules the Valley Spirit for describing Vallandigham as a "Patriot," and
                    asserts that the local Democratic organ would no doubt label Jeff Davis the
                    same.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Death of a Soldier</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shockey</ln>
                        <fn>Jeremiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jeremiah Shockey, member of Co. I 106th Reg. Illinois Volunteers, died at
                    Boliver, Ky, on May 24th. Shockey, a former resident of Waynesboro, was 32 years
                    old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Copperhead Love of Free Speech</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"On Monday evening of last week, the Copperheads of New York city, held
                    a meeting to denounce the arrest of Vallandigham and to assert the right of free
                    speech. An old gentlemen was introduced on the platform, who said:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>To highlight the copperheads' hypocrisy regarding free speech, the piece
                    relates the story of a elderly gentleman who was heckled and ultimately dragged
                    from the stage at a copperhead meeting in New York because he asserted that
                    South Carolina started the war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Coming Draft</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Dispels the rumor circulating that drafted men will not have to serve
                    longer than 9 months from the date of enlistment. According to the 11th section
                    of the Enrollment Act, the article declares, all men conscripted into the
                    military shall remain in the service during the war, but not longer than three
                    years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Important About the Prospective Draft</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Provost Marshall will begin conscripting soldiers immediately, though
                    he will not call on nine-months men for the first draft. Those men who fall into
                    that category and opt to volunteer, it is said, will be paid a large bounty.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Since being admitted to the military, reports the article, black soldiers
                    have received considerable praise for their actions thus far. Black troops are
                    grouped as follows: under Gen. Thomas, 11,000; under Gen. Banks, 3,000; in
                    Kansas, 1,000; in South Carolina, 3,000; in North Carolina, 3,000; under Gen.
                    Rosecrans, 5,000; under Gen. Schofield, 2,000; Massachusetts regiments, 1,200;
                    District of Columbia, 800. The total number of black soldiers is 30,000; there
                    are also 5,000 black men in the navy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Western Correspondence</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>"Keystone"</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>A booster, and former resident of Pennsylvania, writes glowingly about his
                    new home in Illinois, though he does concede that all is not perfect. There is a
                    divide among the state's populace over the Civil War: in the northern section of
                    the state, he contends, the people are "more intelligent than in the Southern
                    portion" where there is a far greater number of copperheads.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Storming of Port Hudson--Our Losses One Thousand--Heroism of the Negroes</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">The Storming of Port Hudson--Our Losses One
                            Thousand--Heroism of the Negroes</emph>.</p>
                    <p>WASHINGTON, June 9.--General Hanks, in his official report, dated before Port
                        Hudson, May 30th, gives an account of the attack at that place similar to
                        the facts already published. In speaking of the negro troops he says they
                        answered every expectation. Their conduct was heroical. No troops could be
                        more determined or more daring. They made, during the day, three charges
                        upon the batteries of the enemy, suffering very heavy losses, and holding
                        their position at nightfall with the other troops on the right of our line.
                        The highest commendation is bestowed upon them by all the officers in
                        command on the right. Whatever doubt may have existed heretofore as to the
                        efficiency of organizations of this character, the history of this day
                        proves conclusively to those who were in a condition to observe the conduct
                        of these regiments, that the Government will find in this class of troops
                        effective supporters and defenders. The severe test to which they were
                        subjected, and the determined manner in which they encountered the enemy,
                        leaves upon my mind no doubt of their ultimate success, they requiring only
                        good officers, command of limited numbers, and careful discipline, to make
                        them excellent soldiers.</p>
                    <p>Our losses from the 23d to this date, in killed, wounded, and missing, are
                        nearly one thousand, including, I deeply regret to say, some of the ablest
                        officers of the corps.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>According to Gen. Banks report, black soldiers performed "heroical[ly]"
                    during the attack on Port Hudson, which, he noted, was a severe test of their
                    abilities and bravery.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Tomb</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harper</ln>
                        <fn>Bruce Anderson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harper</ln>
                        <fn>D. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harper</ln>
                        <fn>M. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On June 6th, Bruce Anderson, son of D. B. and M. N. Harper, died in
                    Greencastle. He was 2 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Tomb</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sollenberger</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Kate</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sollenberger</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sollenberger</ln>
                        <fn>Bella</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On June 5th Mary Kate, infant daughter of John and Bella Sollenberger, died
                    in Waynesboro. She was 7 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vr.1863.06.12.03">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vr.1863.06.12.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
