<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vr1863/pa.fr.vr.1863.01.09">
    <header>
        <title>Waynesboro Village Record</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>10/16/00</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Waynesboro</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1863-01-09">
            <year>1863</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day>09</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vr.1863.01.09.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Judicial Loyalty</head>
                <origin>Washington Chronicle</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article dismisses the notion that rebel sympathizers in the loyal
                    states should be dealt with by the judiciary as "suicidal," particularly in the
                    wake of the violence perpetrated against soldiers in Baltimore, who were
                    attacked while on their way to defend the capital. The judiciary, it complains,
                    has failed to protect the interests of the state and has instead focused its
                    energies on limiting the power of the government to prosecute the war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vr.1863.01.09.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Sudden Death</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Good</ln>
                        <fn>Christian</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Christian Good, "an aged and highly respected citizen," died suddenly last
                    Friday. Good was in church attending a funeral when he was struck by apoplexy.
                    He was 79 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Another</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gonder</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gonder</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Gonder, wife of Michael Gonder, died suddenly at Waterloe last
                    Tuesday. It is believed that apoplexy was the cause of her death.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Proclamation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"It is not an argument, or a defence, or a declaration; it is simply the
                    frank announcement of a brave and frank man."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">The Proclamation</emph>.--Abraham Lincoln (says the
                        Press,) has proclaimed the downfall of slavery in the United States. The
                        Proclamation we print this morning announces his decree in brief, eloquent,
                        and immortal sentences. It is not an argument, or a defence, or a
                        declaration; it is simply the frank announcement of a brave and frank man.
                        Those who expect to read an invocation to blood and massacre and rapine will
                        be surprised by the sincere and affectionate warning of the President to the
                        people whose deliverance he proclaims. The beneficial power that declares
                        freedom does not incite murder; it takes away the burden of national death
                        from the hereafter, and makes the country of our children the country of
                        freedom. This is the general thought that pervades the Proclamation; but
                        that which is practical and immediate, is the conversion of this silent,
                        oppressed, and anxious race into active allies of the Union. It adds a
                        reserve force to the army of the Union, and makes three million of slaves
                        three million of able-bodied recruits, who have only to see the Union banner
                        to follow it with their lives. It takes away the labor that sustains the
                        power of the South, and adds to the military power of the North. It is a war
                        measure, and will add strength to our armies and glory to the object of the
                        war. These ideas should be impressed upon the minds of all who read the
                        Proclamation this morning. Let the people accept this great deed in the
                        spirit that animates the President, appreciating the beautiful sentiments in
                        which he declares it to be an act of justice warranted by the Constitution,
                        upon military necessity, and invokes the considerate judgement of mankind,
                        and the gracious favor of Almighty God.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article praises President Lincoln's Emancipation Proclamation as both
                    an act of benevolence and an intelligent tactical maneuver.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Arrest of Deserters</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Herr</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Constable</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stone</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>It is reported that three deserters from Frederick, Md., were arrested by
                    Constable Herr near Waynesboro last Saturday. After committing several robberies
                    in Frederick county, the deserters took flight but were pursued and eventually
                    captured in Franklin county. Following an examination by Judge Stone, the trio
                    was sent to Chambersburg to be held in that town's jail. The property that they
                    absconded with--several horses--has been returned to its rightful owners.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Meeting of the Legislature</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>On Tuesday, the state legislature met in Harrisburg; G. V. Lawrence, of
                    Washington county, was re-elected Speaker of the Senate and John Cessna, of
                    Bedford county, Speaker of the House.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Killed</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Housum</ln>
                        <fn>P. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>It is reported that Col. P. B. Housum, of the 77th Regiment, P. V., died
                    during the Battle of Murfreesboro. Housum was from Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Can These Things Be?</head>
                <origin>Shippensburg News</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Can These Things Be</emph>.--The [illeg] (says the
                        Shippensburg <emph rend="italic">News</emph>) [illeg] hour in live history
                        of this once happy and prosperous country--an hour which makes every true
                        patriot feel that we are trembling on the brink of ruin, and that we cannot
                        be too watchful lest the dangers which surround us overwhelm us and crush us
                        as a nation. An army of traitors has risen up as if by magic, and is
                        spreading distress and desolation over the land, and the sight of the pallid
                        corpse and the mangled and careworn veterans has made even the child
                        familiar with the horrors of the fearful struggle in which we are engaged.
                        But there are dark shadows where there should be nothing but sunrise. Even
                        on the soil where all hearts should beat with unison for the preservation of
                        this glorious Republic, there are men who sympathize with those who are
                        undermining the pillars of our beautiful edifice, and who are sending sorrow
                        and distress into thousands of homes that hitherto have been happy. It will
                        be impossible to estimate the evils that have been brought upon the nation
                        by this mad festival of treason. Cities in its wake have become dens of
                        pauperism and of crime, towns have been sacked, fair fields have been laid
                        waste, and families that have heretofore lived in luxury and ease, have been
                        reduced to abject poverty; and yet the men who have brought this calamity
                        upon our country, can find those who palliate their crimes, and who denounce
                        those who are striving to save the nation from destruction. The new made
                        graves in every village church-yard, bear melancholy evidence of their
                        treason; and the maimed and mutilated heroes whom you meet in your daily
                        walks are living, speaking witnesses of the enormity of the crimes of these
                        blood-stained villains; yet you meet hourly those who would extend to them
                        the right hand of fellowship, and would welcome them back into the Union,
                        and confer upon them all the rights and privileges enjoyed by men whose
                        souls are free from the guilt of treason and murder.</p>
                    <p>To-night many a widowed mother, sits with crushed heart, sorrowing for her
                        gallant son, who fell at the post of honor and of duty, and who, perhaps,
                        lies buried among the promiscuous dead of the battle-field. Many a fireside
                        is sad and desolate to-night, that but recently was made joyous and happy by
                        the pleasant jest and merry laugh of some loved one whose tongue is now
                        silent and whose heart is still in death; yet we are told that the men who
                        have brought this desolation and sorrow upon our country and people, are our
                        brethren and should be forgiven. Can the fond mother forget that the hope of
                        her heart--the idol of her declining years, has been hurried down to a
                        premature grave by the ruffian hand of our traitor "brethren." Can the
                        sorrowing father forget the tears which he so recently shed on the last
                        resting place of his heroic son who fell by the hand of these "brethren."
                        When these wrongs can be forgotten, they will forgive the murderers; but not
                        till then.</p>
                    <p>Can it be possible that the loyal men of the nation, after having suffered
                        all the evils which have resulted from this unholy rebellion, will consent
                        that the foul fiends who organized it, shall be brought back into the Union,
                        and be again clad in the robes of power, and be permitted to hold up their
                        bloody hands in the councils of the nation, the equals of those who have
                        stood by their flag in sunshine and gloom? Can they stand beside the graves
                        of their honored kindred, whose blood reddens the battle-field, made
                        memorable by their heroism and their death, and say with those who
                        sympathize with treason, that they will so dishonor the memory of the
                        gallant dead, as to forget and forgive those who slew them? Will they
                        consent to any settlement of this struggle, which will permit the leading
                        spirits of this rebellion to escape without satisfying the demands of
                        justice by ending their criminal lives on the gallows? Let those now be
                        dealt with as they dealt with John Brown, and the loyal men of the nation,
                        and those who are mourning over the grave of the immortal dead, will be
                        convinced that our rulers are not afraid to deal out impartial justice to
                        all, and to punish those who offend against the majesty of the law.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article rules out the possibility of rekindling relations with the
                    South anytime soon in light of the death and destruction caused by the war,
                    which, it argues, was initiated by the South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that the President has approved the bill admitting West Virginia into
                    the Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Emancipation Proclamation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A transcript of President Lincoln's Emancipation Proclamation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Altar</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Price</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoner</ln>
                        <fn>Harriet J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Good</ln>
                        <fn>D. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Jan. 6th, Benjamin E. Price and Harriet J. Stoner were married by Rev.
                    D. F. Good.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Altar</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bonebreak</ln>
                        <fn>H. X.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fouke</ln>
                        <fn>Agnes L. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Krebs</ln>
                        <fn>W. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Nov. 12th, H. X. Bonebreak and Agnes L. E. Fouke, daughter of Dr. George
                    S. Fouke of Westminster, Md., were married by Rev. W. E. Krebs.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Tomb</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Resh</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Resh</ln>
                        <fn>Susan R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Resh</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Dec. 30th, Elizabeth Catharine, daughter of Daniel B. and Susan R. Resh,
                    died. She was 3 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Tomb</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>James Buchanan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Jan. 3rd, James Buchanan, son of John and Susan Harbaugh, died in
                    Waynesboro. He was 6 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Tomb</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gossert</ln>
                        <fn>Jeremiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gossert</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gossert</ln>
                        <fn>Susannah Virginia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Jan. 1st, Susannah Virginia, daughter of Jeremiah and Mary Gossert, died
                    of diphtheria. She was 6 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vr.1863.01.09.03">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vr.1863.01.09.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
