<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vr1863/pa.fr.vr.1863.01.16">
    <header>
        <title>Waynesboro Village Record</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>10/16</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Waynesboro</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1863-01-16">
            <year>1863</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day>16</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vr.1863.01.16.01">
            <pageNote>A variety of human interest stories and anecdotes as well as extracts from the
                sermons of two preachers, Rev. R. C. Grundy, of Kentucky, and Rev. Dr. Paxton, of
                Pittsburg.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vr.1863.01.16.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Personal Property for Sale</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilbert</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mong</ln>
                        <fn>G. V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>An announcement that John Gilbert's property will be sold at a public sale
                    on Jan. 29th. The auctioneer will be G. V. Mong.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Drought</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>With many wells failing and the water level of streams so low that millers
                    are unable to grind, the article notes that the region is in grip of severe
                    drought.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Election of United States Senator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Election of U. S. Senator</emph>.--The election of Mr.
                        Buckalew by the Legislature of Pennsylvania as U. S. Senator, over such a
                        man as Hughs, Randall and others of like ilk, must prove gratifying to all
                        loyalists. His election certainly affords sympathisers with treason no
                        grounds for exultation. We doubt not some persons in this town who threw up
                        their hats at the announcement of his election, will find that their <emph
                            rend="italic">little</emph> demonstration was premature by the time they
                        shall have digested the following paragraph which we extract from Mr. B's
                        address on being conducted to the Chair:</p>
                    <p>"While the heart sickens at this loss of life and expenditure of treasure,
                        let no loyal man hesitate as to our future course. The Union should, and I
                        trust, will be preserved. The Constitution respected and the laws enforced,
                        at whatever expenditure of life and money; the interest involved demands the
                        sacrifice. It should be the ardent prayer of all just men that the cause of
                        this unhappy strife, which is plainly apparent should be stricken down.
                        Christians, patriots and philanthropists throughout the world, will approve
                        this course, and peace when conquered, will be perpetual. Let the
                        administration rise to a higher appreciation of its duties to the people.
                        Let there be no jealousies, no exhibition of party strife, no sympathy with
                        rebels. <emph rend="italic">Opposition to the constitutional authorities in
                            this struggle to maintain and preserve the Government by all legitimate
                            means, whether by force of arms or by proclamations calculated to weaken
                            and destroy the power of the government, and to remove the cause of the
                            strife forever, is little short of</emph> TREASON. Let us, then, in our
                        action here on the <emph rend="italic">question at least</emph>, as may be
                        presented, show our devotion to the government, to the interest of our
                        children, and to the cause of civil liberty throughout the world."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Senate and House met in a joint session in Harrisburg last Tuesday and
                    elected Charles R. Buckalew as the state's next Senator. Buckalew won the
                    contest by a slim majority of two votes. With the exception of Mr. Laporte, the
                    Republicans all cast their support for Simon Cameron. Laporte voted for W. D.
                    Kelly.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Small Pox</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Several "mild" cases of small pox have been reported in Chambersburg, but,
                    as yet, the "loathsome and terrible disease" has failed to make an appearance in
                    Waynesboro.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Counterfeit Postage Currency</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is reported that counterfeit lithographed fifty-cent postage stamps are
                    currently circulating. The forgeries, it seems, are of a substandard quality.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Court</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Russelll</ln>
                        <fn>D. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>Russell</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lesher</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mickley</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Summers</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Slaughenhaup</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wishard</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Besore</ln>
                        <fn>Josiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Funk</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garlinger</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stamy</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Amberson</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hooflich</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jacobs</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snider</ln>
                        <fn>K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shank</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A notice informing readers that court will be in session next week in
                    Chambersburg. The following men have been selected to perform jury duty: Grand
                    Jurors, D. B. Russell, Abraham Baker, Henry Lesher, Daniel Mickley, Jacob
                    Summers, William Slaughenhaup, and John Wishard; Traverse Jurors, Josiah Besore,
                    John Funk of H., Daniel Garlinger, Abraham Stamy, W. S. Amberson, J. H. Gordon,
                    William Hooflich, George Jacobs, K. Snider, and Daniel Shank.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Election of U. S. Senator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lauding the election of Buckalew as "gratifying to all loyalists," the
                    article contends that the new Senator will not relent in prosecuting the war to
                    its end. The piece employs an extract from Buckalew's victory speech to validate
                    its position.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Altar</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ditch</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ripplin</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Oiler</ln>
                        <fn>J. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Jan. 8th, Jacob Ditch and Susan Ripplin were married by Rev. J. F.
                    Oiler.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Tomb</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boult</ln>
                        <fn>Clare Samantha</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Jan. 1st, Clare Samantha Boult, 12, died near Waynesboro.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Tomb</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wiesner</ln>
                        <fn>Charles Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wiesner</ln>
                        <fn>Franklin Edward</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wiesner</ln>
                        <fn>Philip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wiesner</ln>
                        <fn>Mary C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Jan. 1st, Charles Henry, 21 months old, and Franklin Edward, 8 months,
                    sons of Philip and Mary C. Wiesner, died near Waynesboro.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vr.1863.01.16.03">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vr.1863.01.16.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
