<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vr1863/pa.fr.vr.1863.02.20">
    <header>
        <title>Waynesboro Village Record</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>10/31</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Waynesboro</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1863-02-20">
            <year>1863</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day>20</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vr.1863.02.20.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>A Heroine</head>
                <origin>Altona Register</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A Correspondent of the <emph rend="italic">Atlanta Register</emph>, writing
                        from Broadtop City, Huntingdon county, says he had the pleasure of meeting
                        at a place called Dudley, a woman named Mary Owens, who had just returned
                        from the army, in full uniform. This remarkable woman accompanied her
                        husband to the army, and fought by his side until he fell. She was in the
                        service eighteen months, and took part in three battles, and was wounded
                        twice; first in the face above the right eye, and then in her arm, which
                        required her to be taken to the hospital, where she confessed the deception.
                        She had enlisted in Danville, Montour county, Pennsylvania, under the name
                        of John Evans, and gives as her reason for this romantic undertaking, the
                        fact that her father was uncompromising in his hostility to her marriage
                        with Mr. Owens, threatening violence in case she disobeyed his commands;
                        whereupon having been secretly married, she donned the United States
                        uniform, enlisted in the same company with her husband, endured all the
                        hardships of the camp, the dangers of the battlefield, saw her husband fall
                        dead by her side, and is now wounded and a widow. Mrs. Owens looks young, is
                        rather pretty, and is the heroine of the neighborhood. She is of Welsh
                        parentage.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A story on a woman named Mary Owens who joined the army with her husband.
                    Under the assumed name of John Evans, Owens passed herself off as a man and
                    enlisted in Montour county, Pennsylvania. During her eighteen month tenure,
                    Owens took part in three battles and was wounded twice before her husband was
                    killed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>On The Choice Of A Wife</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Go my son, said the Eastern sage to Talmore, go forth to the world, be wise
                        in the pursuit of knowledge--be wise in the accumulation of riches--be wise
                        in the choice of friends; yet little will avail thee, if thou choosest not
                        wisely the wife of thy bosom.</p>
                    <p>A wife! what a sacred name--what a responsible office? She must be the
                        unspotted sanctuary to which wearied man may flee from the crimes or the
                        world, and feel that no sin dare enter there. A wife? She must be the
                        guardian angel of his footsteps, on earth, and guide them to Heaven; so firm
                        in virtue that should he for a moment waver, she can yield him support, and
                        replace him upon his firm foundation: so happy in conscious innocence, that
                        when from the perplexities of the world he turns to his home, he may never
                        find a frown where he sought a smile. Such, my son, thou seekest in a
                        wife--and reflect well ere thou choosest.</p>
                    <p>Open not thy bosom to the trifler; repose not thy head on the breast that
                        nurseth envy and folly and vanity. Hope not for obedience where the passions
                        are untamed; and expect not honor from her who honoreth not the God who made
                        her.</p>
                    <p>Though thy place be next to the throne of princes and the countenance of
                        loyalty, beam upon thee--though thy riches be as the pearls of Omar, and thy
                        name honored from the East to the West, little will avail thee if darkness
                        and disappointment, and strife be in thine own habitation. There must be
                        passed thine hours in solitude and sickness--and there must thou die.
                        Reflect then, my son, ere thou choosest, and look well to her ways whom thou
                        wouldst love; for though thou be wise in other things--little will it avail
                        thee if thou choosest not wisely the wife of thy bosom.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A homily on the importance of choosing a good wife.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vr.1863.02.20.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Returned</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>W. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>After a furlough of several weeks in Waynesboro, Capt. W. W. Walker
                    returned to his regiment yesterday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ford</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Forney</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Last Friday, Lieut. Ford, of the Provost Battalion, died at McConnelsburg
                    from injuries he suffered several weeks earlier while pursuing a deserter named
                    John Forney.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is reported that the controversy involving the Anderson Troops has been
                    rectified. One regiment has been released from confinement and has returned to
                    duty. An agreement was reached with the soldiers, granting them the right to
                    select their own officers. Additionally, they have been given new assignments:
                    body guards for General Rosecrans.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Letter From The 158th</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Camp [illeg] Newbern<lb/> January [?]th, 1863.</p>
                    <p>[illeg] [illeg]--In [illeg] letter I informed you that on our arrival at
                        Suffolk, Va., December 17th we were marched about 9 o'clock, P. M., 14 miles
                        from town, into a dense thicket of dwarfed jack-oaks, young pines, vines,
                        thorn bushes, &amp;c. The following day, we policed the ground, cleared
                        about 5 acres, burned the brush, uprooted the stumps and smoothed over the
                        ground. Expecting to remain here, the men, during leisure hours betook
                        themselves to building cabins, carrying suitable timber about 1 1/2 miles,
                        dressing it, and thus performing no small amount of labor. Scarcely had they
                        rendered themselves comfortable, when marching orders were received, tents
                        struck, and the line of march taken up, for North Carolina. On arriving
                        here, we were encamped in the neighborhood of a cypress swamp, in a thicket
                        like the one that greeted us at Suffolk. Presuming this time that we would
                        not be again moved for some time, the men underwent the same labors as in
                        their late camp. Not a week elapsed before marching orders again reached us,
                        when we flitted to a more <emph rend="italic">healthy</emph> location on the
                        banks of the Neuse and encamped in a clearing, dense with stumps of green
                        pine; and while I write the ring of five hundred axes, intermingled with the
                        curses not loud but deep, of the men, breaks the morning stillness. Our
                        Regiment has performed more and severer labor than any other of the late
                        draft, and we are wearying of it.</p>
                    <p>My servant Hanabal Napoleon Jackson and his fate.</p>
                    <p>Charles Jackson, alias Hanabal Napoleon Jackson, was born, and doubtless,
                        bred, in Orange county, New York. His early history is wrapped up in the
                        archives of the Harpies; for <emph rend="italic">he</emph> is entirely
                        oblivious of parents or relatives, and thinks, like Tobsy, that he never was
                        born, but <emph rend="italic">growed</emph>. He stoutly avers that he was
                        keeper and groom of the celebrated thorough-bred, Tom Crib, prior to the
                        rebellion; and his knowledge of the use of <emph rend="italic"
                        >ginger-root</emph>, and such other medical herbs, as the learned Farriers
                        brings into requisition on certain peculiar occasions inclines me to believe
                        this part of his autobiography. Hanabal was in "the war on the Peninsula."
                        "When morning come, in dem days, and dem d--m hissing acorns come whissin'
                        roun' dis nigger cut off his train, and down he went behind de sand hills;
                        till some ball would dash into de sand and cover dis chile; when out he
                        creeps, and gives de double-shuffle, till de balls come, too thick agin; den
                        he dodges down agin. Dis nigger don't like dem balls nohow. Ah, Lord, Lord,
                        dem were hot times. I tell you de niggers had no tar on dare heels den; dey
                        handled dem as if they were treaden on a galvanie mushine; one time dey run
                        dis way, till de d--d Rebels fotched up fore dem, den dey turns round and
                        runs tuder way, and den de Rebels was too, and so dare woolly heads were
                        popin up and down all over de plain, every day. Oh! Lord, what a
                        flusterfication dare was den, Kunels yelling, Captins shouting, hosses
                        jumping, and niggers blowin' scared to def, and de rat--at, bomb, bomb,
                        hiss, hiss, I golly dis nigger tout he'd quit soldierin', if he ever got
                        alive out of dat scrape. In this strain the Dark continues for hours,
                        rolling his chalky eyes, and his quid, grinning like an ape, and some times
                        maneuvering in illustration, thus making many an hour pass by lightly and
                        jollily. His strong military name, I gave him, on account of his knowledge
                        of tactics. He goes through the manual like a regular. He performs the part
                        of orderly, well; every beat or call is familiar to him; his chief
                        peculiarity is hatred of "conklabands!" if he sees one approach, he cries
                        out: "dont cum near me, you d--d nigger;" reason, the contrabands work
                        cheap, are polite and respectful, and more idling. As cook, Hanabal does not
                        excel: but he has profound respect unto his stomache; he is ever fearful
                        that Captain or Lieut. will eat <emph rend="italic">too much</emph>, is sure
                        to have a meal ready, just a few moments before the hour for drill, etc, is
                        particularly careful to retain a large portion for himself; and has a
                        thousand excuses for burning or otherwise spoiling a dish. A few days ago a
                        catastrophe occurred that dissolved Hanabal's connection with us. He was
                        standing over the store busily cooking and chattering, when Lieut. M.
                        happening to pass close by him, beheld one of those "<emph rend="italic"
                            >varmints</emph>," that usually haunt a soldier's dream, leisurely
                        napping on the young man's shirt collar. Consternation filled the tent.
                        Hanabal was marched to the woods, to undergo an examination. It was highly
                        amusing to hear the many apologies and excuses he had to make against
                        undergoing the scrutiny of his eben form. After many threats and a little
                        rough handling he slowly shed his shirt, when horror of horrors! Hanabal was
                            <emph rend="italic">alive</emph>, the aptera charging over him in
                        battalions, or building cities, or settling down to undisturbed rural life!
                        Alas poor Hanabal! I fear he will be doomed to habitate with the "d--d
                        Conklabands!</p>
                    <p>How Now? Why we are cooking <emph rend="italic">ourselves</emph>. Now,
                        wouldn't you wish to see your very humble servant hanging, <emph
                            rend="italic">breathlessly</emph>, over--a pot! or broiling a steak, or
                        frying oysters! or my second Lieut. stirring the meal into the water,
                        boiling mush! him who had rejoiced for years over the viands so deliciously
                        gotten up, by that Princess of cateras Mrs. B?--It's an ill wind that blows
                        no one any good; we imagine that we eat 60 pr. ct. less dirt; we are <emph
                            rend="italic">sure</emph> that our meals are concocted in better style,
                        etc., besides, we'll hire another cook as soon as we can obtain one, minus
                        the aptors. Nothing new. We get your paper, the only one we see. Won't some
                        of our friends send us the 'Press occasionally.' In my next of sundry
                        matters relating to soldiering, Adio. W. T. B.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>W. T. B.</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>A letter from a soldier in the 158th Regiment detailing his experiences in
                    the first weeks following his arrival in Virginia. Included in his account is a
                    description of and anecdote about a black man hired to cook for the officers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Tomb</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Funk</ln>
                        <fn>Granvil E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Funk</ln>
                        <fn>Henry M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Funk</ln>
                        <fn>Emily</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Feb. 5th, Granvil E. Funk, son of Henry M. and Emily Funk, died near
                    Leitersburg. He was 20 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Tomb</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garver</ln>
                        <fn>Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Feb. 5th, Ann Garver, 83, died at the residence of F. Harbaugh near
                    Hagerstown.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Tomb</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Philips</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Philips</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Philips</ln>
                        <fn>Myrtle</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Philips</ln>
                        <fn>Minnie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Feb. 5th and 6th, John and Susan Philips lost their two daughters,
                    Myrtle and Minnie. The two girls were victims of scarlet fever.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vr.1863.02.20.03">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vr.1863.02.20.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
