<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vr1863/pa.fr.vr.1863.01.23">
    <header>
        <title>Waynesboro Village Record</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>10/27</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Waynesboro</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1863-01-23">
            <year>1863</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day>23</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vr.1863.01.23.01">
            <pageNote>A variety of miscellaneous articles.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vr.1863.01.23.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Another Citizen and Soldier Gone</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pilkington</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Thomas G. Pilkington, post master of Waynesboro and a member of Co. A.
                    126th Regiment P. V., died of diarrhea in the Washington hospital last Thursday.
                    Prior to his death, Pilkington was wounded in the "terrible" battle of
                    Rappahannock, suffering injuries to his hands and arms, though he managed to
                    recover from his ailments.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Support the Government</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Support the Government</emph>.--The present
                        administration will administer the government for two years longer. Every
                        official movement towards ending the rebellion must be made by and through
                        them. The natural and, in fact, the only enemy of the rebellion is the
                        government of the United States. The only weapon by which a blow can be
                        struck at the rebellion is the executive of the United States. Every good
                        citizen should endorse and set upon the sentiment of the Washington <emph
                            rend="italic">Chronicle</emph>, that those who strengthen the arm of
                        President Lincoln, weaken the rebels, and those who attack, embarrass or
                        hinder the administration, give aid and comfort to them, and help to prolong
                        their efforts. In a state of peace, any amount or kind of opposition to the
                        administration is justifiable, but in time of war, it is the duty of every
                        man who desires the good of his country, to give all the moral support he
                        can to the executive.</p>
                    <p>It has often been the case that a large minority of a nation has been opposed
                        to entering upon a long and expensive war; but when the step is once taken,
                        and the honor of the nation is once committed, that minority has always
                        rallied to the support of their country. While their judgement might be
                        opposed to the war, their pride and their patriotism alike compel them to
                        smother all opposition, even if they cannot lend their active co-operation.
                        But history nowhere records of any people so wide spread and cordial a
                        sympathy with their enemies as exists to-day among the people of the United
                        States of America. Still less does history afford an example of a great
                        people who have been wantonly attacked and insulted, furnishing a large and
                        powerful minority, who openly sympathise with their enemies, rejoice at
                        their reverses, and advocate the very cause in support of which they are
                        unjustifiable attacked. The government of the United States has been forced
                        by circumstances into supporting the cause of human freedom against not only
                        its own citizens in rebellion, but against all sovereignties of the
                        civilized world. Independently of the holiness of the cause, the concert,
                        the malignity and the magnitude of the attack ought to call out the pride
                        and the patriotism of every man who has a spark of courage in his heart.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>With two years remaining before the President's mandate is set to expire,
                    the piece admonishes readers to remain steadfast in their support for the
                    administration and the war effort. Unlike during times of peace, when opposition
                    is "justifiable," it maintains, the circumstances currently dictate that "it is
                    the duty of every man who desires the good of his country, to give all the moral
                    support he can to the executive."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Negroes Hanged in Charleston</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A British subject who arrived in Norfolk, from Charleston, South Carolina,
                        within a few days, gives the information that nineteen Negroes were hung in
                        the streets just prior to his departure. This occurred in consequence of a
                        discovery made in a rather singular manner. The whites there for some time
                        past have been closely watching the movements of the blacks, and thinking
                        that they observed an unusual number of funerals among them, a white man
                        disguised himself, and following in one of the processions, on arriving at
                        the burial ground he discovered that the coffin contained arms, which were
                        taken from it and buried in a vault, in which a number had already been
                        deposited. The consequence of this discovery was the execution of nineteen
                        of the most intelligent of the conspirators.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is reported that 19 blacks were recently killed in Charleston after it
                    was discovered that slaves in the city were involved in a conspiracy to
                    stockpile arms. The authorities targeted for execution the "most intelligent of
                    the conspirators."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Altar</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fahrney</ln>
                        <fn>David D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Benchoff</ln>
                        <fn>Susan Francis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Colder</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Dec. 30, 1862, David D. Fahrney and Susan Francis Benchoff were married
                    by Rev. James Colder.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Altar</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McFerren</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Savidge</ln>
                        <fn>C. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Jan. 23rd, George W. McFerren and Maggie E. Beard, of Washington county,
                    Md., were married by Rev. C. H. Savidge.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Tomb</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rodgers</ln>
                        <fn>Clinton Jerome</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Jan. 19th, Clinton Jerome Rodgers, 6, died near Waynesboro.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Tomb</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>Julia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Jan. 16th, Julia Davis, 49, died in Funkstown.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Tomb</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tallhem</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tallhem</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tallhem</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Jan. 17th, William, son of William and Susan Tallhem, died near Shady
                    Grove. He was 13 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vr.1863.01.23.03">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vr.1863.01.23.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
