<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vr1863/pa.fr.vr.1863.05.08">
    <header>
        <title>Waynesboro Village Record</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>11/29</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Waynesboro</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1863-05-08">
            <year>1863</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day>08</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vr.1863.05.08.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Loyal or Disloyal</head>
                <origin>Harper's Weekly</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>I lately dined in company with one of those insane young gentlemen who, as
                        Theodore Winthrop says in "Cecil Dreeme," praises slavery and think they are
                        aristocratic. The young gentleman went on for some time when Mrs. -- said to
                        him politely:</p>
                    <p>"If you sympathize with the rebels, why don't you go and join them?"</p>
                    <p>"I, madame? I assure you I am perfectly loyal."</p>
                    <p>"Indeed?"</p>
                    <p>"Why, certainly, only I stand by the government, not by the administration."</p>
                    <p>"So Vallandigham says."</p>
                    <p>"I mean I am no abolitionist."</p>
                    <p>"So Brooks says."</p>
                    <p>"That is, I am afraid we are alienating the South."</p>
                    <p>"So Tom Seymour says."</p>
                    <p>"In other words, I am a Union man, but I don't think war can restore it."</p>
                    <p>"So Toucey says."</p>
                    <p>"But, my dear madame, the war is unconstitutionally carried on."</p>
                    <p>"So George Ticknor Curtis says."</p>
                    <p>"I mean that our liberties are in danger."</p>
                    <p>"So Fernando Wood says."</p>
                    <p>"Come, then, isn't it hopeless?"</p>
                    <p>"So the <emph rend="italic">London Times</emph> says."</p>
                    <p>"Yes, my dear madame, but what on earth do <emph rend="italic">you</emph>
                        say?"</p>
                    <p>"I say that whoever stands against the administration in this war stands
                        against the government. I say that whoever says he is no abolitionist means
                        that he intends to embarrass the war. I say that whoever is afraid of
                        alienating the South is afraid of irritating a snake that has already stung
                        him. I say that whoever thinks that force cannot restore the Union does not
                        know that union is the most irresistible instinct of the American people. I
                        say that whoever says the war is unconstitutionally carried on is in danger
                        of being split by the tempest in which he is trying to split hairs. I say
                        that whoever says our liberties are imperiled by the government and not by
                        the rebellion, works and prays for the rebellion and the annihilation of all
                        civil liberty and order. I say that whoever calls the war fratricidal has no
                        more conception of national honor than lottery dealers are said to have of
                        honesty. I say that whoever considers the cause of the United States as
                        hopeless hates that cause in his heart, and is utterly ignorant of the
                        character of the people and the facts of the situation. That is what I say,
                        and that is what every truly American man and woman says and believes."</p>
                    <p>The young gentleman made no reply; but the next day, at the club, he said to
                        a friend "I dined yesterday at Mrs.--'s. What an awful abolitionist she
                            is!"--<emph rend="italic">Harper's Weekly</emph>.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An anecdote about a young man who is chastised, in a variety of ways, for
                    his anti-war sentiments by a female dinner companion.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>"Copperheads" Rebuked</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A copy of the resolutions passed by the officers of the 171st Pennsylvania
                    Regiment, stationed in New Bern, N. C., in support of the war effort and the
                    Lincoln administration's policies.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="-2" image="pa.fr.vr.1863.05.08.-2">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Arrest of "Copperhead" Chief</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on the arrest of the "notorious Ohio 'Copperhead,' Vallandigham," a
                    development that is sure to antagonize local war opponents.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Borough Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Welsh</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hahn</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Morrison</ln>
                        <fn>L. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bender</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zindorff</ln>
                        <fn>Pius D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The following is the result of the recent borough election: Chief Burgess,
                    Jacob R. Welsh; Councilmen, David Hahn, L. K. Morrison, Joseph W. Miller, Joseph
                    Bender, and George Harbaugh; High Constable, Pius D. Zindorff.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Thieves About Again</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hess</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Last Friday, thieves broke into the office of the Snow Hill Society and
                    stole thirty loaves of bread and large quantities of sugar, butter, and apple
                    butter. The next day, Jacob Hess's smoke house was burgled, it is presumed by
                    the same party; the thieves escaped with all of his bacon, eight hams and a
                    number of shoulders.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Another Soldier Deceased</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snowberger</ln>
                        <fn>Amos</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snowberger</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>News has arrived that Amos Snowberger, son of David Snowberger, of Quincy
                    township, died on April 18th in New Bern, N. C. Snowberger, a private in the Co.
                    E. 158th Regiment Penna. Infantry, was the second son in his family to die while
                    serving his country.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Death of Young Shockey</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shockey</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shockey</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On May 3rd, William Shockey, of Co. G. 17th Penna. Cavalry, died near Aqua
                    Creek Landing, Va. of typhoid fever. The soldier's remains were brought to
                    Waynesboro on Tuesday and interred the following day on the burial ground on Mr.
                    Hoover's farm, near Ringold.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Union Loyal League Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Union Loyal League Meeting</emph>.--In another column
                        will be found the proceedings of the Union Loyal League Meeting which was
                        held in the Hall on Monday evening, with the Pledge and Resolutions offered
                        and adopted. The meeting having been organized, after some very timely and
                        appropriate remarks by Mr. GEORGE BESORE, Mr. M. S. NEWCOMER of this
                        vicinity was called for and delivered a most eloquent and patriotic address
                        which was highly applauded by the audience. As is usual on such occasions,
                        the sneaking "copperhead" was about and efforts were made to interrupt the
                        meeting. A pack of these slimy reptiles gathered about the door and upon the
                        steps of the Hall, bellowing and making all possible noise which they kept
                        up during the evening. It seemed that the audience were determined to just
                        see to what extent these "copperheads" would carry their meanness. Not
                        satisfied with the noise, hissing the speaker, hallowing for the "C. S. A.,"
                        etc., just before the meeting adjourned an egg was hurled against one of the
                        windows breaking the glass. Notwithstanding all this there are those who
                        have the affrontry to get up and make great professions of loyalty and at
                        the same time declare that there are no disloyal persons here nor elsewhere
                        in the north. Why this attempt then to interrupt the speaker and insult the
                        audience? The meeting was not a political one. The invitation was to loyal
                        men of all parties. Could a loyal person be guilty of such conduct?
                        Assuredly not. The fact is, parties who thus demean themselves are not loyal
                        to the Government, and hence union meetings, union speakers and union
                        newspapers are obnoxious to them. The man who asserts that nobody is
                        disloyal in the loyal states must be one of two things, a fool or
                        full-fledged traitor. Who tore down under cover of darkness, in Waynesboro,
                        months ago, the American flag? Were they loyal hands?</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editorial relates that the organizational meeting for local chapter of
                    the Union League went off smoothly with the exception of the expected
                    interruptions of several copperheads who, like "slimy reptiles," milled about
                    the hall "bellowing" throughout the evening.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Provost Marshall</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George Eyster, of Chambersburg, was named Provost Marshall for Franklin
                    county's Congressional District. According to the Conscription Law drafted the
                    year before, Eyster will be responsible for overseeing the draft, should one be
                    necessary, and the arrest of all deserters.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Negro Recruitment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Negro Recruits</emph>.--A Recruiting Officer from
                        Massachusetts, was in Mercersburg, a couple of days last week, and
                        succeeded, in the short time he remained there, in enlisting twenty
                        able-bodied Colored men for the United States service.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is reported that a Recruiting Officer from Massachusetts enlisted 20
                    black men for the army from Chambersburg during his stay in town last week.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Physician Dead</head>
                <origin>Pilot</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Luther</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowles</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. Luther M. Miller, of Welsh Run, died last Tuesday of pulmonary disease,
                    from which he had been suffering for the past couple years. Prior to his death,
                    Miller was in the care of Thomas Bowles.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Seven Negroes Burned To Death</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sprigg</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Last Sunday seven blacks--one man, one woman, and five children--were
                    killed in a blaze that destroyed Joseph Sprigg's stable, where the victims were
                    living. The fire, says the article, was deliberately set.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>William T. Barnitz</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnitz</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snowberger</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snowberger</ln>
                        <fn>Amos</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A letter to David Snowberger from Capt. Barnitz detailing the last moments
                    of his son's death. Amos Snowberger died suddenly in New Bern from the effects
                    of disease.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Army Correspondence</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>New Berne, N. C.<lb/> April 28, 1863</p>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">Farewell to New Berne--On Pamlico Sound again--to Little
                            Washington!--Our quarters--The Secesh Hegira!</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>In my previous letters I endeavored to keep pace with our expeditions, and
                        advise you of our fortunes; but latterly we have been on the tramp or move
                        continually and I find it impossible to detail all the events occurring:
                        viz., how, in the regular order of things, we marched on 'Blunts Creek,'
                        killed eighty Rebs with a coolness not conceivable, took a gross of Rebs,
                        and an old grey hoss, confiscated honey, sweet potatoes and niggers; ignited
                        Rebel shanties, turned up trumps and made things git, generally;--marched,
                        as usual, through swamps, water, mud, and terrible rain-storms, drenching us
                        completely,--then turned homeward, footsore and weary, hoping that on
                        reaching camp, we would enjoy a rest of a week or two;--how on reaching
                        Neuse river, we were marched into the brush and ordered to encamp for the
                        night!--as the Paymaster, that lovely being was coming across in the morning
                        with pay for four months; how the boys rejoiced on the receipt of the $58.50
                        in <emph rend="italic">greenbacks</emph>, and immediately enclosing it in
                        proper style sent it by Adam's Express to their families or friends; how the
                        next morning we marched on Swift creek Village, drove in the Rebel pickets,
                        took possession of their rifle pits and entrenchments, extending for miles;
                        how our hearts were surcharged with sorrow at seeing the afflictions and
                        sufferings of widows, whose husbands had been pressed and killed in the
                        rebel service. One case I shall never forget. Going into a small house, I
                        found a widow surrounded with six little ones, and one in her lap, but five
                        weeks old! The Col. asked her whether our men were disturbing her; with
                        despair marked on her every feature, her eyes swollen with recent weeping,
                        she sorrowfully replied, "They can't disturb me; I have, as you see, nothing
                        for them to take, I have had nothing for myself and children to eat for two
                        days!"--and then, bursting into tears, she said, "Yes, I have two chickens,
                            <emph rend="italic">don't let them take them!</emph>"--her children
                        meanwhile gathered close about her, their eyes glittering, cheeks hollow,
                        and faces looking cadaverous, all showing that they were starving! Unable to
                        bear the sight the Col. turned away, told the boys her condition, and asked
                        them if they would share their rations with her. Immediately haversacks were
                        opened, and a perfect stream of crackers and coffee, and sugar, and meat
                        poured into the little cabin; money also was given her, and her face and
                        those of the little ones brightened up at this exhibition of sympathy and
                        kindness, and with thanks, she said, "Ah! the South was wrong, in commencing
                        this war; the rich don't feel it; the poor lose all; we must starve!" The
                        little children seized the crackers, and oh! with what avidity they ate
                        them! With many a tear and heavy hearts we turned away to enter a large
                        house, where niggers were dancing attendance, and where want was unknown;
                        where plenty formerly reigned and luxury stalked unchecked. Here a young
                        lady, in barred-silk, hauty as a queen, with nose and upper-lip upturned,
                        presented herself and tauntingly inquired why we did not come yesterday, as
                        the Rebs had just left? We replied by inquiring why they did not wait for
                        us? She didn't see it exactly, but started off in a flow of southern
                        eloquence, that reminded me of the dashing little stream without depth, all
                        noise and sound. She wished she was a man that she might rejoice in killing
                        Yankees! The Col. handed her his pistol and told her to shoot <emph
                            rend="italic">him</emph>! "She gave in!" "Well" says she, "I'm tired of
                        this war; I wouldn't like to kill any one; would to God we could have
                        peace!" This is the heartfelt wish of every Reb we have met.</p>
                    <p>The Rebs having scattered, Gen. Foster marched two brigades to
                        Washington--the siege having ended,--and our brigade was ordered back to New
                        Berne. Rumors were rife the few days we remained at New Berne, that we were
                        going to be moved; some hoped, <emph rend="italic">heard</emph>, BELIEVED
                        that we were going to Washington D. C.--some that we were to be sent home to
                        have an opportunity to enlist; others conjectured Roanoak Island to be our
                        destination; this morning all doubts were removed, our suspense ended by
                        being marched aboard the fine steamer Long Island destined for Little
                        Washington! Though the sky was again concealed in ominous clouds, as when we
                        started before for the same place, and were shoaled, and frightened and
                        sickened; yet the air remained calm, and the steamer glided over the waters
                        like Anseres, the men filling the decks, smoking, chatting, playing cards,
                        the officers in the cabin, reading, writing, amusing themselves in every
                        possible manner, and enjoying the fine fare the steward so plentifully
                        provided, and so richly and deliciously served up.</p>
                    <p>We reached here, early in the evening and were assigned quarters. I have
                        command of two Block-Houses, in which my company is comfortably quartered;
                        Co. C. does provost duty in town, the other companies are on duty at other
                        points in the vicinity. Little Washington is beautifully over arched by the
                        long majestically blowing limbs of the stately trees, thickly planted on
                        either side. I merely marched through it, and hence cannot give an accurate
                        description of it. The Rebs shelled our fortifications, blockhouses,
                        &amp;c. two weeks with no effect, no body was hurt.</p>
                    <p>To-day there is great commotion in town; all those refusing to take the oath
                        of allegiance must vamose,--move beyond our lines; they have been trifled
                        with long enough, and lived off the government; let them feel some of the
                        joys, the genial fruition of rebel rule. Would to God, that all such stock
                        were beyond our lines; we would fight with better heart and better spirit,
                        and with more effect. Hereafter our friends will address us at this place.</p>
                    <p>Adio,<lb/> W. T. B.</p>
                    <p>P. S. Col. McKibbin returned a few days before we left New Berne, much to the
                        satisfaction of the whole regiment, which turned out immediately in front of
                        his quarters, and after having given him cheer after cheer in token of their
                        joy at his return, he made a speech which evidenced his attachment to his
                        men and the generous feelings of his heart; long may he wave!</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>W. T. B.</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Another letter from W. T. B., member of the 158th Penn. Regiment.,
                    regarding his most recent exploits in the South. Among the anecdotes related in
                    the piece is a story about a widow whose pitiful condition prompted Union
                    soldiers to share their rations with the woman and her seven children.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Union Loyal Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>According to a previous call for a meeting for the purpose of forming a Loyal
                        Union League, the citizens of Waynesboro and vicinity assembled this
                        evening, and organized by electing WM. ASKWITH, President and J. F. KURTZ,
                        Sec'ry, pro tem. The following Pledge was then read and unanimously adopted:</p>
                    <p>We the undersigned, citizens of the United States, hereby associate ourselves
                        under the name and title of the Union Loyal League of Waynesboro and
                        vicinity.</p>
                    <p>We pledge ourselves to an unconditional loyalty to the Government of the
                        United States, to an unwavering support of its efforts to suppress the
                        rebellion, and to spare no endeavor to maintain unimpaired the National
                        unity, both in principle and territorial boundary.</p>
                    <p>The primary object of this league is, and shall be, to bind together all
                        loyal men, of all trades and professions, in a common union to maintain the
                        power, glory, and integrity of the Nation.</p>
                    <p>On motion the report of the committee on resolutions was referred back to the
                        committee, to which was added the names of Geo. Besore and John Philips, for
                        their reconsideration and revision. The report of the committee on
                        organization was then received and adopted. The officers selected are as
                        follows:</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">President</emph>--John Woolson.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Vice Presidents</emph>--George Besore and H. X. Stoner.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Corresponding Secretary</emph>--J. R. Gaff</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Recording Secretary</emph>--Jacob B. Resser.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Treasurer</emph>--John Philips.</p>
                    <p>On motion, J. R. Gaff, John Philips and J. B. Resser, were appointed a
                        committee to procure a book, transcribe the pledge and solicit subscribers
                        to the same.</p>
                    <p>After the business of the evening had been attended to, M. S. Newcomer was
                        called for and delivered a most stirring and patriotic address. The meeting
                        then adjourned to meet Friday evening, May 8th.</p>
                    <p>WM. ASKWITH, Pres't.</p>
                    <p>J. F. KURTZ, Sec'ry.<lb/> Waynesboro, May 4, 1863.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Askwith</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kurtz</ln>
                        <fn>J. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woolson</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Besore</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoner</ln>
                        <fn>H. X.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gaff</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Philips</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Resser</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newcomer</ln>
                        <fn>M. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A copy of the resolutions passed at the organizational meeting for the
                    Waynesboro chapter of the Union League.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vr.1863.05.08.03">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vr.1863.05.08.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
