<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vr1863/pa.fr.vr.1863.06.19">
    <header>
        <title>Waynesboro Village Record</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/19</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Waynesboro</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1863-06-19">
            <year>1863</year>
            <month norm="06">June</month>
            <day>19</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vr.1863.06.19.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>A Romantic Story</head>
                <origin>Louisville Journal</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Louisville Journal of the 20th ult., narrates the following romantic
                        story:</p>
                    <p>A few weeks since a captain, accompanied by a young soldier apparently about
                        seventeen years of age, arrived in this city in charge of some rebel
                        prisoners. During their stay in the city the young soldier alluded to had
                        occasion to visit headquarters, and at once attracted the attention of
                        Colonel Munday as being exceedingly sprightly and possessed of more than
                        ordinary intelligence. Being in needs of such a man at barracks No. 1, the
                        Colonel detailed him for service in that institution. He soon won the esteem
                        of his superior officers, and became a favorite with all connected with the
                        barracks.</p>
                    <p>A few days ago, however, the startling secret was disclosed that the supposed
                        young man was a young lady, and the fact was established beyond doubt by a
                        soldier who was raised in the same town with her and knew her parents.</p>
                    <p>She "acknowledged the corn," and begged to be retained in her position to
                        which she was assigned; having been in the service ten months, she desired
                        to serve during the war. Her wish was accordingly granted, and she is still
                        at her post.</p>
                    <p>We learned the above facts stated yesterday, and took occasion to visit the
                        barracks and were introduced to "Frank Martin" (her assumed name,) and
                        gleaned the following incidents connected with her extraordinary career
                        during the past ten months.</p>
                    <p>"Frank" was born near Bristol, Pa., and her parents now reside in Alleghany
                        City, Pa., where she was raised. They are highly respectable people, and in
                        very good circumstances. She was sent to the convent in Wheeling, Va., at
                        twelve years of age, where she remained until the breaking out of the war,
                        having acquired a superior education and all the accomplishments of modern
                        usage. She visited home after leaving the convent, and after taking leave of
                        her parents, proceeded to this city in July last, with the design of
                        enlisting in the 2d East Tennessee cavalry, which she accomplished and
                        accompanied the Army of the Cumberland to Nashville.</p>
                    <p>She was in the thickest of the fight at Murfreesboro, and was severely
                        wounded in the shoulder, but fought gallantly, and waded the Stone river
                        into Murfreesboro on the memorable Sunday on which our forces were driven
                        back. She had her wound dressed, and here her sex was disclosed, and Gen.
                        Rosecrans made acquainted with the fact. She was accordingly mustered out of
                        the service, notwithstanding her earnest entreaty to be allowed to serve the
                        cause she loved so well. The General was favorably impressed with her daring
                        bravery and superintended the arrangements for her safe transmission to her
                        parents. She left the Army of the Cumberland, resolved to enlist again in
                        the first regiment she met. When at Bowling Green she found the 8th Michigan
                        there, and enlisted, since which time she has been and is now connected with
                        it.</p>
                    <p>She is represented as an excellent horseman, and has been honored with the
                        position of regimental buglar in the regiment. She had seen and endured all
                        the privations and hardships incident to the life of a soldier, and gained
                        an enviable reputation as a scout, having made several wonderful
                        expeditions, which were attended with signal success.</p>
                    <p>"Frank" is only eighteen years of age, quite small and a beautiful figure.
                        She has auburn hair, which she wears quite short, and huge blue eyes,
                        beaming with brightness and intelligence. Her complexion is naturally very
                        fair, though slightly bronzed at present from the effects of exposure. She
                        is exceedingly pretty, and very amiable. Her conversation denotes more than
                        ordinary accomplishments, and, what is stranger than all, she appears very
                        refined in her manners giving no evidence whatever of her rudeness which
                        might naturally be expected from her late associations.</p>
                    <p>"Frank" informs us that she has discovered a great many females in the army
                        and is now intimately acquainted with a young lady who is a lieutenant in
                        the army. She had assisted in burying three female soldiers at different
                        times whose sex was unknown to any but herself.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The piece recounts the story of a young woman who disguised herself as a
                    man and enlisted in the Army of the Cumberland. While serving, it reports, the
                    woman fought valiantly but was wounded in the Battle of Murfreesboro, at which
                    time her identity was discovered and she was mustered out. Soon after, however,
                    the woman re-enlisted with the 8th Michigan where she has remained since.
                    According to the female soldier, she is not unique; in fact, she relates, she
                    has discovered "a great many females in the army and is now intimately
                    acquainted with a young lady who is a lieutenant in the army."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vr.1863.06.19.02">
            <pageNote>Page missing.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vr.1863.06.19.03">
            <pageNote>Page missing.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vr.1863.06.19.04">
            <pageNote>Page missing.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
