<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vr1863/pa.fr.vr.1863.03.13">
    <header>
        <title>Waynesboro Village Record</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>11/07</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Waynesboro</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1863-03-13">
            <year>1863</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day>13</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vr.1863.03.13.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Arbitrary Arrests in the Time of the Revolution</head>
                <origin>Journal of Congress, 1777</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A copy of the resolution passed by Pennsylvania and Delaware as the nation
                    prepared for an imminent attack by the British. The resolution authorized the
                    arrest of those individuals suspected of "aiding or abetting the cause of the
                    enemy," and called for the seizure of their arms. The act also included a
                    provision that temporarily suspended the writ of habeas corpus.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vr.1863.03.13.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Disgraceful</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that, by a strict party vote, the Pennsylvania Legislature refused
                    to allow Gov. Andrew Johnson, of Tennessee, and Gov. Wright, of Indiana, to
                    address the General Assembly while the two men were in Harrisburg. The article
                    regrets the "infamous and disgraceful" occurrence and suggests that it "will be
                    applauded" by local "'copperheads.'"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Treasonable Document</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is reported that several local, prominent copperheads are involved in a
                    scheme to distribute pamphlets containing a speech recently delivered by "the
                    Ohio traitor, Vallandigam." Despite the fact that Vallandigam was threatened
                    with violence in his own state for his pro-southern views, the piece
                    sardonically notes, for some reason, parties in Franklin county "applaud the
                    villain and seek to give him notoriety by disseminating his treasonable
                    documents among the people."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The 87th Pennsylvania</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A copy of the resolutions recently passed by the officers of the 87th
                    Pennsylvania, now stationed in Winchester, Va., excoriating northern rebel
                    sympathizers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Copperheads in 1814 and 1863</head>
                <origin>Telegraph</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Comparing them to the Federalists who convened the infamous Hartford
                    Convention, the article declares that "[c]opperheadism of today is the offshoot
                    of copperheadism of 1812-14." But, it adds, just as the Federalists were dealt a
                    stunning blow as a consequence of their actions following the U. S. victory over
                    the British, a similar result will befall "the latest generation," which "will
                    be visited with the scorn and damnation of not only all American freemen," but
                    by the "lovers of freedom throughout the world" as well.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Union Ticket</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Union Ticket</emph>.--The following is the ticket
                        nominated by the Union party of Washington township, to be supported at the
                        coming spring election:--</p>
                    <p>Judge, Josiah Besore; Inspector, Christian Shockey, jr.; Assessor, Geo
                        Summers, sen.; Auditors, Nicholas Bonebreak, one year, Jacob S. Good, three
                        years; School directors, Abraham Shockey, John Oller; Supervisors, Jacob
                        Bonebreak, Valentine Kechler, Daniel B. Resh; Magistrate, Jacob Carbaugh;
                        Constable, Joseph Funk; Constable, (Borough) Jacob Foreman.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Besore</ln>
                        <fn>Josiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shockey</ln>
                        <fn>Christian</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Summers</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bonebreak</ln>
                        <fn>Nicholas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Good</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shockey</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Oiler</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bonebreak</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keehler</ln>
                        <fn>Valentine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Resh</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Funk</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foreman</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A list of the Union party candidates for office in Washington township in
                    the upcoming election.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Democratic Ticket</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Leckrone</ln>
                        <fn>Simon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hartman</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koons</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Oaks</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wetzel</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Funk</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walter</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Unger</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Morganthal</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Little</ln>
                        <fn>Eli</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sibbett</ln>
                        <fn>H. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A list of the Democratic nominees for office in the upcoming election in
                    Washington township.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Army Correspondence</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>New Orleans, [illeg]<lb/> February 2[?], 1863.</p>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">Grand review of the 18th Army Corpse--Cook
                            Wanted--[illeg] Copperheads, and Traitor Females, etc.</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>A grand Review of the 18th Army corpse, took place yesterday. The evening
                        previous we were ordered to be in readiness at 8 o'clock the next morning.
                        The morning broke in beauty; the sun rolled up the eastern horizon like a
                        boiled lobster, and shone in majestic splendor out of a cloudless sky; the
                        air was soft and serene; the spring birds were warbling their cheeriest
                        notes; everything betokened a brilliant Review.</p>
                    <p>Our camp being located near the spot selected, our Brigade was first on the
                        ground, and drawn up by Regiments immediately in front of the position,
                        where the corpse was to "march in Review." We were hardly arranged by the
                        Lt. Colonel--the Colonel being absent--when from every side came wafted the
                        martial strains of bands of music, the bright sunbeams blazed from thousands
                        of polished bayonets and sabers, and the appearance of the regiments as they
                        came marching rapidly into view, the cavalry dashing along in full array,
                        and the artillery whirling on in proper order, was magnificent beyond
                        description. Now the artillery thundered a welcome to Gen. Foster and staff
                        as they flashed into view; the bands struck up Hail to the Chief, and the
                        long roll thrilled along the line. Forthwith the regiments broke into
                        "columns of companies," and the "march in Review" commenced. General Foster
                        is a noble looking officer, portly, but erect, and seemingly in the prime of
                        manhood. His countenance is expressive of firmness and decision, pre-eminent
                        qualities in a commanding officer, while his polished address and suave
                        manners, bespeak the well bred gentleman. When the company of the
                        undersigned passed the post, himself and his elegant Lieutenant moved erect,
                        as mullen-stalks, and a smile waved over the Generals rubicund face, when
                        saluted. Though reviews are wearisome in consequence of the fact, that one
                        must remain standing about six hours, in line; yet the ever-changing scenes,
                        the brilliancy of display, the dashing hither and thither of aids, beguiles
                        one's attention so completely, that he "takes no note of time." Reviews
                        generally indicate movements; but as we belong to Brigadier Brindle's
                        Brigade, the impression is general that we will remain here.</p>
                    <p>COOK WANTED--On the departure of our lively servant Napoleon Hannabal
                        Jackson, we immediately advertised for another; but a day elapsed before an
                        applicant presented himself, with strong self-recommendatory appeals for the
                        position. Externally he was clean and eligible. I told him that we had
                        laterly been unfortunate in having a servant who was densely inhabited by
                        aptera of a most obnoxious species; he averred that he had "none of dem." I
                        told him he must undergo an examination. He consented. I gave command; Draw
                        coat! off came the coat; shirt! He was about to obey when my first Lieut.
                        observed an outsider big as a grain of wheat! I raised the curtain and
                        commanded, backward march! with the precautionary command to step lightly
                        fearing the detested creatures would drop off.</p>
                    <p>Now we abominate these little aptera equally with those <emph rend="italic"
                            >bimanous wretches</emph>, that infest the North, and drag their slimy
                        length along the body politic, to irritate and madden, to beslime and render
                        foul the whole mass, so that it may easily fall asunder like apples of
                        Sodom, at the first blast of Treason's storm, so assiduously attempted to be
                        raised. Hence friends of your country! patrons of Liberty! do not allow
                        yourselves to come in contact with these miserable wretches, who throw
                        themselves in your way, whenever possible; who, though generally of the
                        whiskey drinking, "mud-sill" order, yet sometimes endeavor to worm
                        themselves into respectable society, and with head erect strut you streets
                        to insult if <emph rend="italic">it be possible</emph>, those who are
                        infinitely their superiors. Professed disciples of Jeff. Davis, they seem to
                        imagine that an aristocratic air is thereby reflected upon them, forgetting
                        that without worth and virtue there is no greatness, and that a borrowed
                        effulgence serves but to exhibit more strongly native deformity, to
                        illuminate the hideous blackness that is painted upon them by the pencil of
                        that arch-traitor, the Devil. Instead of carefully concealing their
                        traitorous passions, as wisdom would dictate, this fallacious pride
                        stultifies them so completely, that they are unable to control them.</p>
                    <p>In my last I showed them up, <emph rend="italic">constitutionally</emph>; now
                        I learn from private sources that they have, pro. tem. laid aside that theme
                        to vent their spleen upon the Emancipation Proclamation. They will doubtless
                        busy themselves in fabricating and propagating such stories as they formerly
                        did, respecting the status of the army; which are uniformly and
                        unqualifiedly false, for the army is willing to see any steps taken that
                        will serve to crush the enemy. The soldier will not foolishly oppose the
                        marching of a negro Brigade against the enemy; especially when he is wearied
                        by constant fighting and marching. Oh! but say these miscreants, the nigger
                        will be put on an equality with the whites! the old song! now have not their
                        miserable sheets argued the last five years that this thing of equality is
                        impossible? No man, nor any body of men can effect this. But, they say, the
                        whites should be brave and patriotic enough to do this themselves! Then why
                        are they not engaged? The miserable cowards! One company of <emph
                            rend="italic">ordinary niggers</emph>, would whip a whole regiment of
                        such jack-asses; for, you know reader what pretensions this breed of whelps
                        may make to courage, who unfortunately curse your surroundings: and take
                        them all in all, are they equal in <emph rend="italic">virtue,
                        sobriety</emph> and <emph rend="italic">courage</emph>, to the same number
                        of niggers, you have ever known? "Oh! but you must not subjugate the
                        Rebels!" By the <emph rend="italic">eternal</emph>, we <emph rend="italic"
                            >must</emph> and <emph rend="italic">will</emph> and <emph rend="italic"
                            >them</emph> too, the hell-hated niggards! baser than open Rebels, whose
                        allies they claim to be, and yet are too dastardly to join them through mere
                        cowardice! A baser, meaner, more ignoble, more wolfish, and, therefore more
                        contemptible set of bipeds, than these copperheads of the North, were never
                        begotten in Africa. And, Mehercule! what shall I say of the women, whose
                        silly heads have been turned by the Southern air? It is said that when woman
                        falls, her course into the lowest depths of degradation, is rapidly run; all
                        the barriers erected by society to restrain her are dashed unthinkingly
                        down; she plunges into utter darkness like a blazing ship! Hence, she speeds
                        upon the very gales of treason! Thoughtlessly she buys up brogans for the
                        busy Reb, forgetting the vigilant eye of the patriot; or stuffs her corset
                        or bustle with quinine--the wr--g [illeg] [illeg] [illeg] expensive--which
                        all must [illeg] on the border, or if unable [illeg] busy her [illeg], her
                        little wits are at work, and her loose tongue rattles treason, like a sweet
                        morsel; while with head erect she stalks the streets, or struts into the
                        sanctuary, like the daughter of Dives,--a sheep without a golden fleece, a
                        wolf in nigger plucked cotton, a perfect child in wit and sense, the sport
                        of the wise, the incarnation of foolishness and ignorance combined. "W. T.
                        B."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A second in a series of letters written by a W. T. B., a member of the
                    158th Regiment. In the correspondence, the soldier equates northern rebel
                    sympathizers with body lice.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Deceased</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGrath</ln>
                        <fn>T. J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGrath</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>ex-Sheriff</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>T. J. C. McGrath, son of ex-Sheriff McGrath, of Franklin county, died of
                    Typhoid Fever on Feb. 5th. He passed away while stationed in Falmouth, Va.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Altar</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>E. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Murray</ln>
                        <fn>Beckie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Krebs</ln>
                        <fn>W. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Feb. 3rd, E. L. Taylor, of Altoona, Pa., and Beckie Murray were married
                    by Rev. W. E. Krebs.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Altar</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flory</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schriver</ln>
                        <fn>Ann Maria</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Krebs</ln>
                        <fn>W. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On March 8th, William A. Flory and Ann Maria Schriver were married by Rev.
                    W. E. Krebs.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Altar</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hinam</ln>
                        <fn>Christian</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Raben</ln>
                        <fn>Sidona</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On March 11th, Christian Hinam and Sidona Raben were married.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Tomb</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lesher</ln>
                        <fn>Susie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lesher</ln>
                        <fn>Leah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lesher</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Feb. 8th, Susie, daughter of Jacob and Leah Lesher, died near
                    Greencastle. She was 15 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vr.1863.03.13.03">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vr.1863.03.13.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
