<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vr1863/pa.fr.vr.1863.01.02">
    <header>
        <title>Waynesboro Village Record</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>10/16/00</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Waynesboro</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1863-01-02">
            <year>1863</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day>02</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vr.1863.01.02.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Austrian Officers Desiring To Enter Into The Service Of The Union</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A letter from a Dr. Montley, who is in Vienna, in which he explains that,
                    on a daily basis, Austrian officers have inquired about the possibility of
                    coming to America to fight for the Union Army. Because of his status as a
                    diplomat, however, he has been "obliged to decline the service" of these
                    soldiers, who, he laments, "would have done honor" to the Union cause.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Page contains a variety of anecdotal articles and human interest
            stories.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vr.1863.01.02.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Returned</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brotherton</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brotherton</ln>
                        <fn>George M. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>W. H. Brotherton has returned from his trip to Rappahannock without
                    success, relates the article. Brotherton had ventured there to secure the
                    remains of his brother, George M. D. Brotherton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Ill-Bred</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that a number of "half-grown, half-brained" and "half-secesh" girls
                    have been running around town lately, under the cover of dark, insulting Union
                    citizens.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Sad Accident</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shrader</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Last Friday, the daughter of Charles Shrader was severely burned. She died
                    the next day as a result of her injuries. She was 6 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Another Old Citizen Gone</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. Thomas Walker, 69, died at his residence last Friday. Walker, a
                    "prominent physician" for 40 years, sent five sons to the Union Army.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Another Soldier Gone</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tracy</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Tracy, of Co. E 126th Regiment, returned to his home in Leitersburg
                    from Fredericksburg last Friday and died the following day at 1:00. Tracy had
                    been suffering from his wounds for sometime prior his arrival in town, but his
                    sudden death, says the article, came as a surprise.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is reported that Federal troops under Gens. Kelley and Milroy captured
                    Winchester, and intend to hold the town. Additionally, the counties of
                    Jefferson, Berkley, Morgan, and Frederick have once again been placed under the
                    federal authority.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Fredericksburg (?)</origin>
                <commentary>"The following is an extract from a letter written by Orderly Sergeant
                    Frederick Barcle, of Co. E, 196th Regiment, to his wife in Quincy township:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">The Fredericksburg [illeg]</emph>--The following is an
                        extract from a letter written by Orderly Sergeant, FREDERICK BARCLE, of Co.
                        E, 186th Regiment, to his wife in Quincy township:--</p>
                    <p>On the 13th of December we crossed over the river about noon, into
                        Fredericksburg, the Rebels shelling us all the time. We marched through town
                        and took our position in a meadow, but the place proved too hot for us. The
                        first shell killed several of Co. A and wounded a number of the same
                        company. We left in double quick and took shelter behind a hill, having one
                        of our batteries in front. At this time the cannonading was awful. About
                        half an hour before night we (Tyler's and Albaugh's Brigades) were ordered
                        to charge the Rebels' rifle pits and battery, which we did in splendid
                        style. We started at double quick, the enemy pouring a shower of shot,
                        shell, canister and grape into our devoted column; but on we went, our
                        gallant Col. Elder leading, until ordered to halt at a board fence, near the
                        enemy's works. Here we had to tear down the fence. The fire of the enemy
                        became hotter and hotter, but we pushed on over the dead and wounded until
                        within 80 yards of the enemy. There they poured a deadly volume of rifle and
                        musket balls among us, when the Colonel ordered us to fall back, as it was
                        folly to attempt a further advance. We retreated to our starting place and
                        formed again in line. In the charge our Colonel was severely wounded, and I
                        regret to add that Sergeant Geo. M. D. Brotherton and Simon P. Rouzer of Co.
                        E were killed. Our Regiment suffered terribly. We lost, officers and
                        privates, killed, wounded and missing, 187, but many of the missing it is
                        probable will yet turn up and join us. Our loss in the brigade was over 900
                        in that terrible charge. Balls and shells flew in every direction, and we
                        can only thank God that we escaped unhurt. Many were shot through their
                        canteens, caps and coats. During the night we encamped in a graveyard in the
                        town. In the morning the Rebels shelled the town for a couple of hours. On
                        the 15th our Brigade was ordered out on picket, our Regiment doing duty
                        outside and within fifty yards of the rebel pickets. By daybreak we were
                        withdrawn and marched back to Fredericksburg and by daylight re-crossed the
                        river, covering the retreat of the whole corps. There again our escape from
                        destruction was miraculous for the rebels with their batteries might have
                        cut us to pieces.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The letter gives an account of the Battle of Fredericksburg, during which,
                    Barcle writes, his regiment "suffered terribly," losing 187 officers and
                    privates.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Three Disastrous Fires</head>
                <origin>Chambersburg Dispatch</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huber</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lambert</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Wednesday and Thursday of last week, says the article, arsonists set two
                    fires in Chambersburg, both of which completely destroyed the buildings that
                    were torched. The first blaze ripped through the Caledonia Springs Company's
                    "massive building" in South Mountain, causing over $20,000 worth of damage. In
                    the second attack, John Sollenberger's Brick Barn was the target of the
                    incendiaries; the fire destroyed 1200 bushels of wheat and 1500 bushels of oats
                    and hay. The third fire occurred last Saturday at the building where the Straw
                    Paper Mill company is located, but it is not believed to be the work of arson.
                    Rather, it has been surmised that a spark from an oven started the fire earlier
                    in the day. The owners of the company, Messrs. Humber and Lambert, suffered a
                    loss of $1500 and, unfortunately, have no insurance.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Missouri Legislature</head>
                <origin>Jefferson City</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is reported that the Missouri Legislature passed a resolution on
                    December 29th in favor of the President's scheme for compensated emancipation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vr.1863.01.02.03">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vr.1863.01.02.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
