<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1860/pa.fr.vs.1860.09.26">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Jeff McClurken</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/22/95</tagDate>
            <tagNote>2nd Pass; Colleen Doody did first pass.</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1860-09-26">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day>26</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.09.26.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Regular Nominee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The only hold Mr. Douglas has on the Democratic party is that he claims to
                    be the 'regular nominee.' Take that away and his last and only prop is knocked
                    from under him."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The only hold Mr. Douglas has on the Democratic party is that he claims to be
                        the "regular nominee." Take that away and his last and only prop is knocked
                        from under him. Let us briefly examine his claim: The National convention
                        expressly decided that it required two-thirds of the whole vote of that body
                        to impart regularity and validity to a National nomination. The two- thirds
                        of the Convention was 202. Mr. Douglas never received that vote. The highest
                        vote he did receive on any ballot was 181 1/2. Had the Convention remained
                        in session until dooms-day he could not have received the two-third
                        vote--the vote necessary to make him the "regular nominee." It was secession
                        alone that gave him a nomination of any kind. He is merely the nominee of a
                        conclave of his partisans.</p>
                    <p>How does the case stand with Mr. Johnson; We suppose that he claims to be a
                        "regular nominee" also. Mr. Fitzpatrick declined the honor of running on the
                        same ticket with Mr. Douglas, so did Mr. Yancey. But the convenient Mr.
                        Johnson accepted the nomination from the hands of three men in a back parlor
                        of a hotel at Washington. How easily regular nominees are manufactured
                        now-a-days! The Democratic party we trust will not suffer itself to be
                        cheated and deceived any longer by this clamor about regular
                    nominations.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spirit changes its position and decides no longer to support Douglas.
                    It denies that Douglas is really the regular nominee of the party, since he
                    never received the required two-thirds of the vote from the National Convention.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/sept60.html#9.26a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Bad Faith</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"They [The Constitutional Democracy] have no confidence in a public man who
                    openly proposed to cheat any section of the Union out of the rights adjudicated
                    to them by the Supreme Court, especially by such unmanly legislative tricks as
                    'non-action' or 'unfriendly legislation.'"</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The chief objection to Judge Douglas is his want of faith. In July, 1856, in
                        his seat in the United States Senate, he declared that if the Supreme Court
                        should decide that slavery was recognized in the Territories under the
                        Federal Constitution, there was no power on earth could deprive the owner of
                        his rights. Mr. Douglas then agreed to submit the whole question of slavery
                        in the Territories to the adjudication of the Courts. After the question was
                        decided, however, in favor of the equal rights of the South in the
                        Territories, Mr. Douglas declared, at Freeport, that it did not "matter what
                        the decision of the Supreme Court might be, the Territorial Legislature
                        might <emph rend="italic">legally</emph> exclude slavery, either by
                        non-action or unfriendly legislation."</p>
                    <p>It is because Mr. Douglas has thus shown his hands--because he has declared
                        that he would submit to the decision of the Court, and they declared that
                        the decision might be <emph rend="italic">legally</emph> overthrown by a
                        Territorial Legislature, that the Constitutional Democracy can no longer
                        trust him. They have no confidence in a public man who openly proposed to
                        cheat any section of the Union out of the rights adjudicated to them by the
                        Supreme Court, especially by such unmanly legislative tricks as "non-action"
                        or "unfriendly legislation."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>States that the paper can no longer support Douglas because he flip-flopped
                    on a key issue. In 1856, Douglas said that no power could deprive slave-holders
                    in the territories of their slaves after the Supreme Court stated that slavery
                    was recognized in the territories. However, in the Lincoln-Douglas debate at
                    Freeport he stated that the Territorial Legislature could legally exclude
                    slavery.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/sept60.html#9.26b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Mr. Douglas's Latest Insult</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Accuses Douglas of sneering at the courage of Southerners by stating that
                    they want to break up the Union, but are afraid to be sent to the gallows.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Then and Now</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In 1851, Herschel V. Johnson stated that the right of secession must be
                    maintained. However, on September 12, 1960, he denounced the conservative
                    Democrats of New York as secessionists.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Work! Work!! Work!!!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges Democrats to organize and work for the election of Foster for
                    governor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Cresson Compromise</head>
                <origin>The Democratic Messenger (Douglas) of Indiana, PA</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>If the party supports a straight Douglas ticket, it will be defeated. Only
                    the Cresson compromise will lead to victory.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Extract from Gen. H.D. Foster's Philadelphia Speech</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Foster denies the Republican charge that he is a free-trade man.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Highly Interesting Document</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprint of Herschel V. Johnson's letter from 1851 in which he states that
                    secession is the only hope of the South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Township Meetings of Breckinridge Clubs</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stenger</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Esq.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Douglas</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewer</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letter states that the county has a number of Breckinridge clubs. Many of
                    the most prominent Democrats in the county support Breckinridge.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Hope Fire Company</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Montgomery</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGrath</ln>
                        <fn>A.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Hope Fire Company passed a resolution that its equipment was to be used
                    by the company only.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Our Band and the County Fair</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Frey</ln>
                        <fn>P.D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wunderlich</ln>
                        <fn>D.K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Discussion of why the Fayetteville Band rather than the Chambersburg Brass
                    Band was chosen to play at the County Fair.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.09.26.02">
            <div type="l">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Letter of Rev. Daniel Wm. Cahill, D.D. to the Small Farmers, Tradesmen and
                    Laborers of Ireland</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Description of his trip by train from Philadelphia to Pittsburgh. He is
                    amazed and impressed by the engineering and genius of American railroad
                    builders.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Pacific Railroad Contract</head>
                <origin>New York Herald</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Discussion of the awarding of the contract for building the Pacific
                    telegraph.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Letter from Pike's Peak</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Extract of a letter from "A.R.K.", a young man who went west, to his
                    sister.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Democrats Organize!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges Democrats to organize to elect Foster for governor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>[none]</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Republicans claim to support protective tariffs. However, there is no
                    evidence that Lincoln is a "protective tariff man" and Hamlin is a known free
                    trader.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>[none]</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Col. Curtin concedes that Gen. Foster is a protective tariff man. Many Bell
                    supporters and Republicans will vote for Foster.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Severe Sentences</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Two women were convicted of keeping a "house of ill fame" in Cumberland
                    County and were sentenced to one year in prison. "An example or two of this kind
                    might have a tendency to close some of the many pitfalls that beset the path of
                    the youth in our city."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>[none]</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Pittsburgh Gazette accused the Catholic priests of Berks and Schuylkill
                    of telling their followers to vote for Foster for governor. The Church denied
                    the charge. The Spirit accuses the Gazette of routinely making false charges
                    against Catholics and failing to respond with any proof.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>[none]</head>
                <origin>New York Tribune</origin>
                <commentary>"Republican principles are clearer and more forcibly expressed in this
                    little paragraph than all the platforms of that party made in the last twelve
                    months."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Tribune, the "leading Republican journal of the United States," called
                    for New York state to outlaw the property qualifications for blacks.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.09.26.03">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.09.26.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>County Committee Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewer</ln>
                        <fn>Geo.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn>J.R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Democratic County Committee will meet on Oct. 3rd in Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>To the Democracy of Franklin County</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reminds voters that the local and state elections are only two weeks away
                    and that this is an extremely important election. The article then goes on to
                    state why the paper turned against Douglas, who "prefers the election of Lincoln
                    to that of Breckinridge."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>How Does It Look?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In Massachusetts, an immigrant has to wait two years before he can vote
                    while a black man only has to wait for six months. The Spirit sees this as an
                    example of Republican attitudes toward foreigners and blacks.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>[none]</head>
                <origin>Lewistown Democrat (Douglas)</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Continues to support the Cresson compromise.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Old Line Whigs</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Accuses Douglas of slandering Henry Clay in 1844, while pointing out that
                    Breckinridge always admired Clay. Since many former Whigs have moved into the
                    Democratic Party, the Spirit asks "which of these two men you could support
                    without sacrificing your personal pride or self-respect?"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Johnson on Free Labor</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In a 1856 speech, Herschel V. Johnson placed the white worker of the North
                    on the same level as a southern slave.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>How Is It?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spirit responds to Douglas' charge that every disunionist in America is
                    a Breckinridge supporter by stating that Herschel Johnson is a noted leader of
                    disunion.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Foster Triumph</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>States that Foster has effectively crushed the Republican charge that he is
                    a free-trade man.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Haldeman's Proposition</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Criticizes R. J. Haldeman's proposal for a fusion ticket because it
                    disproportionately favors Bell supporters.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.09.26.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Hurrah for Democracy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spirit believes that Foster is very likely to win.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Changes in the Campaign</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The various factions of the party have come together to support Mr. Foster.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Republican Mass Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Republicans had a mass meeting in Chambersburg, but few people
                    attended.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Inconsistency of Douglas</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>States that Douglas appears to have few fixed principles. He has
                    contradicted himself on both the Dred Scott decision and the Missouri
                    Compromise.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Douglas and the English Bill</head>
                <origin>Columbus Fact</origin>
                <commentary>Mr. Cox, M.C. of Ohio, claimed that Douglas is not always
                    straightforward.</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Cox voted for the English bill after consulting Douglas and receiving his
                    approval. However, Douglas voted against the bill in the Senate.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Country in a Blaze</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Brief paragraphs about numerous meetings held in support of Breckinridge
                    and Lane throughout the state and country.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lytllenon Tyler requests the Spirit to inform its readers that he is no
                    longer a candidate for Assistant Elector for Prince William County. He had
                    supported Douglas until the latter's speech in Norfolk convinced Tyler that
                    Douglas was no friend of the South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>West</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnston</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harrison</ln>
                        <fn>W.J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnston</ln>
                        <fn>Clarinda</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on September 12.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bishop</ln>
                        <fn>Jas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shoaff</ln>
                        <fn>J. Gideon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peters</ln>
                        <fn>Sue</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. Shoaff married Sue Peters on September 18th at the Pleasant Retreat
                    Parsonage.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brandt</ln>
                        <fn>Nancy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Died on September 15th at 51 years of age.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kobler</ln>
                        <fn>Eve</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Died on September 17th at 71 years of age.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Detwiler</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Died on September 20th at 72 years of age. She was a member of the 2nd
                    German Reformed Church of Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.09.26.06">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.09.26.07">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.09.26.08">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Hon. Wm. P. Schell</head>
                <origin>Juniata Register</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Register supports Mr. Schell for Congress and denies that he had any
                    role in starting the Juniata True Democrat, as the opposition claims.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Hon. William P. Schell</head>
                <origin>Juniata True Democrat</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>States that Mr. Schell is a fine Democratic candidate who the paper
                    supports. Mr. Schell has come out in favor of the Union Electoral Ticket.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Hon. W.P. Schell</head>
                <origin>Bedford Gazette</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Gazette heartily supports Mr. Schell for Congress.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
