<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1860/pa.fr.vs.1860.11.28">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Jeff McClurken</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/22/95</tagDate>
            <tagNote>2nd Pass; Colleen Doody did first pass.</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1860-11-28">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="11">November</month>
            <day>28</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.11.28.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The State Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The official county-by-county vote totals for the presidential election.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Governors of States for 1861</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>List of governors and their party affiliations.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The War of Races Begun</head>
                <origin>New York World</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A black man named Charles Sanderson was charged with assault and battery
                    after he struck a street-car conductor. Sanderson had gotten on a car
                    "especially set apart for white people" and sat down. When the conductor asked
                    him to leave, Sanderson refused and stated that "he was just as good as any of
                    the white trash in the car." When the conductor took hold of him, Sanderston
                    struck the man in the head. During the court case, he stated that he was in a
                    hurry and couldn't wait for the colored car. "He was committed for examination."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>A Most Valiant Dogberry</head>
                <origin>Patriot and Union</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Makes fun of James S. Brisbin, the publisher of the Centre Democrat, who
                    wrote a letter to the governor of Virginia. In it, Brisbin said that he was
                    ready to lead the freemen of the North into battle to crush disunion "'as the
                    strong man crushes an egg shell in his hand.'"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Lynch Law</head>
                <origin>Frederick Examiner</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The rumor that a man was lynched for voting for Lincoln and uttering
                    abolitionist doctrines isn't true. Instead, a Russian of "bad character" was
                    hanged after he had stolen some money. The men who hanged him only intended to
                    choke and frighten him, but they almost killed him.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Southern Emigration Westward</head>
                <origin>Shelbyville (Tenn.) Expositor</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An unprecedented number of Southerners are emigrating west and are taking a
                    large number of slaves.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Thrilling Incident at a Theatre</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>During a performance of Taylour's "Lessons for Husbands" at the St. Louis
                    Threatre, an actor counted all the stars on the flag and "exclaimed, with deep
                    feeling, 'Thank God, they are all there.' The attitude and earnestness of the
                    speaker, and the peculiar force of he remark, passed like an electric shock
                    through the audience, and the house rose en masse and applauded most
                    vociferously."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>[none]</head>
                <origin>Fredericksburg (VA) Herald</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>6,000 stand of arms passed South to an unknown location on the 12th and
                    7,000 passed through the following day.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.11.28.02">
            <pageNote>Stories</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.11.28.03">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.11.28.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>News of the Week</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Financial panic has "spread to an alarming extent" as a result of Lincoln's
                    election.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>What Has Been Gained</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spirit hopes that the poor men who voted for Lincoln in hopes of better
                    times will not forget the lesson the country is learning--voting for the
                    Republicans is leading to financial panic.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Give Them Their Share</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lincoln and the Republicans alone cannot be blamed for the current
                    financial and political crisis. The Douglas Democrats also have to receive some
                    share of the blame.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>A Ball to the Prince</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is stated that the Republicans in Congress plan on throwing a ball for
                    John W. Forney, "the Prince of Traitors."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Let Pennsylvania Unite with Virginia to Save the Union</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"A careful scrutiny of the doings of the people of certain Southern States,
                    has satisfied us that the American Union will be smaller three months hence than
                    it is now, unless the Northern States strike from their statute books all laws
                    that infringe the constitutional rights of the South. It is plain that South
                    Carolina and several other States are resolved on going out; and it is certain
                    that if the North attempts to coerce them the whole South will unite in their
                    defense."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We have watched with an anxious eye the movements now going on at the South.
                        We believed that the election of Lincoln would induce some to the Southern
                        States to withdraw from the Union. Our fears did not magnify the danger. A
                        careful scrutiny of the doings of the people of certain Southern States, has
                        satisfied us that the American Union will be smaller three months hence than
                        it is now, unless the Northern States strike from their statute books all
                        laws that infringe the constitutional rights of the South. It is plain that
                        South Carolina and several other States are resolved on going out; and it is
                        certain that if the North attempts to coerce them the whole South will unite
                        in their defense.</p>
                    <p>But we do no yet despair of the Union. There is encouragement in the attitude
                        of Virginia, that ancient and glorious commonwealth, which never losses
                        sight of true principles and never swerves from the path of patriotism.
                        Virginia, whilst firmly maintaining the constitutional rights of the section
                        to which she belongs, will, we are told, remain in the Union and act as
                        mediator between the North and the seceding Southern States. She will
                        endeavor to obtain from the Northern States a repeal of their laws
                        obstructing the reclamation of fugitive slaves; and these being repealed,
                        she will use her influence to induce the seceding States to return to the
                        Union. She proposes to herself a great and glorious mission, and confiding
                        in her wisdom, her moderation and her patriotism, we believe that she will
                        be successful.</p>
                    <p>The present would seem to be a proper time for the final adjustment of the
                        questions in dispute between the North and the South. The quarrel has gone
                        on too long already. Let the two sections sit down calmly together and talk
                        over the points in issue, and if agreement is out of the question, let them
                        peaceably separate. We do not believe that it is impossible for them to
                        agree. The Northern people have <emph rend="italic">apparently</emph>, but
                        we think not <emph rend="italic">really</emph>, gone crazy on the subject of
                        slavery. Adroit politicians of mischievous propensities have caused the
                        enactment of obnoxious laws which are unknown to three-fourths of the people
                        in whose name they were enacted. How many, for instance, of the people of
                        Pennsylvania, are aware that there is on the statute book of the State a law
                        obstructing the recapture of runaway negroes? How many old Whigs are
                        prepared to hear that this law was drafted by a Whig Senator? How many
                        Democrats will learn without surprise that it was approved by a Democratic
                        Governor? Yet all this is the fact.</p>
                    <p>Now in spite of this law, we venture to affirm that the people of
                        Pennsylvania are <emph rend="italic">not</emph> opposed to the recapture of
                        runaway negroes and are not in favor of obstructing the execution of the
                        fugitive slave law. They have in their midst more free negroes than they
                        want; and they know very well that if they prevent the recapture of runaway
                        negroes on their soil, the effect will be to increase largely the number of
                        negroes in the State.</p>
                    <p>What then ought they to do? The answer is plain. They ought to demand of
                        their Legislature the repeal of the obnoxious, irritating and unjust law
                        alluded to. If they permit that law to stand unrepealed, now that their
                        attention has been called to it, then it may justly be inferred that they
                        sympathise with those Northern Disunionists who would rather break up the
                        Union than carry out the provisions of the Federal Constitution.</p>
                    <p>Let this subject be agitated. Let the press, or at least the Democratic
                        portion of it, speak out for repeal.--Let the people petition the
                        Legislature to wipe out our nullifying law. Let Andrew G. Curtin, when he
                        takes the Governor's chair, be called upon to show whether he stands with
                        the slave-stealing Yankees who have settled in the Northern part of our
                        State, or with the great body of the people of Pennsylvania, who respect
                        that clause of the Constitution which provides that slaves who may run away
                        "shall be delivered up." Let the various aspirants to the dignified position
                        of United States Senator be compelled to show their hands. What say you
                        Messrs. McClure, Stevens, Wilmot, Moorhead, and the rest of that host of
                        Republican patriots who are willing to serve Pennsylvania in the Senate of
                        the United States--Are you in favor of retaining in force a law which
                        obstructs the execution of the fugitive slave law and practically denies to
                        the people of the South a right guaranteed to them by the Constitution?</p>
                    <p>There will probably be a separation of one or more States from the Union
                        before the obnoxious laws passed by some of the Northern States can possibly
                        be repealed. But the separation will not be final if Pennsylvania,
                        responding to the patriotic suggestions of Virginia, shall set her sister
                        States of the North the example of repealing an act conceived in
                        unreasonable hostility to the South, and beyond all question violative of
                        the just rights of the people of fifteen sovereign States.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Southern states will leave the Union if Northern states don't "strike from
                    their statute books all laws that infringe the constitutional rights of the
                    South." However, it appears that Virginia will stay in the Union and act as a
                    mediator between the Union and the secessionists. The Spirit hopes that
                    Pennsylvania will act in conjunction with Virginia to settle the key issues.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/nov60.html#11.28a</note>
                <look>Look</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Kansas</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Montgomery, a former associate of John Brown, has been making trouble in
                    Kansas again. The Spirit hopes that he is caught and hanged.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Begging a Notice</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spirit doesn't want to be drawn into any further quarrel with the
                    Times, while the Times appears to want to "keep up the quarrel to the bitter
                    end."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Repeal is the Issue</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges the Pennsylvania Legislature to repeal the law "making the master
                    responsible for any tumult the slave-stealing and slave-rescuing abolitionists
                    may create when the master attempts to retake his slave." Southern states will
                    surely secede if such laws aren't removed from the books.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>The Bank of Chambersburg</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges citizens of Franklin county not make a run on the Bank of
                    Chambersburg, which the Spirit believes is in sound condition.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Douglas Disunionists</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>John Forsyth, the editor of the Mobile (Alabama) Register, was a Douglas
                    supporter who constantly accused Breckinridge of being a disunionist. Yet,
                    shortly after Lincoln's election, Forsyth stated that Alabama should leave the
                    Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Virginia</head>
                <origin>Washington Constitution</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A large meeting that took place in Essex County passed a resolution that
                    appealed to South Carolina to wait until Virginia could be heard. It also called
                    on all the states to meet in a convention to attempt to preserve the Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Resignation of Chief Justice Taney</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is rumored that Taney will resign. It is believed that Jeremiah S. Black
                    of Pennsylvania will be appointed to replace him.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Mississippi</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"The members of Congress from Mississippi are reported to have declared,
                    after consultation, in favor of a Southern Confederacy. An immense meeting was
                    held in New Orleans, on Friday night, to promote military organization and
                    concert of action."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Vermont</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"Judge Thomas, a Democratic member of the Legislature, has introduced a
                    bill to repeal the 'personal liberty act' of Vermont. This is a step in the
                    right direction, but we fear the Republican majority in the Vermont Legislature
                    will defeat the measure."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.11.28.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heyser</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schmeck</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLellen</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greenwalt</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duncan</ln>
                        <fn>C.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Linn</ln>
                        <fn>S.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingerd</ln>
                        <fn>A.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Culbertson</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Piper</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stouffer</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stouffer</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nill</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The men listed were elected as Directors of the Bank of Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>The New Abolitionist Raid--Excitement on the Missouri Border--The People
                    Arming in Self Defence</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Missouri citizens have organized a military company to help defend their
                    "brothers on the border" if necessary.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>From the South</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Brief excerpts of news articles dealing with Southern issues, including the
                    suspension of specie payment in Baltimore, Petersburg, and Richmond banks; and a
                    report of a meeting of the minute men in Norfolk.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cummins</ln>
                        <fn>Jesse</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Died November 24th, aged 81 years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Oyler</ln>
                        <fn>E. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Died November 11th, aged 82 years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bunn</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Died November 9th, aged 78 years. She was a life-long communicant of the
                    Methodist Episcopal Church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.11.28.06">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.11.28.07">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.11.28.08">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Words of Prophecy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Excerpts from a President Fillmore campaign speech in 1856 in which he
                    warns of the consequences of sectional rule.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Apology for Assassination</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spirit criticizes the Republican press for its defense of Montgomery,
                    who murdered a number of pro-slavery men in Kansas.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Financial Pressure</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In New York, some leading banks discussed the possibility of issuing scrip
                    to relieve the financial pressure. In Virginia, the banks of Richmond,
                    Petersburg, Wheeling, and Norfolk were suspended.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
