<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1860/pa.fr.vs.1860.07.25">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Jeff McClurken</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/22/95</tagDate>
            <tagNote>2nd Pass; Colleen Doody did first pass.</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1860-07-25">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day>25</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote>Doesn't include pages 6 and 7.</editionNote>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.07.25.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Henry B. Foster</head>
                <origin>Mifflintown Democrat</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Pennsylvanians shouldn't overlook the important upcoming gubernatorial
                    election and shouldn't let the split in the national Democratic party get
                    carried over into state elections. The paper supports Henry D. Foster.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>All the Ratical (sic) Abolitionists for Lincoln</head>
                <origin>Genius of Liberty</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Believes that, since a man may be told by the company he keeps, the fact
                    that the Anti-Slavery Convention supports Lincoln means that he is a radical
                    abolitionist.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Artemas on Abraham</head>
                <origin>Cleveland Plaindealer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A "racy burlesque" about Lincoln.</summary>
                <note>The ending is difficult to read.</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Republican Economy</head>
                <origin>New York Tribune</origin>
                <commentary>The Covode Committee was created to prove the Republican charges that
                    the Democrats were extravagant and that they used public money for partisan
                    purposes. The Tribune wrote the following article about the committee.</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Republican charges were disproved before the committee. Furthermore,
                    the "Black Republican House" printed 100,000 committee reports at government
                    expense. The sole purpose of the committee, the paper argues, was to make
                    political capital.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Distressing Event</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolf</ln>
                        <fn>Anna Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Anna Mary Wolf of Hamilton Township, PA, fell and broke her neck.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>The KGC--"Mexico is to be Southernized and Americanized"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>General Bickley published an address to the Knights of the Golden Circle
                    stating that Texas has raised money to Americanize and Southernize Mexico,
                    "looking to the establishment of a Southern Confederacy." He encourages other
                    southern states to contribute.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.07.25.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Gov. Johnson's Acceptance</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprint of Johnson's Acceptance speech for the Vice Presidential
                    nomination. In it, he states that the secessionists were waging war against
                    Douglas at the convention, not fighting for principle.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.07.25.03">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.07.25.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Transcript on the "Nigger Question"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt> "The negro must be the master and the white man the slave. The "persecuted
                    race of helpless, hapless beings--poor, ignorant Africans" may "live in
                    idleness" but "white sons and daughters" must work, work, work. This is the
                    doctrine laid down by the <emph rend="italic">Transcript</emph>, and we have
                    long suspected it to be the aim of the Republican party, but never before found
                    an editor fool-hardy enough to make the declaration." </excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The whole policy of the Nigger Democracy has been, for years, to crush out
                        Free White Labor and substitute the unpaid toil of negro slaves in the
                        places accustomed to be filled by white sons and daughters of industry who,
                        regardless of the sneers of the oligarchy, voluntarily prefer to work with
                        their own hands for an honest livelyhood to living in idleness supported by
                        the sweat and toil of a despised, abused, persecuted race of helpless,
                        hapless beings--poor, ignorant Africans.</p>
                    <p>We need scarcely tell our readers that the above elegant extract is from the
                        luminous editorial columns of the <emph rend="italic">Transcript.</emph> It
                        bears so much evidence on the face of it of the stupendously brilliant mind
                        that presides over that sheet that there is no mistaking the source. Our
                        readers will recognize it at once, and without any trouble, as one of the
                            <emph rend="italic">"feats of agility"</emph> that the smart editor of
                        that paper weekly performs, in conformity with its motto, that "it is
                        essential that public opinion be enlightened." Well, he is the boy to
                        "enlighten" it as "clear as mud," and we are sure our readers will feel
                        grateful to us for transferring this small sample of his light to our
                        columns, and thus allow the ambitious editor more room to spread himself, as
                        his own paper is becoming entirely too contracted for his extensive
                        pretensions, and wonderful capacity, to show off with advantage. We,
                        therefore, take him under "our wing" as one of our "tender brood," and <emph
                            rend="italic">considering</emph> the material we have to work on, we
                        hope to bring him out full fledged and able to crow like a respectable
                        "bantam" and earn a "<emph rend="italic">lively</emph>hood" by his <emph
                            rend="italic">lively</emph> scratching. The orthography belongs
                        exclusively to the <emph rend="italic">Transcript</emph>.</p>
                    <p>It will appear by the extract from the <emph rend="italic">Transcript</emph>
                        that the maudlin sympathies of its editor is strongly enlisted in behalf of
                        the "poor, hapless, ignorant Africans."--He means the niggers, of course,
                        but is too polite to his esteemed wooly-headed friends to call them by any
                        other name than that of "Africans." The Democracy, however, in his exalted
                        estimation, are "niggers"--he professes to know them by no other name than
                        that of "nigger Democracy!" His phelinx for the <emph rend="italic">"poor
                            Africans"</emph> are so much worked up that his outrageously strong
                        christian propensities are excited to such a degree as to induce him to hug
                        the whole wooly-headed race to his bosom and boo-hoo over them as his
                        "tender brood," but the "Nigger Democracy" are not dark-skinned enough to
                        find a place in his affections. Should he be crossed in his love for the
                        nigger, it is to be hoped that he may not commit suicide, or die of a broken
                        heart, as the Democracy could not well get along without the valuable
                        assistance they expect from him in the present campaign.</p>
                    <p> We suppose we must take him as we find him--the embodiment of the Republican
                        party in Franklin county--the head and front of that institution--the organ
                        from which is ground out the music to which that party must dance--well
                        then, as the exponent of the principles of that party, we have from him
                        their platform on the "nigger question," in a nut-shell, in the above
                        extract. It is their intention to set the niggers all free and make the
                            <emph rend="italic">"white sons and daughters of industry"</emph> take
                        their place. The negro must be the master and the white man the slave. The
                        "persecuted race of helpless, hapless beings--poor, ignorant Africans" may
                        "live in idleness" but "white sons and daughters" must work, work, work.
                        This is the doctrine laid down by the <emph rend="italic">Transcript</emph>,
                        and we have long suspected it to be the aim of the Republican party, but
                        never before found an editor fool-hardy enough to make the declaration.</p>
                    <p>We feel loath to deprive the <emph rend="italic">Transcript</emph> of the
                        pleasure it finds in terming us the "Negro Democracy," but after the love it
                        has expressed for the "ignorant African," and its avowed intention to set
                        the negroes free and enslave white men and women too, we must consider the
                        Republican party fairly entitled to be called the "nigger party." The <emph
                            rend="italic">Transcript</emph> cannot hereafter, with any show of
                        consistency, call us ugly names. I must give up the beauty and burthen of
                        its editorials, and acknowledge that it prefers the nigger to the white man,
                        or eat its own words.</p>
                    <p>Will the poor laboring white men, of Franklin county, be found in the ranks
                        of a party that is constantly expressing so much love and so much pity for
                        the nigger and not one word of sympathy or condolence for them? The "abused,
                        persecuted race of helpless, hapless beings--poor, ignorant Africans," is
                        the burthen of their song. All their efforts are now directed to stock the
                        sugar plantations of Louisiana, and the cotton fields of Georgia, with white
                        slaves in place of black ones, so that the nigger may be the nabob and live
                        in idleness. O! How they do love the nigger, and if they could only get him
                        to vote here, as they have in Massachusetts, their happiness would be
                        complete.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Includes an excerpt from the Transcript on what it terms "Nigger
                    Democracy," which aims to crush free white labor with slave labor. The Spirit
                    criticizes this view and says that the Republicans care more for slaves than for
                    poor laboring white men.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/july60.html#7.25h</note>
                <look>Look</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Slavery Question in Congress</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Calls for an end to all the slavery agitation in Congress, which is
                    seemingly unable to accomplish any business because of Republican agitation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Disunion Nomination</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that the men who nominated Breckinridge and Lane did so because they
                    supported dissolving the Union and dividing the Democrats, not because they
                    believed that this ticket could win.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Democratic Mass Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Democratic Party of Pennsylvania will meet in Harrisburg on July 26th.
                    The Spirit hopes that Franklin County Democrats will stand by the regular
                    nominees of the party.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Sound Talk</head>
                <origin>Mt. Vernon (Ohio) Banner</origin>
                <commentary>This paper opposed Douglas before his nomination, but "now comes out in
                    the following manly language."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Banner considers it the duty of every Democrat to support the regular
                    nomination wholeheartedly.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Mr. Editor</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Writer argues that the secessionists are demanding protection of slavery in
                    the territories; this is not the traditional Democratic stand for
                    non-intervention. He believes this new position would increase friction between
                    slave holders and abolitionists in the territories.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.07.25.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Railroad Prospects Increasing</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"While Philadelphia and Baltimore Merchants and Capitalists remain
                    inactive, as they too frequently do, New York has a competent and intelligent
                    citizen now going over the route of the Allegheny and Connelsville projected
                    railroad, gathering such information as will enable him to place as true and
                    correct a statement of the route as he can do by a visit and information
                    obtained from old surveyors before the Capitalists of New York."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>While Philadelphia and Baltimore Merchants and Capitalists remain inactive,
                        as they too frequently do, New York has a competent and intelligent citizen
                        now going over the route of the Allegheny and Connelsville projected
                        railroad, gathering such information as will enable him to place as true and
                        correct a statement of the route as he can do by a visit and information
                        obtained from old surveyors before the Capitalists of New York. Mr. J. E.
                        Wharton, the gentleman alluded to above, arrived here on Thursday noon last,
                        had letters of introduction to many of our citizens, with whom there was
                        much communicated on the subject of the contemplated railroad; he appears to
                        have no fear of the controlling influence of the Pennsylvania Central
                        Railroad over the Cumberland Valley, he views the matter thus: they cannot
                        discriminate, or charge more than their charter allows, and the short
                        distance of the Cumberland V. R. R., being only fifty miles, is but a drop
                        in the bucket when the length of the Road from New York west and southwest
                        is taken into consideration. That New York must have an outlet to the great
                        west and southwest shorter than she now has to keep her commerce and
                        business in advance of <emph rend="italic">Philadelphia and Baltimore where
                            she now has it</emph>. And who can blame them for acting on the
                        principal of the man whose only prayer was "bless me and my wife, my son
                        John and his, we four and no more," while we acknowledge a degree of
                        mortification, that Philadelphia the metropolis of our State thus far has
                        shown no disposition to avail herself by immediate action to secure the
                        advantages of this route to build up their city, compete with, and get in
                        advance of New York. We at Chambersburg, as well as Fulton, Bedford and
                        Somerset counties who have had to pay our full quota of State taxes for the
                        Canal and Central R. R., by which Philadelphians are enriched, and however
                        mortified we may be at their apathy, we hail with pleasure the action of New
                        York in the case, and feel disposed to vary the prayer alluded to and say
                        "Bless Chambersburg and the city who builds the road, we two and that will
                        do.</p>
                    <p>On Friday morning last, Emanuel Kuhn, Esq., an old surveyor of this county,
                        took Mr. Wharton in a carriage as far as Loudon.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Hezikah Easton, who is perfectly acquainted with the locality of the
                        route from there to Cowans Gap, and form the Gap to the Burnt Cabins,
                        conveyed Mr. Wharton to Burnt Cabins, and when there, it was calculated from
                        the known anxiety of Mr. James Kelly to get out of the mountains by
                        Railroad, he would see to his comforts for the balance of the road to
                        Bedford, where Mr. Wharton will be put under the care, we suppose of the
                        Little Giant John Cesna and others, who can aid him.</p>
                    <p>In our next issue we expect to give some railroad statistics of Somerset
                        County, as she had either five or six delegates at the Harrisburg R. R.
                        Convention, to whose names the significant letters were attached, Hon.,
                        which ought to mean able to write, and additional information from Mr.
                        Wharton's survey of the route from this to the Sand Patch.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kuhn</ln>
                        <fn>Emmanuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Esq.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Easton</ln>
                        <fn>Hezekiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kelly</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A New York railroad company sent out a Mr. J.E. Wharton to survey the
                    proposed road near Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/july60.html#7.25a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Douglas and Johnson Club</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beaver</ln>
                        <fn>D.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brand</ln>
                        <fn>A.J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deihl</ln>
                        <fn>D.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duncan</ln>
                        <fn>C.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duncan</ln>
                        <fn>Augustine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillan</ln>
                        <fn>Matthew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoskinson</ln>
                        <fn>J.T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keyser</ln>
                        <fn>H.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClintock</ln>
                        <fn>J.P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCoy</ln>
                        <fn>Vincent</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKesson</ln>
                        <fn>S.R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nead</ln>
                        <fn>B.F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nill</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn>T.X.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reilly</ln>
                        <fn>Wilson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reilly</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ripper</ln>
                        <fn>J.G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rowe</ln>
                        <fn>D. Watson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rowe</ln>
                        <fn>D.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seilers</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharpe</ln>
                        <fn>J.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Esq.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>Hiram</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A special meeting of the Douglas and Johnson Club was held on July 21 to
                    select permanent officers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Railroad Survey</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--The following gentlemen have been appointed Committees for their several
                        Districts to make collections to defray the expense of making a survey for a
                        Rail- Road between Chambersburg and Burnt Cabins:</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">For Chambersburg</emph>--E. Kuhn, Wm. Seibert, J. W.
                        Fletcher.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">St. Thomas township</emph>--Dunlap Dickson, Peter Hollar,
                        Samuel Linn.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Peters township</emph>--H. Easton, Geo. Stenger, Hartman
                        Dickhout.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Metal township</emph>--Charles Campbell, Samuel Walker,
                        James Brewster.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kuhn</ln>
                        <fn>B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seibert</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fletcher</ln>
                        <fn>J.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dickson</ln>
                        <fn>Dunlap</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hollar</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Linn</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Easton</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stenger</ln>
                        <fn>Geo.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dickhout</ln>
                        <fn>Hartman</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewster</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The above-listed men were appointed to a committee to make a collection for
                    the defraying of expenses for a railroad survey.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/july60.html#7.25b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Agricultural Association</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A meeting of the board of directors of the Farmers and Mechanics Industrial
                    Association of Franklin County was held on July 21st to complete arrangements
                    for the upcoming fair.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Insurance Companies versus Individuals</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"If Insurance companies wish to stand well with the public they should act
                    promptly and repair all damages that they have stipulated to make good, or place
                    the amount of insurance in the hands of the owner of the property destroyed,
                    that he may go to work at once and repair the loss he has sustained."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--If any of our readers desire to witness a specimen of the energy with which
                        individuals can go to work and repair their damages, when not trammeled by
                        Insurance companies, let them visit the scene of the late fire. Mr. Ditman
                        was not insured and he has his property now repaired and doing business as
                        usual. Mr. Ott was also not insured and he has his house now under roof and
                        will have it ready to remove into a short space of time. Mr. Deckelmayer,
                        the only party insured, owing to the dilly-dallying of the Insurance
                        companies, has been unable to make any repairs and is suffering a heavy
                        pecuniary loss every day. If Insurance companies wish to stand well with the
                        public they should act promptly and repair all damages that they have
                        stipulated to make good, or place the amount of insurance in the hands of
                        the owner of the property destroyed, that he may go to work at once and
                        repair the loss he has sustained.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Mr. Ditman and Mr. Ott, who were not insured, have rebuilt their property
                    more quickly after the recent fire than has Mr. Deckelmayer, who was insured.
                    The paper criticizes insurance companies for not acting promptly.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/july60.html#7.25d</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Boat Excursion</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We would say to parents bring out your little ones and treat them to a
                    ride on our romantic and beautiful stream, and let them enjoy the fun "as they
                    sail, as they sail" and it will plant a bloom on their hearts as well as their
                    cheeks."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--We take pleasure in informing the ladies and gentlemen of this place that
                        Mr. Solenberger has fitted out a safe and elegant boat in which parties can
                        enjoy a delightful boat excursion on the Conococheague. His terms are very
                        reasonable and the ride is certainly a safe and pleasant one, infinitely
                        more agreeable and conducive to health, than a drive through the dust and
                        heat of our streets. Mr. Solenberger may be found, every evening, at the
                        "wharf" at the Baptist church. We hope Mr. Solenberger's enterprise may be
                        liberally patronized. We would say to parents bring out your little ones and
                        treat them to a ride on our romantic and beautiful stream, and let them
                        enjoy the fun "as they sail, as they sail" and it will plant a bloom on
                        their hearts as well as their cheeks.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Mr. Solenberger has fitted out a boat for parties to rent out for
                    excursions on the Conococheague.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/july60.html#7.25e</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Extract of a Letter</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt> "'Agents, (now on the route exploring--see another article in this week's
                        <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph>,) have been appointed in New York to press
                    the claims of this road on Capitalists, and there is a constant correspondence
                    between that City and those interested in this road.'" </excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>From a highly respectable gentleman, well known to our citizens, of Somerset,
                        Pa., July 15, 1860.</p>
                    <p>"Our friends here are active in pressing forward the Rail-Road project.
                        Agents, (now on the route exploring--see another article in this week's
                            <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph>,) have been appointed in New York to
                        press the claims of this road on Capitalists, and there is a constant
                        correspondence between that City and those interested in this road. Funds
                        have been raised to have a survey made, the New Yorkers to furnish the
                        engenuity. By their means we will be able to furnish statistics to convince
                        the skeptical as to the feasibility of the enterprise. When this is once
                        accomplished, the money will be forthcoming, so say the knowing ones."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter from a citizen of Somerset, Pennsylvania about the railroad survey.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/july60.html#7.25f</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Wire Walking</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"On Monday, in this place, Prof. Price, performed the hazardous feat of
                    walking a wire stretched from the roof of Fisher's Hotel to the top of the
                    building occupied by Mr. Heyser as a Drug Store, the distance being about one
                    hundred and fifty feet."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--On Monday, in this place, Prof. Price, performed the hazardous feat of
                        walking a wire stretched from the roof of Fisher's Hotel to the top of the
                        building occupied by Mr. Heyser as a Drug Store, the distance being about
                        one hundred and fifty feet. The feat was performed in a very clever manner,
                        was everything promised, and gave entire satisfaction to witness the daring
                        and interesting exhibition.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prof. Pries performed his high-wire walk between Fisher's Hotel and Mr.
                    Heyser's Drug Store, over one hundred and fifty feet.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/july60.html#7.25g</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Water Works</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper is gratified to learn that the Town Council is determined to
                    build a water works. They have written to the Chief Engineer of the Philadelphia
                    Water Works to ask for his help in surveying and estimating costs.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Almost a Fire</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reidell</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Someone set a fire in the stable of Mrs. Margaret Reidell on West Market
                    street. It was extinguished before it destroyed her property.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Constitution and By Laws</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprint of the Constitution and bylaws of the Chambersburg Douglas and
                    Johnson Club.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.07.25.06">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.07.25.07">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.07.25.08">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
