<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1860/pa.fr.vs.1860.11.21">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Jeff McClurken</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/22/95</tagDate>
            <tagNote>2nd Pass; Colleen Doody did first pass.</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1860-11-21">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="11">November</month>
            <day>21</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.11.21.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>White and Black Labor</head>
                <origin>Philadelphia Evening Journal</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Warns that, if the "irrepressible conflict" occurs, then free blacks will
                    move into northern towns and cities "where they will seek employment as a
                    resource from starvation, and, in doing that, they will compete with free white
                    laboring men and women."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.11.21.02">
            <pageNote>Stories</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.11.21.03">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.11.21.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Secession Movement</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"If the North would act in good faith towards the South and not set the bad
                    example of nullifying the plain provisions of the Constitution and the laws of
                    Congress this trouble would not now exist and peace, confidence and prosperity
                    would be restored to the country. The blame lies at the door of the North--let
                    us act righteously towards the South and we will bear nothing more of Secession
                    or Nullification."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We present in the columns of the <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph>, this
                        week, copious extracts from our exchanges, all over the country, in relation
                        to the secession movement in the South. We give the news on both sides as we
                        find it. While one portion of the Southern people appear determined to set
                        up for themselves, another portion, evidently the minority, tell us the
                        disunion sentiment is rapidly losing ground and that the "great panic" will
                        subside without "firing a shot." Our readers can peruse the extracts and
                        judge for themselves how portentous are the dangers which threaten the
                        Union.</p>
                    <p>That the South has just ground for complaint, and much danger to apprehend
                        from a sectional administration of the Government, cannot be doubted or
                        denied; but we do not believe that secession from the Union is the best
                        remedy to right her wrongs. We put in no protest against her war-like
                        preparations, we do no object to her arming her citizens, we have no fault
                        to find with her for placing herself in a complete state of defense ready
                        for any emergency that may arise requiring her to protect her honor, safety
                        or property. That course is all right--that is patriotic. Thus far the South
                        has now advanced and if she maintains her stand there she will find plenty
                        of "aid and comfort" in the North. It is certainly much to her credit that
                        amidst all the excitement and turmoil which prevails among her populace not
                        a single act of resistance to the laws of the United States has yet been
                        committed. While this is her position, and so long as she maintains this
                        attitude, she will not only command the admiration of the North but will
                        find no lack of willing hands and sympathising hearts to assist her in
                        repelling any and every aggression that may be essayed against her
                        constitutional rights. If the South, however, has made up her mind that we
                        are bad neighbors and is determined to cut loose from us and nullify the
                        laws of the land, without a good and sufficient cause to show for it, she
                        may place herself beyond the pale of sympathy or support from any quarter
                        and will have to depend on her own resources to "carry the war into Africa."</p>
                    <p>While we have no hesitancy in asserting that there is a strong feeling among
                        the masses in the North in favor of the South, and no disposition to meddle
                        with her affairs, we would not at the same time desire to conceal the fact
                        that a portion--and a very large and influential portion too--of the
                        northern people would readily plunge the country into civil war if they
                        thought they could thereby inflict injury on the slave-owner. The tone of
                        the Republican press, pretty generally, indicate this state of feeling.
                        Their deep unmitigated hatred of the slave-holder is the moving spring of
                        their policy--not because they desire the freedom or happiness of the
                        slave--that is [sic] words without meaning to them--but because the Southern
                        States are strongly Democratic in sentiment they would drive them out of the
                        Union. The language of irritation and menace which the North is so fond of
                        applying to the South is not very well calculated to allay excitement and
                        restore good feeling between us and our Southern brethren. If the North
                        would act in good faith towards the South and not set the bad example of
                        nullifying the plain provisions of the Constitution and the laws of Congress
                        this trouble would not now exist and peace, confidence and prosperity would
                        be restored to the country. The blame lies at the door of the North--let us
                        act righteously towards the South and we will bear nothing more of Secession
                        or Nullification.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spirit reprints numerous extracts from Southern papers dealing with the
                    secession question. While they believe that the South has "just ground for
                    complaint," they don't think that secession "is the best remedy to right her
                    wrongs." They invite the reader to peruse the extracts and "judge for themselves
                    how portentous are the dangers which threaten the Union." The Spirit blames the
                    Republican press for the desire to "plunge the country into civil war."</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/nov60.html#11.21a</note>
                <look>Look</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Election Returns</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spirit still has not received the official election returns from
                    Pennsylvania.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Interesting Exposures</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The election results make it apparent that the Douglas camp fraudulently
                    gained the nomination of the Democratic convention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Northern Nullification</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Northern Republicans have nullified the fugitive slave act, which is the
                    law of the land, by seizing fugitive slaves out of the custody of the Marshals
                    who were supposed to return them to their masters. Southerners, on the other
                    hand, have not yet violated any laws.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Hard Times</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>While many northerners voted for the Republicans in hopes of bringing about
                    good times, the opposite has occurred. Lincoln's election has led to a loss of
                    business confidence. In addition, the South is draining the North of specie. The
                    North is unable to balance its trade because the South isn't buying Northern
                    manufactured goods.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The President's Position</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>President Buchanan can be counted on to protect the Union if any states
                    violate the Constitution.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04-06</column>
                <head>Secession Movement in the South</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Numerous excerpts from Southern papers that provide both pro- and
                    anti-secession statements.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>Look</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.11.21.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Prentice</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>George D. Prentice, editor of the Louisville Journal, gave a slimly
                    attended lecture on Politics and Politicians.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Horse Thieves About</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Josiah Atherton and another man stole two horses. Atherton was caught, but
                    the other man got away.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Nichols Monument</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nichol</ln>
                        <fn>Aaron</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Columbus and Chambersburg Lodges, I.O.O.F. are going to erect a
                    monument to Post Grand Master Aaron Nichol over his grave in the Cedar Grove
                    Cemetery.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>A Week of Special Prayer</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"It has ben proposed to observe the week commencing with the first Tuesday
                    in January next, as a season of special prayer for the conversion of the world."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Repaired</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The iron bridge in Gas Alley has been repaired. This was necessary because
                    "this very public thoroughfare was rendered impassible for some time by the
                    unsafe condition of the bridge."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Military Excursion</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"The Chambers Artillery, under command of Capt. Housum, made a very
                    pleasant excursion to Greenvillage on Saturday last. They had a very find
                    parade, and a good time generally, and returned home in the evening delighted
                    with their visit to the village."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Geoffrey J. Levalle was shot with a horse-shoe nail in a fight with T.B.
                    Kershaw. "The nail was found in his brain, where it had been for nearly a
                    month."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harden</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Curtis</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on November 11th at the Methodist E. Parsonage.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burkholder</ln>
                        <fn>Anna</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Died on November 13th, aged 71 years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Watson</ln>
                        <fn>Charlotte</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Watson</ln>
                        <fn>W.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Charlotte Watson died on October 22nd, aged 46 years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.11.21.06">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.11.21.07">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.11.21.08">
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Unjust Taunts</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Southerners believe that the North is using its greater strength to injure
                    the South. Northerners "treat with derision and scorn the just complaints of the
                    South, and pronounce her threats of secession a humbug and a trick."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
