<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1860/pa.fr.vs.1860.06.27">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Jeff McClurken</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/22/95</tagDate>
            <tagNote>2nd Pass; Andy Morris did first pass.</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1860-06-27">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="06">June</month>
            <day>27</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.06.27.01">
            <pageNote/>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Power of Religion</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Poem about the power of religion, which "elevates our race."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Proceedings of the Democratic National Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Preceedings of the convention that adjourned to Baltimore from Charleston,
                    VA. Douglas was declared the nominee after receiving 179 votes on the second
                    ballot.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>The Convention of the Seceders</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The convention of some or all of the representatives from Virginia, North
                    Carolina, Missouri, California, Oregon, Florida, Louisiana, Texas, Mississippi,
                    Tennessee, Kentucky and Arkansas nominated Breckinridge and Lane.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.06.27.02">
            <pageNote/>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01-06</column>
                <head>Report of the Attorney General on California Land Claims</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Attorney General, in response to a resolution of the House of
                    Representatives, provides a statement of the amount spent for the defense of
                    private land claims in California.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.06.27.03">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.06.27.04">
            <pageNote/>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Nominations</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"From the course pursued at Charleston it was evident that the same men
                    would enact the same scenes over again at Baltimore. A portion would stick by
                    the Convention 'till the moment of balloting, and then, when they found their
                    disorganizing efforts too puny to trample the wishes of the masses of the party
                    under their feet, they would withdraw and present a ticket with a view to stab
                    deeper at the vitals of the party by an attempt to defeat the regularly
                    nominated candidate of the Convention. This they have accomplished, but it is
                    all that they will accomplish."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The National Democratic Convention re-assembled at Baltimore on the 18th
                        inst., pursuant to the order of adjournment adopted at Charleston, and
                        continued in session six days. A full account of the proceedings are
                        contained in the present number of our paper. The action of the Convention
                        has not disappointed any one. From the course pursued at Charleston it was
                        evident that the same men would enact the same scenes over again at
                        Baltimore. A portion would stick by the Convention 'till the moment of
                        balloting, and then, when they found their disorganizing efforts too puny to
                        trample the wishes of the masses of the party under their feet, they would
                        withdraw and present a ticket with a view to stab deeper at the vitals of
                        the party by an attempt to defeat the regularly nominated candidate of the
                        Convention. This they have accomplished, but it is all that they will
                        accomplish. The distinguished statesman whose name they have taken the
                        liberty to use without his knowledge or consent will certainly not allow
                        himself to be made the tool of a disorganizing faction. There are honors in
                        store for him too great to be sacrificed by a willing complicity with such a
                        scheme to overthrow the party. The Democratic party can not--must not--be
                        divided in this or any other contest; and woe to the men who will attempt
                        it. We cannot see the wisdom or glory of suffering a defeat with <emph
                            rend="italic">two</emph> candidates in the field, when victory with
                            <emph rend="italic">one</emph> is certain. Those who will lend their
                        support to an irregular nomination at this time can have no other object in
                        view than the breaking up of the party altogether. Such a calamity to the
                        whole nation can only be averted by extending a faithful and undivided
                        support to the candidates regularly nominated by the Democratic National
                        Convention. The ticket that we this day place at the head of our columns
                        received the support of the representatives of the party who stuck by our
                        National Convention--remained in it at Charleston and held their seats at
                        Baltimore by an unbroken and uninterrupted claim. Their decision we are
                        bound to respect and can know no other. Love of party--love of country, and
                        fidelity to every recognized usage of the Democratic organization, sacredly
                        demands for this nomination our hearty support. We honestly believe that in
                        the end all the jealousies, heart-burnings and antagonism that now exist
                        will be healed, and that the sober, good sense of the party will impel every
                        man in the ranks to unite harmoniously and with enthusiasm on our ticket and
                        carry it forward to victory.</p>
                    <p>We have not the space to say much in respect to our candidates in this issue
                        of our paper, nor is it required--the name and fame of STEPHEN A. DOUGLAS
                        are household words over the land. Our nominee for Vice President, BENJAMIN
                        FITZPATRICK, now holds the position of United States Senator from Alabama.
                        He has long sustained the reputation throughout the entire South of being
                        one of the most sensible and conservative of her statesmen. In 1841 he was
                        elected Governor of the State of Alabama, after a warm contest, by a
                        majority of ten thousand. As a mark of regard for the faithful manner in
                        which he had discharged his duties as Governor the people re-elected him in
                        1843 without opposition. He is now serving his third term as United States
                        senator, having last year beaten Hon. Wm. L. Yancey the distinguished
                        Secessionists for that position. No better man morally and intellectually,
                        and no stronger name, could have been placed upon the ticket for Vice
                        President than Hon. Benjamin Fitzpatrick.</p>
                    <p>The course of the Hon. J.L. Dawson, chairman of the Pennsylvania delegation,
                        points out the path of duty and patriotism which every true Democrat must
                        indorse and follow. He was all along opposed to Mr. Douglas, but after his
                        nomination was fairly and justly made, he gave his hearty concurrence to the
                        choice of the Convention in the following sensible remarks:</p>
                    <p>Mr. President and gentlemen of the Convention--It is scarcely necessary for
                        me to say that at no time during the sitting of this body did Judge Douglas
                        receive the united vote of the delegation from Pennsylvania, and I may
                        further add that in the consideration of the platform, a majority of us
                        united with our Southern friends ready to give them all we believed them
                        entitled to under the Federal Constitution. In our judgement they asked for
                        nothing more, and we were not willing to offer them less; in our action we
                        have been overruled by a decided majority of this body. And for
                        Pennsylvania, I am free to say, that attached there as we are to the
                        Democratic party, its principles, its discipline, its organization--standing
                        there forever, in the eloquent language of the President of the Convention
                        in his opening speech at Charleston. "Standing as perpetual sentinels upon
                        the outposts of the Constitution," I trust we will abide its decisions and
                        support its nominees.--(Cheers and applause)</p>
                    <p>Judge Douglas is a man of acknowledged talent and everywhere regarded as the
                        accomplished statesman, skilled in the art of ruling. Born under a New
                        England sun yet, by adoption, a citizen of the West, honored alike in the
                        valley of the Ohio and on the slopes of the Atlantic, he now should belong
                        to the whole country. (Applause) Untrained to some extent in early life in
                        the learning of the schools, the deficiency, if any exists, has been largely
                        compensated by the generous measure in which nature has dealt upon him her
                        choicest gifts of intellect and character. [Applause] Like Henry of the
                        Revolution, like Peel of England, these noble qualities have made him the
                        architect of his own fortune. [Applause]</p>
                    <p>That the Union is a confederacy endowed with special powers, the States
                        composing it retaining all the undelegated attributes of sovereignty, is the
                        fundamental truth of our political system. In defense of this truth we are
                        about to engage in a new contest, and in the comprehension of its true
                        character we have thoroughly to educate the public mind. The popular heart
                        is to be won back to loyalty by holding up to its contemplation the image of
                        the Constitution in its severe beauty of lineament and proportion.
                        [Applause]</p>
                    <p>The erring conclusion of our fellow citizens of all sections are to be
                        corrected by a thorough and persevering exposition of their fallacy, and in
                        place of these are to be included the paramount claims of the federal
                        compact to the hearty allegiance in letter and spirit of every American who
                        can comprehend and appreciate the institutions of his country, and who
                        really cherishes a desire for their perpetuity. [Applause]</p>
                    <p>If here, in this beautiful city, which looks out upon the Chesapeake, any
                        incitement could have been needed to a broad patriotism in our
                        deliberations, it should have been found in the association in the midst of
                        which we are assembled; for it was at Annapolis, at the close of the
                        Revolution, that Washington resigned his commission. It is also within sight
                        of the spot at which we are convened that imposing monuments rise to the
                        greatness of his memory and to the patriotism of the sons of Maryland.
                        [Applause]</p>
                    <p>Pennsylvania, the State in which independence was first proclaimed, and the
                        work of the Revolution secured by the construction of the Federal compact;
                        the State which holds within her bosom the ashes of Franklin, and boats the
                        first battlefield of Washington, will be true to her noble memories,
                        (cheers,) and in the fullness of that enlightened conservative sentiment,
                        for which she has been distinguished, will rally, I trust, in giant strength
                        cast the dust from her eyes, and aid the friends of the Democratic party
                        once more to elect their nominee. [Loud cheers and applause.]</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spirit supports Douglas for president and criticizes the men who
                    attempted to disorganize the Convention and who then nominated a rival
                    Democratic ticket.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/june60.html#6.27a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Hon. Wm. P. Schell</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Democratic party of Bedford met on June 19th and recommended W.P.
                    Schell as their candidate for Congress.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Covode Committee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Says that the Covode Committee has been "working the wrong way lately,"
                    much against the wishes of the Republicans. They blame Forney, a disappointed
                    spoils-seeker, for setting the Committee on foot.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Slavery Agitation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spirit is critical of those men who have created and maintained
                    Northern and Southern branches of the Methodist Church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>A Small Business</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spirit criticizes the Times, which felt compelled to display its
                    erudition by pointing out an error in a Spirit article. The Spirit claims that
                    it was a typo.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Editorial Correspondence</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter from J.G.R. in which he describes his trip to the Democratic
                    convention in Baltimore.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.06.27.05">
            <pageNote/>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Railroad Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A meeting of Franklin County citizens will be held to "take into
                    consideration the propriety of having a survey made of the proposed Railroad
                    route from Chambersburg to Burnt Cabins."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Rail Road</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spirit has been trying to get Baltimoreans interested in making a
                    connection from their city to Chambersburg and beyond. While it would be helpful
                    to the citizens of Chambersburg, it would be immensely useful to the trade of
                    Baltimore to have a link to St. Louis.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Graduating Exercises and Concert</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The graduation exercises of the Chambersburg Female Seminary will take
                    place on Wednesday evening.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Arrested</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smidt</ln>
                        <fn>Gotleib</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bitner</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Constable</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A young German named Gotleib Smidt was arrested on Friday by Constable
                    Bitner.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>A Suggestion</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spirit hopes that the bridge on 2nd Street can be replaced.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>An Outsider</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Joe is naturally a quiet fellow, but when they put fighting whiskey into
                    him it works its way out."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Joe Harper has been "incarcerated for making violent demonstrations upon
                    one of the Hotels here," claiming that he (a African-American) was a part of the
                    Harper's Ferry insurrection.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rife</ln>
                        <fn>Anna</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Died on June 11th at 77 years of age.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.06.27.06">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.06.27.07">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.06.27.08">
            <pageNote/>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>English View of the Cotton and Slavery Question</head>
                <origin>London Chronicle</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Discussion of how the English will react to having the cotton supply
                    endangered.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
