<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1860/pa.fr.vs.1860.04.18">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Jeff McClurken</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/22/95</tagDate>
            <tagNote>2nd Pass; Andy Morris did first pass.</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1860-04-18">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day>18</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.04.18.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Indian Massacre in California</head>
                <origin>San Francisco Bulletin</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Description of massacre of settlement of peaceful Indians by settlers in
                    California.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>The State Legislature</head>
                <origin>Philadelphia Inquirer</origin>
                <commentary>Comments on bills rushed through before the end of the legislative
                    session, including banking and railroad bills "that should never have passed."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes the past legislative session as "corrupt and intriguing."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Travelogue; non-fiction anecdotes</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.04.18.02">
            <pageNote>Poetry, fiction</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.04.18.03">
            <pageNote>Poetry, fiction, advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.04.18.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Tariffs</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Outlines the Valley Spirit's opposition to tariffs as indirect and
                    excessive taxation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>More Chapters in the "Irrepressible Conflict"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Attacks English abolitionists and author of Helper's Impending Crisis as
                    signs of the Republicans' evil designs on the Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>White Slavery in England</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that the employment of children in English industry is far more
                    pernicious than "our more humane institutions," namely, black slavery.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Epistle No. 4</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"It is the universal testimony of people here that negroes are a worthless
                    and dishonest class, and they are consequently looked upon with contempt and
                    disgust."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>EXPERIENCE IN THE NORTH. Being a Series of Letters from the Correspondence of
                        a young Carolinian, on a Tour of observation in the Northern States, to his
                        Uncle in South Carolina.</p>
                    <p>EPISTLE NO. 4</p>
                    <p>Darrow, Ohio, March 15th 1860.</p>
                    <p> Respected Sir: I believe I owe you an apology for not writing sooner. The
                        fact is I had begun several letters, but before finishing, I always found
                        something in the beginning concerning which I have had occasion to change my
                        views. Indeed I must confess that recent events and observations have led me
                        to look upon Slavery in a somewhat different light; though not to such a
                        degree as to make me an advocate of slavery or to cause me to condemn the
                        doctrine of the Republican Party. The recent negro riots in Canada have
                        convinced me of the danger we are in from the negro element. I should be in
                        favor of colonizing the free negroes to some Territory in Africa or South
                        America, to be acquired by the United States by purchase or conquest; and I
                        entertain no doubt that the Northern States would cheerfully pay the cost of
                        their removal, not only for themselves but also for those of the South, if
                        emancipated-- Without colonization I am opposed to emancipation. It is the
                        universal testimony of people here that negroes are a worthless and
                        dishonest class, and they are consequently looked upon with contempt and
                        disgust. In the free States there appears to be an irrepressible conflict
                        between the two races which manifests itself in such outbreaks as that at
                        Chatham. Where there are few negroes in any community, with little
                        influence, not much harm is done, but when they form a numerical majority in
                        any precinct township or School-district, where they exercise the right of
                        suffrage, the case is different. Their motto is rule or ruin. No party
                        questions divide <emph rend="italic">them</emph>; it is a question of <emph
                            rend="italic">white</emph> or <emph rend="italic">black</emph>, and
                        whites must succumb, and allow their educational interests and township
                        affairs to rest in the hands of negroes.</p>
                    <p>It was with feelings of extreme horror that I read the account of the late
                        Pendleton Mills catastrophe, and I cannot find terms sufficiently strong to
                        denounce the spirit of avarice and grinding oppression which induced the
                        inhuman proprietors of this establishment to allow this building to be
                        occupied by these unfortunate <emph rend="italic">white</emph> men and
                        women, knowing it to be unsafe! Had a southern man allowed his slaves to
                        occupy such an untenable building as a workshop, thereby causing the death
                        of six hundred human beings, what a howl of horror would have been heard in
                        the north from Maine to Oregon! And yet this affair is passed over in
                        comparative silence, and this social Nero is allowed to pursue the even
                        tenor of his way. I am obliged to call this an inconsistency on the part of
                        the Free Party of the North, which can only be exccused [sic] by the
                        consideration that their great philanthropists are so occupied by the
                        project of ameliorating the condition of the slaves of the South that these
                        enormities have escaped their notice, <emph rend="italic">though committed
                            beneath their very nose.</emph></p>
                    <p> This inconsistency is also strikingly manifested by the stolid indifference
                        and want of sympathy shown by the Republican press for the shoemakers of New
                        England in their present contest for a fair compensation for their labor. It
                        is stated, on good authority, that in some cases they have been compelled to
                        make shoes for four or five cents per pair, and this while their employers
                        were rolling in Luxury, yet this wholesale robbery is not rebuked by the
                        Republicans. Even Greely, the champion of free labor, in the <emph
                            rend="italic">Tribune</emph> of the 18th says that "having resolved to
                        demand higher wages, even at the cost of an industrial war, they should
                        quietly proceed to send a large proportion of their number to the Great
                        West, where there are a great many who are willing to give bread and meat
                        for shoes, though unable to pay money." This is certainly very cool for an
                        editor who is constantly prating about the deplorable condition of the
                        negroes in the South and who would sever the Union to better it, and yet has
                        not a word of sympathy for the poor downtrodden and oppressed white laborers
                        of the North. He must have been reading "A Penny a Day and how four Mouths
                        it fed;" yet all rational men must acknowledge that the man who is compelled
                        to make shoes for five cents per pair must lead a life miserable indeed.</p>
                    <p>Dayton is a handsome inland City. There are a great many negroes in the place
                        and vicinity. (Please say nothing about those "Congo Indians") and the
                        present being the second generation from those who came here from the South.
                        I know of no better place of judging of their character and capacity, which
                        in all truth I must say are low enough, even when compared with the slaves
                        of a Carolina plantation. They are generally found in a degraded condition,
                        doing the very meanest kind of drudgery. Their constitutional laziness,
                        however, induces them to shirk hard labor as much as possible, and we often
                        find the more intelligent and better classes serving in such as boot-blacks,
                        porters, barbers, cooks and hotel waiters. At the Hotel where I am stopping
                        we are regularly, served by negroes and you might imagine yourself in a
                        Southern Inn, except that the negroes are very rude and ill-mannered, and
                        also that no person is expected to use the least politeness in his dealings
                        with them. People seem to be very fond of aping the manner of a
                        slave-driver, and "Clean my boots, you black rascal," and "attend to my
                        horse, you d--n nigger," are not unusual mandates. Here in Ohio, where I had
                        expected something better, I find that the negroes are more despised and
                        maltreated than in any place I have visited. It seems to be considered a
                        duty to hate these unfortunate beings, and to oppress them in every possible
                        way. A person here would be ashamed to lend a helping hand to a negro, to
                        speak a word of sympathy, or to address one in a gentlemanly tone. My
                        experience has taught me that the slaves of the South occupy an enviable
                        position when compared with these poor northern outcasts. I have conversed
                        with several refugees who would gladly return to their old masters if an
                        opportunity offered. They long for the flesh pots of Egypt. The other day
                        one of them to whom I had spoken a kind word, and who knew me to be a
                        southerner, came to me and begged me to write a letter to his old master,
                        offering to return if allowed. I did so and if it succeeds in securing for
                        him a home, I shall be satisfied with the part I took in the affair, much as
                        I hate slavery as a principle. If, however, negroes are in a worse
                        condition, poor whites must be infinitely better off. I shall have something
                        to say on this point in a future letter; meanwhile I must now close.</p>
                    <p>Respectfully your Nephew,</p>
                    <p>Berkley.</p>
                    <p> P. S. You are probably aware that the <emph rend="italic">Republican</emph>
                        "National" Convention meets at Charleston on the 23d of May. It will pay you
                        to attend as you will then have an opportunity of hearing some of our big
                        guns. By the way, I think it argues bad for Southern hospitality that the
                        delegates are to be fleeced out of $50 per day for board, as stated by the
                        papers.</p>
                    <p>B.</p>
                    <p> P. P. S. Mr. Peyton says it is the <emph rend="italic">Democratic</emph>
                        Convention that is to meet at Charleston; but he must be mistaken, as it is
                        the Republicans who are making all the Row about the high price of
                        provisions there, and if this is the case they are certainly not interested
                        in the matter.</p>
                    <p>B.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Berkeley</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter from nephew on tour in North to uncle in South. Once an
                    abolitionist, the nephew now writes that he opposes abolition unless blacks are
                    removed to some colony. Writes of a northern mill accident and compares northern
                    industrialism unfavorably to southern slavery.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/april60.html#4.18c</note>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>The Attempt of the Republicans in Congress to Degrade the President</head>
                <origin>Cincinnati Enquirer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Denounces the creation of a committee to investigate corruption charges
                    against President Buchanan over printing contracts.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.04.18.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Borough Extension</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A court injunction was lifted that was granted to parties in Hamilton
                    Township against the annexation of their property into Chambersburg Borough. The
                    Valley Spirit approves of the annexation in principle but hopes that any further
                    land acquired will be with an eye toward the extension of the borough.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Survey Completed</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The party of gentlemen engaged in the survey of a route for a Railroad
                    from Chambersburg to Gettysburg arrived in this place on Thursday last."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--The party of gentlemen engaged in the survey of a route for a Railroad from
                        Chambersburg to Gettysburg arrived in this place on Thursday last. The point
                        at which they terminated the survey was somewhere near the Franklin Railroad
                        bridge. We understand the examination of the route has proven very
                        satisfactory to the gentlemen engaged in the survey. It has been found
                        perfectly practicable, of easy grades, and not requiring any unusual
                        expenditures in the construction of the Road. We are promised a copy of the
                        Report on the Survey in time for publication in our paper of next week.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The survey party laying out a survey for a railroad from Chambersburg to
                    Gettysburg finished their work, and has laid out a good route that would not
                    require any unusual expenses.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/april60.html#4.18a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Natural Curiosity</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We were shown by Mr. J. S. Nixon, who is well known in this community to
                    possess a penchant for collecting everything that is curious in Nature and Art,
                    a double-headed snake, which he has now in his possession. His snakeship has two
                    veritable heads and no mistake or deception about them, both of which he seemed
                    to use."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--We were shown by Mr. J. S. Nixon, who is well known in this community to
                        possess a penchant for collecting everything that is curious in Nature and
                        Art, a double-headed snake, which he has now in his possession. His
                        snakeship has two veritable heads and no mistake or deception about them,
                        both of which he seemed to use. Whether this sample belongs to a regular
                        species of double-headed snake or is merely a <emph rend="italic">lusus
                            naturae</emph> in that way we are not prepared to say. Two heads on a
                        snake we look upon as a waste of the raw material, we would rather prefer
                        them with no head at all.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nixon</ln>
                        <fn>J.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. J.S. Nixon, a well-known collector of "everything that is curious in
                    Nature and Art," showed the editors a two-headed snake.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/april60.html#4.18b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Admitted to the Bar</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gehr</ln>
                        <fn>Hastings</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pittenos</ln>
                        <fn>Leonard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Goodyear</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Gehr, Pittenos, and Goodyear were admitted to the bar in Franklin County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="j">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Court Proceedings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swingley</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf>Colored</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wayman</ln>
                        <fn>Louisa</fn>
                        <sf>Colored</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewer</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Long</ln>
                        <fn>Ludwig</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Montgomery</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donaldson</ln>
                        <fn>Anna</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf>Colored</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf>Colored</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keith</ln>
                        <fn>Jemima</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf>Colored</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dosh</ln>
                        <fn>Fred</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shearer</ln>
                        <fn>Walker</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nave</ln>
                        <fn>Solomon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shearer</ln>
                        <fn>Elias</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shearer</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shuman</ln>
                        <fn>Philip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nave</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rosenthal</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maclay</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Immel</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dechert</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Corwell</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reasner</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foltz</ln>
                        <fn>Christian</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ely</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ely</ln>
                        <fn>Solomon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Senseny</ln>
                        <fn>Ab.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Senseny</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clippinger</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Suesserrott</ln>
                        <fn>J.L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rhinehart</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rhinehart</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sellers</ln>
                        <fn>W.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Disposition of cases at trial on April 9th.</summary>
                <note>Law firms names not included</note>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hammon</ln>
                        <fn>P.</fn>
                        <sf>J.P.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitmore</ln>
                        <fn>J.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Starleeper</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on April 10th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nelson</ln>
                        <fn>A.K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hay</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hilands</ln>
                        <fn>R.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on April 12th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kelley</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Father</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>Ben</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zettell</ln>
                        <fn>Anna</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on the previous Wednesday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneck</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Conrad</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nolte</ln>
                        <fn>Anna Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on April 15th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Bottom of page illegible.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.04.18.07">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.04.18.08">
            <pageNote>Miscellaneous stories, market information, advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
