<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1860/pa.fr.vs.1860.02.22">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Jeff McClurken</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/22/95</tagDate>
            <tagNote>2nd Pass; Andy Morris did first pass.</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1860-02-22">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day>22</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.02.22.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Great Speech of Stephen A. Douglas on Harper's Ferry Invasion</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Speech of Douglas on January 23, supporting legislation allowing federal
                    intervention in the case of a raid across state lines to rescue John Brown.
                    Douglas also discusses Lincoln's assertion that the country cannot exist
                    half-slave and half-free, and argues that it is needless inflammation of
                    sectional tension.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.02.22.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Two Views of the Case</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Story making fun of the short-sightedness of Northern abolitionists.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Fiction, poetry, morality stories, advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.02.22.03">
            <pageNote>Advertisements, legal notices</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.02.22.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Need of a Tariff</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The fact that every branch of productive industry is completely paralyzed;
                    that all classes of society are suffering from the effects of the ruinous policy
                    of Federalist locofocoism -which produced the terrible panic in the financial
                    world during the Fall of 1857, as a necessary result of destroying the
                    manufactories of our own, to build up those of foreign countries -should open
                    the eyes of the blindest, and shine in upon the most obtuse intellect in the
                    lower House . . . "</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It seems like a work of supererogation to attempt to urge upon Congress the
                        necessity for a good, wise, protective tariff. The first principle of nature
                        -self-preservation- should furnish the one great, powerful argument in favor
                        of remodeling the present nominal impost laws -amounting almost to Free
                        Trade. The fact that every branch of productive industry is completely
                        paralyzed; that all classes of society are suffering from the effects of the
                        ruinous policy of Federalist locofocoism -which produced the terrible panic
                        in the financial world during the Fall of 1857, as a necessary result of
                        destroying the manufactories of our own, to build up those of foreign
                        countries -should open the eyes of the blindest, and shine in upon the most
                        obtuse intellect in the lower House; as these facts set forth, unmistakably,
                        the imperative demand for action, by that body, on this all important topic.</p>
                    <p>If, however, any further incentive were needed; any greater light required to
                        clear away the mistiness which beclouds the brains of locofoco, Federalist
                        politicians; if any stronger reasons are necessary to convince all men
                        everywhere, throughout our country, of the necessity, the absolute,
                        immediate, requirement for a thorough readjustment of the revenue laws, so
                        as to discriminate in favor of and protect American made goods from the
                        ruinous competition of the productions of pauper labor on the other side of
                        the Atlantic, we think the following will suffice. If is clipped from a late
                        number of the London <emph rend="italic">Times</emph>: </p>
                    <p>"The importation of cotton into this country has, since the import duty was
                        abolished, increased sixteen fold. Having been 63,000,000 lbs., it is now
                        1,000,000,000 lbs. This is one of those giant facts which stands head and
                        shoulders higher than the crowd -so high and so broad that we can neither
                        overlook it nor affect not to see it. It proves the existence of a thousand
                        smaller facts that must stand under its shadow. It tells of sixteen times as
                        many mills, sixteen times as many English families living by working those
                        mills, sixteen times as much profit derived from sixteen times as much
                        capital engaged in this manufacture. It carries after it sequences of
                        increased quantity of freights and insurances, and necessities for sixteen
                        time the amount of customers to consume, to our profit, the immense amount
                        of produce we are turning out. There are not many such facts as <emph
                            rend="italic">these</emph>, arising in the quiet routine of industrial
                        history. It is so large and so steady that we can steer our national policy
                        by it; it is so important to us that we should be reduced to embarrassment
                        if it were suddenly to disappear. It teaches us to persevere in a policy
                        which has produced so wonderful a result; its beneficent operation makes it
                        essential to us to deal carefully with it now that we have got it."</p>
                    <p>What a commentary on the blindness and folly of the wise-acres of locofoco
                        federalism? England's leading organ boasts of the free importation of cotton
                        into British ports as resulting in the increase of industry throughout Great
                        Britain sixteen fold. The greater part of this raw material was grown upon
                        American soil.--Its manufacture at home would have given constant employment
                        to sixteen workmen at home, and perhaps more, for one now employed without
                        that raw material to work up. English journalists proclaim to the world the
                        secret of British prosperity; showing that industry promoted is the chief
                        source of their success, and yet other nations, whose people are equally as
                        dependent upon the labor of their country, see these statements, believe in
                        their truthfulness, and foolishly refuse to apply the proper remedy,
                        although suffering unheard of privations in consequence of Governmental
                        neglect.</p>
                    <p>The policy of Great Britain, controlled as the <emph rend="italic"
                        >Times</emph> says by the effects produced upon the masses of her people, is
                        to abolish duties or increase Tariffs in proportion to the benefit thereof
                        upon English manufactured wares seeking a market upon British soil, the
                        law-makers lost no time in placing upon the statute Books of her majesty's
                        realm such laws as the people demanded. Here, however, where the people are,
                        or profess to be, the real sovereigns, the loud earnest demands and
                        supplicating appeals of the masses to their servants, the Representatives in
                        both branches of Congress, do not seem to weigh a feather with these
                        dignitaries, elevated for a brief period by the votes of the thousands whom
                        they heartlessly refuse to relieve.</p>
                    <p>We are well aware that there are noble, honorable exceptions to this rule;
                        that there are a large number of the present Congress who are anxious to
                        arrest the madness of the system of transporting all our raw material to
                        foreign work shops to be made up, as is now the case, and who will vote for
                        any fair, honest Tariff laws; bur our surprise is that any American citizen;
                        any lover of his country, can be found so blind as not to see the necessity
                        of prompt action in the present crisis.</p>
                    <p>The disgraceful notice of the departure of a vessel for England, with a
                        certain number of passengers, and upwards of an hundred thousand dollars in
                        gold and silver, which meets the indignant eye of the constant reader of
                        daily papers, almost every few weeks, will be forever disposed of if
                        Congress makes the necessary arrangements for keeping the precious metals at
                        home; by passing laws for the protection of home labor -which will keep the
                        money at home also.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary/>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Valiant Hickman</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes the cowardice of Representative Hickman when he was beaten with a
                    switch by a Virginia Representative.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Abolition Delicacy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Attacks Maria Child for her support of John Brown.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>The Caledonia Railroad</head>
                <origin>Repository &amp; Transcript</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt> "But no place is so much interested in the construction of the Caledonia
                    Road, as Chambersburg, and as that hateful stereotyped ideas of having the
                    monopoly of a railroad terminus, has at last been destroyed--the relaying of the
                    Franklin Railroad has punctured that bubble--and the delusive notion that trade
                        <emph rend="italic">must</emph> come to Chambersburg, and by which the
                    public have so long been <emph rend="italic">lulled</emph> into a quiet
                    indifference, has of late been dissipated, by finding the trade passing off to
                    other roads, the people are awakening to their interests; they find that
                    Chambersburg with its present population, and with its manufactories in steel,
                    iron, wood, &amp; c., has as much need now of another railroad as it had
                    years ago, need of more than one stage line." </excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>There is an erroneous opinion entertained by many persons in regard to the
                        recent movement at Fayetteville, for the extension of the Gettysburg
                        Railroad to Chambersburg which for the sake of brevity may be styled the
                        Caledonia Railroad. It is supposed that that movement has originated in a
                        split of rivalry with the C. V. R. R. This upon an examination with the
                        trade and travel of this valley, will prove to be a misconception of the
                        object.</p>
                    <p>The C. V. R. R., it is true, is one of the oldest roads in the State, and for
                        judicious management, &amp;c., it is one of the best, and will, no
                        doubt, be ever beneficial to the public and profitable to its stockholders,
                        in carrying the trade that legitimately belongs to it; but as a great deal
                        of the produce of this and adjoining Counties, passes to market in a
                        different direction from that in which the C. V. R. R. lies, it becomes
                        necessary now to make another railroad in such direction as may best
                        accommodate this trade.</p>
                    <p>The Baltimore trade had been carried over the turnpikes in wagons until the
                        construction of the Baltimore and Susquehanna R. R.; since the opening of
                        that road, it has been sent over the circuitous Railroad route, via
                        Harrisburg, for the simple reason that a long Railroad is better than a
                        short Turnpike.</p>
                    <p>The extension of the Railroad to Gettysburg has opened a direct Railroad
                        connection with the Eastern Cities, which is the shortest route for produce,
                        &amp;c., of Franklin Co., to be shipped to market. The making of the
                        Caledonia Road will give the people of this and other counties, all the
                        advantages of this short route, without the necessity of hauling so far in
                        wagons.</p>
                    <p>From Fayetteville on the Caledonia route, there is a favorable natural route
                        for the location of a Railroad to Waynesboro, which on account of its
                        connection with the County seat, its easy grades and straight lines, may yet
                        prove the cheapest and most practicable route to that wealthy and
                        enterprising section of the valley. With admiration of the spirit of
                        enterprise that has attempted to overcome so formidable a barrier as the
                        mountain on the Gettysburg and Waynesboro' route, it may be stated that the
                        public have no practical assurance of that route being at all favorable, for
                        indeed, the most skilful engineering can do little else than to lay down a
                        series of reversed curves which would be equivalent to a high grade or to
                        perforate the mountain by tunnelling that would burden the company with an
                        enormous debt.</p>
                    <p>But no place is so much interested in the construction of the Caledonia Road,
                        as Chambersburg, and as that hateful stereotyped ideas of having the
                        monopoly of a railroad terminus, has at last been destroyed--the relaying of
                        the Franklin Railroad has punctured that bubble--and the delusive notion
                        that trade <emph rend="italic">must</emph> come to Chambersburg, and by
                        which the public have so long been <emph rend="italic">lulled</emph> into a
                        quiet indifference, has of late been dissipated, by finding the trade
                        passing off to other roads, the people are awakening to their interests;
                        they find that Chambersburg with its present population, and with its
                        manufactories in steel, iron, wood, &amp; c., has as much need now of
                        another railroad as it had years ago, need of more than one stage line. By
                        means of this Caledonia railroad, Chambersburg can regain the trade that for
                        the want of proper facilities is now forced to Hancock on the B. O. R. R.,
                        to Hopewell on the M. B. T. R. R. and to Mt. Union and Perrysville on the
                        Central Pennsylvania Railroad.</p>
                    <p>In conclusion let it be distinctly understood that the present movement is
                        merely a step toward the construction of a railroad that will be
                        advantageous to all parties of this county, and let it be remembered that
                        the Southern Pennsylvania Railroad route of which this Caledonia project is
                        but a link is no new thing--not only had it been traced by nature through
                        the mountain long before Packer's Path was blazed, or its wagon road was
                        Macadamized, but also was it contemplated a feasible railroad route, shortly
                        after the introduction of railroading. The advantages of its construction
                        will be general, so closely united with its success is the commercial
                        interest of many of the Southern counties of Pennsylvania.</p>
                    <p>The prosperity of these counties demands that this railroad be made. All
                        things connected with its past and present history tell us that it will be
                        made. It remains for the people to say how soon. <lb/>J. B. M.
                        <lb/>Fayetteville, Feb. 10, 1860.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that the movement for a new railroad is not to compete with the
                    existing railroad, but to give Chambersburg the resources it deserves as an
                    expanding economic center.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/feb60.html#2.22a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.02.22.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Chambersburg and Gettysburg Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hughes</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Major</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Meeting proposed to add Waynesboro onto possible routes to be connected to
                    the proposed road from Gettysburg to Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Franklin Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt> "Our article of last week relative to the rates of fare fixed for carrying
                    passengers over this road has raised a perfect howl among the "<emph
                        rend="italic">dead-head</emph>" and "<emph rend="italic">toadies</emph>" of
                    the company, and its windy "<emph rend="italic">organ</emph>" contains <emph
                        rend="italic">only</emph> two communications, and about as many editorial
                    notices in reply, with a promise of something more--"very spicy"--this week!
                    Verily the shoe must have <emph rend="italic">pinched</emph> or there would not
                    be so much outcry." </excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Our article of last week relative to the rates of fare fixed for carrying
                        passengers over this road has raised a perfect howl among the "<emph
                            rend="italic">dead-head</emph>" and "<emph rend="italic">toadies</emph>"
                        of the company, and its windy "<emph rend="italic">organ</emph>" contains
                            <emph rend="italic">only</emph> two communications, and about as many
                        editorial notices in reply, with a promise of something more--"very
                        spicy"--this week! Verily the shoe must have <emph rend="italic"
                        >pinched</emph> or there would not be so much outcry. We thank the <emph
                            rend="italic">peculiar</emph> friends of the road for the seal they have
                        manifested in bringing this matter so prominently before the public. We
                        could hardly have expected such a favor--for favor we certainly esteem
                        it--uninfluenced by <emph rend="italic">extraneous</emph> considerations. It
                        is, as every body knows, an awkward business--to say nothing about <emph
                            rend="italic">honesty</emph>--to defend and bolster up a grasping
                        corporation in its attempts to trample upon the rights of a community, in
                        the very teeth of the law, and no sane man will engage in it unless his
                        self-interest is in some way made to get the better of his judgement. We
                        hope in this instance the company and its champions understand each other
                        and that it may never have cause to exclaim "<emph rend="italic">save me
                            from my friends!</emph>"</p>
                    <p>We have never tried our hand at heaping fulsome praise on everybody connected
                        with this road. We did not suppose that gentleman of intelligence would be
                        tickled with that sort of thing, and for their sakes are sorry to see it
                        essayed; it looks suspicious and indicates a lamentable lack of brains in
                        some quarter. The article of Mr. "Forty Cents" is a small attempt in this
                        way but so <emph rend="italic">small</emph> as to be hardly worthy of
                        notice. There is <emph rend="italic">nothing </emph> in it, and if its
                        authors head be as devoid of brains as his production is of argument, there
                        will be little lost to mankind when he "steps out." We desire him to
                        understand that this is said "<emph rend="italic">lovingly</emph>." He
                        thinks our remarks "<emph rend="italic">unkind</emph>." They were not so
                        intended and whatever he may think about them will fail to pervert them to
                        suit <emph rend="italic">his</emph> purpose. He has heard them "<emph
                            rend="italic">condemned</emph>;" we have not, but on the contrary we
                        have heard them generally approved. He thinks them in "<emph rend="italic"
                            >bad taste</emph>," we don't for according to our notion it is never in
                        "bad taste" to condemn a wrong, and we would, at anytime, rather know that
                        we were RIGHT than split hairs about a matter of <emph rend="italic"
                        >taste</emph>. He thinks we should have "<emph rend="italic">waited</emph>,"
                        we think not, as the best time to nip <emph rend="italic">error</emph> is in
                        the "bud." He thinks we do not reflect the "<emph rend="italic"
                        >Spirit</emph>" of the "Valley," we are quite sure we reflect the "Spirit of
                        the Law" and that is enough for our purpose.</p>
                    <p>Having disposed of the "<emph rend="italic">lovingly</emph>" "FORTY CENTS,"
                        for the present only we trust, we will now turn to Mr. "JUSTICE" who sets
                        himself up as legal expounder for the company. We are considerably surprised
                        at the number of blunders he has made in the law and the facts.--We would
                        have supposed that the company would have intrusted its case in abler hands,
                        for a bad cause always requires skilful management. We will charitably
                        believe that his statements are made through ignorance, for we would be
                        loath to suppose that a <emph rend="italic">motive</emph> could be found to
                        induce any one to attempt to deceive the public by such misrepresentations.
                        He says that the 14th Section of the Act, incorporating the Franklin Rail
                        Road, which prohibits the charging of <emph rend="italic">more than three
                            cents per mile</emph> for carrying passengers, "<emph rend="italic"
                            >seems</emph>" to mean that when other persons run the Cars, the Company
                        shall not charge them more than those rates. Such a construction is in
                        direct conflict with the language of the Section, which says, "the said
                        Company may charge and take toll for the transportation of passengers, any
                        sum not exceeding three cents per mile for each passenger." Individuals were
                        to be allowed to put their cars upon the road and carry <emph rend="italic"
                            >freight</emph>, but it was not then contemplated that other parties
                        should transport passengers.</p>
                    <p>The second point made by "Justice" is that the general railroad law of 1849,
                        allows companies to prescribe the rates they will charge for freight and
                        passengers. That is true with certain limitations, to which we will
                        presently refer, but how does that help the matter? By the Act of the 9th of
                        April, 1856, the State resumed all the rights and privileges previously
                        conferred upon this company, and by the Act of the 12th of May, 1857,
                        appointed Commissioners to "sell and convey the rail road aforesaid, with
                        all the rights and privileges belonging to the same, so that the purchaser
                        or purchasers shall have and enjoy all the rights and privileges that said
                        Company had and passed under their Act of Incorporation, or under any
                        supplement there to."</p>
                    <p>The 3d Section of this Act authorized the C. V. R. R. Company, or any other
                        R. R. Co., individual or association of individuals to purchase the road and
                        upon receiving and recording a <emph rend="italic">Deed</emph> for the same,
                        provides that they shall be invested with the rights, powers and privileges
                        heretofore conferred, and <emph rend="italic">be subject to all the
                            liabilities and restrictions</emph> enjoined upon the Franklin R. R.
                        Company, and the Chambersburg, Greencastle and Hagerstown R. R. Company, by
                        their acts of incorporation and the several supplements thereto.</p>
                    <p>Now this means something--and what? Simply to give whoever might buy the road
                        all the rights and privileges, and subject him or them to all the <emph
                            rend="italic">restrictions</emph> connected with it. The Act of Assembly
                        relating to the road had not been repealed by the Act of 1856. The <emph
                            rend="italic">privileges</emph> and <emph rend="italic"
                        >franchises</emph> of the company had merely been <emph rend="italic"
                            >resumed</emph> by the State, and these latter went with the <emph
                            rend="italic">Deed</emph> to the purchasers. The manner of electing
                        officers and continuing the existence of the company is prescribed in the
                        Act of Incorporation passed in 1832, and the supplement passed in 1859, and
                        was not at all effected by the General Railroad Law in 1849. That is
                        entirely different in all its important provisions, and applies solely to
                        companies incorporated after its passage and made subject to it <emph
                            rend="italic">in terms</emph>. It does not apply to this company, and
                        suppose it did, the charges it allows for carrying passengers does not come
                        up to those now charged on this road. It is folly in any one to say that the
                        general railroad law repealed the 14th Section of the Act incorporating this
                        company. It repealed <emph rend="italic">nothing</emph>, for there is no
                        repealing clause in it.</p>
                    <p>"Justice" admits that the present Franklin Railroad Company was organized
                        under the Act of 1859. In that we agree. We also agree that the Company has
                        all the rights and privileges, and is subject to all the <emph rend="italic"
                            >restrictions</emph> imposed upon the old Franklin Railroad Company,
                        except such as were before that time repealed, or are inconsistent with that
                        Act. We have shown that this restriction was <emph rend="italic">not</emph>
                        repealed by the General Railroad Law, when then was it repealed? We would
                        like "Justice" to inform us, for public satisfaction. Neither is it <emph
                            rend="italic">inconsistent</emph> with the provisions of the Act of
                        1859--because nothing is said in that Act, or in <emph rend="italic">any
                            other Act relative to this company</emph>, about the rate to be charged
                        on freight and passengers.</p>
                    <p>We would also like "Justice" to point out what part of the Act of 1859 gives
                        this company the benefits of the law of 1849.</p>
                    <p>The <emph rend="italic">third</emph> position taken by <emph rend="italic"
                            >quasi</emph> "Justice" is simply ridiculous. The provisions of the
                        charter and supplements of the C. V. Railroad <emph rend="italic">are not
                            now</emph>, and never were designed to be extended over the Franklin
                        Road <emph rend="italic">unless that Company became its purchaser</emph>. A
                        correct reading of the 3d and 7th Sections of the Act of 1857 (pamphlet
                        laws, pages 478-9) will show that in "that case" alone was such an extension
                        to take place. The C. V. R. Road Company never did by, and therefore the
                        legislation fell to the ground.</p>
                    <p>But now a word in relation to our position, and we have done. We referred to
                        the matter of <emph rend="italic">over charge</emph>, because it was our
                        right and we thought it our duty. We felt, and feel yet, kindly towards the
                        owners of this road, and have frequently spoken favorably of them and their
                        enterprise through our paper. But because we did not see proper to pass by
                        in silence an act which was evidently <emph rend="italic">illegal</emph> and
                        would work manifest injustice to the traveling public we have fallen under
                        the ban of the powers that <emph rend="italic">would</emph> be. We do not
                        mean the company for they are "all honorable men" but the toadies that hover
                        round them for the sake of a free ride or other small favors. Such
                        considerations will not induce us to alter our course. We have no toadyism
                        to bestow on any man, or set of men, when the public good demands of us, as
                        public journalists, to speak out and guard its rights.--We very well know
                        that it is often better and cheaper to submit to <emph rend="italic"
                        >wrong</emph> than to struggle for <emph rend="italic">right</emph>--and
                        such is the case with the passengers on the Franklin Railroad. The position
                        taken by the company or its agents is wrong and they should voluntarily
                        correct the error.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reply to articles in an unnamed newspaper which countered the Valley
                    Spirit's assertions that the Franklin Railroad was applying its rates unfairly.
                    The editors claim they are writing impartially and for the benefit of their
                    readers.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/feb60.html#2.22b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingert</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Meeting of Democrats of Guilford Township for purpose of choosing delegates
                    for a township ticket for the spring elections.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements, Market information from Chambersburg, Philadelphia, and
                Baltimore.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.02.22.06">
            <pageNote>Poetry and advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.02.22.07">
            <pageNote>Poetry and advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.02.22.08">
            <pageNote>Continuation of Douglas's speech from page one; advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
