<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1860/pa.fr.vs.1860.08.22">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Jeff McClurken</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/22/95</tagDate>
            <tagNote>2nd Pass; Colleen Doody did first pass.</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1860-08-22">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="08">August</month>
            <day>22</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.08.22.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Our First Object</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>States that the first objective of the Democratic Party is to defeat the
                    Republicans and urges that all Democrats come together to achieve that goal.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Gen. Foster</head>
                <origin>The Centre Democrat</origin>
                <commentary>The Centre Democrat is the Republican organ of Centre County. It
                    recently came out in favor of Gen. Foster for governor.</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Centre Democrat states that the Democrats are treating Gen. Foster
                    badly. The paper vows never to speak ill of Foster.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Henry D. Foster</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spirit believes that every Democrat will support Foster for governor
                    despite attempts by John W. Forney to carry the Democratic voters over to Andrew
                    G. Curtin.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Letter from Lewistown</head>
                <origin>Harrisburg Patriot</origin>
                <commentary>Col. Parker, the author of the letter, is a friend of Douglas. However,
                    "it will be seen that he, like tens of thousands of other good Democrats, is
                    willing to be governed by the wise counsel of the State Executive Committee,
                    which alone can produce that union and harmony necessary to keep the State from
                    falling into the hands of the Goths and Vandals."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Parker states that he was not a delegate to the Harrisburg convention and
                    that he continues to support the resolution that was adopted in Philadelphia on
                    "the 2d inst."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Meeting of the State Central Committee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Committee met at Cresson and adopted the following resolution: "That
                    the Democratic Electoral ticket be headed with the name of Douglas or
                    Breckinridge as an Elector at large, and in the event of the success of said
                    ticket, if a greater number shall have been cast for Douglas, then the vote of
                    the Electoral College of the State shall be cast for Douglas and Johnson, but if
                    for Breckinridge, then for Breckinridge and Lane. . . . This resolution was
                    passed with the view of reconciling the difficulties existing in the party, and
                    we believe it will have the desired effect."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Sumner and Lincoln--Republican Principles</head>
                <origin>Chicago Democrat</origin>
                <commentary>The editor of the Democrat, John Wentworth, was "one of the chief actors
                    in securing Lincoln's nomination at Chicago." According to him, "the sentiments
                    of Sumner's late speech in the Senate, are the sentiments of Mr. Lincoln and the
                    Republican party." In a still later article the same paper says that the
                    Republican party is in favor of "the political equality of all men [ital.] Negro
                    citizenship and negro equality is then boldly proclaimed as "the chief
                    cornerstone of Republican organization![ital.]" We invite attention to the
                    following, and commend it to the especial attention of those who prate so much
                    about Mr. Lincoln's conservatism."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Hails Sumner's speech as the best defense of the Republican principles of
                    political equality for all men and the right to life, liberty and the pursuit of
                    happiness for every human being.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>Look</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Pilgrimage of Col. Curtin</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spirit accuses Col. A. G. Curtin, the Republican candidate for
                    governor, of radically changing his position on immigrants. In 1856, Curtin was
                    an "active and zealous propagandist" against the foreign born. As a Republican,
                    he suddenly "finds in our foreign born citizens everything worthy of admiration
                    and nothing to condemn."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Abolitionism Repudiated</head>
                <origin>Jackson (Michigan) Patriot</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Patriot details a Republican meeting in which the speakers stated the
                    Republican view that all blacks in the South should be freed and then granted a
                    farm in the territories. Four Republicans then stood up and said that, if this
                    was the Republican doctrine, they were no longer Republicans.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Disgusting</head>
                <origin>Sigourney Iowa Democrat</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Labels as disgusting a ceremony that took place in a Republican meeting in
                    Iowa. As a symbol of the equality of the races, a black girl and a "beautiful
                    white girl of the same age of the African [sic], were publicly washed out of the
                    same basin, and wiped with the same towel. Can Garrisonian Abolitionism go
                    farther?"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>[none]</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Criticizes the Philadelphia Press, which professes to support Douglas, for
                    reprinting a "miserably weak and contemptibly fallacious" attack on Douglas. The
                    Spirit believes that the Press is "doing more than all the other papers combined
                    to prevent a cordial union of the Democratic party on one electoral ticket."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.08.22.02">
            <pageNote>Fiction, poetry and anecdotes</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.08.22.03">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.08.22.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Democratic County Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reilly</ln>
                        <fn>Wilson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A meeting was held of the Franklin County Democrats to appoint a time to
                    choose delegates to represent the party at the County Nominating Convention.
                    Wilson Reilly, the chairman, gave a short speech in which he called on all the
                    Democrats to come together so that they could defeat the Republicans.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Democratic County Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"These are trying times in the party and it requires our best and most
                    cautious men to guide the helm aright, and the most careful and judicious
                    management to prevent matters from getting worse."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--If conformity with the resolution of the County Meeting the Democrats of
                        the several townships in this county, will meet at the proper place, in
                        their respective districts, for the purpose of electing delegates on</p>
                    <p>SATURDAY, AUGUST 25, 1860.</p>
                    <p>These Delegates so elected will assemble at the Court House, in this place at
                        10 o'clock, A.M., on <lb/>TUESDAY, AUGUST 28, 1860, <lb/>to nominate a
                        County Ticket to be supported by the Democracy of Franklin County at the
                        general election on the second Tuesday (the 8th) of October next.</p>
                    <p>We trust that our Democratic friends throughout the county will turn out and
                        take an interest in the Delegate elections. These are trying times in the
                        party and it requires our best and most cautious men to guide the helm
                        aright, and the most careful and judicious management to prevent matters
                        from getting worse. If the moderate men of the party will attend the
                        Delegate elections and see that proper men are sent as Delegates to the
                        Nominating Convention it will be the first and most important step toward
                        harmony and success in this county. But if our primary elections be
                        neglected, or left to the management of a few men who take but little
                        interest in the success of the party generally, and who seem to care little
                        whether strife or harmony prevails in its ranks, it will have a bad
                        influence and a falling off of party strength must be the consequence. At
                        this time, more than any other, it behooves every Democrat to exert himself
                        to promote unity and harmony in the party if he desires its success. On the
                        subject of the Governor there is but one sentiment among the Democracy of
                        this county--all are enthusiastic for the gallant Foster, and it is our
                        honest conviction that we can nominate a County Ticket that will be
                        triumphantly elected. Would we then sacrifice all because there exists a
                        difference of opinion on the subject of the Presidency? We must agree to
                        tolerate this difference but it should not be mixed up with our State or
                        County affairs. We want union and harmony in our ranks and we cannot have
                        that and keep up the quarrel, at the same time, about our Presidential
                        nominee.</p>
                    <p>In regard to the formation of a County Ticket we do not doubt but the utmost
                        harmony and good-feeling will prevail. There is no scramble for office in
                        our party. The Convention can select the most tried and trusty men from the
                        ranks of the whole party and not be confined in its choice to a column of
                        applications for office in a newspaper. The Democratic party in this county
                        are not hopelessly in a minority. Whenever we have presented the right kind
                        of men to unite and bring out a full party vote, we have succeeded in
                        electing them, and there is no reason why we cannot do so again. The good
                        sense of the Convention, we trust, will keep down all irrelevant issues and
                        introduce no resolutions, or expressions of preferences, that should have a
                        tendency, in any way, to distract or disturb the harmony of the party. In
                        this county there is no necessity for measures of that sort. We must unite
                        in one solid body on our State and County ticket and let President making
                        alone for the present if we do not want to be beaten for everything.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Official report of the Franklin County Democratic Party meeting, which
                    calls upon Democrats to promote "unity and harmony in the party." All the
                    members support Foster for governor and agree to tolerate the different opinions
                    on the subject of the presidential nomination.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/aug60.html#8.22a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Trouble Among Editors</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Details the difficulties Democratic editors are having as a result of the
                    split between the Douglas and Breckenridge wings of the party. One Tennessee
                    paper even supports Douglas on one page and Breckenridge on another because the
                    paper's two editors could not agree on a candidate.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Don't Like It</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>States that the Republicans are very unhappy that the Democrats are
                    harmoniously uniting.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Union on the Electoral Ticket</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>All Pennsylvania Democrats are happy with the Cresson compromise, agreed
                    upon by the State Central Committee, which unites the party on a single
                    electoral ticket.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Organize</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Calls upon Democrats to organize Democratic clubs in every county. The
                    Spirit notes that the split over the presidential nominee has kept many
                    Democrats from forming local clubs.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Henry D. Foster</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that Foster's prospects for election are "getting brighter every
                    day."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>It Won't Work</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>States that "A few men professing to be Democrats" met in Harrisburg and
                    "entered into a conspiracy to effect the destruction of the Democratic party in
                    this State." The Spirit believes that Forney is their leader.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>A Word for Moderation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This letter, from "an old and highly respectable Democratic friend,
                    residing in this county," calls for all Democrats to agree to disagree about the
                    presidential nominee. However, he believes that they must unify in order to
                    elect state and local Democrats. If they don't, the Republicans will win.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.08.22.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Democratic Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Minutes of the Franklin County Democratic meeting held on August 14th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Panorama of Kane's Voyage</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shryock</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A panorama of Dr. Kane's arctic exhibition will be shown on Wednesday
                    evening for the benefit of the public library.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Street Crossing</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Calls on the borough authorities to repair the street crossing on Market
                    Street near the Post Office.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Pennsylvania Statesman</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announcement that the Spirit has received copies of the new campaign paper
                    published in Harrisburg by J. M. Cooper, former editor of the Valley Spirit. The
                    paper supports Breckinridge.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Balloon Ascension</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reminds readers that Mr. Light will make his balloon ascension on Saturday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Congressional Conferees</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that the local Republicans met on August 21 and nominated someone
                    as their Congressional candidate, "but who that unfortunate individual is we are
                    not informed at the time our paper goes to press." The Spirit thinks that
                    McPherson will force himself on the ticket against the wishes of some of the
                    counties.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="j">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Court Proceedings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Helman</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Horn</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf>(colored)</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Morgan</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf>(colored)</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fallon</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imes</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Demis</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf>(colored)</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McFarland</ln>
                        <fn>R. Parker</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schultz</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flory</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flory</ln>
                        <fn>Matilda</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wayman</ln>
                        <fn>Louisa</fn>
                        <sf>(colored)</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swingley</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf>(colored)</sf>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoover</ln>
                        <fn>Christian</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Adams</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sister</ln>
                        <fn>Eli</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dullabaum</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn>Jeremiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lewis</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf>(colored)</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lindsay</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf>(colored)</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vonkerritz</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whiting</ln>
                        <fn>Benoni</fn>
                        <sf>(colored)</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Earhart</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCurdy</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weiser</ln>
                        <fn>Sol</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bamberger</ln>
                        <fn>Christian</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bamberger</ln>
                        <fn>Rueben</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowermaster</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Evans</ln>
                        <fn>Appleton</fn>
                        <sf>(colored)</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whiting</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whiting</ln>
                        <fn>Benoni</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bitner</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Officer</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hellman</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hellman</ln>
                        <fn>Malinda</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowermaster</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fry</ln>
                        <fn>Geo.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Comfort</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McFarlane</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoner</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Forbes</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Torpin</ln>
                        <fn>Sol</fn>
                        <sf>(colored)</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cobleston</ln>
                        <fn>Geo.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dorn</ln>
                        <fn>Geo.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dohn</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McFerron</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lindsay</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLellan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>List of trials for court session that began on the 18th of August:
                    Commonwealth vs. Andrew Helman--Malicious mischief and Assault on the house of
                    John Horn. Commonwealth vs. Frank Myers (black)--Perjury. Commonwealth vs. Henry
                    Morgan (black)--Stealing a pig from Mr. Fallon. Commonwealth vs. Henry Imes and
                    Jacob Demis (black)--Assault and Battery on R. Parker McFarland. Commonwealth
                    vs. John L. Schultz--Assault and Battery on his wife. Commonwealth vs. Wm.
                    Flory--Surety of the Peace on oath of his wife, Matilda Flory. Commonwealth vs.
                    Louisa Wayman (black)--Surety of the Peace on oath of Mrs. Swingley (black).
                    Commonwealth vs. Christian Hoover--Passing a $5 counterfeit bill on Wm. Adams,
                    Esq.. Commonwealth vs. Eli Sister--Larceny, stealing books, clothing and other
                    articles from John Dullabaum. Commonwealth vs. Jeremiah Martin--Fornication.
                    Commonwealth vs. Alexander Lewis (black)--Assault and Battery on oath of Joseph
                    Lindsay (black). Commonwealth vs. Frederick Vonkerritz--Stealing a watch.
                    Commonwealth vs. Benoni Whiting (black)--Assault and Battery. Commonwealth vs.
                    John Earhart--Assault and Battery. Commonwealth vs. James N. McCurdy--Assault
                    and Battery on Sol Weiser. Commonwealth vs. Christian and Rueben
                    Bamberger--Malicious mischief, conspiracy with intent to defraud. Commonwealth
                    vs. John Bowermaster--assault and battery with intent to kill. Commonwealth vs.
                    Appleton Evans (black)--Larceny, stealing meat from Mr. Brumbaugh. Commonwealth
                    vs. David and Benoni Whiting (black)-- resisting Officer Bitner whilst conveying
                    prisoner to jail. Commonwealth vs. Jacob Hellman and Malinda Hellman, his
                    wife--forgery and passing a note which he knew to be forged. Commonwealth vs.
                    John Bowermaster--Surety of the peace on oath of Geo. Fry. Bills Ignored:
                    Commonwealth vs. Jacob Comfort--Assault and battery. Commonwealth vs. Robert P.
                    McFarlane--assault and battery. Commonwealth vs. William Stoner--Assault and
                    battery. Commonwealth vs. Wm. Forbes--Assault and battery. Commonwealth vs. Sol
                    Torpin (black)--Assault and battery. Commonwealth vs. Geo. Cobleston--Assault
                    and battery. Commonwealth vs. Geo. Dorn-- Assault and battery. Commonwealth vs.
                    George Dohn--Assault and battery. Commonwealth vs. Peter McFerron--Assault and
                    battery. Commonwealth vs. Isaac Lindsay--Assault and battery. Court of Common
                    Pleas: David Smith vs. William McLellan and others--A feigned issue to try
                    validity of judgement of No. 202 of August term 1857.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>The Miserable Forney</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Sarcastically criticizes the Press and Forney for shedding tears over the
                    actions of the Democratic State Central Committee at Cresson. The Spirit
                    believes that Forney isn't a true friend of Douglas but actually is a supporter
                    of Lincoln who hopes to be rewarded with a high office in the new Republican
                    administration.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Henry</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Byers</ln>
                        <fn>Reuben</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bricker</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married August 14th at the White Swan Hotel in Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneck</ln>
                        <fn>B.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shelley</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Herman</ln>
                        <fn>Rachel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on August 19th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Creigh</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>DeHaven</ln>
                        <fn>A.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Alexander</ln>
                        <fn>Eliza</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married August 14th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ault</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hopkins</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Emma</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on August 16th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Philips</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shaffner</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Fanny</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on August 15th at the White Swan Hotel.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.08.22.06">
            <pageNote>Advertisements--illegible</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.08.22.07">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.08.22.08">
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>A Speech by Mr. Lincoln</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprint of a speech Lincoln gave at the Republican Demonstration at
                    Springfield on August 8th.</summary>
                <note>Difficult to read</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>[none]</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spirit is critical of John Hickman and his conversion to Republicanism.
                    They believe that he converted after he could no longer receive support from the
                    Democrats and could only remain in Congress by embracing the Republican party.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
