<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1860/pa.fr.vs.1860.07.11">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Jeff McClurken</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/22/95</tagDate>
            <tagNote>2nd Pass; Colleen Doody did first pass.</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1860-07-11">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day>11</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.07.11.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Bitternuts for Conservatives</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that the Republican party opposes the Constitution and supports
                    abolition, as manifested in their positions at their convention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Mass Meeting of the Democracy of Philadelphia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Discussion of an enthusiastic Democratic meeting held in Philadelphia on
                    June 30th to ratify the nominations of Douglas and Johnson. Includes speeches
                    given by Senator Forsyth of Alabama and Senator Herron of Louisiana.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>A Patriotic Letter</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>Douglas's letter, which was read after his nomination at Baltimore,
                    "breathes the true spirit of a patriot."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprint of two letters, one from Douglas to Richardson of Illinois and one
                    from Alexander Stevens of Georgia. Douglas argues that the Union can only be
                    preserved if Congress adheres to the doctrine of non-intervention. Stevens also
                    asserts the importance of non-intervention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.07.11.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Speech of the Hon. A.S. Herron of Louisiana</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprint of a speech given by Senator Herron of Louisiana to the Democratic
                    meeting in Philadelphia in which he criticizes the secessionists and supports
                    Douglas.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.07.11.03">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.07.11.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Who Are to Blame?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that the secessionists had no right or authority to disorganize the
                    party with their nomination.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Douglas's Letter of Acceptance</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprint of Douglas's letter of acceptance of the Democratic nomination, in
                    which he states that the Union must be preserved.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.07.11.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Ball in Motion!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"In response to the call published last week, a large meeting of the
                    Democracy of the borough of Chambersburg was held at the Public House of A. J.
                    Brand, on Saturday evening, July 7th inst., for the organization of a Douglas
                    Johnson club."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>THE BALL IN MOTION!</p>
                    <p>In response to the call published last week, a large meeting of the Democracy
                        of the borough of Chambersburg was held at the Public House of A. J. Brand,
                        on Saturday evening, July 7th inst., for the organization of a Douglas
                        Johnson club.</p>
                    <p>The meeting was called to order by Hon. Wilson Reilly, on whose motion James
                        Nill was chosen President. On motion of Mr. Hamsher, D. W. Rowe, was
                        selected as Secretary. Judge Nill, on taking the chair, addressed the
                        meeting at length on the exigencies of the party, reviewing the action of
                        the Charleston and Baltimore Conventions.</p>
                    <p>William Kennedy, Esq., then presented the following preamble and resolutions,
                        which were unanimously adopted:</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Whereas</emph>, In these troublous times in our national
                        history, it becomes the duty of every good citizen to avow his belief before
                        the world; and whereas, the Democracy of Chambersburg have assembled in in
                        council, to-night, to sustain the time honored doctrines of the party,
                        therefore, be it,</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, that, as the Democratic State Convention
                        which assembled at Reading, and the National Democratic Conventions which
                        met at Charleston and Baltimore, during the present year, reaffirmed the
                        principles for which the party has battled in the past, and to which she is
                        irrevocably committed for the future, it is the duty of every Democratic
                        organization to recognize such platform as the creed of the party, and that
                        every failure to give adhesion to those principles, by individuals or
                        organizations, places those individuals and organizations outside the
                        Democratic Family.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That we heartily endorse the Nominations
                        of Stephen A. Douglas, of Illinois, for the Presidency, and Herschel V.
                        Johnson, of Georgia, for the Vice Presidency; recognizing in them the only
                        regular Democratic Nominees, for those high offices, no before all the
                        people, and pledging to them, one and all of us, a faithful, earnest, and
                        uncompromising support.-- We do so believing that their election, and the
                        triumph of the principles on which they stand, will give peace to the
                        country and permanency to our institutions.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That in the nomination of Henry D.
                        Foster, for Governor, the Democracy have presented to the people of
                        Pennsylvania, one of their most talented, fearless, and incorruptible fellow
                        citizens. One in every way worthy the support of conservative, national men,
                        one whom it will be a duty and a privilege to sustain, and a pleasure to
                        elect.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That we unhesitatingly repudiate the
                        action of a part of the Pennsylvania State Central Committee which met at
                        Philadelphia, on Monday, July 2nd, in offering a pretended compromise on the
                        electoral ticket of this State, believing it to be a cheat and a fraud on
                        the nominees of the party, and the favorites of the masses, a proposition
                        disgraceful to the proposers, and insulting to the regular organization;
                        that we desire no compromise with the enemies of the Democracy, whether they
                        be northern Republicans or southern Disunionists. Believing the ultimate aim
                        of each to be a dissolution of the Union; and that we desire to have a full
                        electoral ticket, pledged unequivocally to the support of the nominees of
                        the party, Stephen A. Douglas and Herschell V. Johnson.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That these resolutions be signed by the
                        officers of the meeting, and published in the Chambersburg <emph
                            rend="italic">Valley Spirit</emph>.</p>
                    <p>After the passage of the resolutions, Hon. Wilson Reilly, on request,
                        addressed the meeting in earnest support of Judge Douglas.</p>
                    <p>On motion, the president appointed D. W. Rowe, H. C. Keyser, and W. Kennedy,
                        Esq's, a committee to prepare a constitution for the government of the club.</p>
                    <p>On motion of Mr. Keyser, the president was requested to write out his
                        address* of this evening for publication in the <emph rend="italic">Valley
                            Spirit</emph>.</p>
                    <p>Mr. B. F. Nead moved that when the meeting adjourn, it adjourn to meet at the
                        Public House of John Reilly, on Friday evening next, which was carried.</p>
                    <p>The meeting then adjourned.</p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Attest</cell>
                            <cell>JAMES NILL</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>D. W. ROWE,</cell>
                            <cell>President.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Secretary.</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <p>*Judge Nill has complied with this request; his very able speech will appear
                        in our next number.--EDS. VAL. SPIRIT.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reilly</ln>
                        <fn>Wilson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nill</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamsher</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rowe</ln>
                        <fn>D.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Esq.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keyser</ln>
                        <fn>H.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Report of the meeting on July 7th of the Democratic party of Chambersburg,
                    during which a Douglas-Johnson club was organized.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/july60.html#7.11a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Fourth</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dobler</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieutenant</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chambers</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Discussion of the celebration of the Fourth of July in Chambersburg,
                    including a parade and target exercise by the local volunteer militia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Rosedale Female Seminary</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reeves</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>Mattie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tolbert</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Discussion of graduation at the Rosedale Female Seminary.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Trip to Cowan's Gap</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kuhn</ln>
                        <fn>Emanuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>J.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reilly</ln>
                        <fn>Wilson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGrath</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rinkin</ln>
                        <fn>A.N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDowell</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seibert</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cowan</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Haxtet</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Eight residents of Chambersburg took a trip on June 23rd to view the route
                    for the proposed railroad from Chambersburg to Cowan's Gap. They pronounced the
                    route excellent.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Extensive Fire</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"A widow lady, Mrs. Rosenburg, occupied the upper portion of one of Mr.
                    Ott's houses, and had the stove placed in the attic story for the purpose of
                    cooking through the summer; in this stove she had kindled a fire and left it and
                    went down stairs, and in fifteen minutes after, the whole upper part of the
                    house was in flames."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--On Tuesday afternoon, (yesterday, after part of our paper had already been
                        printed.) a fire broke out in the residence of Mr. Samuel Ott, near the
                        corner of Maine and Washington streets, and was not arrested until it had
                        consumed four buildings in that neighborhood. The fire originated from a
                        stove on the attic of Mr. Ott's house.--A widow lady, Mrs. Rosenburg,
                        occupied the upper portion of one of Mr. Ott's houses, and had the stove
                        placed in the attic story for the purpose of cooking through the summer; in
                        this stove she had kindled a fire and left it and went down stairs, and in
                        fifteen minutes after, the whole upper part of the house was in flames.</p>
                    <p>The fire spread rapidly over the two buildings owned by Mr. Ott, which were
                        totally consumed, and to the residence and confectionary establishment of
                        Mr. Joseph Deckelmayer, and the property of Mr. John Dittman adjoining. The
                        upper portion and back building of Mr. Deckelmayer's house was burnt out and
                        the lower story &amp; other room so much damaged by fire and water as to
                        require to be re-built. The roof was destroyed on the building owned by Mr.
                        Dittman and the house otherwise very much damaged. By the noble exrrtions of
                        our firemen and citizens the flames were arrested at this point, when every
                        one at the scene of conflagration predicted the destruction of the whole
                        square of buildings.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ott</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rosenburg</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deckelmayer</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dittman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A fire destroyed the home of Samuel Ott on July 10. It originated in a
                    stove in the attic, which was used for cooking during the summer.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/july60.html#7.11b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>The Opposition in Motion</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Our Democratic friends throughout the county should at once call meetings
                    in every township for the formation of Douglas Clubs."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--Some of the opposition met at Fayetteville on last Saturday evening, made a
                        temporary organization of a Lincoln Club by appointed J. B. McElroy, pres.,
                        and W. E. Cramp, Sec.--The president appointed F. Crawford, A. J. Stevens
                        and W. E. Cramp a committee to report officers for a permanent organization,
                        also a committee. John McLain, Esq., Dr. H. K. Byers, H. C. Greenawalt, John
                        E. Crawford and John G. Bigham to draft Resolutions and By-laws for use of
                        the Club. Adjourned to meet at the public house of John Brown at 8 o'clock,
                        P. M. on the 22d inst. We notice these proceedings for the purpose of
                        prompting our Democratic friends of Fayetteville to action in forming a
                        Douglas Club. There is abundant material there to form a strong Club, and we
                        have no doubt they will proceed at once with the work. Our Democratic
                        friends throughout the county should at once call meetings in every township
                        for the formation of Douglas Clubs.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stevens</ln>
                        <fn>A.J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Byers</ln>
                        <fn>H.K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greenawalt</ln>
                        <fn>H.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bigham</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McElroy</ln>
                        <fn>J.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cramp</ln>
                        <fn>W.E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLain</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Republicans of Chambersburg gathered together to form a Lincoln Club on
                    July 7.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/july60.html#7.11c</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Caledonia Springs</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cooper</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hutchinson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The unnamed writer celebrated the fourth of July at Caledonia Springs.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Barn Burnt</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Neely</ln>
                        <fn>B.F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Esq.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The barn of B.F. Neely was destroyed by fire.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Ladies' Mount Vernon Association</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>List of money given in contributions in Franklin County to the Ladies'
                    Mount Vernon Association in June 1860.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Sabbath School Celebration</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cree</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Esq.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilmore</ln>
                        <fn>Jas.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lull</ln>
                        <fn>O.N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Esq.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Discussion of meeting of the Presbyterian Sabbath School of Chambersburg.
                    Included is a resolution that was adopted at the meeting in which they thank the
                    members of the Presbyterian Sabbath School of Hagerstown for an outing where
                    "North and South met together in fraternal spirit around one alter."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary Stuart died on June 25th at 72 years of age.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDowell</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDowell</ln>
                        <fn>W.E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary McDowell died on July 4th at 79 years of age.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hicks</ln>
                        <fn>Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jane Hicks died at Annapolis.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.07.11.06">
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>White Men Must Rule America: Now is the Time to Subscribe: The Weekly Day-Book
                    for 1860</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Ad for the New York Day-Book, which combats the "modern heresies of
                    Abolitionism."</summary>
                <note>The bottom of this ad is illegible.</note>
                <look>Look</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.07.11.07">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.07.11.08">
            <pageNote>Legal notices are illegible.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
