<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1860/pa.fr.vs.1860.05.02">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Jeff McClurken</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/22/95</tagDate>
            <tagNote>2nd Pass; Andy Morris did first pass.</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1860-05-02">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day norm="02">2</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.05.02.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>By Telegraph!! From Charleston</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Report from the Democratic National Convention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Travelogue</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.05.02.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>By Telegraph!! For the Valley Spirit from Charleston</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Continuation of the report from the Democratic National Convention. Report
                    ends mid-convention, after a fractious debate, on a note of optimism for
                    Douglas's nomination.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Moral stories</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.05.02.03">
            <pageNote>Poetry, aphorisms, advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.05.02.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Abolition of Slavery</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"There are about five million slaves in the country, three millions of whom
                    are taken into the account in apportioning political power among the States. Set
                    them free and the two millions who are now excluded will have to be counted. At
                    the present ratio of representation, this would give twenty more members of
                    Congress to the Southern States! Do the abolitionists wish to endow the Southern
                    States with more political power than they already possess?"</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The abolitionists object to slavery as an element of political power. They
                        complain that the whites of the South vote for their negroes--that
                        three-fifths of all the negroes are taken into the account in adjusting the
                        ratio of Congressional representation. This, they say, gives the South more
                        political power than she is justly entitled to.</p>
                    <p>We reply that the Constitution of the United States provides for the
                        enumeration of three-fifths of all the Southern slaves, and that to attack
                        this arrangement is to attack the work of the founders of our Republic. But
                        how much better off would the North be if slavery were abolished? If the
                        Southern negroes were set free, not merely three-fifths, but all of them.
                        would be counted, as all negroes are now counted at the North.</p>
                    <p>There are about five million slaves in the country, three millions of whom
                        are taken into the account in apportioning political power among the States.
                        Set them free and the two millions who are now excluded will have to be
                        counted. At the present ratio of representation, this would give twenty more
                        members of Congress to the Southern States! Do the abolitionists wish to
                        endow the Southern States with more political power than they already
                        possess?</p>
                    <p>The rooting out of slavery would not promote Northern interests. It would
                        directly conflict with the interests of Pennsylvania, if there is any truth
                        in the claim that the interests of this State require an increased
                        tariff--for the South is opposed to an increase of the tariff, and if
                        slavery should be abolished and twenty more Representatives be added to the
                        Southern strength in Congress, anybody of sense can see that there would be
                        just so many more votes against an increase of tariff.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that freeing slaves would actually hurt the North.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/may60.html#5.2b</note>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The National Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The fears we expressed in our last issue, that it would be difficult to
                    harmonise the conflicting sentiments of extreme quarters of the country, have
                    been realized. There is no disguising the fact that there is considerable danger
                    of a disagreement that will end in the withdrawal of a portion of the
                    Convention."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>At the time we write, several days prior to the date of our paper, it is
                        impossible to say what will be done by the Democratic National Convention.
                        Nearly a week has been spent in organizing the Convention, settling
                        contested seats and endeavoring to frame a platform. The fears we expressed
                        in our last issue, that it would be difficult to harmonise the conflicting
                        sentiments of extreme quarters of the country, have been realized. There is
                        no disguising the fact that there is considerable danger of a disagreement
                        that will end in the withdrawal of a portion of the Convention. This
                        deplorable result ought to be avoided, and we do not despair of being able
                        to announce that it has been avoided.</p>
                    <p>If the policy of the administration upon the Lecompton question had been
                        acquiesced in by all the leading men of our party, there would have been no
                        contention in the National Convention about a platform. That policy would
                        not have made a permanent addition of one foot of slave territory to the
                        Union, but it would have prevented the demand made upon us by the extreme
                        South for a Congressional slave code. Out of the opposition to it have grown
                        all the difficulties that lie in the way of harmonious action at
                    Charleston.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Acknowledges that the Valley Spirit's fears of disunity at the Convention
                    were realized, and that the outcome can not be predicted at this juncture.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/may60.html#5.2a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>For the Valley Spirit</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Truth</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Rebukes Republicans for playing on people's passions, and of libelling the
                    President through the Covode investigation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Cincinnati National Platform</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprint of resolutions from 1856 Democratic National Convention in
                    Cincinnati, which upholds popular sovereignty on which the Douglas supporters
                    were campaigning in the 1860 Convention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.05.02.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Borough Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes upcoming local election and urges Democrats to assemble candidates
                    for local school board to purge the current board of big-spending politicians.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>School Superintendent</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Election for Superintendent for County Schools is coming up. The Spirit
                    urges the School Directors who will elect him to choose a man in the mold of the
                    present Superintendent, who they credit with progress in the county's schools.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Chambers Artillery</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Colonel</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Housum</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieutenant</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Col. Stumbaugh has resigned as captain of the Chambers Artillery, and
                    Lieutenant Housum's name has been placed in nomination for the position.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Pennsylvania Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes with approval the schedule and reputation of the Pennsylvania
                    Railroad.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Extras</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilmore</ln>
                        <fn>Blair</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Valley Spirit has been printing extras during the week to keep people
                    abreast of the events at the Democratic National Convention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Census</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The census is due to be taken soon, and the Valley Spirit urges the federal
                    marshal to appoint deputies "as will give entire satisfaction to the people of
                    the county."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Appointment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armstrong</ln>
                        <fn>A.F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A.F. Armstrong was appointed to a position in the Department of the
                    Surveyor General.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Census of 1860</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Humorous spoof of list of census question.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carothers</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fitzgerald</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Witherspoon</ln>
                        <fn>M. Lucy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. Fitzgerald and Lucy Witherspoon were married on April 26th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Washabaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Harriet</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Died on April 24th at age 50.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sellers</ln>
                        <fn>Leonard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Bridget</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Bridget Brown died on April 24th at 70 years of age.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Includes advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.05.02.06">
            <pageNote>Poetry and advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.05.02.07">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.05.02.08">
            <pageNote>Market information from Chambersburg, Baltimore, and Philadelphia; legal
                notices; miscellaneous national news items.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
