<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1860/pa.fr.vs.1860.11.07">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Jeff McClurken</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/22/95</tagDate>
            <tagNote>2nd Pass; Colleen Doody did first pass.</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1860-11-07">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="11">November</month>
            <day norm="07">7</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.11.07.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Battle--A Ballad by Caxten</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A poem in honor of the election of Breckinridge and Lane.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Glorious News from the South</head>
                <origin>St. Louis Bulletin</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Alexander H. Stephens of Georgia decided to abandon his support for Douglas
                    because he believed that Douglas couldn't win any state in the Union. Rather
                    than allow Lincoln to emerge victorious, Stephens decided that he had to support
                    Breckinridge.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Look Out!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges Democrats to make sure that their ballots are correctly filled out
                    and every name spelled correctly.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>What Will They Do?</head>
                <origin>Philadelphia Argus</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Believes that the "honest portion of Douglas men" will support the Reading
                    ticket in the November election.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Which Will be Best</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Reader, of whatever political faith you are which will be the best? That
                    the country shall remain whole and united as it is, the South being the
                    receptacle and market for the manufactories and workshops of the
                    North--furnishing the raw material and affording labor to toiling millions of
                    the North, and buying the goods again in return, thus causing general prosperity
                    all around,, or that it be disrupted, and the intercourse of the two sections of
                    the country severed, the South opening her own ports and receiving her supplies
                    of manufactured articles from foreign countries, and leaving the work-shops and
                    manufactories of the North desolate and without market. Which will be the best?"</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Reader, of whatever political faith you are which will be the best? That the
                        country shall remain whole and united as it is, the South being the
                        receptacle and market for the manufactories and workshops of the
                        North--furnishing the raw material and affording labor to toiling millions
                        of the North, and buying the goods again in return, thus causing general
                        prosperity all around,, or that it be disrupted, and the intercourse of the
                        two sections of the country severed, the South opening her own ports and
                        receiving her supplies of manufactured articles from foreign countries, and
                        leaving the work-shops and manufactories of the North desolate and without
                        market. Which will be the best? This is a matter for every voter to
                        consider. As the country now exists, the South is the market for
                        manufactories and workshops of the North. North cotton mills get their
                        cotton from the South, thousands of hands are employed in them, and receive
                        their pay for their work, and then the cotton goods are again sold to the
                        South. Other manufactories sell their articles of manufacture South. The
                        little town of Lynn, in Massachusetts, alone sells several millions of pairs
                        of shoes and usually South. The iron works and rolling mills of the North
                        find their best markets South. The cities of New York and Philadelphia, and
                        other northern cities, depend almost entirely upon their commerce with the
                        Southern States, and their teeming millions thus have prosperity.--Which
                        then will be the best? Will you elect Lincoln, the candidate of the
                        "irrepressible" Republican party, who will not receive a single elector 1
                        vote in any southern States and whose election incurs the risk of disturbing
                        the harmony of the several States as they now exist, or will you say it is
                        best to "let well enough alone," and contribute all in your power to his
                        defeat. It is for you, consulting your own interests and the interests of
                        the country to say, which will be best?</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Asks readers to contemplate the best course for the nation: a united
                    country in which the South provides raw materials and markets for Northern
                    manufactured goods or a disunited country in which the South receives her
                    supplies from overseas and the North's prosperity declines as a result.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>"We Will Make Her Submit"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Senator Wilson, a friend of Lincoln, stated that the Republicans will make
                    the South submit if it refuses to on its own. The Spirit doesn't believe the
                    South will ever submit to black enfranchisement or equality. The North would
                    then have to invade the South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>[none]</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Warns "Friends of the Reading Electoral Ticket" to keep an eye on the
                    Forney-Douglas faction because they will vote for Lincoln.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>It is not So?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that the "Massachusetts school" cannot tolerate slavery and thus
                    wants to abolish it, even if that means severing the Union. The Republicans are
                    abolitionists, despite what they say.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>The Negro Government of the Black Republicans--Ohio Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Their votes carried the election. Ohio is thus ruled, not by white men,
                    but by negroes, and that, too under a Constitution that excludes negroes from
                    suffrage."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Republicans rejoice in the fact that 14,000 free blacks voted in Ohio.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Nullifying States</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Republicans complain that Southerners want to nullify the Union. In
                    fact, Northern states are the true nullifiers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>[none]</head>
                <origin>Houston, Texas Telegraph</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A free black woman and her family of six children voluntarily enslaved
                    themselves.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Extract from Jackson's Farewell Address</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprint of extract of Jackson's speech, in which he urges the citizens of
                    every state to "avoid everything calculated to wound the sensibility or offend
                    the just pride of the people of other States." The Union depends on maintaining
                    the affections of the people; it cannot be preserved "by the mere exertion of
                    the coercive powers confided to the General Government."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Another Abolition Ruse</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that the denunciations of Lincoln made by the radical abolitionists
                    are a ruse to make people think that Lincoln is not really an abolitionist.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Letter from Mr. Breckinridge</head>
                <origin>Marion (Ala.) Commonwealth</origin>
                <commentary>The letter is a "correction of certain statements respecting his [i.e.
                    Breckinridge's] recent trip in the mountain regions of Kentucky."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Breckinridge states that he hasn't been making stump speeches in Kentucky,
                    as some have claimed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>"It is Your Bull that has Gored My Ox"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Claims that Northerners believe that it's fine to hang horse thieves
                    without due process, but it is an outrage for Southern men to hang slave
                    thieves, or men who seize slaves in order to free them. The Spirit believes that
                    this is a "strange inconsistency."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Lincoln Good Enough for Ultra Abolitionists</head>
                <origin>New Haven Reg.</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Some of the radical abolitionists are getting scared and are throwing their
                    support behind Lincoln.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.11.07.02">
            <div type="l">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Letter from E. G. Evans, of Chester County</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprint of Evans' letter about Douglas and the unit rule.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Judas Iscariot Totally Eclipsed</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Compares Forney to Judas and Benedict Arnold. Forney's treachery led to the
                    defeat of the Democratic ticket in October, but he won't necessarily be
                    successful in November.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Address of the Democratic State Executive Committee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>W. H. Welsh, Chairman of Committee, states that the party is "united in the
                    support of the regularly nominated electoral ticket." He urges all Democrats to
                    vote in November.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Where they Go</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that straight-out Douglasism is a short cut to Lincolnism.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.11.07.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Prospects in New York</head>
                <origin>Albany Argus</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Predictions of presidential vote in New York based on voting patterns in
                    previous elections.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.11.07.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Where We Stand</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that Breckinridge and Lane have never advocated disunion. "Vote for
                    them and the Union is safe."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Clergymen</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Criticizes a Methodist clergyman named T. M. Eddy, who wrote to the
                    President to complain about the treatment of Methodists in the South. He also
                    sent his letter to a newspaper, leading the Spirit to believe that he was really
                    after publicity. They have little sympathy for him, since the Methodists get
                    into trouble when they give "advice to slaves to cut the throats of their
                    masters."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Who are Disunionists</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that Douglas is the true disunionist since many of his prominent
                    friends, including Herschel Johnson, have openly advocated secession.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>"No Use to Try"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges Democrats to not lose hope--just because they were defeated in the
                    October election doesn't mean that the same will happen in the presidential.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Friends of Breckinridge</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges Breckinridge men not to scratch off the names of any of the electors
                    on the Democratic ballot, even though some of them are Douglas supporters. All
                    the electors are Democrats, and so all will vote to defeat Lincoln in the
                    electoral college.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Douglas' Conspiracy with the Black Republicans</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges straight-out Douglas supporters to analyze Douglas's position on
                    popular sovereignty. He will find that there is little difference between
                    Douglas and the Republicans. "We would ask Democrats to pause and reflect before
                    they are made the dupes of such a treacherous leader as Stephen A. Douglas."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>An Example for Democrats</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Encourages Democrats to follow the example of the gallant Gen. Lane in the
                    battle of Buena Vista and "Stand the fire and fall like men." If they do, the
                    Democrats will win.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Spurious Electorial Tickets!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Because the straight-out ticket has been withdrawn, some former
                    straight-out supporters have drawn up and distributed an electoral ticket of
                    their own. The Spirit published this spurious ticket to warn Democrats not to
                    vote for it.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>The Grammar Critic</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Spirit makes fun of the "college-bred youth" who edits the Times
                    because he loves to quote Latin, cite Shakespeare, and correct the Spirit's
                    grammar.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.11.07.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Effects</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spirit prints a table of stock prices before and after the Pennsylvania
                    election. The fall in price indicates to the Spirit that Lincoln's election will
                    lead to a severe drop in stocks.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Negroes Contributing to the Pennsylvania Election Fund</head>
                <origin>N.Y. Herald</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"It must have been funny to see Forney and all the little Forneys
                    soliciting money from the niggers for the Republican cause."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Black Philadelphians contributed $15,000 to the Republican party.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>No Chance for Judge Douglas</head>
                <origin>Pennsylvanian</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The press states that Douglas knows that he can't win. The Pennsylvanian
                    believes that, in that case, Douglas must be staying in the race in order to
                    help elect Lincoln.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Pay Up</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"The past year having been one of extraordinary prosperity to the farmers,
                    they can well afford to make a display of their small change and pay the
                    printer."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Court Proceedings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gates</ln>
                        <fn>Jeremiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sprinkle</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wise</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davasher</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Diehl</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mahon</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jameson</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Freet</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wade</ln>
                        <fn>Nancy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Corbet</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lindsay</ln>
                        <fn>Brant</fn>
                        <sf>(colored)</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pence</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koonse</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Denig</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Denig</ln>
                        <fn>Louis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>A. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>Hiram</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brand</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kuhn</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnsord</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Cases tried at October Terms of Court: Commonwealth vs. Jeremiah
                    Gates--vulgar and insulting language. Commonwealth vs. David Sprinkle--Assault
                    and Battery on Charles Fisher. Commonwealth vs. Isaac Wise--Assault and Battery.
                    Commonwealth vs. Joseph Davasher--Assault. Commonwealth vs. Lewis
                    Diehl--Assault. Commonwealth vs. Samuel Mahon--Larceny. Commonwealth vs. Daniel
                    Jameson--Larceny, Stealing sheep from C. Freet. Commonwealth vs. Nancy
                    Wade--Assault and Battery on Susan Corbet. Commonwealth vs. Susan
                    Corbet--Assault and Battery on Nancy Wade. Commonwealth vs. Brant Lindsay
                    (colored)--Keeping a tippling house, selling liquor. Commonwealth vs. Mary
                    Pence--Surety of the peace on oath of Abraham Koonse. Common pleas: Sarah Denig,
                    executrix of Louis Denig, vs. A. K. McClure. Hiram M. White vs. Samuel Myers,
                    Jacob Brand and others. Hagerstown Savings Bank vs. Loudon Saving Fund--An
                    action brought to recover $5,000. Isaac Kuhn vs. Jacob Barnsord--An action in
                    ejectment to recover possession of a tract of land. Samuel Myers and Jacob Brand
                    vs. H. M. White--An action in trespass.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rebok</ln>
                        <fn>H. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newcomer</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hollar</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on October 25th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Colestock</ln>
                        <fn>Z. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brubaker</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Showman</ln>
                        <fn>C. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on November 1.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bradley</ln>
                        <fn>Jos.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Colestock</ln>
                        <fn>Z.A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rhoads</ln>
                        <fn>E. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on November 1.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Steck</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyd</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn>Ellen</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on November 1 in the English Lutheran Church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKee</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Died on October 26th, aged 24 years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pieffer</ln>
                        <fn>Philip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Died on October 25th, aged 49 years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.11.07.06">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.11.07.07">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.11.07.08">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Go to the Polls</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Although the Republican gubernatorial candidate received 32,000 more votes
                    than the Democratic candidate, the Democrats shouldn't be discouraged. If all
                    the Democrats vote on Tuesday, Lincoln can still be defeated.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
