<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1860/pa.fr.vs.1860.01.25">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Jeff McClurken</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/22/95</tagDate>
            <tagNote>2nd Pass; Andy Morris did first pass.</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1860-01-25">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day>25</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.01.25.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Save the Union</head>
                <origin>Catholic Mirror</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Holds out the border states of Maryland, Virginia, and Pennsylvania as
                    leaders by necessity of union spirit, and decries radicals on both sides.
                    Article is sympathetic to the South. It argues that slavery is an inherited evil
                    which will die out eventually, but violence by the North against slavery would
                    only bring greater tyranny.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>The Harper's Ferry Investigation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Note announcing subpoenas issued by Senate Investigating Committee.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.01.25.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Praise Your Wives</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Morality story, advising husbands not to neglect complimenting their wives.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>A Mother's Courage</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Story about a mother who, while husband was away on business, defended her
                    baby from a bear.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.01.25.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>My Father's Second Marriage</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Story of how a daughter came to accept her father's second wife, after her
                    mother died.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Poetry and advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.01.25.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Opposition are Responsible</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Hatchet-faced Yankees who prefer the odor of cod-fish and niggers to that
                    of ottar of roses, and Southern Hotspurs whose jaundiced eyes behold an enemy of
                    the South in every Northern citizen, sit side by side in the galleries and gloat
                    over the fratricidal strife going on below."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Blames failure to elect a Speaker of the House on the Republicans and
                    predicts that they will let the election languish. This would prevent the
                    funding of postal operations.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Rev. R.J. Breckinridge</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on letter Rev. Breckinridge wrote to his nephew, Vice-President
                    Breckinridge, hinting at opposition by force if the Republicans take power.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>A Railroad from Gettysburg to Chambersburg</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A Meeting at Fayetteville.</p>
                    <p>The friends of this project met in the Union School House at Fayetteville, on
                        Saturday Evening, the 21st, to consider the expediency of making a survey
                        between these points. The meeting was organized, and it was announced by the
                        president, that the speaker, Rev. W. D. C. Rodrock, who had promised to
                        address the meeting, was unavoidably absent on business.</p>
                    <p>The Secretary then addressed the meeting detailing a few facts connected with
                        the history of Penna. Railroad, beginning with the surveys made by the State
                        in 1838, particularly the Southern Route, the one of most interest to the
                        people of this Valley. When this line was run, railroads had not the recent
                        improvements--iron rails, powerful locomotives, long trains, &amp;c.,
                        were then unknown, therefore, the report of this survey, does not now meet
                        the requirements of a good road. There is, however, one thing by it made
                        certain, that there is an easy railroad passage through the Cove Mountain,
                        Via. Cowens Gap, between Loudon and Burnt Cabbins. About ten years ago when
                        the western trade deserted its natural course to be carried by the Central
                        R. R., leaving the Turnpike road to melancholy quietness, the people then,
                        and since, realized the evil consequences of their supineness.--Several
                        attempts have since been made to construct this Line. In 1853 legislative
                        authorities under the name of the Chambersburg and Allegheny Co. was
                        obtaind, commissioners appointed, and meetings held along the line, but from
                        some cause these measures failed. The Pittsburg and Connelsville R. R. Co.
                        have nearly completed their road Eastward from Pittsburg to Bridgeport--some
                        20 miles west of Bedford. The Shermans Valley &amp; Broad Top and other
                        Co's. were chartered by act of 1854 and supplements since to construct a
                        road from Bridgeport, Via. Burnt Cabins to the Central R. R. The original
                        route from Burnt Cabins to the eastern cities Via. Chambersburg is shorter,
                        has easier grades, and a less number of miles to construct than any other
                        projected route.</p>
                    <p>After the Secretary concluded his remarks it was resolved that the following
                        committee be appointed to take subscriptions, for the purpose of having a
                        survey made as soon as practicable. Messrs. David Goodyear, A. J. Stevens,
                        Robert A. Renfrew, Robert Black, Jacob B. Cook, George Dull, Phares
                        Duffield, Robert F. McElroy, John Crawford of J., John Brown, H. C.
                        Greenawalt, John Baughman, William Rupert, Sam'l Dysart, John Downey,
                        Matthew McKee, and Jacob Strickler. Messrs. John Baughman and Robert A.
                        Renfrew will act as treasurers and will attend to having the survey made.</p>
                    <p>The people along the contemplated line of the road are cordially invited to
                        co- operate in the measure. On motion the meeting adjourned to meet at the
                        same place on Friday evening, Feb. 3d.</p>
                    <p>JOHN DOWNEY, President. <lb/>J. B. McELROY, Secretary. <lb/>Fayetteville,
                        Jan. 21, 1860.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A meeting in Fayetteville was held to propose a railroad survey between the
                    two points.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Also a reprint of Senate debate defending Northern Democrats against charges
                of abolitionism.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.01.25.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Railroad Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Applauds the meeting held in Fayetteville that proposed a survey for a
                    railroad line between Chambersburg and Fayetteville that would connect to the
                    Gettysburg railroad. This would shorten the travel time and lessen the rates to
                    both Baltimore and Philadelphia. Urges local citizens to hold a meeting in
                    Chambersburg to second the Fayetteville proposal.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Court Proceedings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kelly</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowles</ln>
                        <fn>Hiram</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCauley</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bralton</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Break</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kysler</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>French</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewer</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Collins</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reilly</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharp</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kelly</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Churchman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bonebrake</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Folts</ln>
                        <fn>Christ</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reasner</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rosenthal</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carlisle</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snively</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLelland</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bricker</ln>
                        <fn>Francis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf>Col'd</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Slater</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf>Col'd</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Welsh</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duneau</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lenherr</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Everett</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strickler</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hornbreaker</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Metcalf</ln>
                        <fn>Christ</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shearer</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Neff</ln>
                        <fn>Solomon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shearer</ln>
                        <fn>Walker</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>O'Brien</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seibert</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Early</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Early</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snider</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolff</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reinhold</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hostetler</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newman</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Winters</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kurts</ln>
                        <fn>Luther</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McComsey</ln>
                        <fn>Jesse</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tolhelm</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mishler</ln>
                        <fn>Abel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mishler</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoner</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Divilblis</ln>
                        <fn>Fred</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rice</ln>
                        <fn>P.A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolff</ln>
                        <fn>G.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ritter</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnes</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Arts</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>West</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christ</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snider</ln>
                        <fn>Eliz</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snider</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kohn</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barncord</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barncord</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Disposition of cases in criminal court and court of common pleas.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bitner</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McHenry</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stamey</ln>
                        <fn>Fanny</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married January 19.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duncan</ln>
                        <fn>Florence</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duncan</ln>
                        <fn>Augustus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Died January 14, at age 25.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements also on page.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.01.25.06">
            <pageNote>Poetry and advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.01.25.07">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Indian Maiden</head>
                <origin>Banner</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Morality tale of a Cherokee girl who turned her back on her "savage" and
                    "pagan" background and converted to Christianity.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.01.25.08">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>A Few Facts for the Merchants and Manufacturers of the North</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Predicts that the economic consequences of anti-Southern sentiment in the
                    North are already being observed, and that things will get worse if abolition
                    sentiment continues to be acceptable in the North.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>Marriage among the Druses</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Discusses marriage customs among the Druse.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Market information from Chambersburg and Baltimore; advertisements, including
                bank statements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
