<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1860/pa.fr.vs.1860.01.11">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Jeff McClurken</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/22/95</tagDate>
            <tagNote>2nd Pass; Andy Morris did first pass.</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1860-01-11">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day>11</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.01.11.01">
            <pageNote>Transcript of Governor's yearly address to the Pennsylvania legislature; jumps
                to page 8. Illegible on bottom of page.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.01.11.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Husbands</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"No doubt there are more genuine love matches in the United States, than
                    anywhere else in the world. As we grow older and more artificial, we may
                    domesticate the European fashion, as we have done with other follies, and select
                    our wives as we do our horses and dogs, on account of their breed--or our books,
                    on account of their binding--or our stock, on account of their certain revenue."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Perhaps one-half of the marriages that are solemnized in European Christendom
                        are regarded by the parties most interested as nothing more than mere civil
                        contracts. There are certain obligations assumed on both sides--certain
                        promises made in the presence of witnesses; but the true scope and meaning
                        of these are no more thought of than the solemn appeal in the oath of the
                        infidel, drawn upon the Holy Evangely. It is a sort of form required by law,
                        to give full force to the contract which has nothing in it that refers in
                        the slightest degree to the sanction itself. It is true that a man engages
                        to defend, protect, support and cherish the woman to whom he gives his name.
                        It is true that the woman engages to love, honor and obey her husband; but
                        these obligations are like the imaginary dollar in the law paper, "the
                        receipts where of is hereby acknowledged." A legal fiction, meaning nothing;
                        but necessary, because the form is established; the seal affixed to a deed,
                        which is merely the word "seal," surrounded by a fancy border, and bearing
                        not the slightest resemblance to the thing it signifies.</p>
                    <p>In our country, however, such marriages are still exceptions to the rule. No
                        doubt there are more genuine love matches in the United States, than
                        anywhere else in the world. As we grow older and more artificial, we may
                        domesticate the European fashion, as we have done with other follies, and
                        select our wives as we do our horses and dogs, on account of their breed--or
                        our books, on account of their binding--or our stock, on account of their
                        certain revenue.</p>
                    <p>It is a little curious to notice the difference between our practical
                        arrangements for happiness in the wedded life, and the imaginary bliss of
                        novel heroes and heroines. We lay down the novel that ends with the union of
                        the lovers who had sighed and suffered and loved through its pages, and we
                        conclude that the remainder of their lives will be spent in each other's
                        company. Being men, we scorn to grow spooney over the harrowing accounts of
                        the frequent separations--the numberless obstacles in the way of two
                        passionate hearts that beat in unions all the time; but we are conscious of
                        the liveliest satisfaction when the barriers are removed and the <emph
                            rend="italic">denouncement</emph> brings happiness--the more ecstatic
                        because the longer delayed. All this is well enough for the writers of
                        fiction, but the sober realieties of life are far different. While men do
                        not grow tired of their wives or weary of their society, they do sometimes
                        acquire a fondness for <emph rend="italic">other</emph>society. It is to be
                        supposed that in married lovers at least, there will be an increasing unity
                        of tastes, purposes, desires and aspirations. We may cultivate friendly
                        relations with all the world, but from the innermost sanctuary of our homes
                        the world is excluded. In our counting-rooms, offices and work-shops, we
                        toil for daily bread, and we have a kindly greeting for all our
                        fellow-workmen; but we seek our homes and the companionship of our wives for
                        rest and enjoyment.</p>
                    <p>This would seem to be the natural condition of affairs in all those
                        households where true affection reigns. But from some cause--the loss of the
                        novelty, the appetite for excitement, the longing for something new--no
                        matter what--we find that husbands sometimes seek for enjoyment away from
                        their homes. They are unimpeachable, so long as they furnish their wives
                        with sufficient market-money and so long as they do not incur a liability to
                        a suit for divorce. When the society for which they give up the company of
                        their wives, is a male gathering--a place where politics may be discussed or
                        mere amusement sought--it is bad enough; but it is ten thousand times worse
                        when married men habitually seek the society of other woeman [sic] for the
                        enjoyment they can not find at home. It is virtually saying that they find
                        in other women more attractive qualities than any with which their wives are
                        endowed.</p>
                    <p>When men are not capable of constancy, they ought to affect it for decency's
                        sake. The suspicion of the world is immediately aroused when a married man's
                        whole life is spent anywhere rather than home. We do not wish to see him
                        always tied to his wife's apron string, but we admire and respect the man in
                        whose estimation his wife is the first woman in all the world. And next to
                        him, we admire and respect the man who has manliness enough to stimulate the
                        feeling if he is too unstable and volatile to have it deeply rooted in his
                        heart.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Unsigned article comparing American marriages favorably to European; the
                    former are more often based on love, while the latter more often based on
                    convenience. Also discusses what is legitimate company to keep outside of
                    marriage. The end of the article is illegible.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/jan60.html#1.11a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Poetry, fiction, and unsigned editorials on fashion and family.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.01.11.03">
            <pageNote>Poetry and advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.01.11.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The death of an interesting child, and severe illness of other members of
                    the Editor's family will account for the lack of editorial in this week's
                    paper."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cooper</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary/>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>No editorials; news briefs from Congress and from overseas. Also
            poetry.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.01.11.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Leap Year</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt> "I am a little past "sweet sixteen" and in want of a husband. Any good
                    looking young gentleman with mustache, and ten thousand dollars, can have my
                    hand <emph rend="italic">certain</emph> and, <emph rend="italic">perhaps</emph>
                    my ear too if I can fancy him." </excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p> Our young lady friends all, of course, understand that this is Leap Year,
                        and that they have the right to "pop the question," lead to the Altar, pay
                        the boarding bills, or rent house and furnish it, for any young gentleman
                        whom they may see proper to "splice." It were useless in us to exhort them
                        to improve the long-wished-for-opportunity now presented. They will do that
                        on "natural principles" without any prompting from us. Here is one "fast
                        gal" who seems desirous of being <emph rend="italic">in</emph> time.</p>
                    <p>To the Publishers of the <emph rend="italic">Valley Spirit:</emph></p>
                    <p>GENTS: As this is Leap Year I assume the prerogative [sic] it affords our sex
                        and ask the privilege of your columns for the purpose of proposing
                        matrimony. I am a little past "sweet sixteen" and in want of a husband. Any
                        good looking young gentleman with mustache, and ten thousand dollars, can
                        have my hand <emph rend="italic">certain</emph> and, <emph rend="italic"
                            >perhaps</emph> my ear too if I can fancy him. I am not over [sic]
                        particular as to habits, if slightly erratic, though not past reforming.
                        I'll risk it. I may say I am considered handsome though not by any means a
                        beauty. I have some money in my own right and expect to inherit some more. I
                        believe I possess all the requisites to make any man who I can love, and who
                        will love me in return, happy. I make this proposal of marriage in good
                        faith, and as I do not desire to be hoaxed, or imposed upon, I grant you the
                        privilege of opening all my letters and request that you will only send me
                        those that you think, are honorable acceptances. Address the annexed
                        initials, for two weeks only, for if this plan does not succeed, in that
                        time, I intend to try another. You see I am in a hurry, and in earnest, for
                        I expect a rush among the girls for husbands and I do not want to be
                        hindmost.</p>
                    <p>With Respect, <lb/>Yours, &amp;c. <lb/>S A L <lb/>Care of <emph
                            rend="italic">Valley Spirit </emph><lb/>Chambersburg, Pa.</p>
                    <p>The above is a genuine epistle and our young gents in want of a wife would do
                        well to give it their serious consideration. From the following it would
                        appear that "S. A. L" though undoubtedly a "fast gal" is a little too fast.
                        Leap Year does not commence until the 29th of February, l860.</p>
                    <p>Any year divisible by 4, without a remainder is Leap Year which comes every
                        fourth year.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spirit reminds women that, by tradition, they are allowed to propose
                    marriage during leap year. Includes a letter from one young woman who is "in
                    want of a husband. Any good looking young gentleman with mustache, and ten
                    thousand dollars, can have my hand certain and, perhaps, my heart too if I can
                    fancy him."</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/jan60.html#1.11b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Personal</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stock</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. Jacob Stock of Altoona has been elected pastor of the English Lutheran
                    Church of Chambersburg and will preach Sunday.</summary>
                <note>Last name questionable.</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Personal</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lane</ln>
                        <fn>S.G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. S.G. Lane was reappointed Physician to the Poor House by Directors of
                    Poor House, and salary raised from $80 to $100 per year.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Man Haslett</head>
                <origin>from letter</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter from a militia member from Fort Scott, Kansas, who accused Edward
                    Haslett, a member of John Brown's party in Harper's Ferry, of participating in
                    the "murderous raid" on Fort Scott in 1858.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Death of an Editor</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bonner</ln>
                        <fn>B.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Bonner, late editor of Franklin Ledger, died in Greencastle on January 8th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shattuck</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Prof. Shattuck went hunting on "Head-top" mountain and brought back a deer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Includes new advertisements, plus statement of Bank of Chambersburg with
                assets and liabilities, market information from Baltimore.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.01.11.06">
            <pageNote>Fiction and advertisements. Most of the page is hard to read.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.01.11.07">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1860.01.11.08">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Packer</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Continuation of Governor Packer's state of the state address. He addresses
                    several aspects of the sectional crisis. He approves of Kansas's admission under
                    popular sovereignty; he approves of Virginia's execution of John Brown and
                    promises swift action against anyone in Pennsylvania who would aim to stir
                    trouble up against any state. Packer also states that slavery is not open to
                    question, and that moderate heads on all sides should prevail to hold the union
                    together.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Cases For Trial at January Term</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christ</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kerr</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingert</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowman</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowman</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wyncoop</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolff</ln>
                        <fn>G.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLellan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingert</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Artz</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingert</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newman</ln>
                        <fn>A.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Winters</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kohr</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>George</ln>
                        <fn>Jeremiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>J.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kirkpatrick</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tribert</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seibert</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Divilblis</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rice</ln>
                        <fn>P. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dechart</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Corwell</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mishler</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Leidig</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ditzler</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLennan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wiles</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Downey</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sorenson</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nimmon</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foreman</ln>
                        <fn>Fred</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stevenson</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seibert</ln>
                        <fn>P.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>Joshua</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grier</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carlisle</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tosten</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Augle</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tosten</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foust</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Laydig</ln>
                        <fn>Christ.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strock</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Champion</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chambers</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zimmerman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blair</ln>
                        <fn>P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>Alex</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nead</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davidson</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shrader</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shirtz</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huber</ln>
                        <fn>Solomon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foltz</ln>
                        <fn>C.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>List of civil court cases.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
