<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- <!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'> -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1859/va.au.rv.1859.10.14">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Josh Rothman</taggerName>
            <tagDate>6/2/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>3rd Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1859-10-14">
            <year>1859</year>
            <month norm="10">October</month>
            <day>14</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1859.10.14.01">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1859.10.14.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Duty of Democrats</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The great political ball of 1860 is fairly opened, and the cauldron 
                        commenced its seething with more than ordinary virulence and intensity.  
                        Probably not since the inauguration of our system of government have the 
                        press and politicians of the country at large been more earnestly, if 
                        not wisely, engaged in the discussion of the claims of the various 
                        aspirants for the Presidency, and the issues which may enter into that 
                        momentous struggle.  That freedom of thought and expression, which is 
                        one of the legitimate offsprings of our popular institutions, is being 
                        exercised with a liberality that might well institute an inquiry as to 
                        its propriety, and the various schemes and claims of politicians urged 
                        with a tenacity, which, to the unobservant, might savor of anything but 
                        harmony and oneness of action by the friends of individuals in each of 
                        the party organizations.  But, while at this early day the elements of 
                        discord and contention seem prevalent, we have the history of the 
                        Democratic party as a satisfying assurance that the authorized action of 
                        its representatives at Charleston will calm the troubled waters, and 
                        present the country another evidence of that unity of sentiment which 
                        follows an abiding faith in the conservative cardinal principles which 
                        lie at the foundation of our organization.  A simple reference to the 
                        agitation which preceded the contest of 1856, and the fears that loomed 
                        up in the minds of the timid, will justify the prediction that temporary 
                        breaks will be healed, the column closed, and the organization so 
                        consolidated, as to defy the enemy, and achieve another triumph as 
                        significant and glorious as that which crowned our efforts in the 
                        memorable conflict which elevated the present Chief Majistrate to the 
                        position he now occupies.</p>
                    <p> We freshly remember the ominous predictions of the Opposition as to 
                        the result of the action of the Cincinnati Convention, when it was 
                        assumed as one of those events whose shadow had been cast before, that 
                        it would be an assemblage of incongruous and dissentient elements, 
                        eventuating in the total disorganization and, consequently, the 
                        annihilation of the Democratic party.--But the unction thus flatteringly 
                        laid to the soul proved but another of those delusions which has marked 
                        the perturbed existence of the Opposition, and but verified the strength 
                        and power of a party the basis of whose existence and successes is well 
                        defined and immutable principle.  With a combination of all the issues 
                        of which the miasmatic vapors of the North are prolific, to oppose it, 
                        the Democratic party steadily marched on to triumph, and once more 
                        preserved its integrity and traditional adherence to the guarantees of 
                        the Constitution.  The same hopes that encouraged the Opposition then, 
                        and similar fears to those which agitated a portion of the Democratic 
                        party, are again in active exercise.  Indeed, the promise is that the 
                        Opposition will be more firmly, but not the less fatally, united in '60. 
                        If we are to take the Richmond Whig as the authorized organ of the 
                        Opposition of Virginia, a combination as odious as "Bli[text unreadable] 
                        and Black George--the Puritan and Black Leg"--is now in process of 
                        consummation, the election of a Black Republican Speaker of the next 
                        Congress being the first step in the detestable programme.--While we are 
                        averse to receiving the belief that such a union can be effected--that 
                        honest men of the Southern Opposition can fraternize with the bitter 
                        enemies of our interests and institutions at the North--yet we are 
                        irresistibly forced to give peculiar significance and importance to the 
                        suggestions of so influential and able an Opposition journal as the 
                        Richmond Whig.  It behooves us, however the proposition may startle and 
                        surprise us, to anticipate the emergency when Southern Opposition 
                        members of Congress will vote to <hi Rend="italics">"elect the blackest 
                            of Black Republicans' Speaker over "any Democrat North or 
                            South.</hi></p>
                    <p> With these indications staring us full in the face, it is not the 
                        suggestion of wisdom and policy for Democrats to cease their bickerings 
                        and criminations as to men, and reposing a cherished confidence in the 
                        patriotism and party fealty of the Charleston Convention, leave that 
                        body the trusted umpire whose selection shall be year and amen to every 
                        one who cherishes the principles and rejoices in the success of the 
                        Democratic party.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is the duty of Democrats to see to it that unity prevails once again in
                    the party at the Charleston Convention.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvoct59.html#10.14a</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>We must again request...</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Vindicator requests that obituaries written for the paper take up less
                    space.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Federal Court</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brockenbrough</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Watts</ln>
                        <fn>B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Article discusses some of the court's goings-on and then comments that it
                    is lucky for Staunton to have the Federal Court since it brings both strangers
                    and friends to Staunton.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Protestant Episcopal Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The General Convention of the Protestant Episcopal Church is in session in
                    Richmond.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Judge Blacks' Review</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In its next issue the Vindicator hopes to publish the appendix to Black's
                    reply to Douglas.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Accident</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pharis</ln>
                        <fn>Philip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fuqua</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Pharis, the Sheriff of Pendleton, is recuperating at the Virginia Hotel
                    after he accidentally shot himself.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Departure of Emancipated Negroes--Don't Want to Leave</head>
                <origin>Lynchburg (Va.) Republican</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On Sunday last, a crowd of not less than one thousand negroes assembled on the basin to take 
                        leave of the negroes belonging to the estate of the late Mrs. Frances B. Shackleford, of Amherst 
                        county, who, in accordance with the will of the deceased, were about to depart by way of the 
                        canal, for a free State.  The whole number set free was forty-four men women and children, but 
                        only thirty-seven left, the balance preferring to remain in servitude in Old Virginia rather 
                        than enjoy their freedom elsewhere.  Some of these who did leave, were thrown on the boat by 
                        main force, so much opposed were they to leaving, and many expressed their determination of 
                        returning to Virginia as soon as an opportunity offered.  Many were the well wishes tendered the 
                        departing negroes by the crowd assembled, and when the boats started from their wharves, the 
                        freed negroes struck up "Carry me back to Old Virginny," which was joined in by one and all, and 
                        in a tone which indicated plainly that if left to their own free will, they would gladly spend 
                        the remainder of their days in servitude in the home of their birth. 
                        </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Lynchburg (Va.) Republican.</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shackleford</ln>
                        <fn>Frances B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Out of 44 ex-slaves who had been set free, seven "chose to remain in
                    servitude rather than enjoy their freedom outside Old Virginia."</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvoct59.html#10.14b</note>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1859.10.14.03">
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCarty</ln>
                        <fn>W.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spitler</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunter</ln>
                        <fn>Mary J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on October 5, 1859.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brooke</ln>
                        <fn>George G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheets</ln>
                        <fn>Albert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hulvey</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on October 6, 1859 at the M.E. Parsonage.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brooke</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoy</ln>
                        <fn>Mildred</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sutton</ln>
                        <fn>Jeremiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoy</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Sutton and Miss Hoy were married on October 11.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Manker</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cullen</ln>
                        <fn>James K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hassenberger</ln>
                        <fn>Christina</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on September 20, 1859 in Pontiac, Illinois. Both bride and groom
                    are from Augusta.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bayson</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wade</ln>
                        <fn>Medorah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wade</ln>
                        <fn>H.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on September 16, 1859. Miss Wade is from Bath County.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pinkerton</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Life</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf>M.D.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Fannie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on October 4, 1859. Mr. Life is from Highland County.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pinkerton</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kyle</ln>
                        <fn>George H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eubauk</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on October 6, 1859.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitmore</ln>
                        <fn>Bettie J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitmore</ln>
                        <fn>Nancy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Bettie Whitmore died on October 1 at age 27.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hensley</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hensley</ln>
                        <fn>Harriet</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Hensley died on October 10 at age 64.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paul</ln>
                        <fn>Susan P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paul</ln>
                        <fn>James M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paul</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Susan P. Paul died on October 3 at age 10.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1859.10.14.04">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
