<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- <!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'> -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1859/va.au.rv.1859.04.30">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Josh Rothman</taggerName>
            <tagDate>5/31/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>3rd Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1859-04-30">
            <year>1859</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day>30</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1859.04.30.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Potato Cheese</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Recipe for potato cheese.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Root Crops</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"The carrot is unquestionably the best root crop for feeding cows."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Offeres advice on different root crops.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Farmers' Department</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Discusses the value of sheep to the farmer.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Much of front page covered by story "Sam Varney's Venture" (Sam Varney was a
                Green Mountain Boy). The 7th column has political news about Rockbridge and Bath
                counties.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1859.04.30.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Painful Accident</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Hon. Alexander H. H. Stuart, of this place, received a 
                        telegraphic despatch on Tuesday from a gentleman residing in the South, 
                        stating that the steamer St. Nicholas, on board of which was his son Mr. 
                        B. Baldwin Stuart, had exploded near Memphis, Tennessee, and that his 
                        son was very dangerously scalded about the head and hands.  Mr. Stuart 
                        and his wife immediately started South, and we hope by this time are by 
                        the bed-side of their wounded son.  Many others were killed and others 
                        badly scalded by the dreadful explosion.</p>
                    <p> We are pleased to learn by a dispatch dated Thursday evening at 10 
                        o'clock, that young Stuart is improving and his chances much better. 
                    </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>A.H.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>B. Baldwin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A steamer carrying A.H.H. Stuart's son B. Baldwin exploded; he is reported
                    to be okay.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvapr59.html#4.30e</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Terrill</ln>
                        <fn>James Barbour</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Terrill has been appointed to the staff of Gen. Harman.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Public Speaking</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn>William F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Gordon has consented to speak to people of Staunton on Saturday
                night.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Illness of Mr. Letcher--Mr. Goggin Refuses to Meet Mr. Montague</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Goggin</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Montague</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Letcher</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letcher is ill. He would have been replaced on the canvass by his
                    lieutenant Montague, but Goggin refuses to talk to Montague.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Mail Robbery</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>John C. Grove, the carrier of the mail from the depot in Staunton to the Post- office, was 
                        arrested on last Saturday by special agent McGuire, on the charge of having extracted from the 
                        mail a $20 bank note and a small quantity of gold.  The letter containing the money was a decoy 
                        letter, placed in the mail for the purpose of detecting the robber, as for some time back money 
                        and checks had been taken from the mail in this section of the State.  It is rumored that he has 
                        confessed the crime.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn>John C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGuire</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The mail carrier Grove (route: Staunton depot to post office) was arrested
                    last Saturday for stealing $20 and some gold from the mail.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvapr59.html#4.30a</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Congressional Canvass</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Letcher</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lambastes Anti-Convention men for claiming that the Opposition was pledged
                    not to run a candidate for Congress. Article gives plenty of evidence that the
                    Opposition was going to run a candidate.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Political Discussion</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Michie</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>There was a political discussion between Michie and Stuart on
                Monday.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Some Beef</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We observed on Thursday last, pass our office, one of the largest and handsomest Beeves ever 
                        brought to this market, which was raised by Maj. James Crawford, and purchased by our energetic 
                        young friends, Wm. F. Ast &amp; Bro., who will have it on sale at Stall No. 1, this Saturday 
                        morning.  Walk up ye lovers of good beef and get a piece.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ast</ln>
                        <fn>William F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>One of the largest and handsomest Beeves ever brought to market was raised
                    by Crawford and will be on sale at stall No. 1 Saturday.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvapr59.html#4.30b</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Hon. Edward Everett</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>This distinguished gentleman arrived in Staunton by the cars on last Monday, and delivered his 
                        celebrated Washington oration, in the evening, to an appreciative and crowded house.  The 
                        oration was eminently classical and learned, and fully came up to the distinguished author's 
                        reputation as the most elegant and accomplished scholar in America.
                    </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Everett</ln>
                        <fn>Edward</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Everett arrived in Staunton last Monday to give his Washington oration. He
                    once again confirmed his reputation as a brilliant scholar.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvapr59.html#4.30c</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Judicial Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robertson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The vote between Baldwin and Robertson is so close that it won't be until
                    the meeting of the Commissioners in Harrisonburg that the decision will be
                    final.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Amusing Reminiscence</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wise</ln>
                        <fn>Henry A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Charges made by the Opposition about the Democracy's fraud are annoying
                    because they mask the Opposition's own sins. The Vindicator criticizes the Whigs
                    for using the name American to identify themselves. The article attaches a Whig
                    notice that warns fellow Whigs to watch out for Democratic tricks.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Life Insurance</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trotter</ln>
                        <fn>E.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donaghe</ln>
                        <fn>Briscoe</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Article discusses the significance of life insurance. Trotter and Harman
                    have been appointed local representatives of the New York Life Insurance
                    Company; and Donaghe and Anderson have been appointed medical
                examiners.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Weather in Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article describes weather throughout Virginia; on Friday there was snow in
                    Lewisburg!</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Messrs. Editors</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coiner</ln>
                        <fn>Absalom</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cupp</ln>
                        <fn>John J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Buck</ln>
                        <fn>Napoleon J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letter from Many Voters of Upper Augusta asking Coiner, Cupp, and Buck to
                    run for the Legislature.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Fatal Runaway Match</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Robert Miller, of Belleville, Ill., recently hired a man named James 
                        Bracewell, to work in his coal pit.  While holding this situation, Bracewell had an opportunity 
                        to make love to Margaret, Miller's daughter.  It was soon understood that Miller was opposed to 
                        Margaret's marrying her suitor, but the two seemed to be no less determined on that account, and 
                        on Saturday week, consummated their purpose accordingly.  Miller, shortly after meeting 
                        Bracewell on the street, asked him if it was true he had married his daughter.--Bracewell 
                        replied, yes;  whereupon Miller produced a knife with which he inflicted a stab in the left side 
                        of his son-in-laws's back.  Bracewell lingered until Monday last, when he expired.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Robert Miller of Belleville, Illinois hired Bracewell to work at his coal
                    pit. He fell in love with Miller's daughter Margaret, and they got married. Upon
                    hearing the news, Bracewell killed his son-in-law.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvapr59.html#4.30d</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Mr. Goggin at Carolina</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"Mr. Goggin had never, from his infancy, drawn the breath of States Rights--a
                        Federalist, a Whig, an American, and Opportunist, he had "boxed the compass"
                        without ever once holding the opinions of a States Rights politician."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Goggin</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Goggin affected admiration of States' Righter John Taylor, although in no
                    way was Goggin really a states' rights man.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1859.04.30.03">
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Statton</ln>
                        <fn>G.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>George Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoover</ln>
                        <fn>Martha Jank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoover</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Smith married Hoover on April 21, 1859.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moon</ln>
                        <fn>Francis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moon</ln>
                        <fn>Richard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Moon died on April 26.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1859.04.30.04">
            <pageNote>In column 1, times and places when candidates James Skinner (for Congress) and
                James Paxton (state) will be addressing Virginians throughout the state.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
