<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- <!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'> -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1859/va.au.rv.1859.07.22">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Josh Rothman</taggerName>
            <tagDate>6/1/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>3rd Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1859-07-22">
            <year>1859</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day>22</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1859.07.22.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Gubernatorial Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Letcher</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Goggin</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Article lists all Virginia counties and how they voted for Goggin and
                    Letcher; in Augusta, Goggin got 2170 votes; Letcher 1402. Letcher won
                overall.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1859.07.22.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Interrogatory</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Questions the Richmond Examiner's hesitancy to press the issue about
                    whether or not Congress should protect slave property in the
                territories.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Vindicator Appeals</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guy</ln>
                        <fn>R.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>All accounts of the Vindicator have been placed into Guy's hands.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Slave Trade</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    
                    <p>Nothing to us appears a surer guarantee of the stability and probable 
                        permanence of the institution of slavery, than the revolution--radical 
                        in some places, partial everywhere--which has taken place in its favor.  
                        Men are now living who can remember when, throughout the world, even 
                        here in the Southern States of America, it was looked upon as a great, 
                        but necessary evil, and a casual glance at the writings and speeches of 
                        the founders of our Republic, will not fail to make apparent the fact, 
                        that all those great men considered slavery an evil, and its 
                        emancipation a desirable and certain consummation.</p>
                    <p> But soon the revolution which had commenced in its favor, and the 
                        disastrous result of emancipation in the West Indies, convinced the 
                        South that, evil or good, it was something which they must be content to 
                        endure.  Since then, the change in the sentiment of the people has been 
                        so sure and speedy, that now, the world, with the exception of a few 
                        fanatics, has come to look upon the institution with leniency, and the 
                        people of the Southern States with affection and reverence.  So decided 
                        has been the revolution in reference to this question, that the penal 
                        law making the prosecution of the African Slave Trade piracy, is the 
                        only remaining vestige of the ancient prejudice.  We have never been 
                        able to appreciate the consistency of those who, believing slavery, as 
                        it exists in the South, to be morally right, yet denounce the slave 
                        trade--the mode in which that existence was created--as an infamous 
                        traffic.  We have never been able to see anything but nonsense and 
                        fallacy in the distinction drawn between the morality of purchasing a 
                        slave in Virginia to transport to Alabama, and the morality of buying a 
                        slave on the coast of Africa to bring to the United States, where he 
                        will be better fed, better clothed, and humanized and christianized.  
                        Therefore;  conscientiously and devoutly believing the institution of 
                        slavery to be the most noble, humane and christian institution with 
                        which the creator ever blessed a favored people, we are forced to the 
                        logical conclusion, that the slave trade, far from being an infamous 
                        traffic, is, on the other hand, all perfectly right, moral and proper.  
                        We would not be understood as an advocate of the slave trade, for 
                        although our moral and christian duty would prompt us to favor the 
                        extension of slavery at any risk or cost, still we would not be willing 
                        to sacrifice the interests of the South to effect such an end;  
                        consequently, as we are not as yet convinced of the expediency we are 
                        opposed to the immediate re- opening of the slave trade.</p>
                    <p> But it was not our intention in this article to discuss the 
                        expediency or inexpediency, the right or wrong of re-opening the slave 
                        trade, but to add or voice to swell the cry of the aroused and outraged 
                        people of the South, for the repeal of that unjust, unconstitutional, 
                        and infamous law, which declares the slave trade piracy. The reasons for 
                        the repeal of this law are two-fold.  First, it cannot be enforced, for 
                        it is constantly trampled upon with scorn and impunity, and as a general 
                        rule, it is pernicious for any Legislature or Government to pass laws 
                        which, conflicting with public sentiment, are wholly disregarded and 
                        daily broken.  And, secondly, its passage and its maintenance is an 
                        infamous injustice to the South.  The Southern people have long enough 
                        borne with patience a law which stamps with the brand of piracy and 
                        outlawry the actions of their forefathers, and holds up to the scorn of 
                        the civilized world Southern slavery as an institution whose very 
                        inception was attended with a crime worthy of the gallows.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article says it's silly for one to support slavery in the South but
                    denounce the slave trade. Argues that the christianization of Africans is the
                    best thing for them.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvjuly59.html#7.22a</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Abstractions</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>People have been in the habit so long of settling to their own 
                        satisfaction every difficult question rising out of the slavery issue by 
                        pronouncing it an "empty abstraction," until at length the expression 
                        has passed into a common phrase of stereotyped wisdom, lulling the South 
                        to an unnatural and dangerous repose.</p>
                    <p> Did the good people who, on every occasion, are so eager thus to lay 
                        at rest a question which many men, great and small, have considered both 
                        substantial and vital, ever ask themselves what an abstraction is?  Do 
                        they remember that they have but an abstract right to life, until it is 
                        assailed?--Do they not forget that they hold their property, of any 
                        kind, only by an abstract right until it is interfered with by some 
                        person or persons?  In a word, are they not aware that they enjoy life, 
                        liberty and property only as an abstract right, until, being interfered 
                        with, it becomes a living, substantial claim?  Apply this principle to 
                        the question which now agitates the political world, and the myth which 
                        mystifying compromisers have thrown around this issue is at once 
                        dispelled.  We have, as we contend and the compromisers acknowledge, the 
                        same abstract right to protection for our slave property in the 
                        territories which we have to protection for our lives, liberty and 
                        property here in Virginia.  As long as this fact is conceded by the 
                        world, we are content to let the thing rest as an abstraction;  but when 
                        a powerful party, like the combined Black Republicans and squatter 
                        sovereignty advocates, deny that right, and threaten to follow up their 
                        denial by an open and fatal attack upon it, then that which was before 
                        an abstraction is converted into a living, substantial, all-absorbing 
                        principle, for which its advocates ought and will contend to the bitter 
                        end.</p>
                    
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Slavery is not an abstraction, the article asserts, and the issues arising
                    from it should be taken very seriously.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvjuly59.html#7.22b</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p> We call attention to the advertisement of Real Estate Agency by Messrs. R.
                        M. Guy and L. Waddell, Jr. The idea of establishing such an agency is new
                        for Staunton, but we think a very good one. Mr. Guy is well known in the
                        county as an honorable gentleman, and we can assure any one who may wish to
                        place their business in his hands, that it will be promptly and well
                        attended to. Mr. Waddell is well known as the junior editor of the
                        "Spectator." We feel great hesitation in recommending a Know Nothing editor
                        to the public, but we will venture the assertion that the one in question
                        has reached the highest stage of honesty and intelligence to which Know
                        Nothingism is capable. We do hope the prevailing prejudice again his calling
                        will not impair his personal prosperity.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guy</ln>
                        <fn>R.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>L.</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Article says it's a good thing that Guy and Waddell are starting a real
                    estate agency, even though Waddell is the Know-Nothing editor of the Spectator.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvjuly59.html#7.22f</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Staunton Steam Mill</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>This mill, which has been in operation but a short time, promises to be a
                        prosperous and useful enterprise, both to the stockholders and the people of
                        this and the surrounding counties. A Steam Mill at this central point,
                        situated on the Railroad, which will eventually extend to the Ohio, thus
                        bringing all the produce of Western Virginia, on its way to market, through
                        Staunton, will prove a powerful rival to the Richmond Mills, if the
                        stockholders could find it in their power to compete in prices with
                        Richmond. We were informed by one of the proprietors that out of sixty-five
                        bushels of wheat deposited at this mill, fourteen barrels of extra-
                        superfine flour, or a fraction over 4 1/2 bushels to the barrel were
                        produced to the customer, after deducting the miller a toll. This speaks
                        well both for the excellence of the mill and the wheat.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Staunton Steam Mill, opened recently, promises great things for
                    Staunton.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvjuly59.html#7.22c</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Lighting up the Town</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Some how or other we have neglected heretofore to notice the 
                        determination of our "City Fathers" to light up the town with gas.</p>
                    <p> We are delighted at this, and congratulate our citizens on the 
                        opportunity they will soon have to walk the streets of dark nights 
                        without imminent risk of breaking necks or limbs.</p>
                    <p> We think the town owes a lasting debt of gratitude to Messrs. 
                        Waterhouse &amp; Bowes, the gentlemanly, liberal-minded contractors, for the 
                        energetic manner in which they have prosecuted this work.</p>
                    
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waterhouse</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowes</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Celebrates the lighting of the town by gas, and thanks Messrs. Waterhouse
                    and Bowes for their work.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvjuly59.html#7.22d</note>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Staunton Lyceum will meet at the Courthouse next Monday.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Harvest</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>All accounts indicate a good and prosperous wheat harvest.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Federal Court</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Federal Court has been meeting in Staunton for the past two weeks
                    trying the "Jarvis cases," land cases.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Storm</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A terrific storm, accompanied by an unusual amount of thunder and lightning,
                        passed over Staunton on Friday last. Mr. E. M. Cushing's house was struck by
                        the lightning, but no farther damage done than a hearty scare to himself and
                        family. We regret to learn that a valuable young negro man belonging to Mr.
                        Washington Swoope was struck dead by a stroke of lightning early in the
                        evening.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cushing</ln>
                        <fn>E.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swoope</ln>
                        <fn>Washington</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A terrific storm passed over Staunton last Friday and destroyed Cushing's
                    house; one of Swoope's slaves was killed by lightning.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvjuly59.html#7.22e</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Newspaper Pirates</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Criticizes "sharks" who come into the Vindicator's offices and carry off
                    papers.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>The Enquirer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter to the Enquirer endorses Wise for Democratic candidate for
                    presidency.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>To the Editors of the Press</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pryor</ln>
                        <fn>Roger A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letter to the Editors of the Press in which Pryor announces his candidacy
                    for Congress.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Letter from Hon. J.J. McRae of Mississippi</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McRae</ln>
                        <fn>J.J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>McRae writes that the slave trade should be re-opened and placed in control
                    of the states and not the federal government.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Continental Morgan Guard</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Opie</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stribling</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf>Sr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rise</ln>
                        <fn>J.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Meem</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Washington</ln>
                        <fn>B.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Haynes</ln>
                        <fn>J.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barley</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brierly</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fagan</ln>
                        <fn>D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Continental Morgan Guard thanks Staunton and certain individuals.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1859.07.22.03">
            <div type="s">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCarty</ln>
                        <fn>W.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sutton</ln>
                        <fn>Joshua</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bosson</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on July 17, 1859.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements and Staunton markets</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1859.07.22.04">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
