<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- <!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'> -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1859/va.au.rv.1859.12.02">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Josh Rothman</taggerName>
            <tagDate>6/12/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>3rd Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1859-12-02">
            <year>1859</year>
            <month norm="12">December</month>
            <day norm="02">2</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1859.12.02.01">
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>A Religious Epistle from Old Brown</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"Christ...saw fit to take from me a sword of steel after I had carried it for
                        a time; but he has put another in my hand ('the sword of the Spirit')."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter from Brown to Rev. H.L.Vaill thanking him for his spiritual
                    encouragement. He expresses no remorse for Harper's Ferry.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1859.12.02.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Then, Now, and What?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Criticizes Northerners, particularly New Englanders, for supporting
                    abolitionists and expressing sympathy for John Brown. These Northern views have
                    caused the Vindicator to state that "We have not entirely despaired of the
                    republic, but there is everything in the signs of the times to shake our
                    confidence as to the perpetuity of the Union."</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Movements of Military</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilliam</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bushong</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The cadets of the Military Institute were called to Charlestown, but
                    arrived in Staunton too late for the cars. Before they proceeded by special
                    train, they "went through the battalion drill, to the admiration of a large
                    crowd who had assembled to witness the spectacle." The West Augusta Guards and
                    the Mountain Guards were also called to Charlestown, and they responded
                rapidly.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Meeting of Citizens</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Since our last issue, two primary meetings of Citizens have been held at the Courthouse; on 
                        Saturday night, of the Citizens of the town exclusively; and on Monday, in which a large number 
                        of the people of the country took part.  By referring to another column, our readers will 
                        perceive a synopsis of the action of both.</p>
                    <p>There are two facts which appear on the face of these 
                        proceedings as published, and stood out prominently in the manner and tone of the meetings, to 
                        which we wish to draw particular attention, because these facts are clothed with peculiar 
                        significance when the politics, and well known conservatism, of Augusta county are remembered.  
                        We refer to the endorsation of the action of Gov. Wise, from the beginning of the troubles at 
                        Harper's Ferry, to the present time, and the expressed willingness of the people of Augusta, to 
                        support and uphold the Executive of Virginia in any policy which he may think necessary for the 
                        protection of Virginia's soil and Virginia's honor.  We say when the politics and conservatism 
                        of Augusta are remembered, the action of these meetings is doubly significant; for it shows that 
                        the people of Virginia are divided by no party lines in reference to the late outrage against 
                        its sovereignty; and that the conservatives and patriots of all parties unite in denouncing it, 
                        and recommending preparation for the prevention or resenting of like outrages.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A meeting of Staunton citizens took place at the Courthouse on Saturday
                    night and a similar meeting for county residents occurred on Monday. In these
                    meetings, the citizens expressed their support for the actions of Gov. Wise in
                    the Harper's Ferry crisis and promised to uphold the governor in any actions
                    that he may think necessary "for the protection of Virginia's soil and
                    Virginia's honor." These professions of support are "doubly significant"
                    according to the Vindicator because they show that "the people of Virginia are
                    divided by no party lines in reference to the late outrage against its
                    sovereignty."</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvdec59.html#12.2a</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Capt. Harper's Speech</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We were peculiarly struck and interested by the speech of this 
                        gallant Whig veteran on last Monday.  The conservative and Union 
                        sentiments of Capt. Kenton Harper are well known, and those sentiments 
                        he did not fail to express on Monday; but he acknowledged that the 
                        occurrences of the last month or two had for the first time shaken his 
                        confidence in the Union of these States, and for the first time made him 
                        entertain the thought that a possible contingency might arise when a 
                        dissolution might be expedient.</p>
                    <p> When such men and patriots as Kenton Harper express such views, the 
                        emergency must indeed be imminent, and the outrage which has brought on 
                        that emergency must indeed be gross.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harper</ln>
                        <fn>Kenton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Vindicator editor was "peculiarly struck and interested" by Capt.
                    Kenton Harper's speech, in which he acknowledged that the recent occurrences had
                    shaken his confidence in the Union. "When such men and patriots as Kenton Harper
                    express such views, the emergency must indeed be imminent."</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvdec59.html#12.2b</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Staunton Artillery</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The following are the officers, elected and appointed, of the 
                        Staunton Artillery:<lb/> 
                        Imboden, Jno. D., Captain;<lb/> 
                        Harman, Thomas 
                        L., 1st Lieut.;<lb/> 
                        Michie, John C., 2nd Lieut.;<lb/> 
                        Peyton, Wm. H., 
                        1st. brevet Lieut.;<lb/> 
                        Garber, A.W., 2nd brevet Lieut.;<lb/> 
                        Berkeley,  T.A. Dr., Surgeon;<lb/> 
                        Balthis, Wm. L., Qr. Master and Com;<lb/> 
                        Imboden, Geo. W., Ord. Sergeant;<lb/> 
                        Armentrout, Geo. A., 2nd Sergeant;<lb/> 
                        Garber, M.C., 3rd Sergeant;<lb/> 
                        Stoddard, H.M., 4th 
                        Sergeant;<lb/> 
                        Turk, R., Ensign; <lb/>
                        Waddell, L.Jr., 1st Corporal;<lb/> 
                        Kayser, A.S., 2nd Corporal;<lb/> 
                        Harrison, Powell, 3rd Corporal;<lb/> 
                        Wood, Henry, 4th Corporal;<lb/> 
                        Burnett, Wm. A., Sec'y and Treasurer</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn>Jno. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Michie</ln>
                        <fn>John C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garber</ln>
                        <fn>A.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Berkeley</ln>
                        <fn>T.A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Balthis</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn>Geo. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armentrout</ln>
                        <fn>Geo. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garber</ln>
                        <fn>M.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoddard</ln>
                        <fn>H.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turk</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>L.</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kayser</ln>
                        <fn>A.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harrison</ln>
                        <fn>Powell</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wood</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burnett</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>List of the elected and appointed officers of the Staunton Artillery.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvdec59.html#12.2e</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Town Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    
                    <p>At a meeting of the citizens of Staunton, on Saturday evening, the 
                        26th inst., N.K. Trout, Esq., Mayor of the town, was called to the 
                        Chair, and the editors of the two papers of the town, appointed 
                        Secretaries.  The object of the meeting having been explained, on motion 
                        of Gen. Harman, a Committee of five was appointed to prepare resolutions 
                        for the consideration of the meeting.  The Committee consisted of Gen. 
                        W.H. Harman, R.G. Bickle, C.R. Mason, Jno. D. Imboden, and L. Waddell, 
                        Jr., who, through their Chairman, reported the following resolutions 
                        which were adopted:</p>
                    <p> Whereas, the people of Staunton being solemnly impressed with the 
                        alarming condition of public affairs, feel called upon, as good citizens 
                        and ardent lovers of their State, its Constitution and laws, to assemble 
                        and give expression to their feelings and firm resolve in the present 
                        crisis. This crisis, which has been brought about by a mockish and 
                        sacrilegious sentiment, fostered and encouraged among a large number of 
                        the citizens of the non-slaveholding States of this Confederacy, under 
                        the false name of philanthropy, it becomes our duty, as loyal citizens 
                        of Virginia, to meet without shrinking and with manly courage.</p> 
                    <p>The foray upon our border at Harper's Ferry, we recognize as the 
                        legitimate result of the fanatical teachings of Wm. H. Seward and his 
                        party, and whilst we claim to be "order loving and law abiding 
                        citizens," we are yet prepared to say to the non-slaveholding States, 
                        with the determination of freemen, thus far you have gone, but you shall 
                        go no farther!"</p>
                    <p> 1st. Resolved, That we applaud the Governor of this time-honored 
                        Commonwealth, for the patriotic zeal and vigilance with which he has 
                        taken "care that the laws be faithfully executed."</p>
                    <p>2d. Resolved, That in his preparations to maintain the majesty of the 
                        laws, in the execution of the condemned felons at Charlestown, he has 
                        given proof of this patriotic fidelity to that Commonwealth whose 
                        dignity and honor were outraged by the thieves and assassins who invaded 
                        her borders at Harper's Ferry. </p>
                    <p>3d. Resolved, that now, or hereafter, whenever our chief magistrate 
                        calls upon us to assist him in the defense of Virginia institutions, 
                        Virginia homes and Virginia laws, we will respond with the offer of our 
                        lives and fortunes, and the pledge of our sacred honor to sustain 
                        him.</p> 
                    <p>4th. Resolved, That in the opinion of this meeting the cultivation of 
                        a military spirit among our young men, and the organization of volunteer 
                        military companies for the protection of our own firesides, the defense 
                        of the honor of our State and the resistance of invasion, come from what 
                        quarter it may, is demanded by the threatening aspect of affairs at the 
                        present time; and that it is not only the duty, but should be esteemed 
                        the high privilege, of the old and substantial men of the town and 
                        county, to lend 'material aid' in the way of pecuniary contributions to 
                        those who may be willing to risk their lives in defense of the lives and 
                        property of others. </p>
                    <p>5th. Resolved, That the Chairman appoint a Committee of ----- to 
                        solicit contributions for the full equipment of our military companies, 
                        such as will insure their preparation and readiness for every emergency. 
                        On motion of M.G. Harman,</p> 
                    <p>6th. Resolved, That there be raised $500 forthwith, to carry out in 
                        part the purpose of the above resolutions.</p> 
                    <p>7th. Resolved, That the proceedings of this meeting be published in 
                        the newspapers of the town.</p> 
                    <p>During the progress of the meeting animated addresses were delivered 
                        by Jno. D. Imboden, Esq., Maj. Watts, Powell Harrison, B.A. Stuart, and 
                        others, and in response to the solicitations of the Committee, nearly 
                        $400 were raised on the spot for the purposes indicated in the 4th 
                        resolution.  There being no further business, the meeting adjourned.</p> 
                    N.K. Trout, Ch'm. H.B. Michie, Jr., L. Waddell, Jr., Acting Sec'ys. 
                    Richmond papers please copy.
                </transcript>
                <trailer> N.K. Trout, Ch'm. H.B. Michie, Jr., L. Waddell, Jr., Acting Sec'ys. Richmond papers 
                    please copy.</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>N.K.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>W.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickle</ln>
                        <fn>R.G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mason</ln>
                        <fn>C.R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn>Jno. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>L.</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Minutes of the town meeting held on November 26. In the meeting, the
                    citizens of Staunton resolved to continue to support the governor in his actions
                    to protect the state and agreed to organize volunteer military companies.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvdec59.html#12.2c</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Meeting of the Military in Spring Hill</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kibler</ln>
                        <fn>B.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bushong</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Mountain Guard adopted the following resolutions at their meeting on
                    November 21: they pledged to defend the state against invasion by "Black
                    Republicans and fanatics," agreed to support the governor in his actions against
                    the guilty parties, and thanked the Georgia Legislature for offering to help
                    Virginia maintain order against the attackers.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>County Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harper</ln>
                        <fn>Kenton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn>John L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn>J.D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guy</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>J.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Michie</ln>
                        <fn>T.J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickle</ln>
                        <fn>R.G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>J.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn>H.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Antrim</ln>
                        <fn>G.T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A meeting of the people of Augusta county was held on November 28 in
                    reaction to the events at Harper's Ferry. The meeting resolved to support the
                    governor and agreed to appoint a committee to solicit contributions to aid in
                    the equipping of volunteer companies.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Railroad Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A meeting was held at the Court-house on Monday last for the purpose of considering the 
                        propriety of a movement in behalf of the construction of a Railroad from Salem to Harrisonburg. 
                        Kenton Harper, Esq., was called to the Chair, and L. Waddle, Jr., and H.B. Michie, Jr., 
                        appointed Secretaries.  Jno. B.I. Logan, Esq. of Salem, presented the cause in an appropriate 
                        manner, and read the proceedings of a meeting in Botetourt.  On motion of H.M. Bell, Esq., a 
                        Committee of five was appointed to correspond with other parties on the line of the proposed 
                        road, and take such other steps as may best promote the object.  The Chairman appointed H.M. 
                        Bell, Wm. M. Tate, John B. Baldwin, R.L. Doyle, and J.D. Imboden, as the Committee, whereupon, 
                        on motion, the meeting adjourned. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>K. Harper, Pres. L. Waddell, Jr., H.B. Michie, Jr., 
                    Secretaries</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harper</ln>
                        <fn>Kenton</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>L.</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Michie</ln>
                        <fn>H.B.</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Logan</ln>
                        <fn>Jno.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>H.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tate</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doyle</ln>
                        <fn>R.L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imoboden</ln>
                        <fn>J.D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A meeting was held at the Courthouse to consider the propriety of a
                    "movement in behalf of the construction of a Railroad from Salem to
                    Harrisonburg." A committee of five was appointed to take steps to promote the
                    construction of such a railroad.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvdec59.html#12.2d</note>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1859.12.02.03">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1859.12.02.04">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
