<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- <!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'> -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1859/va.au.rv.1859.09.09">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Josh Rothman</taggerName>
            <tagDate>6/1/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>3rd Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1859-09-09">
            <year>1859</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day norm="09">9</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1859.09.09.01">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1859.09.09.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Editorial Responsibility</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The editors of the Spectator and ourselves must agree to differ on 
                        the question of the duty and responsibility of editors. - Nor do we 
                        perceive that the examples quoted of the editors of the National 
                        Intelligencer, and three exchanges, illustrate the question between us, 
                        even by precedent, (which is always a bad mode of argument in ethics, 
                        equally condemned by reason and scripture.) We suppose no one will deny 
                        that the editor is responsible for his own editorials.  Nor do we 
                        understand that the Intelligencer and the other papers referred to 
                        having noticed the subject editorially, question their responsibility to 
                        the advocates of Camp-meetings, and to the public, for the sentiments 
                        they have seen fit to utter against the propriety of such meetings.  Our 
                        proposition is, simply, that the editor of a newspaper, who admits into 
                        his columns an anonymous production, assailing individuals or 
                        communities (especially without comment,) is just as responsible for it 
                        as for his editorials, either legally or morally.  That he is so legally 
                        no one who knows the law of slander or libel doubts, and it is proper 
                        that the press should be cognizant of the fact.  That he should be held 
                        so morally, deeply concerns the purity of the press and the peace of 
                        society. Without such  responsibility, the freedom of the press would 
                        degenerate into licentiousness, and the characters of the purest men, 
                        and the most innocent ad useful association, would be no protection from 
                        insult and abuse.  The illustration put by the Spectator, showing its 
                        own course in reference to a piece signed "Justice," published in its 
                        columns the week before, contains no argument.  It is a mere comparison 
                        of itself with itself - a justification of one by another - and we can 
                        only reaffirm the opinion, (not assailed by the illustration,) that the 
                        editor was just as responsible for that publication as if it had been 
                        his own.  The question between us would be greatly simplified, by the 
                        separation of it  from other questions, with which the Spectator 
                        continually confounds it.  The question is of responsibility - not of 
                        propriety or of public necessity. We do not pretend to determine what an 
                        editor should or should not do--that is a matter for every free agent to 
                        decide for himself.  We only affirm that for what he does he is and 
                        ought to be responsible.  His paper being his, he must answer to 
                        individuals and the public for its contents.</p>
                    <p> As to the piece signed "Conservator," if we misconceived it, we did 
                        so after very careful perusal and while we would be very happy to 
                        believe the author meant no attack on the Methodist Church, we can only 
                        express the belief that ninety-nine of an hundred readers would be apt 
                        to fall into the same misconception that we did, and those of that 
                        church who did so misconceive it ought not to be held to the severe 
                        accountability that the Spectator visits on "Parnassus," and others, who 
                        have naturally written under a sense of injury.  But these are matters 
                        that we have nothing to do with further than, with all good men, to 
                        desire an end of such strife.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article expounds on significance of editorial responsibility and criticizes
                    the editor of the Spectator for forgetting this lesson in his editorial about
                    the Methodist Church.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvsept59.html#9.9b</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Virginia Index</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ellis</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Goode</ln>
                        <fn>J. Edwin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>DeWitt</ln>
                        <fn>B.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Ellis and Goode sold their interest in the Virginia Index to
                DeWitt.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wise</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gov.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Last Tuesday, Gov. Wise caused a sensation at the American Hotel here by
                    staying overnight.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Messrs. Tombs and Soule</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tombs</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Soule</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>These two men have come out in support of Douglas's squatter
                rights.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Kansas</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"What could the 'Republicans' do in Kansas without a row?"</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>There was a brush between Democrats and Republicans in Leavenworth, but
                    nobody was hurt.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Humphrey Marshall</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"In that case, every true Southerner, whose love of party does not over reach
                        his patriotism, will be found on the side of the Constitution and the
                        Union."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Marshall</ln>
                        <fn>Humphrey</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Marshall has committed himself to vote for Democrats in 1860 presidency; it
                    appears the election will be between the Democracy and the Black
                Republicans.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Iowa and Missouri Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lessley</ln>
                        <fn>James C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lessley</ln>
                        <fn>H.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>H.C. Lessley, son of James C. Lessley of Augusta County, has been made one
                    of the directors of the Iowa and Missouri Railroad.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Fine Mutton</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We have rarely, if ever, seen a finer 
                        mutton than was exhibited on Saturday last, at the stall of Messrs. Wm. F. Ast &amp; Bro.  It 
                        weighed about 130 lbs. and was so fat that a lean steak could hardly be found about it.  We 
                        hazard nothing in saying that for fine Beef and Mutton the Staunton market cannot be beaten.
                    </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>There was a fine mutton of 130 lbs. exhibited by Messrs. Wm. F. Ast.
                    &amp; Bro. last Saturday.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvsept59.html#9.9a</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Vegetables</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doom</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Doom of the Public garden left a cabbage big enough to feed 12 hungry men
                    at the Vindicator's office.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Slave Trade</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An article from the St. Augustine Examiner asserts that cargoes of Africans
                    are constantly landing in the United States.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Emancipation in the West Indies</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article gives a history of the disastrous effects of emancipation in the
                    West Indies.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="3" image="va.au.rv.1859.09.09.03">
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Steem</ln>
                        <fn>Sansford H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pannel</ln>
                        <fn>Francis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pannel</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on August 31, 1859.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1859.09.09.04">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
