<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- <!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'> -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1859/va.au.rv.1859.01.08">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Josh Rothman</taggerName>
            <tagDate>5/30/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>3rd Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1859-01-08">
            <year>1859</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day norm="08">8</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1859.01.08.01">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1859.01.08.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Coalition of the Opposition</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Denounces meeting in Washington of southern leaders of the
                Opposition.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Town Hall</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p> Some six or eight months ago, we suggested to the town council the idea of
                        building over the market house, then being constructed, a large and
                        commodious town hall, sufficient to accomodate any assembly, political,
                        agricultural or religious, which might meet in Virginia in the future. At
                        that time, the inducements to build such a hall were as great as ever
                        before,--it being only a few months previous to the assemblage of the
                        Democratic Convention which met at Petersburg, and which most assuredly
                        would have convened here if we had had a hall large enough to have
                        accomodated them during their deliberations,--and the objections as far as
                        least as the present outlay of money was concerned, were infinitely less, as
                        the price of the ground and the foundation would have been saved by the
                        proposed plan. We had thought that the council had decided upon this
                        question, and that all their arrangements had been made for carrying out
                        this improvement, so beneficial in its results to our town, but for some
                        reason, of which we are not cognizant, the movement fell through, and we are
                        still destitute of any public room large enough to hold a common size
                        country meeting. But we did not commence this article for the purpose of
                        investigating the reason for, and complaining of the failure of the council
                        to complete this most desirable improvement, but it is our intention again
                        to suggest to the council, to form some plan by which the town and county
                        may be supplied with a suitable public hall for their own convenience, as
                        well as the convenience of the State at large. The importance of such a hall
                        is obvious to every one. Staunton is the centre of the State, and to
                        Staunton all eyes are turned whenever a political convention or any other
                        assembly is to be convened, and it is only the want of a suitable room for
                        the accomodation of the delegation in their deliberations, which prevents
                        every convention of every kind from meeting in Staunton. This position was
                        well illustrated last fall when the democracy of Virginia were casting about
                        them for a place to hold their convention. Staunton was immediately
                        suggested,--in fact, was the first town in the State spoken of, and the only
                        legitimate objection which could be urged against the convening of the
                        convention here, was the deplorable want of a hall sufficiently large for
                        the accomodation of the delegation, and neither of the journals of this
                        place could with any show of truth deny the existence of this objection.
                        Now, to form some idea of the importance of such an improvement to our town,
                        just consider what an amount of money was lost to the currency of the town
                        and county, by the failure of that single convention to meet here. From all
                        accounts, there were at least, 800 delegates to that convention.--We have no
                        means of telling how many mere spectators were in attendance, but put down
                        the whole number of strangers present at 1000, which is a very low figure,
                        the necessary expenses of each individual would have been here, $2 per day.
                        The convention being in session four days, would make the whole assets to
                        our hotels alone, $8000. Taking into consideration what would have been
                        expended with our different mercantile establishments, and we do not think
                        that $10,000 would be too high a figure at which to place the sum which
                        would accrue to our town from one single convention. Thus we see that in a
                        pecuniary point of view, we would be amply remunerated for any expenditure
                        which we might incur in the completion of such an improvement. We could
                        mention many other important reasons for our suggestion, such as the
                        bringing together of strangers from all parts of the State in our town where
                        they may become acquainted with the lands of our farmers, the different
                        productions of our soil, our public works, our schools, ;&amp;c.,-- but
                        this article has already extended to a length which we did not intend. We
                        will conclude by recommending the building of a large and commodious town
                        hall, to the serious consideration of our city fathers.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article advocates construction of a new town hall to accommodate larger
                    political meetings, both state and local.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvjan59.html#1.8a</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Trial of Geo. E. Deneale Before the Committing Magistrate</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deneale</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shands</ln>
                        <fn>N.A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Deneale is standing trial for falsely claiming rights to
                property.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The "Harmonious Opposition"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p> Below, we give the report of the opposition meeting on the 27th of Dec. Our
                        neighbor of the "Spectator" says that it was "one of the most spirited and
                        animated we have ever seen assembled in our Court House." We consider it a
                        very fortunate circumstance that human nature is so endowed that all men do
                        not view the same circumstance in the same light, and on this point, we must
                        beg leave, with all due deference to our neighbor's opinions, to differ with
                        him, and say that it was not a harmonious meeting. The elements would not
                        unite, and unity of sentiment did not prevail, and we will adduce one
                        instance to show it. Mr. Imboden is an acknowledged leader of the American
                        party and it is to be supposed that his opinions have weight, but when he
                        offered a resolution to this "harmonious meeting," he was instantly pounced
                        upon, and his resolution defeated. And we would especially call attention to
                        this fact for the benefit of our democratic friends. We infer, and the
                        inference !<lb/> is a fair one, that the opposition of this county, and
                        district too, will run a candidate for Congress if a suitable opportunity
                        presents itself, and in view of this fact, it becomes our duty to advocate
                        the time-honored principles of democracy, and call for a convention, if we
                        have more than one candidate in the field. But we are digressing from our
                        subject, viz: the meeting, which was opened by Mr. Christian in quite a
                        lengthy and pointless speech, in which he failed to prove a single
                        proposition laid down. Mr. Doyle was then called to the stand, and after an
                        unlimited amount of slang, abuse, billingsgate, and a mean anecdote, which
                        neither edified nor amused, took his seat; and here we would take occasion
                        to remark that pity for a helpless foe, or contempt for a bootless and
                        powerless opposition, are the only incentive which would induce us to mingle
                        with them in their political gatherings, and when in these meetings our
                        party is made the subject and butt of an abusive and slanderous tirade,
                        candor compels us to say that even the pity which we feel for their weakness
                        or the loathing for their contemptuous subterfuges, but confirms within us
                        the belief that could they once more obtain possession of the reins of
                        government, not even the sacred memory of a Washington, a Henry or a
                        Jefferson would stay their ruthless hands, from our only chart of safety.
                        After Mr. Doyle had take his seat, Mr. Powell Harrison was loudly called
                        for. The speech of our young friend marked him as a rising man, but we would
                        earnestly advise him, in the disinterested spirit of friendship to "turn
                        from his evil ways," before the becomes too thoroughly imbued with the old
                        fogy principles of whigism, for it is our experience that the dreadful
                        disease becomes chronic if not arrested in its first stages. But we want to
                        hear from many other "harmonious meetings," and finally the "harmonious
                        meeting" which is to assemble in Richmond, on the 18th of Feb., which is to
                        be the progenitor of the "great opposition convention," to assemble in 1860,
                        in which all the combustibles of the Union are to unite and immortalize
                        themselves by a grand finale, after which they will be content to disperse
                        to their homes and sink once more into oblivion. But we must let this
                        "harmonious" speak for itself. </p>
                </transcript>


                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>Bolivar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doyle</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harrison</ln>
                        <fn>Powell</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Disagrees with the Spectator's characterization of the Opposition meeting
                    on December 27th as "harmonious." In fact, according to the Vindicator, "the
                    elements would not unite, and unity of sentiment did not prevail."</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvjan59.html#1.8b</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Opposition Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>At a large and enthusiastic meeting of the Whigs and Americans of Augusta,
                        held at the Court House on Monday, December 27th on motion of J. Givens
                        Fulton, Esq., Robert Guy, Esq. was called to the chair, and L. Waddell, Jr.,
                        appointed Secretary. The objects of the meeting having been briefly
                        explained by the Chairman, spirited and animated addresses were delivered by
                        Bolivar Christian and R.L. Doyle, Esqs., after which the following
                        resolutions, offered by Mr. Christian, were unanimously adopted: Resolved,
                        1. That as Whigs and Americans, we have adopted and cherished our political
                        principles from an honest conviction of their truth and patriotic virtue,
                        and such conviction is neither weakened nor strengthened by the
                        circumstances of temporary defeat or final triumph. 2. That our confidence
                        in the wisdom of that policy which leads us to foster and rely upon the
                        resources of our own country as the basis of a great "American system," has
                        received a signal support in the recent Message of the President
                        recommending to the party of which he is the representative, and which has
                        heretofore been opposed to such policy, the adoption of a tariff recognising
                        the principle of protection to American manufactures. 3. That we cannot,
                        consistently with a sense of duty to our convictions and our country's
                        prosperity, encourage by our votes the candidates of the Democratic party
                        who oppose the principles we profess; and that we esteem it a privilege to
                        sustain our faith by voting for candidates of our own party uninfluenced by
                        the prospect of either victory or defeat. 4. That we approve the proposition
                        of the Whigs of Richmond, to hold a State Convention on the 10th of February
                        next, and that the Chairman and Secretary of this meeting, together with
                        _____ others, to be selected by the Chairman, be appointed to represent this
                        county in said Convention. 5. That these proceedings be published in the
                        Staunton Spectator, Vindicator and Richmond Whig. On motion of G. W.
                        Imboden, Esq., it was further Resolved, That the blank in the 4th resolution
                        be filled by ten from each Magisterial District, and that any Whig or
                        American from this county who may be in the city of Richmond be authorized
                        to act as a delegate. A motion was offered by John D. Imboden, Esq.,
                        proposing as the sentiment of the meeting that no candidate should be
                        brought out by the Opposition in this Congressional District. The motion was
                        opposed by Messrs. Harrison and Christian and was subsequently withdrawn by
                        Mr. Imboden, who proposed that the present meeting adjourn to the February
                        Court for the purpose of taking the matter into consideration. The motion
                        was not carried, whereupon, on motion of Ael. Wm. A Bell, the meeting
                        adjourned sine die. ROBT. GUY, chairman. L. Waddell, Jr., Secretary. The
                        list of delegates will be published hereafter.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fulton</ln>
                        <fn>J. Givens</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guy</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>L.</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>Bolivar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doyle</ln>
                        <fn>R.L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn>G.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn>John D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harrison</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Report on meeting of the Opposition on December 27.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvjan59.html#1.8c</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Complimentary</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Abington Virginian supports John B. Baldwin as Opposition candidate for
                    governor.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Hon. John Letcher's Letter of Acceptance</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Letcher</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Letcher accepts the Democratic nomination for governor.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="j">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Virginia to Wit</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>M.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sheriff</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>G.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hogshead</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burnett</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Disbursements made to the Poor House</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Congressional news; letters left at post office</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1859.01.08.03">
            <div type="l">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>To the Voters of the Ninth Congressional District</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>The papers of the District are respectfully requested to copy.</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>James H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Skinner accepts the nomination for Representative to Congress as a
                    Democrat.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>For the Vindicator; Mulberry Grove, near Brandy Station</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Spectator, Harrisonburg, Shenandoah, and Lexington papers will please copy.</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>James H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Montagne</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Old</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>C.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Harris thanks his fellow legislators for their votes for his nomination for
                    Lt. Governor.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>For the Vindicator; Monterrey, Dec. 21, 1858</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Several Voters</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Letcher</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Voters supporting the nomination of Skinner to replace Letcher.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brooks</ln>
                        <fn>G.G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pilmer</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnston</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on December 26.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brooks</ln>
                        <fn>G.G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Butterly</ln>
                        <fn>John P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn>Ann Maria</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on December 27.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ray</ln>
                        <fn>George H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>William G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hardy</ln>
                        <fn>Mary A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on December 28.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wise</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Wise died on December 25 after a protracted illness.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1859.01.08.04">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
