<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- <!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'> -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1859/va.au.rv.1859.08.19">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Josh Rothman</taggerName>
            <tagDate>6/1/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>3rd Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1859-08-19">
            <year>1859</year>
            <month norm="08">August</month>
            <day>19</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1859.08.19.01">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1859.08.19.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The African Slave Trade Laws</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Long article that supports re-opening the slave trade and criticizes Judge
                    Douglas's opposition to the re-opening.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Our neighbors of the "Spectator" deny flatly that they desire a "coalition
                        with free-soilers and free-negroes" and become quite indignant with us for
                        charging it upon them. As for the "free niggers" all we know is, that a
                        prominent Opposition politician expressed a willingness to accept their aid
                        should they be constitutionally entitled to vote, and the "Spectator," we
                        are confident, defended him in that position.- We grant, though, that this
                        may have been done under the excitement of "a heated political campaign,"
                        and our neighbors may now repent of it; but that the Opposition party of the
                        South desires a coalition with free-soilers and abolitionists, we still
                        believe and assert, without fear of successful contradiction, and if we are
                        not grievously mistaken, the Spectator has had several articles earnestly
                        advising this policy--that is, a "coalition of all the elements of
                        Opposition" North and South. When the Spectator can show us the distinction
                        between a "coalition of all the elements of Opposition" and a coalition with
                        free-soilers and abolitionists, we will knock under and acknowledge we have
                        done them injustice. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Despite the Spectator's denials, the Vindicator claims that the Opposition
                    desires an alliance with free-soilers and free blacks.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvaug59.html#8.19d</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Morning News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crane</ln>
                        <fn>A. Judson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Botts</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Vindicator welcomes the return of Crane's pen to the news.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Dr. Schultz</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schultz</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. Schultz, the wonderful Chiropodist, will be in town for a few days at
                    the National Hotel.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Penmanship</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In another column will be found the card of Prof. Sherbrooke, of Washington
                        City, who has opened a Writing School, in the room over the Post Office.
                        From the high testimonials which Prof. S. brings with him from other places
                        where he has taught, both as a gentlemen and teacher of writing we have no
                        hesitation in commending him to the favorable consideration of those who may
                        desire to improve their hand-writing.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sherbrooke</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Prof. Sherbrooke has opened a Writing School over the Post Office.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvaug59.html#8.19c</note>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Van Amburg's Great Circus and Menagerie will be in town today and
                tomorrow.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Free Tickets, or "Dead Heads" on Rail Roads</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It is attended with some difficulty to determine what is precisely 
                        the true line of policy for a Railroad Company, on the subject of free 
                        tickets;  that there is some danger of the practice running into abuse, 
                        is admitted, but we have always thought that it was wise policy to make 
                        a judicious use of the courtesy of free tickets, to those who have been, 
                        or can be useful, in sustaining their interests.</p>
                    <p> The suggestion of this policy may be said to savor a little of 
                        favoring the practice of indirect bribery.  It has been rather too much 
                        the habit in Virginia, to refine in the support of abstractions, 
                        forgetting what is lost by neglecting the observance of practical 
                        utilitarianism.  We are not to be suspected of being influenced by 
                        interested motives, in recommending a more liberal policy, than has been 
                        pursued on this subject, by our "Central Road," for we have a contract 
                        by which we enjoy the free ticket privilege now.  We do not mean to say 
                        that a Railroad Company ought, by the offer of free tickets, to attempt to influence men to do what is 
                        morally wrong, but we think it would be wise in the Stockholders of our 
                        Central Company, to remember, that they are dependent on popular favors 
                        for success;  that men have to be dealt with, as they are with all their 
                        imperfections, and that it will cost very little to make a few friends, 
                        by occasionally extending the courtesy of a free ride, to those who have 
                        it in their power to render them valuable service, and who are not bound 
                        to do it.  We think the morality of this cause, as well as the policy 
                        suggested, is not contrary even to the precepts of the Bible.</p>
                    <p> We have been led into these reflections, by reading the Editorial 
                        copied below from the Railroad Journal, in reference to the course of 
                        the Erie Railroad Company. The President of that Company, Mr. Moran, 
                        signalized himself, by making war on the "Dead Head" system.  The Editor 
                        of the Journal, gave him many friendly warnings of the impolicy of 
                        putting in practice, his extreme notions on that subject. He would not 
                        heed at 
                        the time, but from the following, taken from the Journal of July 30th, 
                        we may conclude that he has been fully convinced of his error, and that 
                        it would have been better for his Company not to have attempted to be 
                        wiser or more moral in this matter.  May not our Central Company profit 
                        by Mr. Moran's experience.</p>
                    <p> FREE PASSES ON THE ERIE RAILROAD.</p> 
                    <p>We understand that the 
                    cardinal point so long made by this Company, to grant no free passes, 
                    has, like some other of its "rules founded on principal," gone the way 
                    of all earth.  The dead head system is restored.  To what extent, we do 
                    not care to enquire;  but the principle so long contended for by Mr. 
                    Moran, is completely given up. Without going into the policy of having a 
                    dead head list, we may say that the thing is considered indispensable 
                    and is practiced by our best managed roads.  If it has been found 
                    politic for Erie to return to it, it was certainly impolitic to abolish 
                    it altogether.</p>
                    <p> This company pertinaciously held on to its
                        position till all the injury was suffered that a mistaken injury could 
                        inflict, it now yields, when yielding will gain neither credit nor 
                        friends.   A disposition to institute radical changes in important 
                        affairs, ought always to be accompanied by a keen appreciation of their 
                        effect, so that an obnoxious point can be receded from before its 
                        injurious effects can be felt, and, before the moral position of their 
                        authors can be weakened.  To adhere to them till forced to yield by the 
                        pressure of necessity implies more stubborness than good sense, and more 
                        self-will than high principle.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Supports the proposal that the Railroad Company offer free tickets to show
                    customer appreciation.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvaug59.html#8.19a</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Official Vote for Lieut. Governor</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Montague wins the lieutenant governorship, 76,030 to Willey's
                68,031.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A Camp-meeting, under the direction of the methodist Episcopal Church, will
                        commence near Parnassus, in this county, to-day, (Friday.) </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>There will be a camp meeting of the Methodist Episcopal Church today.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvaug59.html#8.19b</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Indiana Weekly Courier protests the Vindicator's assertion that the
                    slave trade is just based on the premise that slavery is just. The Courier
                    argues that slavery is not just, and therefore the slave trade is
                unjust.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Congressional news in column 6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1859.08.19.03">
            <div type="s">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Staton</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Simson</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Love</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on August 14, 1859.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>Lawson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Radener</ln>
                        <fn>Nancy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on August 11, 1859.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1859.08.19.04">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
