<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- <!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'> -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1859/va.au.rv.1859.02.05">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Josh Rothman</taggerName>
            <tagDate>5/30/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>3rd Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1859-02-05">
            <year>1859</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day norm="05">5</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1859.02.05.01">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1859.02.05.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Democratic Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announcement of a Democratic meeting on February 1 at the Court House in
                    order to nominate someone to replace John Letcher in Congress.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Is a Convention Necessary or Not?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"The democrats of the county, of the district, we appeal to you on the ground
                        of party allegiance, of party discipline and custom, to throw off the
                        lethargy which seems to have seized you, and rally to the rescue of the
                        party."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Letcher</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Powell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gov.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Argues that a convention can only strengthen the Democratic Party and would
                    battle the Opposition; partly illegible.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Mr. J.W. Bridegame</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bridegame</ln>
                        <fn>J.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Bridegame purchased the paper the Valley Democrat.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Post Office</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The revenue arising from the present rates of postage having been found
                        greatly inadequate to the support of that important department of
                        Government, the question of raising the postage is being agitated, and is
                        creating considerable excitement throughout the country. We are decidedly of
                        the opinion that this department ought, if possible, to be a self-sustaining
                        one, but before an y such measure as increase in the postage is reported to,
                        we think that searching inquiry should be made into the expenditures of the
                        post office department, and retrenchment and reform should be the maxim
                        whenever such is possible. The people will never and ought never to consent
                        to an increase in the postage, until this is done. The system of extending
                        indiscriminately and by wholesale the franking privilege and many other
                        obviously unnecessary and extravagant expenditures, ought immediately to be
                        discontinued and when, after a fair trial of the retrenchment policy, it is
                        found that the department is inadequate with all possible economy, to the
                        support of itself under the present rates of postage, it will then be time
                        to taken into consideration the wisdom of an increased postage. As is well
                        remarked by the Enquirer, "the post office is emphatically the poor man's
                        Department of the Federal Government." In its numerous ramifications it
                        reaches the interest of every man, woman and child of the Union, and it is
                        of the utmost importance that it should be carried on with as much economy,
                        and with as little expense as possible, so we hope our worthy
                        representatives will go to work in earnest to bring the outlay of the Post
                        Office, inside of its income. This the people are certain can be done, and
                        they will never believe the contrary unless it be proved by something
                        infinitely more to the point than long heavy speeches on the subject, and
                        resolutions which are never acted upon.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article tells of present debate over the raising of postage rates and
                    argues that the people should only consent to an increase if the office is
                    reformed.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvfeb59.html#2.5a</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Mr. Letcher and the Old Soldier's Pension Bill--The Ruffner Pamphlet</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"...the time is approaching when every Southern man will contend that the
                        Slave trade is morally, religiously and politically right, and when support
                        of that trade will be made a test of fealty to the South."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Letcher</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Summers</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Article written by "we of the Tenth Legion" criticizes the Old Soldiers'
                    Pension Bill as an unnecessary drain on the treasury and defends Letcher against
                    Know-Nothing charges that he is an abolitionist.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Valuable Machine</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Connell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A machine that works lumber is on display at the American Hotel.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Homestead Bill</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article lambastes the Homestead Bill.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Significant</head>
                <origin>Blue Ridge Republican</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunter</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Hunter of Jefferson has refused to let the Opposition submit his name for
                    gubernatorial candidacy.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Democratic Caucuses</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunter</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bigler</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A caucus of Democratic senators met to consider the President's proposal to
                    change the tariff.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Congressional news</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1859.02.05.03">
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Suicide</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chappell</ln>
                        <fn>C.E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Chappell, a student at Hampden Sidney College, committed suicide by taking
                    poison.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1859.02.05.04">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
