<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- !DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd' -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1859/va.au.rv.1859.12.09">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Josh Rothman</taggerName>
            <tagDate>6/12/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>3rd Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1859-12-09">
            <year>1859</year>
            <month norm="12">December</month>
            <day norm="09">9</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1859.12.09.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Arrest and Extradition of Witnesses</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stevens</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Stevens, one of the Harper's Ferry conspirators, is being held in Staunton,
                    Virginia.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Capt. Brown and Capt. Pate</head>
                <origin>Charlestown Spirit of Jefferson</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Brown was visited by Henry Clay Pate, the commander of the pro-slavery
                    forces at the battle of Black-Jack.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1859.12.09.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Governor's Message</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Wise gave a very sectional speech on Harper's Ferry to the Virginia House
                    of Delegates, calling Brown's invasion an invasion on slaveholders and on their
                    property. Wise recalls the events of the invasion.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Execution of John Brown</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article details what happened the day Brown was executed; claims that the
                    prisoner was affectionate to everyone except for Cook. Before his hanging Brown
                    visited with the other prisoners.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Charlestown Intelligence</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Brown was refused his request to let Mrs. Brown stay with him; during her
                    visit they discussed family matters and his impending death.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Demonstrations of the Sympathizers of Brown's Execution</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The African-American community of Boston is holding vigils in memory of
                    Brown; in Albany, New York, there were church meetings in his honor. There were
                    also demonstrations in Ohio; Massachusetts; and Canada, New Hampshire.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Most of the page contains Wise's speech to the Virginia House of
            Delegates.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1859.12.09.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Governor's Message</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"If this contruction obtains--if the Federal Government refuses to interpose
                        to prevent such inroads as that which took place at Harper's Ferry, while
                        Virginia is forbid by the Federal constitution, to protect herself--she must
                        of necessity go out of the Union, and provide for her own defence."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Vindicator endorses Wise's message, noting the significance of the
                    difference between the governor and the president over the use of federal power,
                    especially in situations like Harper's Ferry.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Eclectic Magazine</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The following letter from the editor and proprietor of the "Eclectic 
                        Magazine," (to a gentleman in this place) of denial of all knowledge of, 
                        and responsibility for, the action of his agent Rood, who was arrested 
                        in Charlottesville on suspicion of tampering with slaves, we publish 
                        with pleasure.  It has never been our desire to misrepresent or injure 
                        any one, either in their person or business, and if unintentionally we 
                        do the one or the other, we are always ready, when approached in the 
                        proper manner, to make all the reparation in our power.--The fact that 
                        the agent of a Magazine, who was sent about by its editor to procure 
                        subscribers in the South, had been caught tampering with the slaves of 
                        the community in which he happened to be, was, we thought, sufficient 
                        evidence to convict his employer of complicity, or at least knowledge of 
                        his designs;  but we are willing to receive his emphatic disclaimer, and 
                        acquit him of either complicity or knowledge of the affair. We are al!
                        so, as a reader of the Eclectic, willing to bear testimony to the 
                        general soundness and conservatism of that magazine:</p>
                            <lb/>
                            <p> *  *  *  *  * "<lb/>
                                I should regret to find myself deceived in the views and conduct of the 
                                agent to whom you allude, especially in the face of his own solemn 
                                declarations.  But I am not his keeper.  He is not under my control or 
                                direction, as such.  But if he has, by word or deed, knowingly and 
                                intentionally done aught to disturb the peace, or trench on the rights 
                                of the community, where he many happen to be, then I am with you to 
                                denounce him to the law, and invoke that stern old magistrate to teach 
                                him better manners and a proper regard to the rights of others.  He can 
                                have no sympathy from me beyond his good behavior.  I disclaim all 
                                responsibility on his account.</p>
                            <p> I thank you for your kind testimony to the course of the Eclectic as 
                                unexceptionable during the long years in which you have been its reader 
                                and patron.  I enclose you a slip of the cover upon which I printed, 
                                some sixteen months ago, an expression of my views.  I hope and trust 
                                the good opinions and confidence of our friends in the South will not be 
                                easily disturbed or impaired in regard to the Eclectic, without good 
                                reason.  Let me say, I shall feel personally obliged to the editor of 
                                the "Vindicator"--a slip of which you enclosed--if he will make some 
                                kind explanation of the matter, using this hasty letter if needful, to 
                                neutralize the injurious effects of the paragraph, which I am sure he 
                                would not unnecessarily do. But enough.  My pen has run on beyond my 
                                intention in replying to your very friendly note.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>I am, very truly and cordially yours,
                    W. H. BIDWELL.</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rood</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Eclectic Magazine denies any responsibility for the wrong-doings of its
                    agent Rood, who has been accused of tampering with slaves while seeking
                    subscriptions. Article includes a letter from the magazine.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvdec59.html#12.9a</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Davis and Harris</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Vindicator blasts Mr. Harris and Mr. Davis, representatives from
                    Maryland, for voting for Mr. Sherman, a Black Republican, for Speaker. The paper
                    questions how a Southern man could do such a thing.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Correspondents of the Staunton Vindicator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Haymond</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letter from a "Mountaineer" advising Vindicator readers of goings-on in the
                    Virginia legislature; Robert Burke of Augusta was elected 2nd door keeper.
                    Richmond has a war-like appearance due to the presence of all the returning
                    troops from Brown's execution.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dooley</ln>
                        <fn>Edward</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dooley died on December 2 at age 50 in Staunton.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Long</ln>
                        <fn>J.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Long died near Buffalo Gap on November 27 at age 21.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Installation Services</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilbert</ln>
                        <fn>D.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baum</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>J.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richardson</ln>
                        <fn>X.J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Gilbert will be installed as new pastor of the Evangelical Lutheran
                Church.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Column 2 contains national congressional news.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1859.12.09.04">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
