<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- <!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'> -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1859/va.au.rv.1859.01.15">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Josh Rothman</taggerName>
            <tagDate>5/30/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>3rd Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1859-01-15">
            <year>1859</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day>15</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1859.01.15.01">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1859.01.15.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Senator Douglas and the Charleston Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Douglas</ln>
                        <fn>Stephen</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Senator</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>From the Chicago Times, the Vindicator discovers that Douglas will not run
                    for president in 1860 unless his nomination is sought.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Fred Douglas' Daughter for Sale</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"...as Fred is amply able to make the outlay, he should either purchase his
                        own flesh and blood from servitude, or cease his shrieks over an institution
                        which possesses such untold horrors."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Douglas</ln>
                        <fn>Fred</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Claims that Fred Douglas's daughter is for sale.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Spectator Desires to Know</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"The Spectator" asked what keeps the Democratic Party together; the
                    Vindicator responds that there is much greater unity of sentiment within the
                    Democratic party than within the Opposition.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Judgeship</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Samuels</ln>
                        <fn>Green B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuels died, leaving a judgeship open to candidates from many Virginia
                    counties, including Augusta.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Fire</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Merrilatt</ln>
                        <fn>S.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Fire broke out at the Institution of the Deaf, Dumb, and Blind; discovered
                    to be the shed of Dr. S.C. Merrilatt. Shed was saved. On Monday the cry of fire
                    was again raised, but proved to be the chimney.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Mount Vernon Association</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p> We publish in another column, at the request of one of the State managers of
                        the "Mount Vernon Association," for this County, the "appeal to the Ladies
                        of Virginia for the purchase of Mount Vernon," from the gifted pen of Mrs.
                        Anna Cora Ritchie, Vice-Regent for this State. We trust this appeal will not
                        be in vain. Each subscriber of one dollar and upwards, becomes a member of
                        the Association; the name and residence of each subscriber will be carefully
                        recorded and preserved in the archives of the Association of Mt. Vernon. It
                        is confidently expected that if proper efforts are made throughout the
                        country, the entire balance due on the purchase will be paid by the 22d of
                        February next. It is hoped that the Ladies of this County will co-operate
                        with each other in their respective vicinities, in enlarging the list of
                        subscribers, so that the State Manager's Record Book, which is to be
                        returned to the Vice-Regent on or before the first of March next, may bear
                        ample testimony to the fact, that nowhere are the name and memory of
                        Washington more warmly loved and cherished than in old Augusta. The
                        gentlemen named below are requested to transmit the subscription lists made
                        up, and the money collected in their respective neighborhoods, either to Wm.
                        H. Tams, Esq., Cashier of the Central Bank, or to Edwin M. Taylor Esq.,
                        Cashier of the Valley Bank, Staunton. Middlebrook,--Dr. Wm. S. McChesney and
                        Elijah Hogshead, Esq. Greenville,--Messrs. Bumgardner and McClure, John J.
                        Larew and John Newton. Waynesborough,--Nathaniel Massie and Clinton G.
                        Miller. Fisherville,--Franklin McCue and Philip Schmucker. Barterbrook,--Dr.
                        Thomas W. Shelton. New Hope,--Dr. Wm. R. Roberts and James M. Stout. Mt.
                        Meridian,---Maj. James Walker and Joseph D. Craig. Mt. Sidney,--Capt. K.
                        Harper, Wm. Crawford, and Dr. W. E. Bruffy. Spring Hill,--Dr. R. Gamble, N.
                        D. Poe, and James A. Clinedinst. Mt. Solan,--S. Marshall McCue and D. Newton
                        Vanlear. Parnassus,--William D. Hogshead and Dr. Wm. R. Blair.
                        Churchville,--George A. Hanger, and Dr. R. Hamilton. Deerfield,--Wm. Guy,
                        Kennerly Craig and Joseph Mason. Craigsville,--David Kunkel and R. S. Craig.
                        New Port,--Wm. S. Sproul, Arch'd Stewart and Harvey Fulton. Midway,--Capt.
                        James Henry and J. W. McCormick. West View,--Dr. W. L. Walters and W. W.
                        Taylor.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Toms</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>Edwin M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Article supports appeal made by the Mount Vernon Association to raise funds
                    for purchase of the estate; project strenuously supported by the Ladies of the
                    (Augusta) County.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvjan59.html#1.15a</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Case of the "Wanderer"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It has already been announced that a vessel, the "Wanderer," had been
                        captured on suspicion of having landed a cargo of slaves in South Carolina
                        and Georgia, and that it was hailed as a good omen by many of the planters.
                        Indeed, it is and should be a cause of rejoicing to every right thinking
                        Southern man. It is a question which has been but recently revived, but no
                        question of national policy has been so generally discussed and approved
                        since its second advent. The most potent argument in its favor is, that we
                        need negro labor. Negroes at the present prices are too high to cultivate
                        the soil by them to any advantage, and the Southern and Western section of
                        our Republic being better adapted to such products as require slave labor,
                        we will be compelled to increase our stock as we increase our territory. It
                        may be argued that Congress has legislated against it, but Congress has
                        passed laws prohibiting other things, yet when necessity demanded it she has
                        promptly repealed them, and such we conceive to be her duty under the
                        present circumstances; or at least to give such encouragement that the
                        traffic may be protected. It may be argued again, that it is our duty to
                        elevate this fallen race, instead of keeping them in a state of bondage, but
                        has not experience taught us that this is the surest and most speedy way of
                        civilizing and converting them to Christianity? Should the opposition of our
                        neighbor across the water, who connives at and encourages the French system
                        of apprenticing, be any object in our way? Then better give up every
                        cherished principle for which we have fought, and submit ourselves to her
                        dominion at once. But we think that several laws would be repealed by
                        Congress rather than this should come to pass.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A vessel named the "Wanderer" was captured landing a cargo of slaves in
                    Georgia and South Carolina. Many planters have hailed the renewal of the slave
                    trade because they feel that there is a need for more slave labor in the South
                    and in the new Western territories.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvjan59.html#1.15b</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Increase of Patronage</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Vindicator has increased its subscriber list; nevertheless, the paper
                    will never forget that it is a Democratic herald.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Ladies of Staunton propose holding a fair on February 22 to benefit the
                    West Augusta Guards.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Communications</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>"The same papers which were requested to publish my article, will please
                    give this an insertion also."</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>C.R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letter partly illegible but appears to apologize to Skinner for any
                    unintentional smearing of his character by Harris.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>"The papers of the District will please copy this and the appended
                    remarks."</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>James H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>C.R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Old</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Montague</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Skinner writes that apparently Harris did receive a substantial number of
                    eastern votes in the Petersburg Convention for the office of Lt. Governor. The
                    attached article recounts how Skinner initially supported Harris but then
                    changed his vote to Montague in order to balance of the ticket between eastern
                    and western parts of Virginia.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Messrs. Editors</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wise</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letter from A Democrat ridicules the Opposition for disarray in choosing a
                    congressional candidate. Writer also supports the idea of holding a Democratic
                    convention in Staunton to ensure the unity of the party.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>I have seen nothing lately...</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letter supports Skinner for Congress.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Congressional Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"It is the only remaining national and conservative organization in which the
                        whole people of the confederacy can unite, and which has the power to
                        maintain the Union."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Democratic papers of the District please copy.</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Letcher</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letter argues that most Democrats support the idea of holding a convention
                    for nominating a candidate for Congress. A convention will both ensure unity
                    within the party and will help the party throw its support behind one agreed
                    upon candidate.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>To the Editor of the Tenth Legion</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Letcher</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letter on behalf of Tenth Legion supports William Harman to replace Letcher
                    for the magistracy.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="j">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>By the Governor of Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Samuels</ln>
                        <fn>Green B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mumford</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The governor declares April 14, 1859 an election day to replace deceased
                    Samuels as judge on the Supreme Court of Appeals.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Congressional news</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1859.01.15.03">
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bladsow</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mattie</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on January 6.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>William B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cameron</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cameron</ln>
                        <fn>Warwick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr.Cochran married Miss Cameron on January 6.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1859.01.15.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Democratic Party--its Vitality--its Future</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"Like the giant Anteus, it has struck the earth; and it will, as it ever has,
                        gain new vigor and vitality with the rebound."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Praises the Democratic party and assures voters that each defeat brings
                    renewed vitality to the party.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
