<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1865/pa.fr.fr.1865.06.14">
	<header>
		<title>Franklin Repository</title>
		<tagger>
			<taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
			<tagDate>07/21</tagDate>
			<tagNote/>
		</tagger>
		<address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
		<date n="1865-06-14">
			<year>1865</year>
			<month norm="06">June</month>
			<day>14</day>
			<weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
		</date>
		<frequency>weekly</frequency>
		<extent>04</extent>
		<editionNote/>
	</header>
	<paperBody>
		<page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1865.06.14.01">
			<div type="a">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>The National Humiliation</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>A copy of the address Rev. Joseph Clark was scheduled to give on the Day of
					Humiliation, which was called by President Johnson to memorialize Lincoln. Clark
					died suddenly on the eve of the ceremony from injuries he suffered in an
					accident that occurred several days before.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>7</column>
				<head>Gov. Curtin and the Soldiers</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>A copy of Gov. Curtin's speech to soldiers at Camp Curtin in which he
					praised the contributions and grave sacrifices made by the men who formed the
					Union army.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1865.06.14.02">
			<div type="e">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Rebel Vandals In State Courts</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>Attorney General Speed has published an official opinion relating to the
						status of rebels who may be indicted in the State Courts for arson, robbery,
						murder, &amp;c., committed while in the service of the so-called rebel
						government. The question arose in Kentucky where some of the paroled rebels
						have been arrested for crimes committed during the Morgan raid in that
						State, and the Attorney General was asked whether the government would
						interfere and protect them as prisoners of war. In answer to this Mr. Speed
						says that "the government of the United States ought not to prevent or
						interfere with the execution of such process" issued by the State Courts.
						Again he says--"whether such persons are guilty of robbery, or whether they
						have any adequate legal defence to such charge, <emph rend="italic">are
							questions for the judicial determination of the Court before which they
							may be tried</emph>. The jurisdiction of the Court to decide these
						questions, after the parties are arrested, is unquestionable, and the
						government of the United States should not interfere to take the cases in
						question out of , or place them beyond the cognizance of, the State
						tribunals." The opinion is also endorsed by the War Department, and may be
						accepted as expressing the settled purpose of the government.</p>
					<p>Under this decision the question of the guilt of such vandals as M'Causland,
						Gilmore, Smith and others who sacked and burned Chambersburg, is left solely
						to the judicial tribunals of the State, and it will be for our courts to
						determine whether thay can be protected by the plea of belligerent rights.
						Such a plea would not, we apprehend, avail in the court of this State, for
						we are not aware of any act of this State, either judicial, legislative or
						of any other kind, by which the rebels have been recognized as public
						enemies, and in the absence of any such recognition they can have no defence
						other than is afforded to any other robbers or murderers who offend against
						the peace and dignity of the Commonwealth. Early, who ordered the
						destruction of Chambersburg, is reported dead; but as he was not in the
						State we presume that he would not be amenible; but M'Causland is now living
						comfortably on his farm in Western Virginia, and within the reach of the
						civil power of the State. Gilmore, who was the chief in the work of
						destruction, who fired a number of buildings himself, and insulted all who
						came in his way, is also alive, and many turn up under the persuasive
						appeals of a requisition. Capt. Smith still boasts a habitation on this
						sublinary sphere, and is probably enjoying his fathers fine home in
						Washington, Virginia, which was always carefully guarded by Union troops
						when they occupied that part of the State, and his family supported
						themselves by selling vegetables to our officers. We speak advisedly when we
						say that Gov. Pierpont will respond to a requisition from Gov. Curtin, and
						no one need be told that Gov. Curtin will perform his part whenever the
						cases come probably before him. If these chief actors escape the law, it
						must be by becoming fugitives from justice, and we are for pursuing them
						until some of them are brought to Chambersburg free of charge, and brought
						to face a Franklin county court and jury in the midst of the ruins they have
						so wantonly wrought. If M'Causland and Gilmore run off, it might be well
						enough to send after one Robert E. Lee who passed through here in 1863 and
						issued public orders for plundering our people generally. He was a first
						class highway robber in his way and would answer admirably to test the
						question whether because a set of perjured cut-throats see fit to attempt
						the overthrow of the most beneficent government of Earth by war, they can
						rob, and burn and murder at will within the limits of Pennsylvania without
						violation of her laws. There is plenty of material for Mr. Stenger to try
						his hand on and we presume that the August grand jury will give him plenty
						to do in that line.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Following the publication of the Attorney General's opinion that the
					federal government should not intervene to prohibit states from indicting rebels
					who committed arson, murder, robbery or other heinous crimes while "in the
					service of the so-called rebel government," the editors contend that McCausland,
					Gilmore, Smith, and the other "vandals" who sacked Chambersburg should be
					brought before "the judicial tribunals of the State" to face justice.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="e">
				<column>2</column>
				<head>Our Returned Soldiers</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>Let every one extend a most cordial welcome to the bronzed and battle-scarred
						heroes, who have just returned from their victorious fields to resume their
						places among us as citizens. Let them be greeted as they deserve with
						generous hearts and considerate efforts to promote their well-being. Their
						heroism and achievements afforded the richest material for fourth of July
						orations and speeches of welcome; but the true test of a just appreciation
						of the services of gallant soldiers of the Republic is to make their welcome
						home substantial by providing them prompt employment and aiding them in
						every possible way to resume the arts and labors of peace. They have been
						absent for months and some for years, and others have filled many of their
						places in the various channels of industry. Many of them have families
						dependent upon their labor, and every true friend of the returned soldier
						will manifest his friendship by aiding him to attain success in the
						industrial pursuits of life. Many who in time of war were not conspicuous
						for their friendship for the soldier and his cause, now forsee social
						disorder as one of the fruits of a large army disbanded into peaceful
						pursuits. We do not fear such a result. A good soldier cannot be a bad
						citizen; and the history of warfare gives no instance of a more heroic and
						invincible soldiery than was embraced in the Union armies. They were good
						soldiers, because they were good citizens; and they will resume their places
						in society without even a ripple upon the surface. But they will need kind
						friends. They must have aid to procure employment, and let every faithful
						man see at once that the returned soldiers in his neighborhood are proffered
						suitable labor. It would be heartless ingratitude on the part of a people
						whose liberties have been preserved by the valor of our volunteers, should
						any soldier seek employment in vain and suffer want in the land he has
						rescued from the peril of treason by his sacrifices. Let one and all extend
						a kind hand and generous heart to the heroes of the Republic in our midst.
						We owe it to them to do so, and let the debt be paid promptly and
						cheerfully, and all will be well.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>The editors admonish local residents to offer a warm welcome to the
					returning soldiers and to aid them in their efforts to re-integrate into civil
					society.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="e">
				<column>2</column>
				<head/>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>The editors "joyously" note that it is believed that President Johnson
					"will speedily issue a Proclamation restoring the privilege of Habeas Corpus and
					ordering a general clearance of the Military Prisons."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Washington</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>The Repository's correspondent informs readers that a riot occurred in
					Washington following the Grand Review. According to his account, drunken
					soldiers went on a rampage in the black sections of the city. Armed "with axes
					and maddened with rum," they indiscriminately attacked blacks, "helping
					themselves to any and everything." Soon after the assault began, he relates,
					blacks took up arms to defend themselves. The fighting finally came to an end
					when a detachment from Hancock's 5th Regiment arrived to restore order. It is
					reported that several people on both sides were killed in the battle.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="p">
				<column>7</column>
				<head>Welcome Home</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>WELCOME HOME<lb/><lb/> O, the men who fought and bled,<lb/> O, the glad and
						gallant tread,<lb/> And the bright skies overhead,<lb/> Welcome home!<lb/>
						O, the brave returning boys,<lb/> O, the overflowing joys,<lb/> And the guns
						and drums and noise,<lb/> Welcome home!<lb/><lb/> Let the deep voiced
						cannons roar,<lb/> Open every gate and door,<lb/> Pour out, happy people,
						pour,<lb/> Welcome home!<lb/> Bloom, O banners, over all,<lb/> Over every
						roof and wall,<lb/> Float and flow, and rise and fall,<lb/> Welcome
						home!<lb/><lb/> Splendid column moving down,<lb/> From veterans soiled and
						brown,<lb/> Grim heads, fit to wear a crown,<lb/> Welcome home!<lb/> Grim
						heads, which a wall have been,<lb/> Keeping sacred things within,<lb/>
						Keeping out the hosts of sin,<lb/> Welcome home!<lb/><lb/> There the women
						stand for hours,<lb/> With their white hands full of flowers,<lb/> Raining
						down the perfumed showers,<lb/> On the dear men marching home!<lb/> Do you
						see him in the line?<lb/> Something makes him look divine,<lb/> And a glory
						makes him shine,<lb/> Coming home.<lb/><lb/> Look out where the flag
						unfurls,<lb/> Look out through your tears and curls,<lb/> Give them welcome,
						happy girls!<lb/> Welcome home!<lb/> Welcome home from war's alarms,<lb/>
						Welcome to a thousand charms,<lb/> Waiting lips and loving arms.<lb/>
						Welcome home!<lb/><lb/> Strong man, with the serious face,<lb/> If you saw
						him in his place,<lb/> Marching swift to your embrace,<lb/> Coming
						home,<lb/> You would weep with glad surprise<lb/> At the dear dead boy that
						lies<lb/> Underneath the Southern skies,<lb/> Far from home.<lb/><lb/>
						Women, with the tender eye,<lb/> Weeping while the boys go by,<lb/> Well we
						know what makes you cry,<lb/> Weary home!<lb/> God be with you in your
						pain,<lb/> You will look and look in vain,<lb/><emph rend="italic">He</emph>
						will never come again<lb/> To his home!<lb/><lb/> So amid our joy we
						weep<lb/> For the noble dead who sleep<lb/> In the vale and on the
						steep,<lb/> Far from home;--<lb/> For the chief who fought so well,<lb/> For
						the Christ like man who fell<lb/> By the chosen son of Hell,<lb/> And went
						home!<lb/><lb/> And we thank you, Slavery's dead,<lb/> And the hosts of
						Wrong are fled,<lb/> And the right prevails instead.<lb/> Welcome home!<lb/>
						Limb, and tongue, and press are free,<lb/> And the nation shouts to see<lb/>
						All the glory yet to be,<lb/> Welcome home!</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>A poem dedicated to the returning soldiers.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1865.06.14.03">
			<div type="e">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Local Items--Gossip With Our Friends</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt>"We have not done all when we have freed the slave. We are yet deeply in
					his debt. Will we, dare we repudiate?"</excerpt>
				<transcript>
					<p>Gossip With Our Friends--While walking past the Germantown depot, the other
						day, a curious sight arrested my steps--a carriage, driven by a white man,
						and containing a negro and two little darkies. That innate curiosity which
						makes one a bad citizen, but a good gossip, impelled me to try to discover
						who the sable travellers were. The wool of the man was sprinkled with grey;
						and the boys, severally eight and ten years old, had that
						look-about-where-are-we-air, that marks the stranger, black or white. The
						carriage drove up to the depot, and the party descended, the old man saying
						in true Virginia pathos (<emph rend="italic">I</emph> know the tones, its
						tricks and its manners; for did not Lee's army occupy our town for three
						weeks: "Now, chill-un, tote up you' traps; be keerful. How much, sah?" he
						said, turning to the driver. "Two dollars," was the prompt reply. From one
						pocket and another came, here a twenty-five cent and there a ten cent note,
						and now some fives, and then some pennies, until the amount was made up.
						With true editorial pertinacity I followed the party into the ticket office,
						and into the cars, where I seated myself beside the old man, and elicited
						the following recital, which I will not attemp to clothe in his dialect: "I
						am sixty years old. I have lived in Virginia all my life. I was a slave
						until Mr. Lincoln made me free, about seven months ago, since which time I
						have served in the army as a cook, and in the forage department at $25 a
						month. I am as glad to be free as though I were ten years old. These boys
						are mine; and I hope they will grow up to enjoy what I am almost to old to
						use as I should. For the last seven years I have been hired out by my master
						in Petersburg. I was separated from my wife and boys, and have been looking
						for them a long time. She was looking for me and the boys too. Once we were
						on opposite sides of the river for a whole month, dying to see each other;
						but neither of us could find out where the other was. At last I heard they
						were away North. I earned enough money to bring me here, and yesterday I
						found my old woman in Germantown, where she has a good place. She told me
						the children were in Salem. I went down there for them, and here I am on my
						way to Germantown, to show them to her. We are all going South again, where
						we can now live together, and where we can work for ourselves. Bless God and
						Mr. Lincoln for it." I asked him how his money held out, and why he spent
						two dollars on a carriage. He answered, "I am almost out of money, and I
						hired a carriage because I could not find my way. <emph rend="italic">I am a
							stranger</emph>." I <emph rend="italic">returned</emph> the old man a
						very small part of what <emph rend="italic">the white man</emph> owed him;
						and he reverently asked God to bless me. It is true he said, "May God
						Almighty bless you," but I think God Almighty understood him. For the sake
						of truth, justice and mercy, let us be kind to the negro. We have been
						fearfully scourged, North and South (and old Chambersburg has come in for a
						full share) for our participation in this monstrous evil of slavery. We have
						not done <emph rend="italic">all</emph> when we have freed the slave. We are
						yet deeply in his debt. Will we, dare we, repudiate?</p>
					<p>New York is now nearly at its heighth in dirt, and mud, and dust, and stink.
						Were it not for the occasional pleasant breeze from the sea, that rich and
						poor can alike enjoy, it would be almost uninhabitable. Monday of last week
						I saw a man dying from sun-stroke on the side-walk, and the day after winter
						clothes felt quite comfortable.</p>
					<p>Our female correspondent who accompanied Jeff Davis from Irwinsville to
						Fortress Monroe, has reached New York, and is preparing a careful account of
						her conversation with J. D. Mr. Bennet has seen the manuscript as far as it
						has progressed, and professes to be much pleased. He says "it will please
						the public taste as well as though it was false." This unqualified praise
						from so eminent a journalist is sufficient to advertize the forthcoming
						pamphlet, which will be entitled</p>
					<p>"THE LAST TIMES<lb/> OF<lb/> JEFFERSON DAVIS, ESQ.,<lb/> and a full
						account<lb/> of his<lb/> APOTHEOSIS,<lb/> with minute details of how<lb/> he
						became his own<lb/> MOTHER."</p>
					<p>Business is very dull--every one holding off for lower prices. Manufacturers,
						jobbers, retailers, and consumers acting in council.</p>
					<p>Barnum has a large painting on the outside of his museum illustrative of the
						capture of J. D., and every window of the print stores exhibits pictures of
						all sizes and at all prices commemorative of the same historical event. How
						grateful these exhibitions must be to the representatives of the Southern
						chivalry who had made their homes in N. Y. We had a big meeting at the
						Cooper Institute, last Thursday night, which Gen. Grant honored with his
						presence. Such a crowd was in and outside of the Hall that the Police were
						almost useless, and indeed were as enthusiastic as any of the great
						unwashed. Grant made a speech exactly seven seconds in length, and was quite
						exhausted in consequence. He can't make a speech as well as McClellan, but
						he took Richmond.</p>
					<p>"His deeds exceed all speech."</p>
					<p><emph rend="italic">There</emph>, Shakespeare makes a good ending.<lb/> New
						York, June 10, 1865.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Gossip recounts a touching encounter he had with a freedman who had
					recently found his children and was in the process of preparing his reunited
					family for the return to the South.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>2</column>
				<head>Local Items--Maj. Gen. Crawford</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>A short biography of Maj. Gen. Crawford, whose father, Rev. Dr. Crawford,
					hails from Franklin county. The younger Crawford served honorably in campaigns
					in Virginia and, assures the article, "will doubtless be speedily promoted."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>2</column>
				<head>Local Items--Oil Developments</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Foreign companies are showing great interest in Franklin, Bedford, Fulton,
					and Juniata counties, where they believe there are significant deposits of oil.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>2</column>
				<head>Local Items--The Vandal McCausland</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>According to information provided by a "reliable officer in the Veteran
					Reserve Corps, contrary to earlier reports, Gen. McCausland, the rebel who led
					the attack on Chambersburg, is still alive. After turning himself over to Union
					troops near Charlestown, Va., recently, he was paroled and is now "said to be
					very comfortably fixed, and living in luxury."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>2</column>
				<head>Local Items</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Informs readers that the annual meeting of the Snow Hill Society, known as
					the Seventh Day Baptists, that was held near Waynesboro was well-attended. It is
					estimated that between 3,000 and 5,000 people were present for the occasion.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>3</column>
				<head>Local Items--The Repository Building</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Announces the Repository Association's purchase of the lot on the corner of
					the Diamond, which, until recently, was occupied by Franklin Hall. The
					Association intends on constructing a three story building there to house the
					newspaper's counting and editorial rooms. There will also be space for five
					stores and offices on the first floor and a "commodious Public Hall" on the
					second.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>3</column>
				<head>Local Items--Died Of Starvation</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Eyster</ln>
						<fn>George S.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>George S. Eyster, a member Co. E., 11th Penna. Cavalry, died on Feb. 1st
					from starvation while being held at a prisoner camp in Florence, South Carolina.
					Eyster was captured by the rebels on the Weldon Railroad last summer.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>3</column>
				<head>Local Items--Consolidation of Railroads</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>On May 31st, the stockholders of the Cumberland Valley and Franklin
					Railroad unanimously approved the agreement to merge the two companies. The new
					partnership, chartered under the Franklin Railroad Company, controls a line that
					extends from Harrisburg, Pa., to Hagerstown, Md., a distance of 72 miles.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>3</column>
				<head>Local Items--Mustered Out</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>After serving in Chambersburg for several months, Battery A. 1st New York
					Artillery left for Elmira where it will be mustered out.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>3</column>
				<head>Local Items--Returned</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Having been honorably discharged, the companies under Capt. Kuhn (formerly
					McCulloch's) and McKnight returned last Wednesday. The troops saw battle in the
					Richmond campaign, under Sheridan, and were present for Lee's surrender.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Everett</ln>
						<fn>William S.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Reed</ln>
						<fn>Charlotte S.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Williams</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On June 6th, William S. Everett and Charlotte S. Reed were married by Rev.
					Williams, of Pittsburgh.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Reedy</ln>
						<fn>J. M.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Copp</ln>
						<fn>Lydia C.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Smith</ln>
						<fn>S. H. C.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On June 13th, J. M. Reedy and Lydia C. Copp, both of Shenandoah county,
					Va., were married by Rev. S. H. C. Smith.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Creigh</ln>
						<fn>James Jacob</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Barber</ln>
						<fn>Emma C.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Barber</ln>
						<fn>John</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Creigh</ln>
						<fn>Thomas</fn>
						<sf>D. D.</sf>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On June 6th, James Jacob Creigh and Emma C., daughter of John Barber, were
					married by Thomas Creigh, D. D.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Walker</ln>
						<fn>Robert Elliot</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Walker</ln>
						<fn>John H.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Walker</ln>
						<fn>Caroline</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On May 30th, Robert Elliot, son of John H. and Caroline Walker, died.
					Robert was 4 years old.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Reed</ln>
						<fn>Susana</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On June 1st, Susana Reed, 50, died after suffering the effects of a
					"lingering illness."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Burket</ln>
						<fn>John Barr</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Burket</ln>
						<fn>Frederick</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Burket</ln>
						<fn>Eliza</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On May 26th, John Barr, son of Frederick and Eliza Burket, died of scarlet
					fever. John was 7 months old.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Leader</ln>
						<fn>Henry</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Maj.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Leader</ln>
						<fn>Henry</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Dr.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On May 26th, Maj. Henry Leader, formerly of Franklin county, died at the
					home of his son, Dr. Henry Leader, in Michigan. Leader was 79 years old.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Tosten</ln>
						<fn>Rosannah</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On June 6th, Rosannah Tosten, 29, died near Welsh Run.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1865.06.14.04">
			<pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
		</page>
	</paperBody>
</hwp>
