<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1865/pa.fr.fr.1865.03.08">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sally Henninger, 1st pass; Susanna Michele Lee, 2nd pass, 1/3/99</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1865-03-08">
            <year>1865</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day norm="08">8</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1865.03.08.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Interesting Questions And Answers Relative to the 7-30 U. S. Loan</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prints a list of questions on the 7-30 loan and answers given by Jay Cooke,
                    the General Agent managing the loan.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>An Incident Of The War</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports the story of classmates who fought on opposite sides of the war.
                    They were mortally wounded in the same battle, recognized each other, crawled
                    near each other, and died.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>The page includes advertisements, legal notices, and anecdotes.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1865.03.08.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Lieut. Gen. Grant</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Discusses a telegram from Gen. Grant to Secretary Stanton, reporting the
                    capture of Charlottesville, Virginia, by Gen. Sheridan. The author predicts that
                    Sheridan moves towards Lynchburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Abraham Lincoln</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"he was this time free from personal perils, . . . Four years ago, he was
                    surrounded by skulking assassins, and a population that heartily sympathized
                    with those who sought revolution."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes the inauguration of Lincoln and discusses the changed
                    circumstances of the country. The author believes that the perils of peace
                    threaten, instead of the perils of war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Military Situation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Speculates on the direction of Sherman's advance, Lee's intentions, and
                    Grant reaction to Lee's movements. The author notes that the Union forces
                    greatly outnumber the Confederates.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Coffroth Explains</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"'I feared more the praise of my political foes than I did the criticism of
                    my friends.'"</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Gen. Coffroth has written an elaborate letter to Mr. Weyland of Somerset in
                        defence of his vote in favor of the amendment to the constitution abolishing
                        slavery, and in vindication of his consistency as a Democrat; but he seems
                        to have failed to satisfy Mr. Weyland "or any other man" on that side of the
                        House. From this extraordinary epistle we learn that Gen. Coffroth knew in
                        advance that when he cast his vote his "political enemies, in order to
                        exasperate Democrats, would be fulsome in their praise," and he adds "I
                        feared more the praise of my political foes than I did the criticism of my
                        friends." As to the criticism of his friends, we cannot pretend to speak
                        advisedly; but we are not perspicacious enough to see where the "fulsome"
                        adulation of his enemies comes in. He will bear as a witness that we have
                        not been malicious enough to speak well of him in terms of unusual
                        extravagance, and we are not aware that any of the Union journals of the
                        district have been so ungenerous as to damn him with violent approbation;
                        while it must be confessed that the criticism of the Democracy has been
                        rather more candid than complimentary. We assure Gen. Coffroth also by way
                        of "indemnity for the past and security for the future," that we shall be
                        more careful hereafter not to shock his sensibilities with rude
                        commendations relative to his Congressional career. To the best of our
                        knowledge he has cast but one vote on the side of patriotism during two
                        sessions, and that he has been persistently trying to explain into suspicion
                        or positive disrepute ever since. Rest easy, General, you shall not fall by
                        the "fulsome" praise of your foes.</p>
                    <p>But Gen. Coffroth goes into the future. When no one was accusing him in any
                        public manner of a disreputable compact with certain Republicans to secure a
                        seat in the next Congress, in the face of his defeat by the people, he
                        rushes to his own vindication, and insists that if any person should happen
                        to think he was so influenced in his vote, they must be at once undeceived.
                        He gives the world to know that he don't affiliate with Republicans, or
                        Abolitionists as he calls them. He did not mean to give vitality to the
                        Republicans by his vote, but he launched it forth upon them with death and
                        widespread destruction. He says--"I assure the abolitionists that are now
                        praising me, I did not vote for the amendment on account of any love for
                        their party or their principles, <emph rend="italic">but it was to stab
                            them!</emph></p>
                    <p>Thus while Coffroth has been censured by thoughtless friends for supporting a
                        favorite dogma of the Republicans, he was in fact playing the part of
                        political assassin and meant by one grand sweep of strategy to kill and
                        entomb the opposition to the Democracy. So far from being the apostate of
                        Democracy, he would prove himself the Brutus of Republicanism and go down in
                        history as the hero who bought gifts to weave in chaplets for the dead. When
                        the impartial limner comes to paint the startling events of the last
                        Congress and the death of the Republican organization, the central figure of
                        that panorama must be the Brutus of the 16th district, with the dying party
                        uttering its last sad words--<emph rend="italic">Et tute Coffroth!</emph></p>
                    <p>Two reasons are given in detail by Gen. Coffroth for the vote in question. He
                        voted for the amendment to destroy the Republican party by destroying
                        slavery and again he tells his constituents that he voted for it to run a
                        corner on the President because the States would inevitably defeat its
                        adoption! Profoundly logical! Since both propositions cannot be accepted,
                        will the General oblige us with a brief letter of not over several columns
                        telling us just what he did mean when he cast the vote for the amendment?
                        Had he been silent, his vote would have needed no explanation. It would have
                        stood forever as a record of which himself and his children could have been
                        proud; but since he has given half a score of reasons for it at different
                        times, no two of which harmonize with each other, and all of which confront
                        the vote itself, we beg the General to give us one sensible explanation of
                        his explanations, and then--stop!</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Recounts Republican and Democrat reactions to Coffroth's vote in favor of
                    the amendment to abolish slavery. The author ridicules Coffroth's reasoning that
                    the end of slavery would destroy Republican party and eventually embarrass
                    Lincoln when the states defeat the amendment. The author accuses Coffroth of
                    giving contradictory reasons and demands a "sensible explanation" or none at
                    all.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces the passage of the bill authorizing an additional $200 raised by
                    taxation to pay volunteers in Franklin County. The bill authorizing Guilford and
                    Green Townships to pay $300 to drafted men or their families has not passed in
                    the Senate.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes the single change in Lincoln's cabinet. Hon. Hugh McCulloch of
                    Indiana replaces Fessenden in the Treasury.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The draft . . .</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"It has fallen with peculiar harshness upon our people, and it has been the
                    more keenly felt because of the wide spread conviction that our quotas are
                    unwarrantably large."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Complains that the draft is unfairly heavy in Franklin County, especially
                    given the losses already suffered.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Major Dodge</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Celebrates the removal of Major Dodge, the Assistant Provost Marshal of
                    Pennsylvania, and replacement by Gen. Hinks. The author believes that Dodge
                    failed to act honorably in his office.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Arlington Place. The Home of the Traitor Robert E. Lee--Mournful Evidences of
                    Treason's Work--Saints for the Capture of Charleston--Soldiers' Cemetery--The
                    Buildings and Grounds--The Retribution.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>"A. K. M."</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes the home of Robert E. Lee, the capture of Charleston, and the
                    soldiers' cemetery.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Harrisburg. Adjournment to Attend the Inauguration. Local Bounty Bills--The
                    Claim Bill Reported--Payment Negatives--The Appropriation Bill--Gov.
                    Curtin--Removal of Major Dodge--Pennsylvania and the Cabinet.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>"Horace"</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>"Horace" reports news from Harrisburg on the Pennsylvania legislature. The
                    bill for the adjudication of claims for war damages in the border counties has
                    been reported to the House, with the "proviso that the State shall not assume
                    the payment of any part of said claims."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Negroes As Soldiers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"'I think the measure not only expedient, but necessary. . . . with the
                    condition of emancipation to all enrolled a sufficient number would be
                    forthcoming to enable us to try the experiment."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Discusses the successful efforts by the federal government to incorporate
                    black men into the military. The author praises blacks for their performance as
                    soldiers. The article includes articles and statements by Gen. Lee that show a
                    similar sentiment in the Confederacy. The Confederates realize they will need
                    the manpower of their slaves to win the war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Inauguration of President Lincoln! Immense Procession! The Oath Administered
                    to the President and Vice President! Inaugural Address of President Lincoln
                    Delivered! Unbounded Enthusiasm Of The People! The Inaugural Address!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes the inauguration of President Lincoln.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1865.03.08.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>At Home</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDowell</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>J. Porter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eiker</ln>
                        <fn>D. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Caufman</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heck</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGrath</ln>
                        <fn>A. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinsler</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Provides an update on the status of the Franklin County residents
                    imprisoned by the Confederates. Thomas H. McDowell returned home by using
                    trickery to get a parole. He reports that J. Porter Brown, D. M. Eiker, and
                    George Caufman escaped on February 18. George Heck, A. C. McGrath and Charles
                    Kinsler remain in prison.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Capt. James R. Gilmore</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilmore</ln>
                        <fn>James R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports a reference to James R. Gilmore, of Franklin County, in the New
                    South newspaper printed in Port Royal. Gilmore manages the telegraphic
                    communication of the army as the Superintendent of Military Telegraphs.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Promotions</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kurtz</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snively</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>1st Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bonebrake</ln>
                        <fn>H. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>2nd Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Porter</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sergt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces the promotions of Co. G, 17th Pa. Cavalry: Kurtz to major, Daniel
                    Snively to captain, H. G. Bonebrake to first lieutenant, and Jacob Porter to
                    second lieutenant.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The 77th Regiment Mounted</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rose</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes the mounting of the 77th Regiment, under Col. Rose, to become part of
                    Gen. Thomas' army.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilmore</ln>
                        <fn>James R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports the display of two bricks from Fort Sumter, sent by Gilmore, at
                    Nixon's store.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Gone To The Front</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hullinger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces that Capt. Hullinger and Co. D, 21st Pa. Cavalry joins their
                    regiment at the front after duty in Schuykill and other counties.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Personal</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Mentions news on John Burns, Gens. Crook and Kelly, and Gen. Joseph E.
                    Johnston.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Summary Of War News.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Summarizes news on the rebel evacuation of Georgetown and the four hundred
                    and fifty pieces of ordnance captured during the attack on Charleston.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Finance And Trade</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLanahan</ln>
                        <fn>James C.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ruthrauff</ln>
                        <fn>Jonathan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snively</ln>
                        <fn>Melchi</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shook</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rowe</ln>
                        <fn>Jonathan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zeigler</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilhelm</ln>
                        <fn>Jonathan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingerd</ln>
                        <fn>A. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crowell</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craig</ln>
                        <fn>Jesse</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bradley</ln>
                        <fn>S. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gehr</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharpe</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces Congress' passage of a bill for a new loan of $600,000,000 to be
                    issued at no more than 7-30 per annum. Congress guards against any increase of
                    currency. The organization of the First National Bank of Greencastle includes
                    James C. McLanahan, Jonathan Ruthrauff, Melchi Snively, Jacob Shook, Jonathan
                    Rowe, George W. Zeigler, Jonathan Wilhelm, A. B. Wingerd, Jacob B. Crowell,
                    Jesse Craig, and S. A. Bradley. McLanahan serves as the president. The
                    Repository defends its warning to banks to be careful about expansion. Reports
                    that Gehr and Sharpe went to Pittsburgh to inquire into the Cherry Run and
                    Pittsburgh Company.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Howe</ln>
                        <fn>Wesley</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoover</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rhodes</ln>
                        <fn>Elmira</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rhodes</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On February 23, at the home of the bride's father, by Rev. Howe, John
                    Hoover, of Greenvillage married Elmira Rhodes, of Hopewell Township, Cumberland
                    County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dyson</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Noggle</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Douse</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On February 28, by Rev. Dyson, Jacob Noggle married Catharine Douse, both
                    of Quincy Township</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dyson</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kimble</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Warden</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On March 5, by Rev. Dyson, John Kimble married Margaret Warden, of
                    Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On March 6, in Chambersburg, Wright died at 85 years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kauffman</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On March 1, near Upper Strasburg, Kauffman died at 64 years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sackman</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On February 18, in St. Thomas, Catharine Sackman, died at 39 years, 5
                    months and 22 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>The page includes advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1865.03.08.04">
            <pageNote>The page includes advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
