<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1865/pa.fr.fr.1865.09.06">
    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/18/00</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1865-09-06">
            <year>1865</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day>06</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1865.09.06.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Richmond</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Frater</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Another installment from Frater, the Repository's correspondent in
                    Richmond. In the article, Frater continues his tour of the war-ravaged city,
                    detailing the immense carnage that occurred during the late conflict.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>A Woman On "Waterfall"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"Mrs. L. Maria Child writes a letter to the Independent, in the course
                    of which she uses the following language inregard to the latest fashions in
                    hair:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An extract from a letter in which the writer, a woman, lambastes the latest
                    style in women's bonnets, asserting that women who sport this new trend could
                    easily be mistaken as "Ojibbeway squaws." The "new head-gear," she maintains,
                    "looks more like a cabbage in a net, tricked out with heads and wampum" than a
                    waterfall, as it is named.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1865.09.06.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McConaughy</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On September 2nd, the district conference unanimously adopted David
                    McConaughy as the Union candidate for State Senator.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Democratic Ticket</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We give elsewhere in to-day's paper the proceedings of the Democratic County
                        Convention which met here on Monday of last week, and nominated a ticket.
                        The Chambersburg patriots bore off every nomination for offices of honor and
                        profit, and the rural districts were left to gather up the odds and ends at
                        the tale end of the ticket. The town has the nominees for Senator, Assembly,
                        Sheriff, and District Attorney--the entire oyster, and the shell goes to
                        their Democratic brethren of the county persuasion. For people who like such
                        tickets, they are, we presume, just the kind that such people like, and if
                        the Democracy is content, we shan't complain. Considering that Chambersburg,
                        where all the honors are crowded, will give from two hundred and fifty to
                        three hundred against the entire list, the compliment to the Concords,
                        Letterkennys, Quincys, &amp;c., which are to give the majorities, can be
                        fully appreciated.</p>
                    <p>The nomination of C. M. Duncan for Senator was a grave political blunder,
                        looking alike to the immediate and ultimate interests of the party, and to
                        the momentous interests of the border people in case the Democratic
                        nominations should be ratified by the people. Mr. Duncan is young,
                        inexperienced, and without claims to the position other than as a mere
                        partizan of the most ultra school. He secured his nomination solely by
                        untiring effort, and against the manifest wishes of the party; but as he had
                        the field to himself until ten days before the Convention, while Mr. Sharpe
                        made no personal exertions at any time to procure delegates, the result is
                        not surprising. In the North Ward, where both reside, a fair contest was had
                        for the delegates, and Sharpe defeated Duncan by two to one, and yet Duncan
                        is made the nominee against the overwhelming protest of his own ward and
                        immediate neighbors. There are men who would have declined a further contest
                        after such a verdict from his own immediate constituents; but Mr. Duncan is
                        of the bolder class and does not become appalled at little conventionalities
                        of that sort. Politically speaking we should not complain of the nomination
                        of Mr. Duncan, as it will chill the ardor of many of the best men in the
                        party, who feel that the wishes of the Democracy were deliberately defied by
                        the Convention.</p>
                    <p>Mr. M'Lellan was nominated for Assembly without the formality of a
                        ballot--the party taking to the new convert with the tenderest evidences of
                        affection. He made a speech accepting the nomination, in which he expressly
                        disclaimed any partizan purpose, and stated that the interests of the
                        plundered border only compelled him to accept. Whether his manifest
                        reluctance related to the company he was in, or the position for which he
                        was nominated, we are not advised; but inasmuch as he announced his purpose
                        to support President Johnson's policy, we infer that he meant to make his
                        own platform in advance within the folds of his new circle of associates.
                        Many years of intimate personal and professional association with Mr.
                        McLellan could not but make us testify to his blameless character, and his
                        unusual candor and integrity as a politician; and we are anxious to see
                        whether he will advocate the destructive measures of the Democratic party,
                        and if so, how he will undertake to do it. He may prove how far a man may
                        lean toward the wrong and yet escape it, or he may demonstrate how a fair
                        man may be mastered by the wrong and scarcely know it. We part regretfully
                        with him in our political struggles, but our paths of duty diverge and the
                        issues at stake rise above all personal considerations in the pending
                        conflict.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Stenger is re-nominated for District Attorney, and, with Duncan, will be
                        the master spirit of the contest. He won his commission three years ago, in
                        defiance of the army vote which defeated him, and the constitution did not
                        then confer the right of suffrage upon our soldiers; but now there will be a
                        fair poll and a full vote, of soldiers and citizens, and his competitor is
                        one of our most gallant veterans who is morally certain to conduct the
                        prosecutions of the county, during the next three years. The rest of the
                        ticket is of little moment. The election of Cap. Doebler for Sheriff is
                        conceded on all hands and Mr. Boyd won a barren honor without a serious
                        contest. The resolutions reaffirm the Democartic State platform and demand
                        restitution for military damages.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duncan</ln>
                        <fn>C. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLellan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyd</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doebler</ln>
                        <fn>Cap</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stenger</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>After noting that the Democratic County ticket is dominated by men from
                    Chambersburg, the editors offer a critique of each of the men selected to
                    represent the party in the election. In particular, they take the Democrats to
                    task for their nominee for State Senate, C. M. Duncan, labeling the decision "a
                    grave political blunder."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Adams County</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article congratulates the Union men of Adams county for selecting "a
                    ticket of peculiar personal and political strength." As in Franklin county,
                    several of the nominees are former soldiers "who have won their scars and fame
                    on the sanguinary field."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Jay Cooke, The Subscription Agent</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article extols the financial acumen and virtues of Jay Cooke who played
                    a significant role throughout the war selling bonds to cover the government's
                    vast expenditures.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is reported that 3,500,000 barrels of oil were produced in Pennsylvania
                    in 1865, worth roughly $24,000,000. Once refined the oil was valued at
                    $60,000,000, or about half as much as the state's wheat crop.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A notice that a book about the rebellion will soon be published by Stebbine
                    of Hartford. The author of the study is Thomas P. Kettell, "a well known writer"
                    who is "particularly noted for research and accuracy."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Assess The Soldiers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An article reminding readers that all returning soldiers must be assessed
                    if they wish to vote. Those who fail to do so will forfeit that right.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1865.09.06.sgml.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Stultified Soldier</head>
                <origin>Philadelphia Press</origin>
                <commentary>"The Philadelphia Press, after a scathing review of the Democratic
                    platform of this State, thus refers to Col. Davis, the soldier who has accepted
                    a nomination for Auditor General on a platform that is a blistering libel upon
                    his heroism in the field:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The piece unleashes a blistering attack on Col. Davis for his support for
                    the Democratic Party during the war. In particular, the article chides the
                    veteran for the views that emanated from his newspaper,which offered veiled
                    support for the Confederate cause.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henshey</ln>
                        <fn>B. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On August 21st, B. B. Henshey, formerly the druggist of Chambersburg, and
                    Emma Wintermule, of Terra Haute, Indiana, were married in Indiana by Rev.
                    Simpson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heckman</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gelwicks</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McHenry</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Sept. 3rd, John A. Heckman and Maggie Gelwicks were married by Rev. S.
                    McHenry.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn>John Johnston</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On August 21st, John Johnston Campbell, 35, died near Concord.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On August 23rd, Elizabeth S. Crawford, widow of the late Hugh Crawford,
                    died at her residence in Guilford. She was 99 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1865.09.06.sgml.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
