<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1865/pa.fr.fr.1865.04.05">
	<header>
		<title type="uniform">Franklin Repository</title>
		<tagger>
			<taggerName>Sally Henninger, 1st pass; Susanna Michele Lee, 2nd pass, 1/5/99</taggerName>
			<tagDate/>
			<tagNote/>
		</tagger>
		<address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
		<date n="1865-04-05">
			<year>1865</year>
			<month norm="04">April</month>
			<day>5</day>
			<weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
		</date>
		<frequency>weekly</frequency>
		<extent>04</extent>
		<editionNote/>
	</header>
	<paperBody>
		<page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1865.04.05.01">
			<pageNote>The page includes advertisements, legal notices, a poem entitled "Back From
				Libby," an article on an Indian tradition, and anecdotes.</pageNote>
		</page>
		<page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1865.04.05.02">
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Richmond Has Fallen!</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt>The rebel capital; the last rebel strong-hold, has surrendered to the
					matchless heroism of the Army of the Potomac. The hope so long deferred has at
					last reached the ful[l]ness of fruition, and the soldiers of crime retire from
					their long and stubbornly defended citadel of power, with their last army
					shattered to fragments; with no safety in retreat; no hope in further resistance
					to the overwhelming might of the brave defenders of the Republic.</excerpt>
				<transcript>
					<p>The rebel capital; the last rebel strong-hold, has surrendered to the
						matchless heroism of the Army of the Potomac. The hope so long deferred has
						at last reached the ful[l]ness of fruition, and the soldiers of crime retire
						from their long and stubbornly defended citadel of power, with their last
						army shattered to fragments; with no safety in retreat; no hope in further
						resistance to the overwhelming might of the brave defenders of the Republic.</p>
					<p>Let loyal men rejoice! We have had victories before--the same dauntless
						courage; equal endurance in the defense of the right; but never has a
						triumph been achieved so crowning in the measure of its results--so utterly
						destructive to the country's foes. It leaves them without an army; without a
						government; without credit; without hope. It is the great retributive stroke
						which in the ful[l]ness of His time, has vindicated Humanity and Justice!</p>
					<p>It proclaims the safety of the Republic! Centuries hence, when the heroism of
						the last four years will still be undimmed on the shifting canvass of the
						past, the victories which culminated in the possession of Richmond, will be
						pointed to as the fields where the sons of the North baptized their Freedom
						in their noblest blood, and re-achieved their title to their proud
						inheritance--the best, the most beneficent government on earth.</p>
					<p>All honor to the gallant Army of the Potomac! How nobly it has struggled,
						undaunted by defeat against the choicest troops of the foe, let its
						sacrifices on the Peninsula, at Antietam, at Fredericksburg, at
						Chancellorsville, at Gettysburg, and from the Wilderness to the South-side
						road and Richmond tell. It has made the heroism of all armies in the history
						of warfare pale before its unfaltering courage, and grand achievements; and
						now it fitly crowns the glory of the war by striking the last great blow to
						make treason hated by all the living, and shunned by all who shall live
						hereafter. Gratefully indeed will a long imperiled Nation cherish the noble
						deeds; the patient endurance; the unflagging gallantry of the Army of the
						Potomac, and the memory of its slain--rich sacrifices to the madness of
						treason--will live in perpetual freshness in every patriot heart.</p>
					<p>The Republic is rescued from the murderous grasp of Treason, thanks to a
						faithful North and to a just and beneficent God!</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Describes the surrender of Richmond.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>The Niagara Peace Effort</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt>"It is now due alike to Mr. Greeley, to the President and to the country
					that the entire correspondence be given to the public, and we hope to see it
					published in a very few days. When it shall appear many who censured President
					Lincoln for the course he was induced to take will feel that he acted then, as
					ever, with enlightened judgment and unfaltering fidelity to our imperiled
					government."</excerpt>
				<transcript>
					<p>We give in another column of to-day's paper a letter written to the President
						in July last, by Mr. Greeley, of the <emph rend="italic">Tribune</emph>, on
						the necessity of proposing or receiving terms of adjustment to close the
						war. Important as is everything coming from the pen of the ablest journalist
						and one of the most intelligent and experienced politicians of the Nation,
						this letter of Mr. Greeley possesses especial importance, because of the
						fact that it was the opening of a correspondence that resulted in the
						memorable letter of Mr. Greeley possesses especial importance, because of
						the fact that it was the opening of a correspondence that resulted in the
						memorable letter of President Lincoln, addressed "To Whom it May Concern,"
						and proposing terms of peace for the consideration of certain rebel leaders
						then in Canada.</p>
					<p>The remarkable letter of the President borne by Maj. Hay to be delivered to
						Messrs. Sanders, Clay and Holcombe, prominent rebel civilians then at
						Niagara, as it then appeared in the public prints without any explanation of
						the circumstances which called it forth, astounded the Nation, and staggered
						many of the truest friends of the administration. Few condemned, but there
						were few who did not regret that such a letter had been written and so
						delivered, as it appeared to afford the rebel leaders the very pretext they
						most desired to "fire the Southern heart," and unite their desponding and
						divided people in support of the rebellion. All the public knew was that
						Messrs. Clay, Holcomb and Sanders were in Canada; that they had been visited
						by prominent Democratic politicians--such as Hon. Jere. S. Black, Gov.
						Bigler, Senator Buckaiew and others of this State; that a crazy adventurer
						named Jewett had been peddling peace propositions to and from everybody with
						whom he could get audience; but in all this there was no visible motive for
						a declaration from Mr. Lincoln in the midst of a Presidential struggle, of
						terms of adjustment which the rebels would most certainly then reject, and
						which might weaken, but could not possibly strengthen the administration and
						its cause.</p>
					<p>We are glad that the letter of Mr. Greeley has found its way into the public
						prints. How it happened to come to us by way of England--as it first
						appeared in the Manchester<emph rend="italic">Examiner</emph>--is of no
						consequence. It is enough that it is now public property; that the door to
						the secret working of the Niagara Peace effort has been unlocked, and we may
						now learn the whole history of that comedy of errors. Mr. Greeley opened the
						correspondence on the subject with the letter we print to-day, and it will
						be observed how earnest is the tone that pervades his sentences in behalf of
						peace. He sought peace not because it would have been right in the abstract,
						or because such a peace was then attainable as the Nation and its great
						cause should command; but he earnestly sought peace to save "fresh
						conscriptions;" "further wholesale devastations;" "new rivers of human
						blood," and to save some little of "our bleeding, bankrupt, almost dying
						country." These considerations in connection with "the momentous election
						soon to occur in North Carolina" and the "draft to be enforced in the Free
						States," induce Mr. Greely to demand, in the most positive terms that Mr.
						Lincoln should do something to prove to all, loyal and disloyal, that he was
						not prosecuting war merely for the love of war.</p>
					<p>This letter was written in July last--just at the darkest period of the year;
						when gloom hung over the Nation like a pall, paralyzing its energies and
						wasting its hopes. Grant had reached the James without decisive results,
						after an appalling sacrifice of life; Sherman had been fought at every step
						from Chattanooga on his perilous march to Atlanta, and his success was
						deemed more than doubtful; new levies had to be ordered to save the
						country's cause; our credit was more depressed than ever before, and the
						shrewdest of politicians confessed the Presidential contest lost miles saved
						to Mr. Lincoln by the folly of his foes, as it was by the Chicago platform.
						It was, under these circumstances that Mr. Greely wrote, and he was
						evidently prepared for peace on almost any terms that would save us a
						respectable semblance of government, and he insisted that unless terms were
						proposed, or notice given that terms would be received and considered, all
						was inevitably lost. The <emph rend="italic">Tribune</emph> was then as now
						the most powerful political organ of the Nation, and an expression in its
						columns of the convictions of its chief editor as given to Mr. Lincoln in
						the letter in question, would have been a confession of hopeless
						discomfiture alike in the pending political struggle, and in the attempts to
						preserve the Union by an appeal to the arburament [sic] of the sword.</p>
					<p>So much the public are now advised of by Mr. Greeley's letter; but the whole
						story is far from being told. No public explanation of the "To Whom It May
						Concern" letter was made by the President, because it could not be done
						without giving to the world Mr. Greeley's first letter, in which there were
						such sad, and as events have proved, such groundless confessions of
						political and National weakness. Such a letter published at any time before
						November 1864, would have been the most potent political document the
						Vallandighams and Woods could have circulated, and it would have been worth
						a corps to the insurgent army. It could not therefore, be given to the
						world, and without it there could be no explanation of the series of events
						which led the President to startle the country by proposing terms of
						adjustment to the rebel citizens in Canada. But now the Nation can afford to
						have the whole history of this bungling diplomacy, and we trust that it will
						be speedily given to the public. Some twenty letters and dispatches passed
						between the President and Mr. Greeley on the subject before the President
						consented to take the step proposed and then, as his letters and dispatches
						will show, he did it with the extremest reluctance, without hope of its
						success, and accepted it only as a lesser evil than have so powerful an
						organ as the<emph rend="italic">Tribune</emph> practically surrender the
						Presidential election and the war.</p>
					<p>When the entire correspondence shall be published, as we doubt not it will at
						an early day, it will be seen that the President fully vindicated himself
						for refusing Mr. Stephens safe conduct to Washington, and that he clearly
						foresaw the result that attended his proposition, but as a necessity he
						accepted the condition imposed, and framed his terms of adjustment in
						substantial accordance with Mr. Greeley's suggestions. In other words, he
						proposed such terms of peace as Mr. Greeley who plead the claims of the
						informal rebel commission as to [illegible] proposition laid down for his
						guidance and such as Mr. Greeley evidently believed and affirmed would prove
						acceptable to the Southern people.</p>
					<p>It is now due alike to Mr. Greeley, to the President and to the country that
						the entire correspondence be given to the public, and we hope to see it
						published in a very few days. When it shall appear many who censured
						President Lincoln for the course he was induced to take will feel that he
						acted then, as ever, with enlightened judgment and unfaltering fidelity to
						our imperiled government.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Details the correspondence between Horace Greeley and Abraham Lincoln which
					began last July. Greeley urged Lincoln to discuss a peaceful end of the war with
					rebel citizens in Canada. The correspondence occurred during a time of Union
					defeats, high casualties, and financial instability.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>2</column>
				<head/>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>The author reports that the Repository has received no information on the
					location of Lee. Still, the author asserts that Lee can not avoid an engagement
					with Union forces.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>2</column>
				<head/>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt>"It is a remarkable fact that the hot-bed of treason has been captured by
					negro troops. General Weitzel, commander of Gen. Butler's negro brigade, was the
					first to enter that doomed city with his brave soldiers, and the 'first
					families' are now under military rule with dark skins."</excerpt>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Describes the military rule in Richmond. The author remarks on the irony of
					"military rule with dark skins" in the "hot-bed of treason."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>3</column>
				<head>Washington. Large Number of Rebel Deserters in Washington--Charges between
					Washington and City Point--Order from the War Department on Raising the Old Flag
					over Sumpter--Bewilderment of the New York papers as to who was the Hero of Fort
					Steadman--Supplemental Draft in the District--Orders to Returned Prisoners</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer>"S. C."</trailer>
				<names/>
				<summary>Describes the rebel deserters in Washington, the capture of Fort Sumter,
					the heroes of the capture of Fort Steadman, the supplemental draft, and orders
					to returned prisoners.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>3</column>
				<head>Harrisburg. The Deserted Village--Perplexities of Our Correspondent--The Draft
					in this District--Pennsylvania and her Executive--Political Gossip--Jack
					Heistund for Auditor General.</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer>"Horace"</trailer>
				<names/>
				<summary>Describes Harrisburg as quiet, the importance of Pennsylvanian troops, and
					the support for Jack Heistund for Auditor General.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Personal</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Sanno</ln>
						<fn>Michael</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Major</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Reports Gen. Anderson's progress toward Charleston to raise the flag over
					Fort Sumter, the admission of 350 children of deceased soldiers to orphan
					schools in Pennsylvania, Lincoln's visit with Gen. Grant within six miles of
					Richmond, and the death of Major Sanno, of Carlisle, on March 20.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Summary Of War News</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Details the rebels' fear of their black troops, the refusal of prisoners
					captured at Fort Steadman to be exchanged, the arrangement of a treaty between
					the rebels in Texas and the Indians, the rebel loss of ten guns and 7,000
					prisoners in the battle of Bentonsville, and Lee's capture of 9 cannon, 8
					mortars and between 500 to 600 soldiers during the Fort Steadman engagement.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>6</column>
				<head>The Niagara Falls Peace Negotiations</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt>"And therefore I venture to remind you that our bleeding, bankrupt, almost
					dying country also longs for peace--shudders at the prospect of fresh
					conscriptions, of further wholesale devastations, and of new rivers of human
					blood; and a wide-spread conviction that the Government and its prominent
					supporters are not anxious for peace, and cannot improve proffered opportunities
					to achieve it, is doing great harm now, and is morally certain, unless removed,
					to do far greater in the approaching elections."</excerpt>
				<transcript>
					<p>New York, July 7, 1864</p>
					<p>My Dear Sir: I venture to inclose you a letter and telegraphic dispatch that
						I received yesterday from our irrepressible friend Colorado Jewett, at
						Niagara Falls. I think they deserve attention. Of course I do not indorse
						Jewett's positive averment that his friends at the Falls have "full powers"
						from J.D., though I do not doubt that he thinks they have. I let that
						statement stand as simply evidencing the anxiety of the confederates
						everywhere for peace. So much is beyond doubt.</p>
					<p>And therefore I venture to remind you that our bleeding, bankrupt, almost
						dying country also longs for peace--shudders at the prospect of fresh
						conscriptions, of further wholesale devastations, and of new rivers of human
						blood; and a wide-spread conviction that the Government and its prominent
						supporters are not anxious for peace, and cannot improve proffered
						opportunities to achieve it, is doing great harm now, and is morally
						certain, unless removed, to do far greater in the approaching elections.</p>
					<p>It is not enough that we anxiously desire a true and lasting peace; we ought
						to demonstrate and establish the truth beyond cavil. The fact that A.H.
						Stephens was not permitted a year ago to visit and confer with the
						authorities at Washington, has done harm, which the tone at the late
						National Convention at Baltimore is not calculated to counteract.</p>
					<p>I entreat you, in your own time and manner, to submit overtures for
						pacification to the Southern insurgents, which the impartial must pronounce
						frank and generous. If only with a view to the moment[o]us election soon to
						occur in North Carolina, and of the draft to be enforced in the Free States,
						this should be done at once. I would give the safe conduct required by the
						Rebel envoys at Niagara, upon their parole to avoid observation and to
						refrain from all communication with their sympathizers in the loyal States;
						but you may see reasons for declining it. But whether through them or
						otherwise, do not, I entreat you, fail to make the Southern people
						comprehend that you, and all of us, are anxious for peace, and prepared to
						grant liberal terms. I venture to suggest the following</p>
					<p>Plan of Adjustment.<lb/>1. The Union is restored and declared
						perpetual.<lb/>2. Slavery is utterly and forever abolished throughout the
						same.<lb/>3. A complete amnesty for all political offences, with a
						restoration of all the inhabitants of each State to all the privileges of
						citizens of the United States.<lb/>4. The Union to pay four hundred million
						dollars ($400,000,000) in five per cent United States stock to the late
						Slave States, loyal and secession alike, to be apportioned <emph
							rend="italic">pro rata</emph>, according to their Slave population
						respectively, by the census of 1860, in compensation for the losses of their
						loyal citizens by the abolition of Slavery. Each state is to be entitled to
						its quota upon the ratification by its Legislature of this adjustment. The
						bonds to be at the absolute disposal of the Legislature afor[e]said.</p>
					<p><lb/>5. The said Slave States to be entitled henceforth to representation in
						the House on the basis of their total, instead of their Federal population,
						the whole now being free.<lb/>6. A National Convention to be assembled so
						soon as may be, to ratify this adjustment, and make such changes in the
						Constitution as may be deemed advisable.</p>
					<p>Mr. President, I fear you do not realize how intently the people desire any
						Peace consistent with the National Integrity and honor, and how joyously
						they would hail its achievement, and bless its authors. With United States
						stocks worth but 40 cents in gold per dollar, and drafting about to commence
						on the third million of Union soldiers, can this be wondered at?</p>
					<p>I do not say that a just Peace is now attainable, though I believe it to be
						so. But I do say that a frank offer by you to the insurgents of terms which
						the impartial world say ought to be accepted will at the worst, prove an
						immense and sorely needed advantage to the National cause. It may save us us
						[sic] from a Northern insurrection.</p>
					<p>Yours truly, Horace Greeley.</p>
					<p>Hon. A. Lincoln, President, Washington, D.C.</p>
					<p>P.S.--Even though it should be deemed unadvisable to make an offer of terms
						to the Rebels, I insist that, in any possible case, it is desirable that any
						offer they may be disposed to make should be received, and either accepted
						or rejected. I beg you to invite those now at Niagara to exhibit their
						credentials and submit their ultimatum.</p>
					<p>H.G.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Reprints Horace Greeley's initial letter to Lincoln, in which he gave a
					"plan of adjustment" that includes abolishing slavery with compensation.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look>**</look>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>7</column>
				<head>The Battle Of Bentonville</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Reports that Gen. Schofield occupied Goldsboro and Major General Terry
					secured Cox's bridge.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1865.04.05.03">
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>About The Draft</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Eyster</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Capt.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Lists the numbers of men provided by the districts in Franklin County that
					provided: Antrim-55, Greencastle-5, Fannett-12, Green-17, Guilford-15,
					Hamilton-26, Letterkenny-43, Lurgan-11, Metal-8, Montgomery-66, Mercersburg-5,
					Peters-2, Quincy-46, St. Thomas-4, Washington-31, Waynesboro-12. Franklin County
					sent 348 of the 1,048 men sent to the front by Provost Marshal Capt. Eyster. The
					article also lists substitute brokers who unsuccessfully attempted to deceive
					Capt. Eyster.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>The Cheering News</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt>"Little girls clapped their hands and waved their handkerchiefs, and
					stout-hearted men who have been bereaved by the murderous work of treason, wept
					tears of joy."</excerpt>
				<transcript>
					<p>The news of the capture of Richmond practically suspended business here on
						Monday last. Citizens greeted each other on every hand, and the church bells
						rang out their loudest peals proclaiming to the world that the death-blow
						had been given to the rebellion. Groups were to be seen on every corner
						discussing the great event, and planning out Grant's pursuit of the defeated
						Lee; and the telegraph offices were thronged during all the afternoon by
						anxious men, women and children, to get the details of the news. The schools
						were dismissed at noon, soon after the official announcement was received,
						and the boys made the welkin ring with their hearty shouts for the triumphs
						of the brave Union army. Little girls clapped their hands and waved their
						handkerchiefs, and stout-hearted men who have been bereaved by the murderous
						work of treason, wept tears of joy. It was a memorable day in desolated
						Chambersburg, and our very blackened walls seemed to proclaim that they have
						been avenged by the valor of our heroic troops.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Details Chambersburg's celebration of the news of the capture of Richmond.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look>**</look>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>1</column>
				<head/>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Whitfield</ln>
						<fn>John</fn>
						<sf>Esq.</sf>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Reports that the Whitfield family, who moved to Chambersburg from
					McConnellsburg, and then to Philadelphia, were caught and killed in a coal oil
					fire in Philadelphia.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Casualties In The 209th</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Wolfe</ln>
						<fn>Jacob D.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Deitrich</ln>
						<fn>G. J.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Sergt.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Bard</ln>
						<fn>Robert</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Riddle</ln>
						<fn>George</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Bouser</ln>
						<fn>David</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Mann</ln>
						<fn>J. B.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Miller</ln>
						<fn>Joseph</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Rennecker</ln>
						<fn>A.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Sherman</ln>
						<fn>S. G.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Swanger</ln>
						<fn>D. C.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Strine</ln>
						<fn>J. G.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>McCulloh</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Capt.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Relates a report from Capt. McCulloh of the casulties in Co. D, 209th
					regiment: Killed--Wolfe (shot in the head); Wounded--Deitrich (arm and leg),
					Bard (head), Riddle (right arm), Bouser (shoulder), Mann (leg), Miller (left
					ankle), Rennecker (groin), Sherman (left hip), Swanger (hip), and Strine (head
					and right side).</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Paroled</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Lewis</ln>
						<fn>Alexander</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Reports the parole of Alexander Lewis, a black citizen of Chambersburg,
					captured at Winchester, Va., in June 1863. Lewis served as a cook for the 3rd
					Pa. Cavalry when captured.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Arrived At Nashville</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Brown</ln>
						<fn>J. Porter</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Eiker</ln>
						<fn>David M.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Caufman</ln>
						<fn>George</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Announces news from J. Porter Brown, David M. Eiker, and George Caufman,
					Chambersburg citizens who escaped from prison in Salisbury, N. C. the three men
					reached the Union lines at Nashville and head home.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>1</column>
				<head/>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Kinsler</ln>
						<fn>Charles</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Mr.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Charles Kinsler, of Chambersburg, who was captured by the rebels at
					Hagerstown in July 1863, died in Philadelphia last Friday. He was exchanged two
					weeks ago.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Postmaster Appointed</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Britton</ln>
						<fn>William W.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Slyder</ln>
						<fn>James S.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Announces the appointment of William W. Britton as postmaster at Upper
					Strasburg, to replace James S. Slyder who resigned.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>2</column>
				<head>Peace Dawns through Victory!! Richmond Fallen!! Petersburg Captured!! Three
					Days Of Deadly Conflict! Lee Routed At All Points! Over 15,000 Rebels Captured!
					Most of Their Guns And Materials Taken! Lee Retreating And Grant Pursuing!
					Sherman and Thomas Closing in on the Rebels!</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Discusses the fall of Richmond and the capture of Petersburg. The
					Confederates abandoned both Petersburg and Richmond.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>3</column>
				<head>The Patience Of Abraham Lincoln</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt>"'But, sir, you do not prove your Claim.' 'We are loyal, sir.' 'Yes, sir,
					and so are the men who stand up in front of Richmond to be shot at, but they do
					not come here to plague me.'"</excerpt>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Describes Lincoln's impatience with Georgian men claiming loyalty and
					demanding compensation for property damage.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>3</column>
				<head>Patriotic</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Relates that the Mennonites, at their annual conference, passed resolutions
					to support the Union's efforts to "crush the present wicked rebellion."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>3</column>
				<head>A Rich Haul</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Details the expensive possessions taken from three men fleeing from
					Richmond during its capture. One of the men moved to Richmond to take advantage
					of wartime money-making opportunities.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Latest from Richmond--Weitzel's Capture--Sheridan Picking up Lee's
					Stragglers--Lee's Army Utterly Routed</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Summarizes a report from Secretary Stanton.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Thanksgiving</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Reports that Gov. Curtin issued a proclamation of thanks at the capture of
					Richmond.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Rejoicing over the Victory Order from Gen. Cadwalder. Rejoicings in
					Washington. Rejoicings in Harrisburg. Rejoicings at Baltimore.</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Describes the celebrations in Washington, Harrisburg, and Baltimore.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Finance And Trade.</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Notes the continuation of the 7-30 loans and the further decline in gold
					prices following the capture of Richmond and Union successes. Advises people to
					stop hoarding their money because there is no scarcity.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Birch</ln>
						<fn>W. F.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Senseny</ln>
						<fn>B. Rush</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Dr.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Murdoch</ln>
						<fn>Rosa</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Miss</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Latham</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Mrs.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On March 22, at the home of the bride's aunt, Mrs. Latham, in Springfield,
					Illinois, by Rev. Birch, Dr. Senseny, of Chambersburg, married Rosa Murdoch, of
					St. Louis, Missouri.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Werdebaugh</ln>
						<fn>Emma Jane</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Werdebaugh</ln>
						<fn>John</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Werdebaugh</ln>
						<fn>Isabella</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Mrs.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On April 4, in Green Township, Emma, daughter of John and Isabella
					Werdebaugh, died at 7 months and 17 days.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Hursh</ln>
						<fn>Catharine</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On March 29, near Welsh Run, Catharine Hursh died of Consumption at 22
					years, 9 months, and 2 days.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Wolfe</ln>
						<fn>Jacob D.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Wolfe</ln>
						<fn>Jacob</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Jacob D. Wolfe, son of Jacob Wolfe, near Marion, was killed (shot in the
					head) at the battle of Fort Steadman on March 25. He was a member of Co. D,
					209th, Regiment Pa. Vols.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote>The page includes advertisements.</pageNote>
		</page>
		<page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1865.04.05.04">
			<pageNote>The page includes advertisements.</pageNote>
		</page>
	</paperBody>
</hwp>
