<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1865/pa.fr.fr.1865.07.26">
    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/26/00</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1865-07-26">
            <year>1865</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day>26</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1865.07.26.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Mrs. Surratt</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Since her execution there has been "some manifestations of expressions of
                    sympathy" for Mrs. Surratt. In an effort to disabuse individuals of this
                    misguided pity, the article presents portions of the evidence that surfaced
                    during the course of the conspiracy trial, evidence that clearly illustrates
                    that the woman was guilty of the charges leveled against her.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Horrors At Andersonville</head>
                <origin>Philadelphia Bulletin</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The history of the civilized world cannot furnish a more atrocious record
                    than that made up for themselves by the leaders of the rebellion, and among our
                    greatest reasons for thankfulness at the close of the war and the death of
                    slavery, is the fact that such horrible outrages on humanity can never more be
                    perpetrated."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A statement carefully prepared by one who had access to official documents,
                        and who was a prisoner himself, has been made out, showing the number of
                        deaths among Union prisoners at Andersonville, Georgia, from February, 1864,
                        to February 1865. The grand total is twelve thousand, eight hundred and
                        eighty four! The highest number of deaths in a single day was one hundred
                        and twenty-seven, the date being August 23, 1864, at which time thirty-two
                        thousand one hundred and ninety-three prisoners were confined there, being
                        the highest number ever imprisoned at that point. The statement was prepared
                        by Charles Lang, hospital steward of the 101st Pa. Regiment, who was
                        captured at Plymouth, N.C. Governor Curtin, who has been eagerly seeking for
                        a list of the Pennsylvania soldiers who died at Andersonville, has received
                        the full roll of Pennsylvania victims from this considerate soldier, and it
                        will be found on an inside page of our double-sheet to-day. The list will
                        also be published in pamphlet form by Surgeon-General Phillips. We
                        understand that the bodies of the victims cannot be removed until October,
                        and before that time Governor Curtin will probably announce the best and
                        most convenient way of securing such removals. The Governor is engaged at
                        this time in an effort to procure full lists of Pennsylvania soldiers who
                        died in other rebel prisons, and it is hoped that a list more or less
                        complete will soon be ready for publication. A statement of those who died
                        at Salisbury, N.C. will probably soon be made public.</p>
                    <p>Nothing has made so deep an impression on the heart of the loyal people as
                        the treatment of Union soldiers who fell into the fiendish hands of the
                        Southern military authorities. The evidence that a deliberate system of
                        starvation was practised accumulates every day. Henry S. Foote, late a rebel
                        Senator from Mississippi, is the most recent witness. In a letter in
                        reference to his efforts to get the Confederate Congress to investigate
                        these cruelties, he says:</p>
                    <p>"Touching the Congressional report referred to I have this to say: A month or
                        two anterior to the date of said report I learned, from a government officer
                        of respectability, that the prisoners of war then confined in and about
                        Richmond were suffering severely for want of provisions. He told me further,
                        that it was manifest to him that a systematic scheme was on foot for
                        subjecting these unfortunate men to starvation; that the Commissary General,
                        Mr. Northrop (a most wicked and heartless wretch), had addressed a
                        communication to Mr. Seddon, the Secretary of War, proposing to withhold
                        meat altogether from military prisoners then in custody, and to give them
                        nothing but bread and vegetables, and that Mr. Seddon had endorsed the
                        document containing this recommendation affirmatively. I learned further
                        that by calling upon Major Ould, the commissioner for exchange of prisoners,
                        I would be able to obtain further information on this subject. I went to Mr.
                        Ould immediately, and obtained the desired information. Being utterly
                        unwilling to countenance such barbarity for a moment, regarding indeed the
                        honor of the whole South as concerned in the affair, I proceeded without
                        delay to the hall of the House of Representatives, called the attention of
                        that strangely constituted body to the subject, and insisted upon an
                        immediate committee of investigation. I grieve to say that this was at first
                        refused, and I was most acrimoniously censured by several members for
                        introducing the subject in the House at all. But I resolved to have an
                        investigation, and to put a stop to such Vandalic atrocities if I could, or
                        at least to rescue my own character from menaced infamy by withdrawing from
                        all further connection with the Confederate cause at once. I introduced a
                        second resolution, next morning, and finally succeeded in getting the
                        committee raised. You will find, in addition to the report made by the
                        committee, a considerable mass of testimony of various kinds reported with
                        it, and among other documentary proofs, the official communications of the
                        Commissary General, above referred to, and the endorsement of Mr. Seddon
                        thereon, in which he substantially says that, in his judgement, the time had
                        arrived for retaliation upon the prisoners of war of the enemy."</p>
                    <p>The history of the civilized world cannot furnish a more atrocious record
                        than that made up for themselves by the leaders of the rebellion, and among
                        our greatest reasons for thankfulness at the close of the war and the death
                        of slavery, is the fact that such horrible outrages on humanity can never
                        more be perpetrated. The oligarchic system which tended to sanction such
                        indescribable cruelties has been ground to powder, not a vestige of it is
                        left, and the entire world has cause to sing to a paen of rejoicing at its
                        destruction.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A recently released report has ascertained that, between February 1864 and
                    February 1865, 12,884 prisoners died at Andersonville. According to the article,
                    a listing of the soldiers who perished will be published by Surgeon-General
                    Philips.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Mr. Nasby On Democratic Prospects</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"Petroleum V. Nasby," whose writings amused Mr. Lincoln so much, says in his
                        last letter that "these is the dark days of the Dimocrasy."--He adds:</p>
                    <p>"We hev no way uv keeping our voters together. Opposin the war won't do no
                        good, fer before the next eleckshun the heft of our voters will hev
                        diskivered that the war is over. The feer of drafts may do suthin in sum
                        parts uv Pennsylvany and Suthren Illinoy, fer some time yit; but that can't
                        be dePendid on."</p>
                    <p>But we hev wun resource fer a Ishoo--ther will alluz be a Dimocrisy, so long
                        ez ther's a Nigger. Ther is a uncompromisin dislike to the Nigger in the
                        mind uv a ginooine Dimocrat."</p>
                    <p>Mr. Nasby then lays down a few plain rules for the guidance of the faithful
                        in this matter, one of which is as follows:</p>
                    <p>"Alluz assert that the nigger will never beable to take care uv himself, but
                        will alluz be a public burden. He may, possibly, give us the lie by going to
                        work. In sich a emergency the dooty ov every Dimecrat is plane. He must not
                        be allowed to work. Associations must be orgenizd, pledged to neether give
                        him employment, to work with him, to work fer any one who will give him
                        work, or patronize eny one who duz. (I wood sejest that sich uv us as hez
                        been foretoonit enuff 2 git credit, pay a trifle on account, so ez to make
                        our patronage wuth suthin.) This course rigidly and percistently follered,
                        wood drive the best uv em to steelin, and the balance to the poor houses,
                        provin wot we hev alluz claimd, that they air a idle and vishus race."</p>
                    <p>Ef ther aint no niggers, Sentrel Committis must furnish em. A half dozen will
                        do fer a ordinary county, ef theyr hustled along with energy. Ef they won't
                        steel, the Sentrel Committis must do it theirselves. Show yer niggers in a
                        township in the mornin, and the same nite rob the clothes lines and hen
                        roosts. Ever willin 2 sacrifice myself fer the cause, I volunteer to do this
                        latter duty in six populous cuntis."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A spoof letter written by a "Dimocrat" who fears for his party's future.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1865.07.26.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Prejudice Against Reason</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"This envenomed hate which this class of men delight in exhibiting toward
                    the negro, instead of evidencing their superiority over the objects of their
                    malevolence, rather estalishes the opposite."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>An honest, intelligent conviction, no matter how different from what we
                        ourselves entertain, should always command our respect. If we cannot concur
                        in the belief of others, we should at least dissent in a respectful manner,
                        admitting all the time the possibility of the error being on our side.</p>
                    <p>It is best always to keep in mind the imperfection of human knowledge, and
                        while tenacious of our opinions to preserve an unbiased judgment. It has
                        often happened that an idea emerging from dark obscurity has exploded
                        beneath the fortifications of error, and blown them and their defenders out
                        of existence. There is no security against the occurrence of such a thing,
                        and it is simply wise and prudent to be prepared at all times to make our
                        escape. But it is not every belief that is intelligent and honest.
                        Notwithstanding the fact that we are living in the latter half of the
                        nineteenth century, ignorance and prejudice still exercise a powerful
                        influence on men's minds and hearts. They did not die with the last century,
                        but still linger on, and if not quite so formidable as they were, they are
                        yet as far removed from reason and fight as obstinately as ever. Towards
                        belief grounded in these unfortunate characteristics of human nature, reason
                        can be tolerant, but never respectful. Men may believe, if they choose, in
                        the transmigration of souls, and no one should object to their recognizing
                        in their favorite horses and dogs the souls of their departed grandparents,
                        but they must not complain if intelligent men do not manifest much respect
                        for their insane notions. Men can believe just what they please, or at least
                        they ought to be allowed to do so, but at the same time there is no law to
                        enforce a respect for opinions against which reason rebels.</p>
                    <p>These remarks have been suggested by the violent and unreasonable hatred
                        toward the negro that is constantly finding expression in the democratic
                        journals, and more especially in by a communication which appeared in last
                        week's issue of the <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph>. Not that the
                        communication expresses any more violent or unreasonable hatred and abuse
                        than has characterized more than one-half of the editorials of our neighbors
                        within the past year, but because the writer boldly anticipates what we are
                        forced to believe would be to the <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> a
                        desirable solution of the difficulty in which, according to its theory, the
                        negro has involved us. In the article in question it is proposed to "turn
                        upon the black-skinned and coffee colored objects of the negro-lovers
                        commiseration and wipe them out." Just when or how this is to be done the
                        writer does not specify, but assures us that it is a condition precedent to
                        the return of peace and harmony. He places a low estimate on the negro's
                        capacity and avows the belief that the GREAT CREATOR fixed a low limit for
                        his intelligence beyond which it will forever be utterly impossible for it
                        to expand.</p>
                    <p>Now we are decidedly of the opinion that the author of this brief but
                        philosophic article has a perfect right to believe what he has written, and
                        we will do all we can to protect him in the enjoyment of this inestimable
                        privilege; but if we see in his views a heartless indifference to the
                        welfare of the human race, a stupidity that would disgrace the degraded
                        people of whom he writes, and a bigotry that could only take root in a weak
                        intellect, we must be permitted to withhold our respect from his sentiments,
                        and instead thereof, to bestow our pity upon the author, who, in our
                        judgment is lamentably deficient in a certain article that is generally
                        supposed to contribute somewhat to man's superiority over the brute
                        creation. We speak of him because, by rushing into print, he has made it
                        convenient for us to do so, and not that we attribute any special importance
                        to him or his communication. We take him to be one of a large class of
                        persons to all of whom our remarks will apply with equal force. Many of them
                        are doubtless as ignorant and bigoted as he, though we confess that we have
                        rarely met with such.</p>
                    <p>This envenomed hate which this class of men delight in exhibiting toward the
                        negro, instead of evidencing their superiority over the objects of their
                        malevolence, rather establishes the opposite. It is not the way superiors
                        generally treat inferiors. If the negro were guilty of any crime or enormity
                        it would be otherwise. If he were even responsible for his present low
                        condition, contempt and scorn might then with some justice be visited upon
                        him, but since he is not, and as his degradation is a misfortune which he
                        could not avert, no matter whether arising from oppression or a law of his
                        nature, it becomes his superiors to manifest pity rather than scorn,
                        benevolence rather than hate. Genuine superiority will invariably manifest
                        itself after this fashion. It is far from creditable to us as a people that
                        this hostility is so widespread; for it rests entirely in ignorance and
                        prejudice. It cannot be defended by a single argument that would commend
                        itself to the respect or judgment of an impartial mind. The negro has not
                        intruded himself upon us voluntarily, but was brought here against his will,
                        by overpowering force and through cunning deceit. He was here when the
                        Republic was founded, fought for its establishment and afterwards in its
                        defence. Though deprived of his rights he has never plotted its overthrow,
                        but has always been true to its flag. He has borne oppression without
                        resistance, and has permitted us to make him a hewer of wood and drawer of
                        water for our convenience and gain. True he is ignorant, lamentably so. But
                        who will undertake to say that in this respect he enjoys a monopoly? If he
                        has any right to such a monopoly, like all others he ever had, it has been
                        disregarded and violated. But MODERN DEMOCRACY doesn't see things in this
                        light and we can understand why. Public plunder once afforded sufficient
                        cohesive power to preserve unity among those professing the faith, but of
                        late years that article has become scarce with them, and where they once
                        appealed to cupidity they are now compelled to appeal to ignorance and
                        prejudice. Every man who has enough of the latter to hate the negro race, as
                        a race, votes the democratic ticket and always will do so. The men who two
                        years ago amused themselves by hanging innocent negros to lamp posts in the
                        streets of New York all vote the regular ticket and so do all their friends.
                        Policy makes it the business of democracy to encourage and intensify this
                        ill feeling. It admitted into its creed that uncharitable and unchristian
                        doctrine that denied the black man any rights the white man was bound to
                        respect, and notwithstanding the fact that it once professed to believe that
                        all government derives its just form from the consent of the governed, it
                        became the special champion of human slavery. It defended its existence and
                        struggled for its expansion. Its zeal in behalf of its strange ally made it
                        overleap all bounds, and has made it responsible to-day for much of the
                        intolerance that disgraces us as a people. It taught its followers to
                        believe that the great DECLARATION of human right in asserting that all men
                        were created equal, referred only to white men, and we doubt not that a vast
                        majority of them to-day believe that the utterance of that voice from
                        Heaven, commanding "Peace on earth, good will toward men," should be
                        restricted in its reference by the same narrow rule. We would infer from the
                        communication in the <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph>, and that journal's
                        editorials, that such at least was their belief, whether it had ever been
                        officially promulgated as an article of democratic faith or not. It is,
                        indeed, humiliating to know that there is a great party in American politics
                        built upon the theory that God did <emph rend="italic">not</emph> "make out
                        of one blood all the nations of the earth," and that the great principle of
                        cohesion in that party is an uncharitable and unchristian hate that springs
                        alone from the accident of color. Our common school system may be very good,
                        but we have abundant evidence before us that it has not yet entirely
                        fulfilled its mission. Reason has the vantage ground, but we still need more
                        school houses.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors condemn those bigoted individuals who hold a "violent and
                    unreasonable hatred" toward blacks, a view, they note, that appears to be
                    prevalent among Democratic journals throughout the North, including the Valley
                    Spirit.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Expatriated</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>This seems to have been the condition of the Democratic party for the last
                        five years. On the breaking out of the rebellion the southern wing formally
                        renounced all allegiance to the United States Government and took, as they
                        thought, a final leave of us. The Northern wing equally hostile to the
                        government, but laboring under the slight disadvantage of being a minority
                        among a patriotic people, contented themselves with mentally absolving
                        themselves from their allegiance and with embarrassing, as far as they were
                        able, every measure of the government for the suppression of the rebellion
                        and the preservation of the country. During the whole war the two wings were
                        in the closest sympathy. A rebel victory was a signal for copperhead
                        rejoicing and a rebel defeat was a source of sorrow deep and lasting. On the
                        principle that "No good can come out of Nazareth" so no one single measure
                        of the government was permitted to pass unassailed.</p>
                    <p>The President of the United States was denounced as a tyrant, and was
                        ridiculed as an imbecile, a buffoon, an ignorant boor, and with a choice
                        selection of all the terms that Billingsgate could supply. All the eminent
                        men in the country, no matter what might have been their political
                        antecedents, even though but lately High Priests of the Democratic faith,
                        who dared to take their stand in favor of liberty and the perpetuity of the
                        Union, were constantly and unsparingly vilified and abused.</p>
                    <p>The Democratic press of the North re-echoed every slander that came to us
                        from abroad, every stupid tale that the ignorance and malice of foreign hate
                        could devise was repeated here. If we might believe the Democratic papers we
                        were a nation of liars and cowards. Our brave soldiers never gained a
                        victory and the reports of our generals to that effect were false. On the
                        other hand rebel victories were magnified, and the reports of rebel generals
                        were taken against those of our own, as the measure of our losses. Grant was
                        a butcher and a liar--Lee a gentleman and soldier. Butler was a
                        beast--Forest an embodiment of chivalry. So the comparisons ran.</p>
                    <p>Resistance to the draft was persistently taught, and in heavy Democratic
                        districts brought forth the expected fruit, treason and bloodshed. The
                        financial policy and resources of the United States were depreciated and
                        every effort made to make the nation bankrupt. And finally, in 1864, at
                        Chicago, in a solemn conclave of the whole Democratic party, the war was
                        declared to be a failure, and the government as far as that party was
                        concerned delivered into the hands of its enemies, for such would have been
                        the result of an abandonment of the war at that time. Happily the people by
                        an immense majority, indignantly refused to endorse this declaration at the
                        polls, and the war went on to a successful issue.</p>
                    <p>This triumph of the nation has however had no effect in abating the animosity
                        of the Democratic party toward it. It is still as bitterly hostile and as
                        active in the interests of treason as during the war. Nothing that the
                        government does or attempts to do is right. When after a long and tedious
                        trial the assassins of our late President are convicted and punished, the
                        sworn evidence of the government witnesses is discredited, and the
                        statements of rebels and rebel sympathizers received and paraded to the
                        effect that the prisoners are innocent. When the treason of the southern
                        wing of the Democratic party compels the government to retain an army of
                        50,000 to 80,000 men, one half of whom will probably be negroes, it is
                        attempted to excite the prejudices of the people against the negroes by
                        denouncing them as servile brutal mercenaries-- worse than Sepoys--although
                        there is no instance on record of their murdering a garrison in cold blood
                        as the Sepoys under Forest did at Fort Pillow--or of their putting to death
                        by slow starvation 60,000 Union soldiers, as was done by the great Sepoy,
                        Jeff. Davis, now occupying a cell in Fortress Monroe. The government is
                        further gravely warned that "the national debt may become a wedge of
                        disunion instead of a bond of Union, unless it be so wisely managed as to
                        forbid the raising of sectional complaints." In other words, if the payment
                        of the rebel debt is not assumed by the United States that the Democratic
                        party will assist the rebel leaders when they again get into power, to
                        repudiate our own debt. And to this end every effort is made by the
                        Democratic party--every press denounces the exceptions in the President's
                        amnesty proclamation, and especially the $20,000 property prohibition, by
                        which rich and truculent rebels who originated the rebellion are
                        disfranchised and kept beyond the power to do further injury. In short, in
                        every possible way in which malevolence to the constituted authorities of
                        the United States government can be shown, the occasion is seized by the
                        Democratic party to do so.</p>
                    <p>The history of our times when fully recorded will present the singular
                        spectacle of a great party living among us, yet not of us. Whose every act
                        in a time of great public danger was against the government which protected
                        them. Who appeared to have lost every sentiment of love and respect for
                        their country and flag and every honorable feeling as American citizens. A
                        party who had so completely abjured all patriotic feeling to the land which
                        gave them birth. Who had departed so far from their original principles that
                        their name was a libel on them--and who had finally arrived at that point
                        that like Salathiel, the Wandering Jew, they might be said to be without a
                        country and a name.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Since the end of the war, say the editors, the Democrats have continued to
                    act in a hostile manner toward the government.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>A Correction</head>
                <origin>Valley Spirit</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The piece offers a corrective to an article that appeared in the Valley
                    Spirit contending that New York City furnished as many soldiers (116,000) as New
                    England; in fact, New England provided more than three times the number
                    (366,945) of soldiers than did New York.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Union State Central Committee, which met on July 19th in Harrisburg,
                    scheduled the Union State Convention for August 17th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Washington</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Repository's Washington correspondent informs readers that blacks in
                    that city have held a number of meetings to "harmonize" their to efforts to gain
                    access to the ballot. But, he notes, there is no consensus among them. Some
                    blacks, in fact, have suggested that the "only chance for political salvation is
                    everlasting separation" from whites. For this reason, they plan to ask Congress
                    to provide them with a homeland within the territories of the U. S. where they
                    will be free to "work out their destiny according to the ability that God has
                    given them, free from the influence of ineradicable prejudice" that they would
                    be forced to endure "by remaining among whites" or the "barbarizing influences
                    to which they would be subjected if transported to Liberia."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Right Man In The Right Place</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Orrstown</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kindig</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The letter nominates Jacob Kindig, who had five sons serve in the army--two
                    of whom "sacrificed their lives on the altar of their country," to represent the
                    Republicans in the upcoming contest for Sheriff.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Destruction of Given's Mill</head>
                <origin>Carlisle Herald</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Last Wednesday, the Givens Brothers' Paper Mill, located at Mt. Holly
                    Springs, was destroyed by a fire. It is believed that the fire was caused by the
                    spontaneous combustion of some damp rags that had been stored on the third
                    floor. The owners of the mill have insurance amounting to $14,000.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Secretary Stanton's Report</head>
                <origin>Philadelphia Ledger</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>During the war, one of the most difficult things to learn, says the
                        Philadelphia <emph rend="italic">Ledger</emph>, was the precise extent of
                        enlistments, and the number of the military force we had in the field.
                        Secretary Stanton has just furnished a report which lets a little light into
                        the popular darkness on this subject. There were enlisted for the army from
                        November 1, 1863, to November 1, 1864, 402,698 white and colored troops.
                        Colored volunteers enlisted in rebel States from January 1, 1864, to October
                        14 of the same year, 22, 143. In the same period the recruits for the
                        regular army were 13,871. Veterans and re-enlisted before the expiration of
                        their service, between November 1, 1863, and November 1, 1864, 136,507.
                        Drafted and substitutes, 75,006. For the naval service and marine corps,
                        from February to November, 1864, 24,683: making a total of 675,452. The
                        report says:</p>
                    <p>"In estimating the number of troops called into the service, it has been the
                        care of the Department to take into account the whole number of men
                        mustered, without regard to the fact that the same persons may have been
                        previously discharged after having been accepted and credited on preceding
                        calls.</p>
                    <p>A large part (near two hundred thousand) of the men accepted in the years
                        1861 and 1862, were soon found to be unfit for service, and were discharged.
                        This accounts, partially, for the large excess carried forward from the
                        calls of 1862 and deducted from those of 1863."</p>
                    <p>The colored troops enlisted up to October 30, 1864 numbered 101,950. This
                        branch of the service, up to that time, lost by battle, discharges,
                        desertions, and diseases, 33,132 men. Up to November 7, 1864, Gen. Thomas
                        had organized along the Mississippi river a force of 56,320 colored troops.</p>
                    <p>The operations of the draft are very remarkable. The report is dated November
                        25, 1864. From July 1, 1864, up to that time, 130,000 names were added to
                        the enrolment list, and 285,398 names stricken off. This enrolment showed
                        the national force, not called out up to November 1, 1864, to consist of
                        2,784,266 men. In the draft of 1863 the quota drafted for was 194,962, with
                        fifty per cent added. The report says:</p>
                    <p>Of this number 39,417 failed to report, and 164,887 were exempted from
                        physical and other causes, 52,237 paid commutation, 26,002 furnished
                        substitutes, and 9,848 were held to service.<lb/> The total deficiency
                        drafted for was .....50,367<lb/> The number reported and
                        examined.....85,861<lb/> The number exempted for physical
                        disability..31,446<lb/> The number exempted for other causes.....19,648<lb/>
                        The number held to personal service.....3,418<lb/> The number furnished
                        substitutes........8,903<lb/> The number who paid commutation....32,446</p>
                    <p>On September 19, 1864, another draft was had, and the result, known up to
                        November 1, was as follows:<lb/> Number reported and
                        examined..............72,432<lb/> Number exempted for physical
                        disability..20,332<lb/> Number exempted for other causes.........19,797<lb/>
                        Number held to personal service.............19,038<lb/> Number furnished
                        substitutes...................13,343</p>
                    <p>These facts, adds the <emph rend="italic">Ledger</emph>, clearly show that,
                        as a means of recruiting the army, the draft was entirely inadequate. Those
                        who were exempted, those who ran away from the draft, and those who paid
                        commutation, swallowed up nearly the entire number drafted. The number held
                        to personal service was but a small proportion of the whole amount. This
                        proves that volunteering, however expensive it may be, is the most popular,
                        surest, and speediest means of raising an army, and of making satisfied and
                        willing soldiers. The average measurement of the chest, at inspection of the
                        recruits was, 33.16 inches. The average height was 5 feet 6.44 inches.
                        Vermont troops showed the greatest number of inches around the chest and the
                        greatest height: but Pennsylvania troop recruits were close upon
                        Vermont--for her men measured an average of 5 feet 7.08 inches, against
                        Vermont's 5 feet 7.62. In the measurement around the chest the men of
                        Pennsylvania were 1.55 inches less than Vermont. The Veteran Reserve Corps
                        shows that nearly every fourth man has been transferred to it on account of
                        disability from honorable wounds. The horses and mules in the army amount to
                        300,000. During the first eight months of the year 1864, the cavalry of the
                        Army of the Potomac was supplied with two remounts--nearly 40,000 horses.</p>
                    <p>The expenditures for the Ordnance Department during the year were
                        $38,502,822, and there remained in the arsenals on the 30th of June last
                        2,037 field cannon and siege guns, 1,304,947 small arms, and 1,831,853
                        pounds of artillery ammunition. There were in operation during the year
                        6,500 miles of military telegraph, of which 76 miles are submarine. One
                        million eight hundred thousand telegraph messages were transmitted during
                        the year, at an average cost, charging the whole yearly expense of
                        construction, maintenance, and operation to them, of only thirty cents.
                        There were purchased during the year about 9,500 army wagons, 1,100
                        ambulances, and harness for 175,000 animals. The special report of animals
                        and means of transportation with the several armies during the year are
                        imperfect, but it is estimated that there were about 300,000 horses and
                        mules in the service of the army, of which the horses were about 170,000,
                        and the mules about 130,000.</p>
                    <p>The number of men who have died in hospitals, in the vicinity of Washington,
                        from August 1, 1861, to August 1, 1864, is stated at 12,708, of whom 4,910
                        were natives of the United States.</p>
                    <p>Over two hundred flags, captured from the rebels in various battles, received
                        during the year, are deposited for safe keeping. Many others are supposed to
                        have been disposed of by persons who captured or had them in possession, in
                        ignorance of their being public property. One hundred and six enlisted men
                        were presented with medals of honor for capturing rebel flags and other acts
                        of bravery.</p>
                    <p>The statistics of the Surgeon General's Department show that there were in
                        operation on the 30th of June, 1864, 190 hospitals, with a capacity of
                        120,521 beds. During the year the health of the entire army was better than
                        is usual with troops engaged so constantly on active duty and in arduous
                        campaigns. No destructive epidemics prevailed in any section, and the number
                        of sick and wounded, although large, was comparatively small in the
                        proportion it bore to the whole army. At the close of the year the number of
                        sick and wounded, both with their commands and in general hospitals, was
                        less than sixteen (16) per cent. of the strength of the army. Of this number
                        9.3 per cent. were sick, and 6.46 per cent. wounded. The deaths from disease
                        during June, 1864, were 2.98 per thousand of mean strength; from wounds,
                        3.10 per thousand; total deaths, 6.08 per thousand, or six-tenths of one per
                        cent. for the month. During the same month of the previous year the total
                        was 7.3 per thousand of mean strength, or over seven-tenths of one per cent.
                        There were furnished during the year to disabled soldiers 669 legs and 330
                        arms.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article summarizes the findings contained in the report issued by
                    Secretary Stanton, which includes data related to the size and composition of
                    the forces contributed by the states.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Education Of Soldiers' Orphans</head>
                <origin>Harrisburg Telegraph</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>According to the article, there are 857 soldiers' orphans presently under
                    the care of the state.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1865.07.26.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Retrospective and Prospective</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoke</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Montgomery</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sellers</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chambers</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hull</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Allen</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schofield</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chambers</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jeffries</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>H. M.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flack</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brand</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Etter</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richards</ln>
                        <fn>Dr.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spangler</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilmore</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gelwicks</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Watson</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wallace</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shoemaker</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lambert</ln>
                        <fn>Dr.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilbert</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hutton</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reisher</ln>
                        <fn>Squire</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Perry</ln>
                        <fn>S. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spahr</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>David L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ludwig</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Feltman</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>C. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Forbes</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ott</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armstrong</ln>
                        <fn>S. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paxton</ln>
                        <fn>Judge</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doebler</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keefer</ln>
                        <fn>John P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Culbertson</ln>
                        <fn>S. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>E. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snider</ln>
                        <fn>N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reges</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolf</ln>
                        <fn>Bernard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>J A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clark</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fishers</ln>
                        <fn>Mrs.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grier</ln>
                        <fn>J. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>R. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chambers</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>George S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Banker</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huber</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huber</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sierer</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewer</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyle</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Caufman</ln>
                        <fn>A. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneck</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gehr</ln>
                        <fn>D. O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duncan</ln>
                        <fn>C. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Culbertson</ln>
                        <fn>Edmund</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brough</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolf</ln>
                        <fn>B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shaffer</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allen</ln>
                        <fn>Josiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolkill</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Finefrock</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>MCulloh</ln>
                        <fn>A. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>C. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>T. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Etter</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eckert</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Austin</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huff</ln>
                        <fn>Matthew G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn>Lyman S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nead</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chambers</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Evans</ln>
                        <fn>Philip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cole</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trostle</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>W. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sierer</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ludwig</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Washabaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Upton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On the one-year anniversary of the burning of Chambersburg, the article
                    describes the physical changes to the town as it has been resurrected.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Local Items--Appointment of Teachers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gaff</ln>
                        <fn>J. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richards</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hockenberry</ln>
                        <fn>W. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eckhart</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McFadden</ln>
                        <fn>D. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoner</ln>
                        <fn>Mary J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wark</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reynolds</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heffelman</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seibert</ln>
                        <fn>Helen M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCulloh</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nesbitt</ln>
                        <fn>M. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heck</ln>
                        <fn>Charlotte A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jeffries</ln>
                        <fn>Sadie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henninger</ln>
                        <fn>Sadie E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tolbert</ln>
                        <fn>Eliza</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snider</ln>
                        <fn>M. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The following appointments have been made by the School Directors of
                    Chambersburg: J. R. Gaff, J. M. Richards, W. A. Hockenberry, Joseph Eckhart, D.
                    S. McFadden, Mary J. Stoner, Mary E. Wark, Sarah Reynolds, Mary E. Heffelman,
                    Helen M. Seibert, Maggie P. McCulloh, M. F. Nesbitt, Sarah A. Wright, Charlotte
                    A. Heck, Sadie Jeffries, Sadie E. Henninger, Eliza Tolbert, M. M. Snider.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Local Items--Nice Present</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chamberlain</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Orderly Sergeant</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The members of Co. D, 21st Penna. Cavalry presented Orderly Sergeant David
                    Chamberlain, who lost a leg during the war, with $325 last week.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Local Items--New Engines</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Cumberland Valley Railroad recently purchased two new engines, which
                    have been named Gen. Sheridan and Gen. Grant.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Local Items--Drowned</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Curriden</ln>
                        <fn>William L.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The nine-year old daughter of Shippensburg's Post-Master, William L.
                    Curriden, Esq., drowned last Thursday after she fell into a cistern containing
                    several feet of water.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stenger</ln>
                        <fn>William S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William S. Stenger gave the Biennial Address before Franklin and Marshall
                    College's Literary Societies yesterday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heart</ln>
                        <fn>J. Milton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinneard</ln>
                        <fn>Kate L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinneard</ln>
                        <fn>John D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>E. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On July 13th, J. Milton Heart and Kate L. Kinneard were married at the
                    residence of bride's brother, John D. Kinneard, by Rev. E. S. Johnson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guise</ln>
                        <fn>Adam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Golden</ln>
                        <fn>Annie E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneck</ln>
                        <fn>S. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On July 10th, Adam Guise and Annie E. Golden were married by Rev. S. S.
                    Schneck.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richards</ln>
                        <fn>James J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roland</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Akers</ln>
                        <fn>J. Benson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On July 13th, James J. Richards, of Buck's Valley, Fulton county, and
                    Catharine Roland were married by Rev. J. Benson Akers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mitchell</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mitchell</ln>
                        <fn>William F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mitchell</ln>
                        <fn>Matilda</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On July 4th, William Mitchell, only child of Dr. William F. and Matilda
                    Trout, died. William was 10 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deal</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On June 17th, Samuel M. Deal, a member of Co. K, 38th Regt. Ill. Infantry,
                    died in Montgomery, Alabama, of Congestive Fever.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brinley</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brinley</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On July 8th, Margaret, wife of Jon Brinley, died at Spring Run. She was 33
                    years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Raffensberger</ln>
                        <fn>William Harry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On June 16th, William Harry Raffensberger, a member of Co. K, 21st P. V.
                    Cavalry, died at the "Soldier's Rest" in Harrisburg. William was 23 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
