<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1865/pa.fr.fr.1865.04.26">
	<header>
		<title type="uniform">Franklin Repository</title>
		<tagger>
			<taggerName>Sally Henninger, 1st pass; Susanna Michele Lee, 2nd pass, 1/7/99</taggerName>
			<tagDate/>
			<tagNote/>
		</tagger>
		<address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
		<date n="1865-04-26">
			<year>1865</year>
			<month norm="04">April</month>
			<day>26</day>
			<weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
		</date>
		<frequency>weekly</frequency>
		<extent>04</extent>
		<editionNote/>
	</header>
	<paperBody>
		<page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1865.04.26.01">
			<div type="a">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>A Complete And Most Graphic Account Of The Movements of J. Wilkes Booth, in
					the Assassination Of Abraham Lincoln.</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Describes Booth's actions before, during, and after the assassination of
					Lincoln. The article also includes murder attempts on the Sewards and the
					reactions to the news.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote>The page includes advertisements.</pageNote>
		</page>
		<page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1865.04.26.02">
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Si Monumentum Requiris--Circumspice! Abraham Lincoln, Sixteenth President of
					hte United States. Born in Kentucky, Feb. 12, 1809. Died at Washington, April
					15, 1865.</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Reports news items relating to Lincoln's assassination including the murder
					of a rebel who approved Lincoln's murder; the rewards for Booth's capture; the
					capture of one of Booth's accomplices, George Alzerott; death threats received
					by Lincoln; threats to Reamer, a rebel sympathizer in Hagerstown, because of his
					efforts to raise money and hire an assassin to kill Lincoln; and Lincoln's
					presentiments of not surviving the war.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>2</column>
				<head>Appearance Of The Corpse</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt>"He has not changed one line of his grave, grotesque countenance, nor
					smoothed out a single feature. The hue is rather bloodless and leaden; but he
					was always sallow."</excerpt>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Provides a detailed description of Lincoln's corpse.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>2</column>
				<head>Summary Of War News</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Reports dissatisfaction with Sherman's terms of surrender to Johnson.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="3">
				<column>$1,000 Reward</column>
				<head/>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>McClure</ln>
						<fn>A. K.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Advertises a reward for the capture of F. W. Smith for burning McClure's
					residence.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>3</column>
				<head>The New Administration</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt>"But of Davis, of Breckinridge, of Cobb, of Benjamin, and it may be others,
					who have wielded the deadly despotism of treason, President Johnson designs a
					different fate. They now have but the alternative of banishment or death; and
					while the Nation would have heartily sustained Mr. Lincoln in the clemency that
					would have allowed them to live dishonored, it will with equal unanimity sustain
					President Johnson now in demanding a new atonement for the assassin's stroke,
					the offspring of treason, that was aimed at the vitals of the Republic.</excerpt>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Expresses confidence in Johnson's administration, but notes the difference
					in Lincoln's and Johnson's policy towards rebel leaders.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>President Johnson</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>The Repository alludes to its earlier reaction to Johnson's apparent
					drunkenness at the inauguration. Notes evidence that Johnson actually does not
					drink and that his behavior then was due to medication for an illness from which
					he is still recovering.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look>**</look>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Maj. Gen. Sherman</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>The Repository reports Sherman's terms to Johnston, made under the
					direction of Davis, and unacceptable to Washington. Grant traveled to N. C. to
					compel Johnston's surrender under terms acceptable to the present
					administration. The Repository notes that Sherman proposed terms in line with
					Lincoln's policies offered before knowledge of Lincoln's assassination.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look>**</look>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>5</column>
				<head/>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Reports, contrary to other papers, that Moseby, the guerilla rebel, has not
					surrendered and continues his efforts north of Richmond. Many of Moseby's men
					have surrendered.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Washington. Solemnity of the city--Policy of the New President--Booth Not
					Arrested--Large Number of Arrests--Disloyal Marshals--Health of Mrs. Lincoln,
					&amp;c., &amp;c.</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt>"Our new President, Andrew Johnson, will adopt a new and different policy
					from that of Lincoln, in dealing with treason and traitors. He is for a
					'vigorous prosecution' of the use of hemp in dealing with leaders in arms. That
					has always been his doctrine."</excerpt>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Reports that Johnson will adopt a more vengeful policy towards treason than
					Lincoln. The article also mentions the continued illness of Mrs. Lincoln.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>6</column>
				<head>Personal</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Reports news on Jefferson Davis, Ella Turner, and Robert E. Lee.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>7</column>
				<head>Funeral Ceremonies Of Abraham Lincoln</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Describes the funeral of Lincoln and reprints the prayers and sermons by
					Bishop Simpson, Rev. Dr. Gurley, and Rev. Dr. Gray.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote>The Repository continues the article on the funeral ceremonies on page
			three.</pageNote>
		</page>
		<page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1865.04.26.03">
			<div type="a">
				<column>2</column>
				<head>Speech Of President Johnson</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Reprints an address by Gov. Oglesby, of Illinois, to President Johnson. The
					article includes Johnson's reply in which he exposed the seriousness of the
					crime of treason and made no pledges for his presidency.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>3</column>
				<head>Lecture</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Riley</ln>
						<fn>J.</fn>
						<sf>D. D.</sf>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Announces Rev. D. D. Riley's lecture in the Methodist Church on April 27.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Tribute Of Respect</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Richards</ln>
						<fn>T. M.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Gaff</ln>
						<fn>J. R.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Reports that at the meeting of the Chambersburg Teacher's Institute,
					President Richards and Secretary Gaff report resolutions in response to
					Lincoln's assassination. They support the restoration of peace and universal
					freedom.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Let Them Be Returned</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Notes Gov. Curtin's intention to demand the "reudition of McCausland,
					Gilmore and others for trial in Chambersburg, for their crimes of destroying the
					town in 1864." The article also contains a reminder of rewards, mentioned
					previously, by McClure and the Repository, for their capture.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Wednesday</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Smith</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev. Mr.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Eyster</ln>
						<fn>C. S.</fn>
						<sf>Esq.</sf>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Describes the observation of Lincoln's funeral in Chambersburg. Owners
					closed businesses. Citizens organized a procession of military and civic groups.
					Smith and Eyster offered prayer and eulogy.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>Gen. Lee's Farewell To His Army</column>
				<head/>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt>"I need not tell the brave survivors of so many hard fought battles, who
					have remained steadfast to the last, that I have consented to this result from
					no distrust in them; but feeling that valor and devotion could accomplish
					nothing that would compensate for the loss that would have attended the
					continuance of the contest, I determined to avoid the useless sacrifice of those
					whose past services have endeared them to their countrymen."</excerpt>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Print Lee's farewell address to his troops.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look>**</look>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Condition of Mr. Seward</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Reports the improved condition of Seward.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Affairs in Georgia--Lee's Surrender Causes Rejoicing--movements of Jeff
					Davis--Suicide of Gov. Milton, of Florida.</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Reports Jefferson Davis's escape to Europe or the trans-Mississippi
					Department, "taking with him a half million in specie."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Finance And Trade</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Reports that Lincoln's death and funeral caused little movement in business
					and stocks.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Roth</ln>
						<fn>G.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Beitsch</ln>
						<fn>George</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Mr.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Pressler</ln>
						<fn>Elizabeth</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Miss</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On April 20, by Rev. Roth, George Bietsch, of Etna, Allegheny County,
					married Elizabeth Pressler, of Chambersburg.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Schneck</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Heckman</ln>
						<fn>Isaac</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Mr.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Gipe</ln>
						<fn>Sophia</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Miss</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Sinke</ln>
						<fn>John</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Mr.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On April 20, at the home of John Sinke, in Chambersburg, by Rev. Schneck,
					Isaac Heckman, from the Greenvillage vicinity, married Sophia Gipe, of
					Chambersburg.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Simmers</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Mrs.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Simmers</ln>
						<fn>John K.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Mr.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On April 12, in Washington, D. C., Simmers, of Co. D, 210th Regiment P. V.,
					died at 34 years, 10 months, and 14 days. Simmers was wounded at the battles at
					Petersburg where his left leg was amputated on April 1. His wife printed a small
					poem with the obituary.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote>The page includes advertisements.</pageNote>
		</page>
		<page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1865.04.26.04">
			<pageNote>The page includes advertisements and train schedules.</pageNote>
		</page>
	</paperBody>
</hwp>
