<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1865/pa.fr.fr.1865.02.01">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sally Henninger, 1st pass; Susanna Michele Lee, 2nd pass, 1/2/99</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1865-02-01">
            <year>1865</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day norm="01">1</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1865.02.01.01">
            <pageNote>The page includes advertisements, a story about a woman finding happiness in
                marriage, and anecdotes.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1865.02.01.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Couch</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>General</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports the reinforcement of Gen. Grant by Gen. Thomas. Gen. Couch's troops
                    are among those sent by Gen. Thomas.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Signs Of The Times</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The signs of the times indicate peace at no distant day. And when it comes
                    our land will be stronger more powerful and wealthier than ever before. Our
                    nation will stand out regenerated, purified, and disenthralled. The States will
                    be united upon a common basis, with freedom the foundation stone, and our people
                    enjoy the envy and admiration of the world."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The American people have for several weeks past been on the tiptoe of
                        expectation, to see the rebellion rapidly fall to the ground, and peace
                        again restored to their distracted country. The loyal armies have everywhere
                        been successful, and treason wherever it dared to present a front has been
                        boldly met and terribly overcome. It is true that Gen. Lee still has an army
                        in Richmond, yet he is so completely out off from the country he dares
                        defend, that to leave the spot he holds is to him irretrievable ruin. At
                        this time the entire coast of the Mississippi is loyal to the Union. The
                        State of Louisiana is bold in her declarations for a representation in the
                        Federal Congress. Arkansas is ready to renounce secession, emancipate
                        Slavery and return to the Union. Missouri, by the largest majority she has
                        ever given, has elected a radical Union Governor and amended her
                        constitution so as to forever prohibit the traf[f]ic of human chattels.
                        Kentucky is wisely deliberating upon her course, and the sentiment of her
                        people is directing affairs in the same channel. Tennessee is side by side
                        with Missouri in the abolition of Slavery and in returning to place herself
                        under the Aegis of the Federal government. Alabama is isolated and at the
                        mercy of Thomas' victorious army. Georgia has been crossed by the noble and
                        gallant Sherman without any opposition; Savannah, the gem of the South, is
                        now enjoying the blessing of our government, and the influence of a kind and
                        conciliatory policy of Gen. Sherman, is fast working out grand results in
                        Georgia, the wealthiest and best State of the South. Fort Fisher has been
                        captured which gives us control of the Port at Wilmington, and shuts off the
                        only door that gave the Rebels material assistance by supplies from foreign
                        powers. Gen. Sherman's gallant army is moving on Charleston, and the fierce
                        determination which characterizes those brave boys, will soon make the
                        Palmetto State feel what she long has deserved, the ruin and desolation of
                        war. Charleston the nest of treason will soon be in the possession of the
                        Federal army, and with the fall of this city, the entire Atlantic coast is
                        ours.</p>
                    <p>Then for future operations we have the army of Gen. Thomas in excellent
                        condition, flushed with Hood's defeat and ready to move anywhere. We have
                        the invincible army of Sherman conquering and to conquer. The army of
                        Sheridan ready for the Spring campaign; and the noble Terry who is not
                        wanting in all the essential elements of a great General. Grant stands with
                        one hand upon the throat of the Rebellion, holding Lee's army at bay. He is
                        ready any moment to replace restraint by constraint. This in brief is the
                        position of our armies. All are in excellent condition. They stand in point
                        of cool courage and daring unsurpassed by the soldiers of any age or any
                        nation--They have braved much, have endured many privations and hardships,
                        and by their undaunted heroism have shed immortal lustre upon their national
                        arms.</p>
                    <p>But this is not all, yet even this State of affairs is so encouraging that to
                        doubt of success, is sheer blindness or what is worse, <emph rend="italic"
                            >treason</emph>. The Rebel themselves are now at war with their own
                        rulers; the conflict is terrible and growing more so every day. Every
                        newspaper brought from the South, comes filled with the reports of angry
                        discussions, and fault finding with those in power, who are not capable of
                        doing more than they have done to bolster up a bad cause. The whole Rebel
                        organization, military and civil, is now growing under internal differences
                        of the gravest sort. The lack of military success; the sad and humiliating
                        defeats; the extreme scarcity of all the necessary munitions of war; the
                        destitute condition of transportation; the worthless condition of their
                        currency; the general disaffection among their leaders themselves; the
                        dissatisfaction of the people and the rapidly growing feeling favorable to
                        reconstruction and reorganization; the request of many of their States for
                        re-admission to the Union; these things not vague chimeras, but stubborn
                        facts that speak to the reason, are working out for us a success as complete
                        as the conquering legions now under the "Stars and Stripes." We have an army
                        outside, and the hearts of the people of the South in the inside, working
                        out the great problem which sooner or later must be announced to the world,
                        that the Rebellion is subdued, the Union saved, and the government of the
                        United States reco[g]nized as supreme.</p>
                    <p>There is one thing yet remaining to the Southern people; and it is discussed
                        by many of their ablest men. The disposition of Jeff. Davis, the abolition
                        of their Congress and the investiture of Gen. Lee with dictatorial and
                        absolute power--This must clearly be the last resort for it is the surrender
                        of national power and private freedom, and when the time arrives to
                        accomplish this, new factions will spring up, and more terrible opposition
                        be manifested by those who are satisfied that the rebellion have proved a
                        failure. The surrender of the liberties of the Southern people will not take
                        place. There are those among them who are jealous of their rights, and whose
                        lives are examples of ambition, to attain positions of influence and
                        respectability. Such men will never submit to the will of a despot no matter
                        what may be offered by such a step. The history of the world is full of
                        examples of nations that have resorted to this form of government one time
                        or another, and every instance too proving a signal failure. The Emperors of
                        Rome wielded their power with despotic will. France has seen its rulers,
                        royal, republican and despotic. Napoleon contrived by the despotic power
                        which he exercised to shake all Europe, and yet his power was his weakness,
                        and at last invited him to the death of an exile. Cromwell was clothed with
                        absolute power, and yet failed in his purposes. So too of Frederick in
                        Prussia and Charles X in Spain. In all these instances great interests were
                        at stake, and great efforts used to achieve results, but the last attempt
                        was a failure and all was lost. When all is put at the disposal of one man
                        and that fails, there is no resort, all is gone. We believe this to be the
                        case with the rebellion, and we do not hesitate to say, that even the
                        conferring of absolute power upon Gen. Lee could not turn the tide of
                        affairs one whit. It is not within the scope of any human power to give
                        victory and replace defeat, to a cause like the Southern rebellion. The
                        heart of the rebellion is surrounded by a power that cannot be overcome, and
                        to clothe Lee with greater powers than he possesses to-day, would only be
                        giving a wider scope to use the army now in his immediate command. He could
                        not recruit it, and greater power would be simply nothing at all
                        practically. The papers themselves expose their weakness. It is clear that
                        madness rules the hour. It requires but little acumen to know, that when the
                        rulers of a country are at war, while the country is itself rapidly sinking,
                        that country is itself rapidly sinking, that country must fall so much the
                        sooner as the discord is greater. The signs of the times indicate peace at
                        no distant day. And when it comes our land will be stronger more powerful
                        and wealthier than ever before. Our nation will stand out regenerated,
                        purified, and disenthralled. The States will be united upon a common basis,
                        with freedom the foundation stone, and our people enjoy the envy and
                        admiration of the world.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Predicts the end of the war. The strength of the Union forces and the
                    weakness of the Confederate forces bode well for the Union. The author believes
                    Union victory so inevitable that "to doubt of success, is sheer blindness or
                    what is worse, treason."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Blair Mission Ended</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"With their dominions desolated, their currency utterly worthless and their
                    credit hopelessly destroyed; their armies shattered and dispirited by successive
                    disasters; their last port closed to add to their already fearful wants; and the
                    most appalling despotism the fruits of their fidelity to treason, still the
                    power that was conceived in perjured ambition, and has marked its tread with
                    hecatombs of dead and wide-spread bereavements, has vitality for a crowning
                    sacrifice, and it is to be made."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We confess to disappointment in the result of the mission of Blair to
                        Richmond. When he first went there we attached little importance to it, and
                        supposed that it was a voluntary effort on the part of Mr. Blair to feel the
                        rebel pulse without any great confidence in success; but when he returned,
                        confer[r]ed with the President and only with him on the subject, and entered
                        a government steamer that had been kept waiting for him, to renew his
                        intercourse with the rebel leaders at Richmond, we supposed that there were
                        substantial hopes of adjustment. Mr. Blair has now returned from his second
                        visit to Richmond. Just what transpired, or what answers were given to his
                        unofficial propositions to close the war on the basis of the integrity of
                        the Union, we are not advised; but enough is known to dispel all hopes of
                        immediate peace. It is evident that the rebel authorities have refused to
                        entertain any proposition looking to the re-union of the States, and the
                        southern people, although widely disaffected, are not yet prepared to end a
                        causeless, wicked revolution by deposing the authors of their desolation.</p>
                    <p>For the present, therefore, we must dismiss the hope of peace, except as it
                        may be strengthened by the crimsoned triumphs of our heroic armies. With
                        their dominions desolated, their currency utterly worthless and their credit
                        hopelessly destroyed; their armies shattered and dispirited by successive
                        disasters; their last port closed to add to their already fearful wants; and
                        the most appalling despotism the fruits of their fidelity to treason, still
                        the power that was conceived in perjured ambition, and has marked its tread
                        with hecatombs of dead and wide-spread bereavements, has vitality for a
                        crowning sacrifice, and it is to be made. The broken columns of Hood have
                        been gathered up and are marching to Richmond under General Johnston. The
                        thrice defeated army of Earley has abandoned the Shenandoah, and now has its
                        position on Lee's left, with a new commander in the person of General
                        Gordon. Davis has been virtually deposed from military control by the action
                        of the rebel Congress, and Lee is made generalissimo of the entire rebel
                        armies. Buckner will doubtless surrender Charleston, if necessary, to join
                        Lee, or will certainly transfer the major part of his force to join the
                        death-struggle for the rebel capital. Thus will Lee have supreme power, and
                        about him for the last desperate effort of treason, will be the whole
                        available force of the rebellion. After Missouri, Tennessee, Kentucky,
                        Louisiana, West Virginia, the Mississippi river and nearly the entire coast,
                        have been wrested from the hosts of crime, the responsibility of saving the
                        shattered remnants of the confederacy is thrown upon Gen. Lee, and he must
                        stake all upon a grand struggle with the combined Union armies under Grant.</p>
                    <p>Nor is treason alone in concentration. Gen. Grant, with that admirable
                        foresight that has ever marked his management of great campaigns, commenced
                        the policy of concentration when Sherman cut loose from Atlanta and swept
                        through to the coast. That triumphant and invincible army, under the
                        greatest of our Lieutenants, is moving upon Richmond. It may attack
                        Charleston or any other point or points on the way; but the objective point
                        is Richmond. When Grant wants Sherman on the James or on Lee's rear, he will
                        be there. Gen. Thomas lured Hood to the very fortifications of Nashville to
                        compass his destruction. When all things were ready, he turned upon his
                        unsuspecting foe, and routed him with terrible loss in men and nearly all
                        his artillery. In despair Hood retraced his steps, leaving thousands of
                        killed and wounded behind him, and fully five thousand deserters. His army
                        was practically destroyed, and has now lost its identity in the army of Lee.
                        Thomas thus nobly fulfilled the task assigned him, and while a portion of
                        his army appeared to be pursuing Hood, the main body was consummating the
                        great plan of Grant by moving to join the hosts about to encircle the doomed
                        capital of treason. Already is most of Thomas' army in supporting distance
                        of Grant to operate against Richmond, and Couch and other well tested and
                        most trusted commanders are leading the western heroes to the final
                        struggle. Gen. Sheridan's victorious legions are also in line at the proper
                        place for the great struggle, and it is confidently asserted that the Hero
                        of the valley will lead the Army of the Potomac to its crowning victory.</p>
                    <p>Such are the movements and such the purpose of the two opposing military
                        leaders. Gen. Lee has every available man that treason can furnish, and
                        Grant has over two hundred thousand soldiers, many of them just from
                        victorious fields, to strike the last blow for Liberty and Law. Negociations
                        [sic] have failed--the olive branch has been rejected by the authors of this
                        war, and the terrible arbitrament of the sword alone can give us peace.
                        There cannot be protracted war. It must be brief, but it may be sanguinary.
                        It may cost many noble sacrifices; but the great issue cannot be doubtful.
                        We shall have peace ere mid-summer, and over the ruins of the last organized
                        army of traitors. They have willed it so--we must accept the struggle, and
                        when victory shall have crowned our efforts, there will be no fountain of
                        treason remaining to poison the life of the rescued and regenerated Union of
                        our fathers.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Expresses disappointment with Blair's failed mission to bring a peaceful
                    end to the war. The author blames the South for its refusal to consider the
                    reunion of the states.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Mr. McClure</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that McClure read a bill in the House for the adjudication of all
                    military damages on the border.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>From The Southern Coast. Details of the Capture of Fort Fisher--The Part Taken
                    by the Navy--The Landing and Assault--The Explosion--List of Officers of the
                    Minnesota.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>"O. B."</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes the capture of Fort Fisher.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Washington. The Assault on Judge Kelley--Prompt Action of Congress in the
                    Affair--The Brooks and Butler Controversy--Amendment to the Enrolment
                    Act--Burning of the Smithsonian--Promotion of Capt. Teo. McGowan.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>"S. C."</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>The correspondent from Washington reports the assault on W. D. Kelley, a
                    dispute between Brooks and Butler over a bank seizure, Senator Wilson's
                    amendments to the enrolment act, the Smithsonian Institute fire, and the
                    promotion of Capt. Theodore McGowan.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Harrisburg. Debate on the Filling of Quotas--Bounty Jumpers--Interesting
                    Divorce Case--The quota of the State--Companies Authorized to fill the Present
                    call.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>"Horace"</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Details actions in the Pennsylvania legislature including debates on
                    quotas, bounty jumpers, and a divorce case.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="j">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Court Proceedings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Morrisson</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kreager</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carlisle</ln>
                        <fn>T. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robinson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phreaner</ln>
                        <fn>B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Teeter</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Justice</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kuhn</ln>
                        <fn>Emanuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crooks</ln>
                        <fn>Washington</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolfe</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christ</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Helser</ln>
                        <fn>Solomon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGrath</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf>Sheriff of Franklin County</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Long</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Erisman</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christ</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Millhouse</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lists the verdicts on court proceedings. The case of Rebecca Morrisson vs.
                    Henry Kreager over ownership of cattle resulted in a nonsuit for the plaintiff.
                    In the case of T. M. Carlisle, surviving partner of Robinson &amp; Carlisle,
                    vs. the Executors of Dr. B. Phreaner, deceased, for the plaintiff to recover
                    fees as the attorneys of the defendants, the judge awarded $50. In the case of
                    Robert Taylor vs. David Teeter, the judge awarded $40. In the case of Emanuel
                    Kuhn vs. the executors of Washington Crooks, deceased, the judge ruled in favor
                    of the defendants. In the case of G. W. Wolfe vs. William Christ, the judge
                    found for the defendant. In the case of Solomon Helser vs. William McGrath,
                    Sheriff of Franklin County over the ownership of rye, the judge ruled in favor
                    of the defendant. In the case of James Martin vs. Michael Long and Abraham
                    Erisman, the judge awarded $80. In the case of John and Elizabeth Snyder vs.
                    William Christ, the plaintiffs fake a nonsuit. In the case of John Millhouse vs.
                    William Eyster, the plaintiff takes a nonsuit. In the case of the Commonwealth
                    vs. James Johnson, the parties made an amicable settlement. The author praises
                    Judge King's courtroom management.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Appointments</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burd</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dickson</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Colestock</ln>
                        <fn>Z. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bishop</ln>
                        <fn>J. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hummelbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>H. Y.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bingham</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clemm</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schlicter</ln>
                        <fn>H. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shoaff</ln>
                        <fn>J. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>T. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lists appointments from Chambersburg to the Pennsylvania Conference of the
                    United Brethren in Christ at the last session in Baltimore: J. W. Burd, P. E.;
                    J. Dickson, Chambersburg; Z. A. Colestock, Big Spring; J. P. Bishop, Rocky
                    Spring; Smith, Greencastle and Altodale Circuit; H. Y. Hummelbaugh, Newville; S.
                    Bingham, Carlisle; J. A. Clemm, Bendersville Mission; H. A. Schlicter,
                    Shippensburg Circuit; J. G. Shoaff, Littlestown; and T. B. Jones, Path Valley.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1865.02.01.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shock</ln>
                        <fn>James L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports the mysterious disappearance of Rev. James L. Shock, formerly the
                    pastor of the Lutheran congregation in Chambersburg. The Boston Journal reports
                    that a letter was found among Shock's papers, which bequeathed money to his
                    sister and informed her that he "'was going to his rest.'"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Dead</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Berkle</ln>
                        <fn>Fred.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Corp.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>J. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces the death of Fred. Berkle, of Co. A, 77th Pa. Vols. (commanded by
                    J. E. Walker), from his wounds. He also served in the Mexican War and as first
                    Sergeant of Co. E, 126th Regiment Pa. Vols.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Magnificent Present</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roth</ln>
                        <fn>G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that G. Roth, the German Evangelical Lutheran pastor in
                    Chambersburg thanks his congregation for "a magnificent present."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Shooting Season</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reminds readers about the law prohibiting the killing of partridges,
                    pheasants, and rabbits, from January 1 until October 1.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Creigh</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pastor</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Creigh</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes the "affection" of the Presbyterian church of Mercersburg in giving
                    Pastor Creigh and his wife nearly three hundred dollars in money and presents.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Summary Of War News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports war news including Gen. Sherman's advance to Salkabatchie, the
                    destruction of Forts Caswell and Campbell by the enemy, and engagements on the
                    James River.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Company Organizations</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprints Gov. Curtin's order to raise fifty companies. Curtin will
                    authorize only experienced officers to raise companies.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Finance And Trade</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that a majority of the banks in the state accepted the provisions
                    of the national banking law. Gold advanced to 220 because of the failure of the
                    Blair mission.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Creigh</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn>James E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKinnie</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKinnie</ln>
                        <fn>Ann Maria</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On January 26, by Rev. Creigh, of Mercersburg, James Campbell married Ann,
                    daughter of Robert McKinnie, all of Peters Township.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bishop</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dietrich</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillan</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillan</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On January 25, at the home of the bride's father, by Rev. Bishop, Daniel
                    Dietrich married Sarah, daughter of John Gillan, both of Franklin County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>West</ln>
                        <fn>W. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Worthington</ln>
                        <fn>L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On January 12, by Rev. West, James Patterson, of Roxbury, married Mrs.
                    Worthington, of Metal Township.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kelly</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGrath</ln>
                        <fn>William P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keefer</ln>
                        <fn>Mary A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On January 12, by Rev. Kelly, William McGrath, of Franklin County, married
                    Mary Keefer, of Newburg, Cumberland County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McHenry</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keller</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sowers</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On January 17, by Rev. McHenry, John Keller married Sarah Sowers, both of
                    Guilford Township.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McHenry</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Diehl</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wagoner</ln>
                        <fn>Salome</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On January 24, by Rev. McHenry, Jacob Diehl, of Hamilton Township, married
                    Salome Wagoner, of St. Thomas Township.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shockey</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On January 7, near Augusta, Braken County, Kentucky, Samuel Shockey,
                    formerly of the Wayesboro vicinity, died at 57 years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duffield</ln>
                        <fn>Lucreta May</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duffield</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On January 22, Lucreta, daughter of James Duffield, died at 6 months.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>The page includes advertisements, market reports, and legal
            notices.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1865.02.01.04">
            <pageNote>The page includes advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
