<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1865/pa.fr.fr.1865.05.17">
    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/19/99</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1865-05-17">
            <year>1865</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day>17</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1865.07.17.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Hand Of God In The War</head>
                <origin>Evangelical Quarterly Review</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Basing its argument on the notion that slavery and liberty are
                    "antagonistic in their very nature, and cannot possibly be harmonized," the
                    article validates the Union's efforts in the late war and contends God
                    influenced the outcome.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>The Crime Of Davis</head>
                <origin>Washington Chronicle</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article expresses utter contempt for Jeff Davis, who, it contends, was
                    responsible for Abraham Lincoln's assassination. Though it may have been "Booth
                    who pulled the trigger, Davis gave him the gun and pointed the muzzle." Thus,
                    the President's murder remains "unavenged."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Status Of Surrendered Rebels</head>
                <origin>Army and Navy Journal</origin>
                <commentary>"There has been much discussion as to the exact status of the officers
                    and soldiers of Lee's and Johnston's armies, recently surrendered to Gens. Grant
                    and Sherman. The following from the Army and Navy Journal presents the case
                    clearly and we regard it as a correct exposition to the relations the
                    surrendered men sustain for the Government:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Responding to those who have criticized Gen. Grant for the "lenient" terms
                    he afforded Lee's surrendering troops, the article notes that it was Lincoln in
                    fact who "in his last great work" determined the "method by which the rebel army
                    might be disbanded safely." Moreover, this plan was the only realistic one
                    available since Grant "could not hold the whole Southern armies as actual
                    prisoners in camps."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1865.07.17.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>National Affairs</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Although intermittent guerilla attacks persist in some areas of the South,
                    in the wake of Lieut. Gen. Taylor's surrender, the war east of the Mississippi
                    has drawn to a close. Reconstruction "in the rebellious States" is underway and,
                    soon, a large portion of the army will be disbanded.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>President Johnson</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>With sublime impudence the Democratic Press has undertaken to patronize
                        President Johnson. They have suddenly discovered that he was formerly a
                        Democrat--that it is but a short time since he abjured the old faith, and
                        that from the length of his associations with the Democratic party he must
                        still have a leaning towards it. He is duly credited with all the Jacksonian
                        attributes, and is cooly informed that if he will allow the Democratic party
                        to control his policy he may hope to attain as high a position in the
                        Democratic calendar of saints as Jackson himself. With a pleasing assurance
                        the policy which will be about the correct thing to please these new and
                        faithful friends is mapped out for him so that there may be no mistake. He
                        has only to reject the radical men of the party he now acts with--otherwise
                        the men who throughout the war for the Union have been most unwavering in
                        their support of the government and in their devotion to the great
                        principles, the full and energetic development of which made the war a
                        success. He has only to repudiate the solemn pledge he made at Baltimore, to
                        support the platform in which these same great principles are embodied. He
                        has only to pursue a policy of reconstruction as will bring back to power in
                        the South the same men who denounced, proscribed, and drove him from his
                        home for his adherence to his country and his flag. The men who for four
                        long and sorrowful years have battled against both--who now are only
                        converts to the right, not by conviction, but by force of arms. In the North
                        he is only required to take into his confidence the men who denounced him
                        throughout the war as a demagogue, boorish tailor and renegade Democrat; who
                        sneered at him as traitor to his section, and ascribes the most debased
                        motives as the cause of his fidelity to the government. Finally, he is
                        expected to take such measures as will restore Slavery--that gigantic crime
                        against God and man--and with it the Democratic party as it stood at the
                        beginning of the rebellion. When he shall have accomplished all this he will
                        be again worthy to be received into the communion of the Democratic fold. He
                        will then have Tylerized the Republican party.</p>
                    <p>But if Mr. Johnson, as insisted on, is a second Jackson, then it would seem
                        unfortunate for these newly galvanized friends. One of the strongest
                        characteristics of Jackson was that he never forgot his friends nor forgave
                        his enemies. If this trait is predominant with Johnson, what must he think
                        of those who have spared no abuse of him while a fugitive from home during
                        the terrible years of our civil struggle, and who are more than suspected of
                        being strongly in sympathy with men who would have included him in the
                        assassination of the late President. Our estimate of the character of
                        President Jackson is a high one. We believe him to have been an honorable,
                        honest and truly patriotic man, such a man indeed as would, if he had
                        survived to these days, been found with President Johnson in opposition to
                        the present miscalled Democratic party. Secession with him would have found
                        no more sympathy or favor than did Nullification. Believing this, and
                        believing as is alleged, that Mr. Johnson possesses the firmness and
                        patriotism of Jackson, we never expect to see him desert the path he marked
                        out for himself, four years ago in opposition to what seemed for him, every
                        consideration of interest and policy, all the blandishments of the
                        Democratic party to the contrary notwithstanding. And so far from present
                        indications these blandishments do not appear to have had much effect upon
                        him.</p>
                    <p>In all his public utterances he has persistently recorded his determination
                        to deal with traitors and treason according to the law, granting them no
                        more latitude nor no more mercy than the extreme letter of the law allows.
                        In all his public acts he has adopted the same course. By a recent Executive
                        order he has declared null and void all acts, proceedings and contracts of
                        the rebel government of Virginia, Confederate and State, since the day the
                        ordinance of secession was passed on the 17th of April, 1861, to the present
                        time. He has refused to recognize the disinterested patriotism of the men
                        who were bold and insolent rebels until after Richmond surrendered and the
                        armies of Lee and Johnston were captured, and who then magnanimously offered
                        to call the rebel Governor back to Richmond and reorganize the rebel State
                        government. Instead he has given his confidence to that little band of loyal
                        men who had shown themselves faithful among the faithless, who during the
                        gloomiest period of the war assembled at Alexandria, organized a government
                        and elected Francis H. Pierpont Governor. By the order above referred to,
                        Governor Pierpont now assumes control of all of old Virginia not included in
                        the state of West Virginia. He is a man, who like the President himself, has
                        been tried by the fire of persecution, who by a common sympathy will
                        recognize men who have come through the same trials, and from them will form
                        a State government truly loyal. Yet President Johnson refuses to coincide
                        with his new Democratic advisors whose opinions are on record, that both the
                        Pierpont government, and the government of the new State of West Virginia
                        are unconstitutional. In North Carolina and other states, President Johnson
                        will probably appoint provisional Governors from the really loyal men, until
                        such times as the States are ready to adopt new constitutions abolishing
                        slavery and repudiating the heresy of secession.</p>
                    <p>In view of all that President Johnson has suffered, done and is still doing,
                        there seems little room for the Democratic party to hope to make a convert
                        of him, and until we see more indication of it than at present, we shall
                        rest perfectly easy.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Despite the Democratic press' recent "discovery" that President Johnson was
                    formerly a Democrat and will therefore promulgate policies to their liking, the
                    editors incredulously dismiss the possibility that he would abandon his
                    Republican principles to join the same men who "denounced him throughout the war
                    as a demagogue" and "sneered at him as a traitor to his section."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Hand Of God In The War</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors extoll the virtues of the article penned by Rev. Dr. Conrad,
                    which was originally scheduled to be presented as a speech on Nov. 19, 1863, at
                    the dedication ceremony for the National Cemetery.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Arch-Murderer Captured</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"It is a crime as much against the laws of war as the laws of peace, and
                    there can be no refuge from its penalty."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>A. K. M.</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article reports on Jeff Davis's capture and calls for his execution, a
                    punishment, it alleges, most northerners find befitting his actions.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Warning To guerrillas</head>
                <origin>Washington</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A copy of Gen. Halleck's order notifying guerilla fighters that from
                    henceforth they will be "treated as outlaws and robbers." As such, they are
                    liable to be "punished with death" should they continue their struggle.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>On To Mexico</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is reported that a large number of applicants, including thousands of
                    former Union soldiers, have volunteered in New York to emigrate to Mexico. The
                    "man at the head of the enterprise," the Mexican republican General Ortega, will
                    provide $1,000 and eight hundred acres of land for each "common emigrant" and
                    much larger bounties for those individuals commissioned as officers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1865.07.17.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Gossip With Our Friends</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A report from "Gossip," a Repository correspondent, who is in New York. In
                    his column, Gossip relates the latest happenings in that city, which includes
                    emigration to Mexico, the drop in the price of gold, and the latest women's
                    fashions. Gossip also relates his experience while riding "in a car between a
                    black man and a black women," which, he sardonically notes, did not result in
                    any discoloration of his clothes or "perceptible alteration" in the "moral tone"
                    of his "general character."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Soldiers' Cemetery</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is reported that the residents of Waynesboro and Washington township
                    have organized a drive to raise $5,000 to purchase a burial ground in order to
                    inter all the bodies of the Union soldiers from the "neighborhood" who died
                    during the war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--President Johnson A Life Director Of The Bible Society</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that President Johnson was granted a "Life Directorship" in the
                    Pennsylvania Bible Society during the anniversary meeting of the Franklin county
                    chapter.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that an effort is being made to consolidate the Cumberland Valley
                    and Franklin Railroad companies. On May 31st, a meeting of the two companies'
                    stockholders will be held in Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rinehart</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greene</ln>
                        <fn>Martha Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McElroy</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On April 30th, James Rinehart and Martha Jane Greene were married by Rev.
                    William McElroy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Slichter</ln>
                        <fn>Simon T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Karper</ln>
                        <fn>Rose R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On May 9th, Simon T. Slichter and Rose R. Karper were married by Rev. M.
                    Snyder.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pague</ln>
                        <fn>J. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snoddy</ln>
                        <fn>Mollie E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hassler</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On May 6th, J. R. Pague and Mollie E. Snoddy were married by Rev. J.
                    Hassler.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Witherow</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tucker</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tucker</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Major</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kephart</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On May 8th, William Witherow, of the 21st Penna Cavalry, and Mary E.,
                    daughter of Major Robert Tucker, were married by Rev. J. L. Kephart in City
                    Point, Va.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1865.07.17.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
