<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1868/va.au.rv.1868.09.18">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>09/27/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1868-09-18">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day norm="">18</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1868.09.18.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1868.09.18.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The cry upon which the Radicals of the North harp most is that the Southern
                        people are still "rebellious." They would make all believe that we are ready
                        to take up arms at the slightest provocation. That, in the election of
                        Seymour and Blair, the opportunity will be offered and embraced by us to
                        carry out our most cherished hopes. That we will then re-inaugurate the
                        "rebellion" and do <sic>divers</sic> things, terrible, on paper, to Northern
                        pacifiers, of the Grant school.--All this is for buncombe. No people or
                        party understand better than the Radicals the state of affairs in the South.
                        They know that, with the fall of the Confederacy, the South became a
                        penniless and impoverished land. They know that, with the loss of labor and
                        property, consequent diminishing and even extensive failure of crops, total
                        demolition of a circulating medium and enormous burdens of taxation heaped
                        upon her, the South has not and will not have a dollar to spare towards
                        another "rebellion" for years to come. They know equally well that our
                        bravest and our best, our General officers and our privates, returned home,
                        not to stir up strife anew, but to engage in some honest calling whereby
                        they might secure a livelihood to those dependent on them, and right nobly
                        have they accomplished their purpose. They know that our people at present
                        are not animated with the passions of the past, else they would send,
                        howling, from our midst such men as Wells, Underwood, Holden and the whole
                        host of "scalawags" and "carpetbaggers," whose sole business it is to
                        humiliate and oppress a fallen foe. We repeat, that not even the fear of the
                        decimation of the whites of the South would prevent them from hurling from
                        their midst the whole "carpet-bag" and "scalawag" tribe, were they in the
                        same humor as from 1861 to 1865. The very fact, therefore, that these pests
                        of community are allowed to hold their soft places in peace, and devote
                        their energies and time to further oppress and humiliate <del/> on the part
                        of the South. This also the Radicals understand equally well, but they want
                        capital for the Presidential campaign. This they must have or they are
                        defeated.</p>
                    <p>To secure it, they will between this time and November, through their
                        emissaries, their scalawag and carpet-bag pets, endeavor further to alienate
                        the white and colored people of the South. If they can incite a strife
                        between them from which they can raise the cry that the whites are beginning
                        their oppression of the blacks it will suit their purposes and they will not
                        hesitate to do it. In fact, they will go further, if possible, and place a
                        few murders and riots, similar to the one they incited in New Orleans, in
                        the catalogue of complaints against the South, which they must have to
                        bolster the waning chances of their candidates in the North.</p>
                    <p>We therefore caution all to a forbearance in many things which will be done
                        expressly to stir up strife. The quiet which has existed for so long a time
                        is telling against the Radicals. Its continuance is <sic>esur</sic> to
                        defeat the election of Grant and Colfax and relieve the country from the
                        burdens, now so heavily weighing down each and every portion of it.</p>
                    <p>With such a consummation in view, who would not restrain the passions which
                        will be sought to be aroused from this time till the Presidential election!
                        Be, therefore, forewarned and fore-armed against all the wiles of
                        Radicalism, and the result will be eminently satisfactory to every patriot
                        in the land.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Refutes the Republican charge that the election of Seymour will be the
                    symbol for a renewal of the rebellion. Points out how economically depressed the
                    South is, and claims Republicans are just stirring up Northern hatred for
                    political ends. Even accuses them of inciting riots in New Orleans.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Sentiments of the Southern People--Statement of a Republican</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that a prominent Republican returned from a tour of the
                    South and stated that reports of ill-will in the South are greatly exaggerated.
                    The KKK, according to this observer, is only a band of lawless miscreants.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1868.09.18.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A Sunday School Picnic will be held at Moscow, Augusta County, on September
                    19th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"Blind" Willie Coffman, the baby pianist, has been amazing audiences in
                    Staunton. The infant prodigy has astonished all listeners.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Bryan's Great Menagerie and Circus</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The circus will be in town on September 25th. Charles H. Castle, general
                    agent, has had difficulty finding a big enough location for the extravaganza.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Mechanics Building Association held their second annual meeting on
                    Tuesday night. The funds on hand were loaned at 66% and the remaining shares of
                    a total 1000 were purchased.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Watchman, Pa.</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article tallies up the so-called "fruits" of the war: "stealings of the
                    Freedman's Bureau;" waste in Congress; and a "plundered" South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tillery</ln>
                        <fn>Lewellen A. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cowger</ln>
                        <fn>Louisa A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cowger</ln>
                        <fn>Job</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Neff</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pinkerton</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lewellen A. S. Tillery of Missouri and Miss Louisa A. Cowger, daughter of
                    Job Cowger, were married on September 10th at the residence of Jacob Neff by the
                    Rev. John Pinkerton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shiplet</ln>
                        <fn>Martin S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>Catherine E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thomas</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Martin S. Shiplet and Miss Catherine E. Wright, daughter of the late
                    William Wright, were married near Moscow on September 3rd by the Rev. Jacob
                    Thomas.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gregory</ln>
                        <fn>James Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gregory</ln>
                        <fn>Charles E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gregory</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James Thomas Gregory, only son of Charles E. and Margaret R. Gregory of
                    Staunton, died on September 10th. He was 18 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>Robert M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Robert M. White died at his residence near Waynesboro on September 3rd. He
                    was 72 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Benjamin Koiner died at his residence near Waynesboro on September 12th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1868.09.18.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
