<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1868/va.au.rv.1868.10.23">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>10/03/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1868-10-23">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="10">October</month>
            <day norm="">23</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1868.10.23.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1868.10.23.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The result of the recent elections in the States of Pennsylvania, Ohio,
                        Indiana and Nebraska has made a great many of the Seymour and Blair party
                        despondent as to the result of the Presidential election in November. The
                        hope of Democratic successes in those States, which vanished with the
                        earliest telegrams received, is the occasion of the despondency and not the
                        actual summing up of Republican majorities. These show a considerable
                        decrease on the previous gubernatorial elections, save in Ohio, where there
                        is an increase from 3,000 to about 15,000 majority. In Indiana the
                        Republican majority in the previous gubernatorial election was over 20,000,
                        while in the late election it is doubtful how the State has gone--in fact
                        both Democrats and Republicans claim the State by very small
                        majorities.--While these States have gone Republican, generally, by
                        decreased majorities, the Democrats have gained ten congressmen.</p>
                    <p>In setting forth these facts, we do not desire to raise false hopes of
                        success for the Democracy in November, but simply to show that they have
                        fought a good fight and that there is no occasion for the despondency which
                        some exhibit.</p>
                    <p>There were, besides the mere issues of parties in the late elections, many
                        local issues introduced, which will not be brought to bear in November.
                        There will then be other issues, equally strong, introduced, besides the
                        policy of the two contending parties. Then the Republicans will have to
                        contend with the hatred to Gen. Grant on the part of our Jewish
                        fellow-citizens, engendered by his famous military order against them. In
                        these elections it is likely the Jewish vote has been divided, but in the
                        Presidential election it is likely it will be cast <emph rend="italic">en
                            masse</emph> against Grant and Colfax. This is no small item and may
                        turn the scale against the now jubilant party.</p>
                    <p>On the other hand the bold letter of Gen. Blair, which secured him the
                        nomination, has been made to tell with considerable effect in the late
                        elections, by the perversion of his position, and the <emph rend="italic"
                            >cute</emph> inference assiduously disseminated that the Democratic
                        party is pledged to overthrow the new State governments in the South <emph
                            rend="italic">by force</emph>.</p>
                    <p>If the Democracy can undo the effect produced by the Republican party on this
                        later score all may be well. It will require incessant work and
                        never-flagging exertion. They will make a bold effort to overcome all the
                        incidental as well as direct issues. In fact both parties will put forth
                        extraordinary exertions. They have merely skirmished with and felt the
                        strength of each others columns, preparatory to the grand campaign to
                        culminate in November. The result thus far is not a sufficient ground for
                        exultation or despondency to either party. The vote in November will be
                        closer than many suppose. Let us therefore neither exult nor cry aloud till
                        then.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on the recent electoral returns from several large states. Admits
                    the Republicans have taken all of them but also notes their majorities have
                    decreased considerably since the last election. Offers a small ray of hope by
                    saying the election in November will still be too close to call.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1868.10.23.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Ladies of Staunton's Baptist congregation will give an oyster supper
                    each night during the fair. The proceeds will go to benefit their church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rusmisel</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Constable</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wells</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Runnells</ln>
                        <fn>Doc</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCutchen</ln>
                        <fn>William F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sterrett</ln>
                        <fn>William G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Constable Rusmisel of Middlebrook arrested John Wells and Doc. Runnells,
                    two black men charged with stealing from the Spring House of William F.
                    McCutchen. They had a hearing before William G. Sterrett who committed them to
                    jail.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper urges residents of the Valley to attend the fair. There will be
                    exhibitions including the world's largest ox. Concerts will be given every
                    night.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Powell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The store of Taylor and Powell was broken into and robbed. "A negro man
                    supposed to be one of the lately escaped penitentiary convicts" is suspected.
                    Mr. Powell spotted him and gave chase, but he escaped. "We think the increase of
                    our police force is imperatively demanded, and private policemen on the part of
                    our business men would not be amiss."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Rice's Richmond Troupe will perform at the Town Hall during the fair. The
                    group includes James B. Smith, Prof. Volker, and a "fine lady vocalist" and
                    "danseuse."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Friends of Temperance</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The third annual meeting of the State Council of the Friends of Temperance of
                        Va., assembled in the Odd Fellows Hall in this place, Tuesday night inst,
                        the President Mr. A.P. Abell in the chair. A larger number of the Councils
                        are represented than has been the case heretofore. There are 47 Councils in
                        the State, and the order is progressing steadily and successfully. The
                        President in his address said: It is matter of fearful regret that the order
                        had not yet been able fairly to present its claims to universal adoption.
                        This, he said, at whatever cost, must be done. The cry of agony comes into
                        our ears, from the ten thousands crushed, bleeding and dying victims of the
                        enemy. Missionaries must be sent forth, public opinion must be commanded,
                        and above all, the potent influence of women must be secured in the
                        "Associated Councils." He alluded gratefully and hopefully to the <emph
                            rend="italic">active campaign</emph> and its success in the Valley. The
                        Council at the University he said, would prove to be a "school of the
                        prophets," and exert a most happy and benign influence in all the Southern
                        States.</p>
                    <p>After the close of the President's address, the remainder of the evening was
                        devoted to hearing statements from members of the good accomplished in their
                        respective neighborhoods. Members of subordinate Councils, although not
                        eligible, were by vote, admitted to the meeting as visitors.</p>
                    <p>The election of officers resulted as follows:</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">President</emph>, Geo. A. Bruce, of Waynesborough. <emph
                            rend="italic">Associate</emph>, J.E. Roller, of Harrisonburg. <emph
                            rend="italic">Chaplain</emph>, Rev. Wm. W. Greene, of
                            Spotsylvania.--<emph rend="italic">Secretary</emph>, Rev. W. B. Wellons
                        of Suffolk. <emph rend="italic">Treasurer</emph>, A.P. Abell, of
                        Charlottesville. <emph rend="italic">Conductor</emph>, Dr. James L. Leitch,
                        of Rockbridge. <emph rend="italic">Sentinel</emph>, James W. Newton, of
                        Staunton.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Abell</ln>
                        <fn>A. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bruce</ln>
                        <fn>George A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newton</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Gives an overview of a meeting of Temperance advocates held in Staunton.
                    Briefly summarizes the speeches made and lists the officers elected.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>At the meeting Tuesday of the Friends of Temperance, a claim was urged for a
                        Council in the Valley as the <emph rend="italic">banner</emph> Council. One
                        of the Representatives from Charlottesville thought the banner should belong
                        to the Boy's Council (Hopewell) as it has sent an old fogy, belonging to the
                        press gang for upwards of 52 years, to represent them, when the following
                        settled the claim. <emph rend="italic">Waynesboro Council</emph>--Who can
                        doubt that this is the banner Council of the Order in the State when at its
                        head is to be found a BRUCE with clarion voice and flashing claymore
                        rallying the GENTRY living in that pleasant WAY, who LONG to FRY out and
                        HUFF off the dram sellers and then crow like CHAPMAN when they are all safe
                        from the tempter's snare and secure within the folds of Waynesboro Council
                        No. 9 Friends of Temperance.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on a disagreement among temperance groups in the state as to the
                    status of one of the Councils.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tanner</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schott</ln>
                        <fn>E. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>George B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Tanner and Miss Mary Susan Cook, both of Augusta, were married near
                    Staunton at the residence of E. W. Schott by the Rev. George B. Taylor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoge</ln>
                        <fn>C. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>French</ln>
                        <fn>A. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McChain</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>C. E. Hoge of Staunton and Miss A. B. French of Abingdon were married in
                    Abingdon on October 15th by the Rev. James McChain.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>Fannie V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McFarland</ln>
                        <fn>Francis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John W. Hays and Miss Fannie V. Wright, both of Augusta, were married on
                    October 1st at the residence of the bride's mother by the Rev. Francis
                    McFarland.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Argenbright</ln>
                        <fn>John R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zimmerman</ln>
                        <fn>Henrietta V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J. I.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John R. Argenbright and Henrietta V. Zimmerman, both of Augusta, were
                    married on October 16th at the house of the bride by the Rev. J. I. Miller.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gabbert</ln>
                        <fn>Sallie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gabbert</ln>
                        <fn>Wilson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Sallie Gabbert died in Arbor Hill at the residence of her nephew,
                    Wilson Gabbert, on October 18th. She was 104 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Conklin</ln>
                        <fn>George H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George H. Conklin died in Staunton on October 19th. He was 57 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1868.10.23.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
