<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1864/va.au.ss.1864.04.12">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Amy Murrell</taggerName>
            <tagDate>9/2/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 9/8/97</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1864-04-12">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day>12</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1864.04.12.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>A New Value of Sorghum</head>
                <origin>Lynchburg Virginian</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Informs readers of the benefits of growing sorghum.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>"Old Abe"</head>
                <origin>New York Herald</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that the New York Herald is frustrated with Lincoln and has abandoned
                    him as a "hopeless case."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Speech of Mr. Roebuck on the American War--His Opinion of the Yankee Nation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prints address given before the British House of Commons that condemns the
                    hypocrisy of the Northern states.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Miscegenation--What it Means--Remarkable Confession of a Republican Journal</head>
                <origin>New York Times</origin>
                <commentary>"The Yankees, says the Richmond <emph rend="italic">Examiner</emph> are
                    running mad in their love for the negro. Not content with sacrificing one
                    million of lives of their own men in this war for the negro, (as confessed by a
                    New York paper)--not content in receiving them "with marked favour" at the
                    President's receptions--not content with riding in the same car with them--not
                    content in having them as pall-bearers at the funeral of their great public men,
                    (one of the pall-bearers at Owen Lovejoy's funeral was, according to their own
                    accounts, a negro, formerly a slave)--not content with making soldiers of them,
                    and placing them on a political equality--not content with all this, the
                    Republican party, in their wild love for the negro, has inaugurated a new
                    chapter in their creed: "Miscegenation"--<emph rend="italic">a wholesale
                        intermarriage of blacks and whites</emph>. This is the last and new phase of
                    abolitionism in the North. It is openly and unblus[h]ingly avowed--preached even
                    from the pulpit! It is the new test of Republican faith. To show how rapidly and
                    alarmingly the infamous and disgusting practice is spreading in the North, we
                    copy a portion of an editorial on the subject from the New York <emph
                        rend="italic">Times</emph>. The reader must bear in mind, when reading the
                    article below, that it is the language, not of a "Copperhead" journal, but of a
                    thorough, out and out Republican journal--an open, voluntary confession of a
                    paper that has never faltered in its support and devotion to the principles of
                    that party, and that has done as much in advocacy of the Lincoln administration
                    and the encouragement of this war as any other paper in the whole North. Now
                    that it sees ruin and degradation and a level with the negro staring it in its
                    face, it is forced to confess (and a very humiliating confession it is for a
                    Republican paper) that the only quarter to which the country can now look to be
                    saved is the Democratic party. But let no one fail to read this article--let it
                    be circulated in every Southern paper far and wide--let it be read, if
                    necessary, to our army. If there is a man in the whole South that can read this
                    confession below without firing his heart and causing a feeling of shame that we
                    should ever have lived with such a people, then he must be dead indeed to every
                    sense of honor, pride and virtue."</commentary>
                <excerpt>"We have no hesitation in saying that if we had at the outset conceived it
                    possible that hostility to slavery would ever have led to wholesale
                    intermarriage with negroes, the Republican party should never have received any
                    countenance or support from this journal."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>[From the New York Times.] <lb/>What Are We Coming To? </p>
                    <p>A rage for marrying black people has lately taken possession of the
                        Republican party. Radicals have carried everything before them, if things go
                        on at their present rate it is feared that, in three months, every white man
                        who is not connected by marriage with a coloured family will be "read out"
                        of the party. The gusto with which the abolitionists go into the insane
                        movement is something at once distinguished and alarming. We shrink from
                        putting on paper the stories which reach us as to the prevalence of this
                        evil. We will only say that there will very soon be hardly a family in the
                        city belonging to the Republican persuasion which will not be glorying in
                        the possession of a negro son-in-law. It is said, we know not with what
                        truth, that the Union Legaue [sic] Club has fitted up a night bell at its
                        door, and keeps a black minister on the premises who marries all couples of
                        different colours at any hour of the day or night. Soon we may expect to
                        hear of duels being fought about some black washer-woman, and crowds of
                        white men thronging the basements of those families who have coloured
                        servants in their houses for the purpose of soliciting the honor (?) of
                        their hands.</p>
                    <p>It is with great reluctance that we speak out our minds in this matter. But
                        we have no hesitation in saying that if we had at the outset conceived it
                        possible that hostility to slavery would ever have led to wholesale
                        intermarriage with negroes, the Republican party should never have received
                        any countenance or support from this journal. We owe it to ourselves and to
                        posterity to say that the thing has taken us by surprisee [sic]. It never
                        entered our head. We now see and confess our errour [sic] and deplore it.</p>
                    <p>The question which now naturally suggests itself to every right-minded white
                        man and woman is, where is this thing to <emph rend="italic">end?</emph>
                        Whither are we tending? What is to be done to stop this unnatural and
                        detestable movement. For it is as plain as a pikestaff that if it continues
                        there will be soon no whites left in this once great and prosperous country.
                        We shall all be mulattoes, and be afflicted with all the peculiarities, both
                        mental and physical, of that unhappy race. The signs of this great and
                        terrible change already begin to make themselves manifest in our streets;
                        for the most careless observer who walks down Broadway can hardly fail to
                        observe the appearance on a vast number of faces of the well-known brownish
                        tinge. Let that tinge once become general, and then fare-well, a long
                        farewell, to all our whiteness. </p>
                    <p>There is but one quarter--and we are not ashamed to own it--in which, in our
                        opinion, we can look for either help or comfort at this crisis, and that is
                        to the great, old, truly national Democratic party. It has its faults;
                        nobody has been forced to call attention to them oftener than we; but it has
                        never yet proved false to its race, and we are satisfied that whatever can
                        be done now will be done by it to preserve the purity of our blood.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Excerpts Northern editorial expressing alarm that the Republican party
                    might go so far as to permit miscegenation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Sugar From Chinese Sugar Cane</head>
                <origin>Southern Recorder</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Explains process involved in obtaining sugar from Chinese sugar cane.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>7</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>A. G. Hamilton, Pres't., G. A. Helmick, Sect.</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Members of Company L, 25th Virginia Regiment, send a copy of resolutions
                    they adopted thanking ladies of Augusta County for providing them with
                    provisions and socks.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Many Voters</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vanlear</ln>
                        <fn>D. Newton</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The authors explain why they intend to vote for D. Newton Vanlear for
                    magistrate of Mt. Solon district.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Company G, 25th Virginia Regiment</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Thanks the ladies near Greenville and Brownsburg for their donation of
                    socks.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Mr. Editor:</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>J. N. McFarland</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echard</ln>
                        <fn>William F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes that a recent tribute to deceased members of Company E, 5th Virginia
                    Infantry, failed to note that William F. Echard died a week after being wounded
                    at Gettysburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Execution of a Deserter</head>
                <origin>Rockbridge Register</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that William Cook was executed last week for deserting the
                    Confederate army.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Ads, poetry, and fiction, columns 1-3; report on the rejuvenated Tennessee
                army, column 7</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1864.04.12.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Papers for the Army</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Explains that the Spectator will pay the postage required to ensure that
                    subscribers in the Army of Northern Virginia receive copies of the paper.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Approaching Conflict</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In a short time the earth will be made to tremble beneath the shock of armed
                        hosts in hostile and deadly conflict. The armies of the South and North are
                        now girding up their loins for a most terrible encounter. The most crimson
                        page in the book of Time will be written in blood the ensuing Summer. The
                        enemy feel that, if they fail to conquer us in this campaign, the task is
                        hopeless, and that anarchy and irretrievable ruin will be their lot.
                        Therefore it is that they are using every possible exertion to overcome us
                        in this campaign. We should prepare with industry, and resolve to meet their
                        assaults with firmness and determined bravery. We have confidence in the
                        justness of our cause, the exalted bravery of our soldiers, and the
                        fortitude and patriotism of our citizens. It will not be long before these
                        virtues will be subjected to another test of their strength. In the language
                        of the Richmond Examiner, "the sun and winds of April will soon leave the
                        roads dry and hard, inviting the roll of artillery wagon-wheels; the fresh
                        green sward will be firm under the feet of marching brigades; the song of
                        birds upon every spray will upbraid the silence of the charging bugle, and
                        the Favonian zephyrs of spring will softly lift and flutter the folds of the
                        regimental flags. All nature pleads with man to come and do his part, and,
                        seeing battle is the business in hand, cries aloud that now is the day and
                        the hour to put it through. Our long endearing and devoted soldiers would
                        surely move to the fray with even a more fiery and invincible alacrity, if
                        they had good reason to hope that one or two stalwart blows, struck this
                        summer, would close the bitter struggle, and enable the most of them to
                        march to their far off homes through a country wild with joy; through towns
                        and villages illuminated with triumph; welcomed and hailed with patriotic
                        music and "orators of the day"; in a rain of roses flung by whitest hands.
                        Surely a reasonable anticipation of so glorious an autumn would nerve our
                        troops to pass more lightly and gaily through a bloody spring and
                    summer."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Predicts that a "most terrible encounter" between the North and South is in
                    store for sometime this summer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Appeal for Fredericksburg</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the citizens of Fredericksburg are in great need of food and
                    supplies.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Robbery of a Church</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Informs readers that some "graceless rogue" has robbed Bethel Church of
                    carpet and tapestries.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Corporation Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Balthis</ln>
                        <fn>William L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stevenson</ln>
                        <fn>R. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sterrett</ln>
                        <fn>William G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Points</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bruce</ln>
                        <fn>A. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scherer</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kayser</ln>
                        <fn>William B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Evans</ln>
                        <fn>Jno. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>F. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hardy</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGuffin</ln>
                        <fn>D. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>James F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tams</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Provides results of the town sergeant and councilmen elections, which were
                    held on April 6. The mayor had no opposition and was reelected; William L.
                    Balthis beat R. W. Stevenson for office of Sergeant; and the following were
                    elected councilmen: Wm. G. Sterrett, B. F. Points, Jas. W. Crawford, F. M.
                    Young, A. W. Bruce, John B. Scherer, Wm. B. Kayser, Wm. H. Wilson, Jno. B.
                    Evans, John M. Hardy, and Geo. Baylor. James F. Patterson was elected clerk,
                    while Wm. L. Balthis received the most votes for Chief of Police. F. M. Young's
                    election was later declared void, and D. C. McGiffin elected in his place. Also,
                    John B. Scherer resigned after the election and Wm. H. Tams was elected to fill
                    that vacancy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Half Rations</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Meat should be freely given, no one should play 'hide and seek.'"</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Explains recent impressment law that will allow families to retain one-half
                    of the meat supply they usually depend on in a given year.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Plant Corn, Potatoes, and Other Edibles</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges readers to plant early and not to hoard their harvests in the
                    upcoming year.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Cultivate the Soil</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The cultivation of the soil is this moment an object of greater importance
                    in the Confederacy than the filling of its armies."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Tells readers that not a foot of ground should be wasted when planting
                    crops.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Mr. Spitler</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Wm. B. Dunlap</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spitler</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spitler</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>News from Point Lookout, Maryland, informs relatives of the death of David
                    Spitler on March 13 of chronic diarrhea.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Justices of the Peace Again</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the Secretary of War has followed Virginia's lead and approved
                    the exemption of justices of the peace of any age.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Mosby Rather Outwitted</head>
                <origin>Richmond Whig</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that Colonel Mosby captured a Yankee picket post with four men but
                    was later overtaken by one of the prisoners.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Reserve Forces</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>By the circular of the Conscription Bureau the commandants of conscripts are
                        ordered forthwith to enroll all persons between the ages of seventeen and
                        eighteen, and forty-five and fifty years of age, allowing them until the
                        first of May to join any company for local defence, formed under the
                        necessary regulations, and liable to service anywhere in the State or to
                        form themselves into voluntary organizations and elect their own officers.
                        Those who do not thus dispose of themselves will be formed into companies,
                        battalions and regiments, under regulations to be prescribed.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the Conscription Bureau will now enroll all men between the
                    ages of 17 and 18, and 45 and 50.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Brief note informs readers that Confederate forces captured 32 prisoners
                    and 29 horses down the Valley without any losses to the South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Many Voters</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ryan</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Provides glowing endorsement of Lieut. Joseph N. Ryan for office of circuit
                    court clerk.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>A List of Killed, Wounded, and Deceased in the 52d VA Infantry Regiment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>G. S. R., Written at Summerville Ford</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Frey</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palmer</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dabney</ln>
                        <fn>E. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Loyd</ln>
                        <fn>Granville</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fauber</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fultz</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McManaway</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woomeldoph</ln>
                        <fn>David B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lamb</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Byers</ln>
                        <fn>John S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turk</ln>
                        <fn>James G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Serg't</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Corporal</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Byers</ln>
                        <fn>Robert G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Corporal</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cale</ln>
                        <fn>David T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brooks</ln>
                        <fn>A. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Croft</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Demasiers</ln>
                        <fn>Robert W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Knight</ln>
                        <fn>John G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kershner</ln>
                        <fn>John R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snapp</ln>
                        <fn>John R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swink</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kerr</ln>
                        <fn>William S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Corporal</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hemp</ln>
                        <fn>William C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trainer</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rusmisell</ln>
                        <fn>George L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Humphrey</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chandler</ln>
                        <fn>A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Creel</ln>
                        <fn>Matthew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Alvis</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bailey</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huff</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rife</ln>
                        <fn>A. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>S. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swink</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>William J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gibson</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weller</ln>
                        <fn>Charles L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bright</ln>
                        <fn>Josiah F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Curry</ln>
                        <fn>Granville S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Serg't</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dinkle</ln>
                        <fn>William J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Humphrey</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beach</ln>
                        <fn>Dabney S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palmer</ln>
                        <fn>William F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Byers</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Curry</ln>
                        <fn>George H. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lloyd</ln>
                        <fn>Granville</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>Addison</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Provides list of those killed or wounded in Captain E. M. Dabney's Company
                    C, 52d Virginia Infantry, since the company organized in 1861. In the Battle of
                    McDowell, May 8, 1862, William H. Frey and Samuel S. Palmer were killed, and
                    Captain E. M. Dabney, and Privates Granville Loyd and John W. Fauber were
                    wounded. In the Battle of Port Republic, June 9, 1862, George W. Fultz, John H.
                    McManaway, David B. Woomeldoph, and David Lamb were killed, and Lieutenants John
                    S. Byers, Lewis Harman, Samuel B. Brown, Serg't James G. Turk, Corporals John H.
                    Kennedy, Robert G. Byers, and Privates David T. Cale, A. B. Brooks, Jacob S.
                    Croft, Robert W. Demasiers, John G. Knight, John R. Kershner, John R. Snapp,
                    John H. Swink, and P. Smith were wounded. In the Battle of Gaines' Mill, June
                    27, 1862, Corporal William S. Kerr, and Privates William C. Hemp and George W.
                    Trainer were wounded. In the Battle of Malvern Hill, July 1, 1862, George L.
                    Rusmisell was wounded. In the Battle of Manassas, August 28-30, 1862, Thomas H.
                    Humphrey, A. J. Chandler, Matthew Creel, Samuel Wright, and George W. Trainor
                    were killed. Wounded were Lieut. John S. Byers, and Privates William Alvis, B.
                    F. Bailey, Daniel Huff, A. S. Rife, S. L. Smith, George W. Swink, and William J.
                    Wright. In the Battle of Fredericksburg, December 18, 1862, Captain E. M. Dabney
                    was mortally wounded, and Privates A. B. Brooks and John W. Gibson were wounded.
                    In the Battle of Marye's Heights, May 1-3, 1863, Lieut. Charles L. Weller was
                    wounded, and Private William H. Alvis was killed. In the Battle of Gettysburg,
                    July 1-3, 1863, Josiah F. Bright was killed. Those who have died from disease
                    are: Serg't Granville S. Curry, December 1861, and the following Privates:
                    William J. Dinkle, November 1861, James Humphrey, January 1862, Dabney S. Beach,
                    March 1862, William F. Palmer, May 1862, John H. Swink, June 1863, Samuel J.
                    Byers, August 1863, George H. A. Curry, August 1863, Granville Lloyd, August
                    1863, and Addison Fisher, 1864.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Wanted</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Charlie Marshall and Ned Lilly, members of Co. F, 5th Virginia Regiment,
                        "Stonewall Brigade," Army of Northern Virginia, are desirous of opening a
                        correspondence with some young Ladies, with a view to matrimony.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Best</emph> reference can be given as to character, both
                        as citizens and soldiers. Any ladies desirous of opening such a
                        correspondence, will please address us as above. </p>
                    <p>April 12--3ts.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Marshall</ln>
                        <fn>Charlie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lilly</ln>
                        <fn>Ned</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Two members of Company F, 5th Virginia Regiment, seek young ladies
                    interested in opening correspondence, with the possibility of matrimony to
                    follow.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shuey</ln>
                        <fn>George A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Glossbrenner</ln>
                        <fn>J. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Bishop</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>George C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shuey</ln>
                        <fn>S. Kate</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Bishop J. J. Glossbrenner married George C. Hanger of the 14th Virginia
                    Cavalry and S. Kate Shuey, daughter of Rev. George A. Shuey, on December 22,
                    1863.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vonce</ln>
                        <fn>William B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Professor</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>H. H.</fn>
                        <sf>C. S. A.</sf>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dove</ln>
                        <fn>Cornelia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Glossbrenner</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Bishop</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Professor William B. Vonce married Lieut. H. H. Hanger and Cornelia Dove,
                    daughter of Bishop Glossbrenner, on April 7.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Tribute of Respect</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>R. C. Walker, Moderator</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>R. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>John D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Members of the Union church pay their respects to John D. Brown, who died
                    March 11.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Reports of victories and setbacks in Tennessee, columns 2-3; previously
                published court and election announcements, columns 6-7</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
