<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1864/va.au.ss.1864.03.01">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Amy Murrell</taggerName>
            <tagDate>8/23/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 9/5/97</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1864-03-01">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day>1</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1864.03.01.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Address of Congress, To the People of the Confederate States</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Members of the Confederate Congress provide a report of the government's
                    accomplishments, which include the mobilization of a "unified" army and
                    citizenry.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>The Health of the Army</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the health of the Army of Northern Virginia has been very
                    encouraging over the last three months.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Important Arrival</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Brief article notes that the steamer Advance has returned to Wilmington
                    after successfully transporting cotton to Bermuda.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Classified ads and poetry, columns 1-3</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1864.03.01.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Stonewall Brigade</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The good people of this county will be greatly astonished, as we were, to
                        learn from the communication published in this issue, of Brig. Gen'l J.A.
                        Walker, commanding the "Stonewall Brigade" that there are two hundred of the
                        gallant soldiers of that famous Brigade who are without shoes and socks.
                        With Gen. Walker, we think it a "<emph rend="italic">shame</emph>", that
                        such should be the fact, but we are sure that the good people of this county
                        would not have suffered such a state of things to exist if they had been
                        apprised of the fact that shoes and socks were needed, had it been possible
                        for them to supply the need. We do not know whether they could have supplied
                        shoes, but socks, they could, and would have supplied with pleasure, if they
                        had been apprised of the need for them. The Government should have supplied
                        these necessary articles, but if it had been known in this county that the
                        Government could not, or had, by mismanagement, failed to furnish them, we
                        know that the citizens of this county would have done all in their power to
                        have the gallant soldiers of the illustrious "Stonewall Brigade" properly
                        shod. Think of it, the thermometer standing at <emph rend="italic"
                        >zero</emph>, and <emph rend="italic">two hundred soldiers of the "Stonewall
                            Brigade" without shoes and socks!!!</emph> This is truly a "<emph
                            rend="italic">shame</emph>," but the culpability does not attach to the
                        patriotic and benevolent citizens of this county. If the Government will
                        furnish the yarn, we promise that the fair ladies of "Augusta" will supply,
                        in a remarkably short time, the <emph rend="italic">whole Brigade</emph>
                        with good socks knit by their own fair hands. They do not regard working for
                        the soldiers as a labor, but a pleasure. For that burpose [sic] they work
                            <emph rend="italic">con amore</emph>, it being with them a labor of
                        love, and we can assure them it will not be "Love's labor lost." As we had
                        heard no complaint from the army this winter of the want of proper clothing
                        we had supposed that the soldiers had been amply supplied by the Government,
                        and consequently we made no appeals to our citizens to supply their wants in
                        that respect. If we had been apprised of the fact that our soldiers were
                        suffering for the want of shoes and socks we would have appealed to our
                        citizens to supply them, and we are satisfied, from their promptness in the
                        past, that the appeal would have been responded to with promptness and
                        cheerfulness. Now that our citizens know the wants of the soldiers in the
                        "Stonewall Brigade," we are sure that they will exert themselves to have
                        their wants supplied. The noble example of Mr. Wm. B. Gallaher and his
                        mother is worthy of emulation, and we hope that it will not be long before
                        the General Commanding the Stonewall Brigade will have the pleasure of
                        acknowledging similar donations from other persons in this county. It is not
                        expected that single individuals shall make such large donations, as but few
                        have the means to do so, but even larger can be made by associated action.
                        Large donations are composed of many small amounts, and if each will give
                        but little the aggregate will amount to a large sum. Even small donations,
                        will be recieved [sic] with gratitude, and, like the widow's mite, will be
                        abundantly blessed. It requires but a short argument to establish that the
                        citizens should contribute liberally to the support of the wants of the
                        soldiers. If our cause shall be successful, it will be due to the efforts
                        and sacrifices of the soldiers, and as they will save our property and make
                        our money good, we should be willing to pay a portion for their comfort. If
                        in spite of their heroic efforts, our cause be destined to fail, then the
                        money will be worth nothing, and the contributor will have lost <emph
                            rend="italic">nothing</emph> whilst he will have the consolation to know
                        that he did a good act, and promoted the comfort of the suffering soldiers
                        who freely spilt their blood in defence of his rights and property. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gallaher</ln>
                        <fn>William B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gallaher</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Expresses shock at a recent report that two hundred Stonewall Brigade
                    soldiers are without socks and shoes. Suggests that the citizens of Augusta
                    County would have provided these supplies had they been notified of the shortage
                    earlier.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Veitch</ln>
                        <fn>E.R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes that the Preachers of the Baltimore Conference in Virginia will be
                    meeting in Rockingham County on March 10.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Tableaux Vivants</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The exhibition of the Tableaux Vivants, given in the Union Hall, on Thursday
                        evening last, was well patronized. The Hall was filled to its utmost
                        capacity, and so great was the <emph rend="italic">press</emph> that there
                        was not a seat for the <emph rend="italic">Press</emph>, which concluded, in
                        good humor, to <emph rend="italic">stand</emph> it. After the Hall had been
                        filled to overflowing, and when it was as hard for any more to gain
                        admittance as it is for a camel to creep through the eye of a cambric
                        needle, the bell jingled, the curtain rose, and the first scene, "The
                        Reception," was exhibited. It was such as is frequently given, but not such
                        as confers pleasure--being formal, stylish and freezingly cold. "Infant
                        Samuel" was well represented, as was also the "Light of Life." "The Soldier
                        and Landlord," illustrated the imposition practised by some Landlords upon
                        Soldiers by charging <emph rend="italic">much</emph> for very <emph
                            rend="italic">little</emph>. "Home Treasures" were <emph rend="italic"
                            >treasures</emph> indeed, and where such "treasures are, there will the
                        heart be also." The "Unfortunate Schoolmaster," like the condemned criminal
                        on board ship, was compelled to "walk the plank," and "great was the fall,
                        my countrymen." This scene should have been entitled, "The fall of man." The
                        "Game of Draughts," <emph rend="italic">won</emph>, and made a considerable
                            <emph rend="italic">draught</emph> upon the approval of the spectators.
                        In "The Soldier's Departure", the departing hero was such a good <emph
                            rend="italic">soldier</emph> that he "stood upon the <emph rend="italic"
                            >order</emph> of his going," instead of going at once," and as the <emph
                            rend="italic">order</emph> to go was not given, his departure was not
                        accomplished. "Family Prayer" was a very impressive scene, and should have
                        impressed some who witnessed it that they should cease to <emph
                            rend="italic">prey</emph> like vultures and learn to <emph rend="italic"
                            >pray</emph> like Christians. "The Orphan Boy" struck the chord of
                        compassion in the "Harp of a thousand strings,"--the human heart. In "All is
                        fair in love and war," the chief art of war--"strategy, my boys,
                        strategy"--was shown to possess as much virtue in the court of Cupid as in
                        that of Mars. "The Marriage" scene was so beautiful and attractive as to
                        inspire many of the youthful spectators with the desire of enacting it--tho'
                        not in a style so mute and statue like. "First Boots" was very well acted,
                        and the proud little possessor of the boots had no idea of obeying the call,
                        so common in the army, "come out'n dem boots!" In the "Soldier's Return,"
                        the reception given the laurel-crowned and battle-scarred hero seemed more
                        of a surprise than a pleasure, owing probably to the fact that he returned
                        before the war was over--the "hurly-burly done, and the victory won." "Day
                        and night" embraced "all the light of dark eye in woman," and "as sure as
                        the night follows the day" it was not appreciated as it should have been.
                        "The Miniature" was quite a pretty scene. "Beautiful Star," though a
                        "bright, particular star", was not the <emph rend="italic">star</emph> scene
                        of the exhibition. "The Dream," though it seemed to partake of the Elysian
                        type, was, like Lord Byron's, "not all a dream." In the scene of "Pocahontas
                        and Capt. Smith," though <emph rend="italic">clubs</emph> were trumps, yet
                            <emph rend="italic">hearts</emph> won the game. "The Contest" concluded
                        the exhibition, and that it gave satisfaction, no one will <emph
                            rend="italic">contest</emph>. The proceeds of this exhibition amounted
                        to $1250. and that of the week before to $850., making an aggregate of
                        $2100., which will be applied to paying the debt of the M.E. Church of this
                        place. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Provides a review of the Tableaux Vivants benefit at Union Hall. Discusses
                    scenes such as those dealing with soldiers leaving home and families praying for
                    the soldiers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Interesting If True</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Summarizes recent reports of infighting among Yankee troops over the issue
                    of reenlistment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turner</ln>
                        <fn>Job</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that after several African Americans entered his property at night,
                    Job Turner is now prepared to shoot any future trespassers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Yankee Congress</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Both Houses of the Lincoln Congress have concurred in the report of the
                        Committee of Conference on the "Enrollment Bill." The report fixes the
                        commutation fee at $300, but renders the drafted man who commutes liable to
                        be drawn again after the expiration of one year. All able-bodied persons of
                        African descent between 20 and 45 years of age, are to be enrolled, and when
                        the <emph rend="italic">slave</emph> of a loyal master is drafted and
                        mustered into service, he shall be free, the master to be paid the sum to be
                        awarded by a commission, not exceeding $300. </p>
                    <p>Lincoln has issued a proclamation declaring the port of Galveston, Texas,
                        re-opened to the commerce of the world, with certain restrictions.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Provides an update on legislation being considered by the U.S. Congress
                    regarding the military enlistment of African Americans and the use of
                    substitutes in the army.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Substitute Question</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The case of Josiah Blackburn, who had furnished a substitute for the war,
                        came up on a writ of <emph rend="italic">habeas corpus</emph> for decision
                        before Judge Halyburton's Court in Richmond on Tuesday last. It was decided
                        by the Court that the recent law of Congress, placing this class of persons
                        in the service, was constitutional, and the men liable to service,
                        notwithstanding they may have been exempted for the war. The Judge denied
                        that the Government had the power to make a contract which would alienate
                        her right to the services of every man capable of bearing arms, and that if
                        such contract was made, it was null and void, and there was nothing in the
                        Constitution to restrain Congress from disregarding such contract, whenever
                        the exigencies of service might require the service of all men capable of
                        bearing arms. The case was elaborately argued by Messrs. Davis and Orvis for
                        the petitioner, the Government not being represented. Upon the rendition of
                        this decision the peti[t]ioner, Blackburn, was remanded to Camp Lee. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blackburn</ln>
                        <fn>Josiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Describes the recent court decision by a Richmond judge that supports the
                    Confederate Government's right to void substitution contracts when the army
                    needs the service of all men.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>A Fighting Governor</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"If you have the spirit which always glows in the hearts of freemen, you
                    will not hesitate; you will show by your acts, that freemen know how to die, and
                    not to falter, in defence of their homes and liberties."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprints part of a speech given by the Alabama Governor that called out for
                    more volunteers to defend that state's ports and western border.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Troubles of the Enemy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Summarizes five recent "failures" of the Union army, including a failed
                    attempt to release prisoners in Richmond and an aborted mission across the
                    Rapidan. The author says that readers should be grateful and encouraged by these
                    developments.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates a story from a Cincinnati paper that discusses how German regiments
                    are unable to reenlist in the Union army now that fighting has broken out back
                    in Germany.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Exchange of Prisoners</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that Generals Johnston and Grant have made plans to exchange
                    prisoners.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>To Mr. Jefferson Kinney</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Many Voters</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>Jefferson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Author urges Jefferson Kinney to consider running again for clerk of the
                    county court, despite having lost in the last election.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Citizens &amp; Soldiers of the Greenville District</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turk</ln>
                        <fn>Rudolph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Urges voters of Augusta County to reelect Col. Rudolph Turk for sheriff.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"To the people of Augusta, particularly, whose homes have never been
                    polluted by the presence of the invader, and whose means of liberality have not
                    been diminished by the war, I would appeal for aid."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Camp Stonewall Brigade, <lb/>Feb. 20th, 1864. </p>
                    <p>p&gt;ED. SPECTATOR: Allow me a short space in your columns, to
                        acknowledge the receipt of 50 pairs of shoes, a gift from Mr. Wm. B.
                        Gallaher, of Waynesboro, to the refugee soldiers of the "Stonewall" Brigade,
                        and 50 pairs of socks from his mother.</p>
                    <p>Such generous conduct speaks for itself, and no words of mine can do it
                        justice.</p>
                    <p>Is it not a shame, Mr. Editor, that there are at least two hundred soldiers
                        in this brigade still barefooted, without either shoes or socks to protect
                        them from the cold weather? Surely the good people of the Valley, whose
                        peculiar pride it is to have furnished the "old Stonewall Brigade" to the
                        country, do not know this, or they would strive with each other who should
                        first come to their relief.</p>
                    <p>To the people of Augusta, particularly, whose homes have never been polluted
                        by the presence of the invader, and whose means of liberality have not been
                        dimished [sic] by the war, I would appeal for aid. Remember Cross Keys and
                        Port Republic; and remember that more than one barefooted man in this
                        brigade can show scars which they received as they stood on the very border
                        of your county, perilling [sic] their lives to keep the enemy from your
                        homes!</p>
                    <p>How many gentlemen and ladies of Augusta county will follow the example set
                        them by Mr. and Mrs. Gallaher, and deliver to Col. Nadenbousch, Commanding
                        the Post at Staunton, similiar [sic] donations to be forwarded to the
                        brigade?</p>
                    <p>I am, Mr. Editor, <lb/>Very Respectfully, <lb/>J. A. WALKER <lb/>Brigadier
                        General. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>J. A. Walker, Brigadier General</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Brigadier General</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gallaher</ln>
                        <fn>William B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nadenbousch</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Brigadier General from the Stonewall Brigade thanks two Augusta County
                    residents for donating socks and shoes, and asks that more follow their example
                    and come to the aid of his troops.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>CAMP AT SUMMERVILLE FORD, <lb/>Feb. 21, 1864 </p>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">My good old Friends of Augusta:</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>Whereas, I think it my duty to inform you of our present condition, I shall
                        endeavor to do so, by first informing you that we now are volunteeringly in
                        for the war. Some few of our regiment refused to re-enlist, from the fact
                        that they want a re-organization, which, I think they will not get, and at
                        last be forced into service when their three year's time expires. It is our
                        duty to re-enlist and serve our country to the last. I have been serving the
                        Confederate States of America for three years. I have never had a furlough
                        since I first volunteered. I have received one wound from the enemy which
                        caused me to be absent from my company a few months. Yet I am determined to
                        remain with my company as long as my services are needed in defence of my
                        country.</p>
                    <p>I am truly happy to inform you that company C, 52d Virginia Infantry, has
                        re-enlisted for the war. This company has fought gallantly in every battle
                        the regiment has been engaged in, which are not a few.</p>
                    <p>The weather is beautiful at present and I hope it will remain so. All is
                        quiet along the lines at present.</p>
                    <p>I am, very respectfully, <lb/>A SOLDIER. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>A Soldier</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>A member of the 52nd Virginia Infantry voices his determination to remain
                    in the service, despite the refusal of other soldiers to reenlist.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Mountains</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>C. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports on a speech given by a former state senator from Augusta County
                    that argued for the South's right to secede. Author notes that the speech was
                    convincing and worthy of the attention of the entire South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>At a meeting of the members of Company D, 52d Va. regiment held at their camp
                        near Summerville Ford, Feb. 18th, 1864, for the purpose of reiterating their
                        determination to remain in the service of the Confederate States until the
                        present war with the United States shall have been brought to an honorable
                        close. On motion, Mr. Jesse Ralston, was unanimously elected Chairman, and
                        Sergt. James W. Marshall was chosen Secretary. On motion of Corpl. George
                        Harman, a committee of five were appointed to draft resolutions expressive
                        of the sentiments of the company. Whereupon the Chairman appointed Sergt.
                        Jas. H. Maupin, Fred. Cupp, Jas. Marshall, Jas. Curry and Corpl. Harman. The
                        committee after a short absence returned and the following resolutions were
                        unanimously adopted:</p>
                    <p>Resolved 1st, That we do recognize the necessity of remaining in the service,
                        and offering our past action as a guarantee of the sincerity of our purpose,
                        do pledge our honor, and, if need be, our lives, to fight this struggle to a
                        successful termination, over the embittered foe now marshalled for our
                        subjugation and destruction.</p>
                    <p>Resolved 2d, That we do, in vindication of what we have expressed, hereby
                        re-enlist for the war, with the reservation that we think the privilege of
                        reorganization ought to be granted us.</p>
                    <p>Resolved 3d, That in view of the exigencies of the crisis and the imperative
                        duty of every patriot, to rally to the bleeding standard of his country and
                        every Southerner to defend the battle torn and powder-stained flag of the
                        Confederate States, do reaffirm, that we will never consent to lay down our
                        arms, until the nationality and independence of our country shall have been
                        achieved.</p>
                    <p>Resolved 4th, That a copy of these proceedings be sent to the Staunton
                        Spectator and Rockingham Register for publication.</p>
                    <p>JESSE RALSTON, Chairman. <lb/>JAMES MARSHALL, Secretary. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Jesse Ralston, Chairman</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ralston</ln>
                        <fn>Jesse</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Marshall</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sergt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maupin</ln>
                        <fn>James H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sergt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cupp</ln>
                        <fn>Fred.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Curry</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Corpl.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Prints a copy of resolutions adopted by Company D of the 52nd Virginia
                    regiment that express those soldiers' determination to remain in service to the
                    Confederacy until the end of the war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>M.</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Terry</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes that the Spectator wrongly stated on February 23 that the 5th
                    Virginia regiment had reenlisted unanimously. It was the 4th Virginia that took
                    this action.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>See</ln>
                        <fn>George B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George B. See, a private in Company G, 52nd Virginia regiment, died of
                    typhoid pneumonia on February 21, 1864.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palmer</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palmer</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Frank Brown, the only son of Andrew J. and Rebecca E. Palmer, died of
                    diphtheria on February 25, 1864, at age 3 years and 4 months.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Announcements</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burnett</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces candidacy of William A. Burnett for clerk of the court.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Announcements</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Larew</ln>
                        <fn>John J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces candidacy of John J. Larew for office of sheriff of Augusta
                    County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Announcements</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paul</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces candidacy of Samuel Paul for office of sheriff for Augusta
                    County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Adjt. &amp; Insp. General's Office, General Orders No. 4</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>S. Cooper, Adj't and Insp'r General</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that General Braxton Bragg has been assigned duty in Richmond in
                    order to direct the conduct of Confederate military operations.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Treasury Notice As To Funding Under Act of Feb. 17, 1864</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>C. G. Memminger, Secretary of the Treasury</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Gives notice that any holders of Treasury Notes may exchange them for
                    certificates that will entitle holders to bonds.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Depositary's Office</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>A. F. Kinney, Depositary</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>A. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Depositary office in Staunton announces that it will conduct this exchange
                    of notes for bonds.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>In the County Court of Augusta</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>William A. Burnett, D. C.</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Francisco</ln>
                        <fn>C. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Berry</ln>
                        <fn>Thornton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trimble</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Larew</ln>
                        <fn>John J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rush</ln>
                        <fn>William T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bruce</ln>
                        <fn>George A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>David S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gentry</ln>
                        <fn>James N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craig</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gamble</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Cyrus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fulton</ln>
                        <fn>John G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rivercomb</ln>
                        <fn>John G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn>James J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lightner</ln>
                        <fn>A. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Montgomery</ln>
                        <fn>William W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Author announces that agents have been appointed to impress supplies from
                    Augusta County residents: C. C. Francisco and Thornton Berry will work in
                    district number one, John Trimble in district number two, John J. Larew and
                    William T. Rush in Greenville district, George A. Bruce and David S. Bell in
                    Waynesboro district, James N. Gentry and Joseph D. Craig in New Hope, William H.
                    Gamble and Cyrus Brown in Mt. Sidney district, John G. Fulton and John G.
                    Rivercomb in Mt. Solon district, William H. Bell and James J. Martin in
                    Middlebrook district, and A. B. Lightner and William W. Montgomery in
                    Churchville district.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Notice</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>George W. Hefner</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hefner</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hefner</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Author reports that his wife has left home and warns the public not to aid
                    her.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Updates on skirmishes around Cumberland Gap, in Mississippi, South Carolina
                and Northern Georgia, and along the Central Railroad</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
