<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1864/va.au.ss.1864.05.24">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Amy Murrell</taggerName>
            <tagDate>9/13/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 10/1/97</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1864-05-24">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day>24</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1864.05.24.01">
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>A Record of VA. Forces</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Jos. Jackson, Jr. Rec. Va. Forces</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Asks members of Virginia regiments to help the government in compiling a
                    list of all men who served Virginia in the war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Discipline of the Young</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Tells parents that setting a good example for children is the best way of
                    educating them about proper behavior.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Drying Vegetables</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Explains how summer fruits and vegetables can be preserved by drying.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>To Veterans of the Confederate Army</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Capt. George Chase</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Magnolia Weekly editor calls on readers to submit essays and sketches of
                    war incidents and developments to be included in a Southern record of the war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>How Grant Made His Men Fight</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"The following order shows the demoralization of Grant's army."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>S. Williams, Assistant Adjutant General</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prints copy of an order from the Army of the Potomac that threatens to
                    shoot any soldier who refuses to continue their duty on the grounds that their
                    term of service has expired.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Popping the Question</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prints fictional dialogue of a man struggling to ask his beloved to marry
                    him.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Military Execution</head>
                <origin>Rockingham Register</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Tells about the execution of a deserter from Rockingham in order to warn
                    others to avoid his fate.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Official Despatches</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prints three dispatches from officers in Spotsylvania, Demopolis, and
                    Charleston that all report the forced retreat of the enemy by Confederate
                    troops.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Congratulatory Order of Gen. Lee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>R. E. Lee, General</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces series of successes achieved by the Confederate army in Virginia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Gen. Dick Taylor's Congratulatory Address to His Troops</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>R. Taylor, Maj. Gen.</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Congratulates the Army of Western Louisiana for a victory in Mansfield on
                    April 8, 1864.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 1-4, illegible page, column 7</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1864.05.24.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>News from the Armies</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports latest news from the field, including a foiled attempt by Grant's
                    army to charge Confederate lines of entrenchment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that a telegram from General Joseph F. Johnston reports that Yankee
                    assaults on his troops' position were repulsed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Battle near Drewry's Bluff</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on the successful defense of Drewry's Bluff, in Southside Virginia,
                    during which 1,1100 Yankee prisoners were reportedly taken.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Battle Near New Market</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes the recent victory at New Market as one of the "most brilliant
                    victories of the war."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Operations in West Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Tells about the Colonel William Jackson's defeat of the enemy around Gap
                    Mountain, West Virginia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Virginia Reserves</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Takes note of recent orders by Brigadier Gen. James L. Kemper that requires
                    all members of the Virginia Reserves to assemble and prepare for duty.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Uniform for Gen. Lee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that General Lee apparently received a uniform that was made in
                    Baltimore.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Spirit of the Boys</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The impulse to this movement received additional strength from the
                    appearance of a negro regiment which occupied the town some weeks ago, the
                    greater portion having joined the army since that time. Such indignation and
                    disgust seized the community, that, not only the boys, but the children, were
                    roused and only wanted years and strength to have placed themselves by the side
                    of their brothers, only a few years older."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We are credibly informed that within the past three months not less than
                        thirty boys, between the ages of sixteen and eighteen, have come out from
                        Winchester, and are now not boys, but fighting men in the ranks of our army.
                        The impulse to this movement received additional strength from the
                        appearance of a negro regiment which occupied the town some weeks ago, the
                        greater portion having joined the army since that time. Such indignation and
                        disgust seized the community, that, not only the boys, but the children,
                        were roused and only wanted years and strength to have placed themselves by
                        the side of their brothers only a few days older. These boys are now
                        fighting as willing and ardent soldiers to reclaim their homes and
                        firesides, outraged and desecrated by the presence of such a foe. May they
                        reap such success as their courage and manliness deserve. This, no doubt, is
                        more or less the case throughout the border wherever these black regiments
                        have made their appearance. Verily, our enemies have served us many a good
                        turn since the commencement of this war. From the generous acts of Mr.
                        Banks, our Commissary General, who has strewn his favors with a lavish hand
                        all over Virginia and Louisiana, to the negro proclamations of Mr. Lincoln,
                        we derive no other feelings than those of the most unalloyed satisfaction.
                        In this connection, an incident worthy of record may be mentioned. Towards
                        the latter part of April, a young man, about seventeen years of age, by the
                        name of Jones, son of Edward Jones, of Winchester, came out and enrolled
                        himself in the cavalry company of Capt. Adams, then stationed in the
                        vicinity of Woodstock. He told his Captain that he had no horse, but thought
                        he would be able to obtain one in a few days, and returning to Winchester,
                        awaited his opportunity. On the Thursday, April 28th, after the rout of the
                        enemy's cavalry from Cedar Creek to Winchester by Capt. Davis, a force of
                        300 Yankee cavalry passed thro' Winchester up the Valley Turnpike for the
                        avowed purpose, smarting as they were under the rout of the previous Sunday,
                        of wiping out the rebels in that section of country. Some time after their
                        departure from the town, one of them returned and halted his horse on Main
                        Street, nearly opposite the house occupied by the father of young Jones.
                        Presently Jones emerged in Confederate uniform and walking across the street
                        directly towards the Yankee, when at a proper distance, accosted him, and
                        demanded his surrender. The Yankee made no reply but moved his hand towards
                        his pistol, which motion Jones perceiving, instantly fired, the ball passing
                        through the left breast of his antagonist. The Yankee fell gently from his
                        horse, and in falling, begged his assailant not to fire again, that he
                        surrendered; whereupon Jones, mounting the horse, ordered him to hand him
                        his sabre and pistols, which he did. Jones then, in double-quick, left town
                        by a by-road, and when our informant passed through Woodstock on the
                        following day, he was safe, fully armed and equipped, and handsomely mounted
                        a fighting private in the company of Capt. Adams. We have no doubt he will
                        do the Confederate States good service until our rights are secured, and his
                        own home rescued from the Lands of these vandal invaders. Many similar
                        instances might be mentioned to show the spirit and daring with which the
                        mere boys of the country have espoused her just and righteous cause. The
                        behavior of the Corps of Cadets, in the late fight near New Market, under
                        Gen. Breckinridge, which, according to his statement, was beyond all praise,
                        is an instance in point. All honor to the youth of our country who
                        everywhere have shown themselves worthy of revolutionary sires.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Explains why boys have become more enthusiastic recently about enlisting in
                    the Confederate army.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Generous Contributions, Soldiers Feasted</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We had intended to publish the names of the generous contributors from
                    each neighborhood, but found that they were so numerous that it would require
                    more space than we could spare. It is sufficient to say, that every neighborhood
                    in this county is well represented in the long catalogue of liberal and generous
                    contributors, as well as Old Providence, and other neighborhoods in our sister
                    county of Rockbridge, which emulates the example of Augusta in every good work."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Praises Augusta County residents who have provided food and supplies to
                    soldiers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Stonewall Brigade</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Lt. Col. Williams</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Williams</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lt. Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>Genl.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>D. C.</fn>
                        <sf>A. A. G.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Forwards message from an injured General Walker to members of the Stonewall
                    Brigade that congratulates the soldiers on their bravery in recent weeks.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Casualties in Company I, 5th VA. Infantry, From May 4th to the 13th</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sergt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dudley</ln>
                        <fn>William G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Corporal</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Alexander</ln>
                        <fn>Franklin</fn>
                        <sf>prisoner</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hall</ln>
                        <fn>John G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harnesberger</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shoemake</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stitson</ln>
                        <fn>Janar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitmore</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wicle</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kiracofe</ln>
                        <fn>W. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stringer</ln>
                        <fn>Thos. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sergt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Amarin</ln>
                        <fn>David H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anaren</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blakemore</ln>
                        <fn>Noel B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Branusman</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Buchanan</ln>
                        <fn>Walter W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carson</ln>
                        <fn>Josiah A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eavy</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fauver</ln>
                        <fn>James H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>James H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lambert</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phillips</ln>
                        <fn>John E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stitzer</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stitzer</ln>
                        <fn>Jonas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Silling</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wiseman</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kiracote</ln>
                        <fn>William H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sibert</ln>
                        <fn>J. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sergt. Major</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lists 5th Virginia soldiers wounded on May 5 at Locust Grove: Sergt. Henry
                    Miller, Corporal William G. Dudley, Franklin Alexander (prisoner), John G. Hall,
                    William H. Harman, Jacob A. Harnesberger, George W. Harman, Joseph P. Shoemake,
                    Janar Stitson, J. A. Whitmore, and Jacob Wicle. Wounded on May 12: W. T.
                    Kiracote (flesh wound in leg). Those missing as of May 12: Sergt. Thos. C.
                    Stringer, David H. Amarin, John H. Anaren, Noel B. Blakemore, John W. Branusman,
                    Walter W. Buchanan, Josiah A. Carson, Isaac Cock, Samuel H. Eavy, James H.
                    Fauver, James H. Harman, Samuel Lambert, John E. Phillips, Jacob Stitzer, Jonas
                    Stitzer, Jacob Silling, Samuel Wiseman, William H. H. Kiracote, George Baker,
                    and Sergt. Major Sibert (once a member of the company). Notes that 339 men are
                    left in the Stonewall Brigade.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Butler's Headquarters Captured</head>
                <origin>[Richmond] Examiner</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Confederates captured the headquarters of General Butler, but
                    missed Butler himself since he had already fled to his other headquarters on the
                    James River.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Augusta</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paul</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ryan</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Urges support for Lieuts. Paul and Ryan in the next election. Notes that
                    these two have sacrificed much for the sake of the Confederacy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>A Card</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Jefferson Kinney</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>Jefferson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Kinney assures readers that despite suffering from rheumatism, he would
                    still be strong enough to perform the duties of court clerk.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Many Voters</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henkle</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Urges support for David Henkle for magistrate of Greenville district.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Jas. W. Craig</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craig</ln>
                        <fn>Jas. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Declares his candidacy for constable in the Waynesboro district.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dice</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thornburg</ln>
                        <fn>T. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shafer</ln>
                        <fn>Kate H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On May 19 in Staunton, Rev. Mr. Dice married T. S. Thornburg and Kate H.
                    Shafer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bixie</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Malony</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cawley</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Caroline</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On May 12 in Bath Alum, Rev. Joseph Bixie married Michael Maloney and Mary
                    Caroline Cawley.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bare</ln>
                        <fn>Cicero</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Corporal</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bare</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Corporal Cicero Bare died on May 12 at age 29, of a severe wound to the
                    shoulder received while skirmishing with the Lee Rifles.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hague</ln>
                        <fn>Jonathan B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jonathan B. Hague died on May 17 at the age of 43.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Fresh Blockade Goods</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces the availability of clothing, fabric, tobacco, and other goods
                    that were recently brought in from England on the Steamer Advance.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Classified ads and previously published election announcements, columns
            6-7</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
