<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1864/va.au.ss.1864.02.02">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Amy Murrell</taggerName>
            <tagDate>9/21/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 9/30/97</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1864-02-02">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day>2</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1864.02.02.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Cure for Stretches in Sheep</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Offers cure for the fatal "stretches" disease currently plaguing sheep in
                    the county.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Confederate States Congress</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on the proceedings of the Confederate Congress. Discusses a heated
                    debate over a bill that would recruit free blacks to work as cooks and teamsters
                    in the military.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Legislature</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Summarizes recent activity of the Virginia Legislature, including the
                    consideration of bills for the relief of soldiers' families.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Vox Populi</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dice</ln>
                        <fn>Washington</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Urges Washington Dice, Esq. to declare his candidacy for sheriff.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>W. P. Cooper, Major Commanding Regt.</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Thanks the women of the Soldiers' Aid Society of Zion Church, Waynesboro,
                    for donating forty-four pairs of socks, ten pairs of drawers, two pairs of yarn
                    gloves, one shirt and two barrels of provisions to the soldiers of the 31st
                    Virginia Regiment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>General Orders, No. 7</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>R. E. Lee, Gen'l</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that a temporary reduction in soldiers' rations is necessary.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>How to Cure Desertion</head>
                <origin>Mobile Register</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lists suggestions for minimizing desertions, including a plan that would
                    declare all marriages to deserters illegal.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Buying Cotton in Texas</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes a Texas plan that would allow the government to purchase half of the
                    cotton produced in that state and to export it through the blockade or into
                    Mexico.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 1-3; poetry, column 4</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1864.02.02.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Strange Sentiments</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In our last issue, we noticed the fact that the Richmond "ENQUIRER" not only
                        advocated the policy of suspending the writ of <emph rend="italic">Habeas
                            Corpus</emph> but denounced it as the "criminal's writ." It seems from
                        an article published a few days after, that the "Enquirer" is not only in
                        favor of suspending the writ of <emph rend="italic">Habeas Corpus</emph>,
                        but also of "tearing up the Constitution as waste paper." The following are
                        extracts from an editorial article in the "Enquirer" of January the 25th: </p>
                    <p>"In common with the people, we would sacrifice every right of person and of
                        property, submit to the unrestricted use of any and every power, that can
                        contribute to the overthrow of the enemy. The success of the cause is
                        embarrassed by the trammels of a Constitution designed and constructed for
                        the development of a people in times of peace, but which fetters the public
                        arm in the present conflict of life and death. Nations, like athletes, must
                        strip for the fight. The earnestness of the enemy, as well as their
                        resolution, is exemplified in the manner in which they broke the fetters of
                        their Constitution, and rushed to the conflict with limbs free from clogs of
                        every kind. But in this conflict with a giant, the Confederacy often finds
                        its hands tied by its own Constitution.</p>
                    <p>This tender regard for the constitution is very much like Mr. Pickwick in the
                        Fleet--"on principle." But it won't drive back the enemy, and won't feed the
                        army; it aids bad men in harboring desserters [sic], and protect traitors
                        who won't plant, because the Confederate Government don't pay as much as the
                        speculator. Speaking only for ourselves but firmly believing we represent
                        the people, we boldly avow that we would tear up the Constitution as waste
                        paper, rather than suffer it to impede the public defence, or embarrass the
                        Government in the conflict for Independence.</p>
                    <p>In noticing the strange and startling sentiments expressed by the "Enquirer,"
                        the Petersburg "Express" inquires, "who would have thought three years, or
                        two years, or one year ago, that any respectable Southern journal would come
                        out and boldly propose to set aside the Constitution <emph rend="italic"
                            >which the President and every officer of the government has solemnly
                            sworn to support</emph> because "the success of the cause is embarrassed
                        by its trammels?" Who would have dreamed that such a journal would have held
                        up as worthy of imitation by our government the example of the Yankee
                        Administration in breaking the fetters of their cons[t]itution that they
                        might rush to the conflict with limbs free from clogs of every kind?" That
                        it would ridicule "a tender regard for the constitution" as Pickwickian
                        foolishness! And that, finally, speaking for itself, with the belief that in
                        so speaking it was representing the <emph rend="italic">people</emph>, it
                        would "tear up the Constitution as waste paper rather than impede the public
                        defence, or embarrass the government in the conflict for independence!" </p>
                    <p>The Constitution, it seems, was intended only to dispense its benefits in
                        times of peace! This, to say the least of it, is a strange idea. There is
                        nothing in the instrument itself that by the remotest &amp; most
                        arbitrary construction can be interpreted into such an intention, and
                        certainly there is everything in the circumstances under which it was framed
                        and adopted to indicate that it was designed to operate as well in times of
                        war as in times of peace, for the country was on the very brink of war when
                        it was framed and accepted as was well known at the time to its framers.
                        When the Permanent Government was organized, of which the Constitution is
                        the life and soul, the country was in the very midst of a war, which had
                        already been waged on a gigantic scale for more than six months, and yet
                        nothing was then said or thought about its being designed only for <emph
                            rend="italic">peaceful</emph> developments. The truth is, the
                        Constitution and the Government (not the <emph rend="italic"
                        >Administration</emph> of the Government) are synonymous things, if not
                        terms, because the last is organized upon the platform of the first and
                        derives from it all its vitality. There is not a power that it possesses
                        that is not granted by the Constitution. The whole orbit in which it moves,
                        and the movements themselves, are ordained and regulated by the
                        Constitution, and the moment this connection between them ceases, the
                        government, such as it now is, dies. </p>
                    <p>We do not--we cannot think that the people of the Confederate States are
                        prepared as yet to give themselves up to the embraces of absolutism. They
                        can conquer the enemy without the shadow of a necessity for resorting to
                        this prodigious sacrifice. They can triumphantly bear themselves through the
                        struggle, and preserve at the same time the Constitution, which is the
                        charter of their rights."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Criticizes the Richmond Enquirer for supporting the suspension of the writ
                    of Habeas Corpus.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Tithe Tax</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reminds farmers that everyone is required to deliver the tithe of their
                    products once they are notified to do so.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Army Bill</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"How the next harvest is to be saved, how the coming corn crop is to be
                    planted, how the next wheat crop is to be sowed, and how the people are to live
                    next year are questions which seem not to have troubled the minds of our
                    Senators. They act as wisely as the desperate gambler who ventures all he has
                    upon a single card. If the war could be brought to a termination within a few
                    months, this bill would be wise, but if the war be continued for several years
                    longer it will result in our exhaustion from the want of Supplies."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Expresses opposition to a bill passed by the Confederate Senate that would
                    tighten up military exemption rules.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Encouraging</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Only let us be true to ourselves, and inspire the army in our front with
                    the moral effect of a harmonious and determined people, and the starry cross of
                    the Confederacy will emerge from the clouds and darkness which now surrounds it
                    in a blaze of glory."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges readers to be optimistic for Confederate success this spring.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Animus of the Enemy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>States that a Yankee resolution to guarantee protection from interference
                    to states that submit to the federal government is unacceptable.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>President Davis</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Provides an excerpt of a patriotic speech given by President Davis in
                    Vicksburg, Mississippi.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Substitute Farmers Exempt</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that the Confederate House of Representatives voted to exempt those
                    men who have substitutes and are engaged in the production of grain.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Northern Democracy</head>
                <origin>Richmond Dispatch</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Warns readers that the Northern Democrats' attempts at conciliation are
                    insincere.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Small Pox</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that small pox is abating in Danville.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>C. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces that Dr. C. R. Harris will address Augusta County residents next
                    Saturday on "the currency and state of the country."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Fight With Swamp Dragons--The Swamps Whipped</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the Swamp Dragons were forced to retreat after confronting
                    Confederate troops in Pendleton County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Duty of the People</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Suggests that anyone not serving in the army should do all he or she can to
                    feed, clothe, and encourage the Confederate soldiers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Cites a letter from a man living near Winchester which reports that several
                    Yankee regiments gave up a planned raid up the Valley when their terms of
                    service expired.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Reward of Virtue</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Pays tribute to the average soldier who selflessly has given up his home,
                    endured bad weather, and faced carnage without complaint or expectation of
                    promotion.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Duty of Each</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Every man has his work to perform in carrying on the war. The farmer, the
                        manufacturer, the mechanic, the editor, and numbers of others, if they
                        faithfully discharge their duty, can render a far more valuable service to
                        the army and country at home than they can with muskets on their shoulders
                        in the field. In fact, it were impossible to conduct the war at all if a
                        sufficient number of these, especially farmers, are not left at home to
                        provide for the wants of the army. Bread and meat are to be made, clothing
                        and other supplies of the army are to be manufactured, intelligence to be
                        disseminated, the spirit of the people to be kept up and made equal to the
                        necessities of the time, and their liberties guarded against
                        encroachment--all this can be done only by those who remain at home, and
                        they constitute as indispensable a class in time of war as the soldiers
                        themselves.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that there are some men who would be more productive for the
                    Confederacy at home on their farms than on the battlefield.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blakemore</ln>
                        <fn>John L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Messersmith</ln>
                        <fn>Delila</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On December 31, 1863, Rev. John L. Blakemore married John B. Harman and
                    Delila Messersmith.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blakemore</ln>
                        <fn>John L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yeakle</ln>
                        <fn>John C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blakemore</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On January 24, Rev. John Blakemore married John C. Yeakle and Elizabeth
                    Blakemore.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Arnold</ln>
                        <fn>D. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bolen</ln>
                        <fn>James E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>Mary A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On January 25, Rev. D. W. Arnold married James E. Bolen and Mary A. Wilson
                    at the residence of the bride's father in Spring Hill.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dice</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>James S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Webb</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. Mr. Dice married James S. Kennedy and Elizabeth V. Webb on January 26.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rennolds</ln>
                        <fn>T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. T. Rennolds died on January 28 after an attack of nervous rheumatism
                    resulted in pneumonia. He was 69 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Amicus</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Risk</ln>
                        <fn>James P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>In the Hospital in Staunton, James P. Risk died of wounds received at
                    Bristoe Station on October 28. He was a member of the 2nd Rockbridge battalion.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>H.</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paxton</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On November 11, 1863, John Paxton died of pneumonia. He was a member of the
                    2nd Rockbridge Battery, McIntosh's Battalion of Artillery.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McIntosh</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On January 13, Margaret E. McIntosh died at age 51 at her residence in
                    Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Recruits Wanted</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pilson</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf>Sergeant</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Calls on men who have the privilege of selecting their company to join the
                    Augusta Lee Rifles of the 25th Virginia Regiment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Army Bill</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Provides transcript of a bill recently passed by the Confederate Senate
                    that makes it much more difficult for men to obtain an exemption from service.
                    The bill includes a provision that repeals the exemption of men who employ
                    substitutes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>In Augusta County Court</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Wm. A. Burnett, D. C.</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burnett</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf>D. C.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Francisco</ln>
                        <fn>C. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trimble</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Larew</ln>
                        <fn>Jno. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rush</ln>
                        <fn>William T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bruce</ln>
                        <fn>G. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>David S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Finley</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craig</ln>
                        <fn>J. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gamble</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Cyrus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fulton</ln>
                        <fn>J. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hogshead</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn>J. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lightner</ln>
                        <fn>A. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Montgomery</ln>
                        <fn>William W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lists men appointed by the court to purchase supplies for soldiers'
                    families: C. C. Francisco, District 1; John Trimble, District 2; Jno. J. Larew
                    and William T. Rush, Greenville district; G. A. Bruce and David S. Bell,
                    Waynesboro district; Samuel B. Finley and J. D. Craig, New Hope district;
                    William H. Gamble and Cyrus Brown, Mt. Sidney district; J. G. Fulton and Thomas
                    S. Hogshead, Mt. Solon district; William H. Bell and J. J. Martin, Middlebrook
                    district; A. B. Lightner and William W. Montgomery, Churchville district.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Home Guards</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>J. Wayt Bell, Captain</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>J. Wayt</fn>
                        <sf>Captain</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces that members of the Staunton Home Guard who are newly liable for
                    conscription should return their arms and accouterments to Lt. James W.
                    Crawford.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Reports of skirmishing in Mississippi and Georgia, column 3; in Tennessee,
                column 4; classified ads, column 7</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
