<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1864/va.au.ss.1864.01.05">
 <header>
  <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
  <tagger>
   <taggerName>Amy Murrell</taggerName>
   <tagDate>9/15/97</tagDate>
   <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 9/30/97</tagNote>
  </tagger>
  <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
  <date n="1864-01-05">
   <year>1864</year>
   <month norm="01">January</month>
   <day>5</day>
   <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
  </date>
  <frequency>weekly</frequency>
  <extent>02</extent>
  <editionNote/>
 </header>
 <paperBody>
  <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1864.01.05.01">
   <div type="a">
    <column>5</column>
    <head>Congressional</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>Summarizes recent business of the Confederate Congress. Includes a report on the
     proceedings surrounding a bill that would eliminate the use of substitutes in the military.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>7</column>
    <head>The Yankee Congress</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary>"From the proceedings of the Yankee Congress it is evident that there is no hope of
     peace, and that we should prepare for a protracted struggle. We should not expend all of our
     strength in one spasmodic effort, but husband our resources for a prolonged contest."</commentary>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>Prints remarks of Mr. Smith, a member of the U.S. Congress from Kentucky, who declared
     that the only hope for the country was to continue fighting a vigorous war against the
     Confederacy.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>7</column>
    <head>Exchange of Prisoners</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt>"You are doubtless aware that by Proclamation of the President of the Confederate
     States, Major General B. F. Butler is under the ban of outlawry. Although we do not pretend to
     prescribe what agents your Government shall employ in connection with the cartel, yet when one
     who has been proclaimed to be so obnoxious as General Butler is selected, self respect requires
     that the Confederate authorities refuse to treat with him or establish such relations with him
     as properly pertain to an agent of Exchange."</excerpt>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>Publishes a letter from Confederate to Union authorities that objects to the selection
     of General B. F. Butler (or "Beast Butler") as special agent for the exchange of prisoners.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>7</column>
    <head>Interesting Statistics</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>Provides summary of a recent report of Confederate tax assessments that valued real
     estate at $1,393,719,759.64 and slaves at $1,480,399,656.17.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>7</column>
    <head>Affairs in Vicksburg</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>Notes that a "lady" from Vicksburg has reported that blacks there are treated equally
     with whites and even better than Southern sympathizers.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 1-4; poetry, column 5</pageNote>
  </page>
  <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1864.01.05.02">
   <pageNote>Page two is missing.</pageNote>
  </page>
 </paperBody>
</hwp>
