<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1864/va.au.ss.1864.05.03">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Amy Murrell</taggerName>
            <tagDate>9/7/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 9/30/97</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1864-05-03">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day>3</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1864.05.03.01">
            <div type="c">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>To Producers of 11th Congressional District of VA</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>O. Smith, Capt. and P. Q. M., 11th Cong'l Dist. Va.</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Quarter Master's office in Staunton calls on farmers to deliver their
                    unpaid tithes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Sentenced for Seduction--Remarks of the Judge</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Tells about a case in Atlanta where a man was convicted of seduction. The
                    article includes the Judge's comments on the evil nature of the crime.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The New York Daily News on Mr. Long</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prints favorable commentary on the character of a pro-Southern Ohio
                    Congressman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Extracts from Mr. Long's Speech</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"If it had been understood in the North, as in the South, that by the terms
                    of the Federal compact a State had a right to secede from the Union, this
                    disruption would never have occurred."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Provides excerpts of a pro-Southern speech given by Congressman Long of
                    Ohio.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Classified ads, previously published court reports and conscription notice,
                columns 1-5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1864.05.03.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Preparing for Action</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Discusses the preparations underway for the impending confrontation between
                    Generals Lee and Grant.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Meeting To-Night</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We believe that Augusta county will do as much as any county in the State
                    to furnish artificial arms and legs to the brave soldiers who have been maimed
                    in the military service of the country."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We noticed last week that a meeting would be held in the Court House tonight
                        for the purpose of organizing an Association in aid of the one established
                        in Richmond for the benefit of maimed soldiers. It is hoped that the meeting
                        will be well attended, and that many ladies will grace the occasion with
                        their presence. It is hoped that Associations for the same purpose will be
                        established in every neighborhood in the county. We believe that Augusta
                        county will do as much as any county in the State to furnish artificial arms
                        and legs to the brave soldiers who have been maimed in the military service
                        of the country. We understand that Rev. J. L. STIREWALT has collected as
                        much as $16,000 in the counties of Rockingham, Shenandoah and Page. These
                        counties have done well, but we cherish the belief that, if Associations be
                        formed in every neighborhood as we think should be done, this county will
                        contribute more than all three of these counties. We hope that the proper
                        kind of an Association will be organized in Staunton that it may be a model
                        for those in the different villages and neighborhoods of the county. Form
                        the Associations without delay, and appoint good committees to wait upon the
                        people. The most efficient committees for such purposes are those composed
                        of ladies. There are now in the Confederacy 10,000 maimed soldiers, and may
                        be nearly as many more before this "cruel war" will be over. What a sublime
                        spectacle it would present to see all these maimed soldiers supplied with
                        limbs by generous, voluntary contributions. The page of our history which
                        would contain the record of this fact would be among the brightest in the
                        whole volume--it would be one which even angels could read with pleasure.
                        This page will be written, and the name of this noble county will be found
                        upon it. Augusta will not be excelled by other counties in deeds of
                        generosity, liberality and humanity to the noble soldiers who have
                        sacrificed their limbs in the service of their country.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges readers to attend tonight's meeting of an association to aid maimed
                    soldiers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Presentation of a Flag</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>See</ln>
                        <fn>C. S. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>See</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes that Mrs. C. S. M. See will be presenting the 31st Virginia Infantry
                    with a flag.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Striped Pig</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Tells anyone wishing to drink alcohol to try chasing down the elusive
                    striped pig.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Grinding Seed Corn</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prints President Davis' comment that sending boys between 17 and 18 to
                    service is like sending corn to the mill to be ground.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Exempting Farmers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Supports the call of other newspapers for the exemption of farmers from the
                    service.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Details</head>
                <origin>Lexington Gazette</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Talks about the suffering that will result if farmers are not granted
                    details.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Lt. E. C. Randolph</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Randolph</ln>
                        <fn>E. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that Lt. E. C. Randolph has returned to the field despite disabling
                    wounds.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>From the Blackwater</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The correspondent of the Petersburg <emph rend="italic">Express</emph> on the
                        Blackwater, gives a detailed account of the infamous conduct of the Yankees
                        and negroes during the late raid into the counties of Isle of Wight and
                        Nansemond. The negroes were turned loose on the women and children in
                        Suffolk, and robbed every house in the town. Watches, jewelry, &amp;c.,
                        were stolen from the persons of ladies, and every indignity and insult
                        offered them. Two of the most respectable ladies in the town, ladies of high
                        school position and refined feelings, being found with no male defenders
                        near, were grossly insulted with propositions and attempted violence too
                        indelicate to appear in print. These ladies were forced to defend themselves
                        with knives against great, black, greasy, buck negroes, whilst their friends
                        were away in the army. This fiendish proceeding has produced a sensation in
                        Suffolk which has been equalled by nothing that has transpired since the war
                        commenced. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Provides an account of a raid of black soldiers in Isle of Wight and
                    Nansemond counties. The article claims that the soldiers were turned loose and
                    attacked women.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Removal of Ladies</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that women working in Richmond as signers of Confederate notes have
                    been sent to Columbia, South Carolina.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Liberal and Patriotic Offer</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Praises offer of a Kentucky Congressman to provide money and education to
                    soldiers disabled by the war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Socks for Soldiers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that the Soldiers' Aid Society of Albemarle County has produced 900
                    pairs of socks since December.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Justices of the Peace</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that the Secretary of War has no plans to exempt any justice of the
                    peace under age 45.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Length and Weight of the Yankee Debt</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Yankee debt is over 94,000 miles long.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Way the Yankee Army is Recruited</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Yankee recruits have in some cases been kidnapped and forced
                    into service.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Congress and the Cultivation of the Soil</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Suggests that it would be wise to let boys between 17 and 18 and men
                    between 45 and 50 stay home to farm.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Scarcity of Supplies</head>
                <origin>Richmond Examiner</origin>
                <commentary>"We should be pleased to know where these 'many farmers in Western
                    Virginia who could spare largely from their hoarded stores' live. They do not
                    live in this part of 'Western Virginia.'"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The South is really menaced by one serious danger only; and that is the
                        failure of adequate subsistence. While superfluous abundance exists in many
                        considerable districts of the Confederacy, it cannot be denied that in those
                        in which there is much the heaviest consumption of food, including Virginia,
                        a most serious scarcity prevails. This scarcity is not only felt in the
                        cities, towns and villages, but throughout the interiour [sic] country.
                        There are many farmers in Western Virginia who could spare largely from
                        their hoarded stores for the general want; but it is a fact notorious, which
                        it were idle to deny, that a considerable proportion of the producing
                        population of Virginia are stinted for the necessaries of life.</p>
                    <p>[We should be pleased to know where these "many farmers in Western Virginia
                        who could spare largely from their hoarded stores" live. They do not live in
                        this part of "Western Virginia."--Ed. SPECTATOR.]</p>
                    <p>As long as two months ago the county of Charlotte, in a region unoccupied by
                        any army, took measures to obtain a supply of grain for the consumption of
                        its inhabitants from the far South; and if this be the case on the South
                        side, imagine what it must be in regions suffering from the presence of
                        armies; where, first, producers voluntarily sold to Government what they
                        could spare; where, second, a molety [sic] of what was left has been
                        impressed by foraging parties sent out from the armies; and where, third,
                        much of the residue has disappeared under the pilfering and robberies of
                        straggling soldiers, over whom no discipline seems to be exerted.</p>
                    <p>[Rich. Examiner.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Examiner suggests that farmers in Western Virginia could spare more of
                    their crops for the benefit of the army.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Impressive Ceremony at Dalton</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on a ceremony at an Episcopal Church in Dalton, Georgia, where both
                    President Davis and General Lee were present.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Present Congress</head>
                <origin>Richmond Enquirer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Expresses admiration for the patriotic leadership of William C. Rives,
                    member of the Confederate Congress.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>More Yankees Captured</head>
                <origin>Rockingham Register</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that seventeenYankees were captured during an attempt on
                    Winchester, Virginia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>New York Metropolitan Record</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Suggests that the South cannot be conquered and praises Virginia for
                    standing up for liberty.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Charlottesville Chronicle</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that the Virginia legislature is asking banks for loans to help feed
                    the hungry.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fauber</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bear</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. C. Beard married John H. Fauber and Elizabeth T. Bear on April 7.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bosserman</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hemp</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. J. H. Crawford married David Bosserman and Sarah Hemp on April 17.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seig</ln>
                        <fn>Henry B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>Mattie A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On April 26, Rev. J. B. Davis married Henry B. Seig to Mattie A. Davis of
                    Rockingham.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dice</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trayer</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf>C. S. A.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Powers</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On May 2, Rev. Mr. Dice married John W. Trayer and Margaret R. Powers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Obituary</head>
                <origin>Hannibal Mercury</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trimble</ln>
                        <fn>George B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trimble</ln>
                        <fn>Jno.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George B. Trimble, son of Jno. Trimble, died in Santa Fe last Friday
                    evening after being injured by a horse.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Announcements</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doyle</ln>
                        <fn>Robert L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces candidacy of Robert L. Doyle for commonwealth's attorney.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Announcements</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Many Voters</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>Absalom</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chapman</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bruce</ln>
                        <fn>George A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ellis</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bush</ln>
                        <fn>William M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Authors state intention to vote for Absalom Koiner, William Chapman, George
                    A. Bruce, and J. S. Ellis for justices of the peace. Also announce plans to vote
                    for William Bush for constable, and William Chapman for overseer of the poor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Announcements</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>John D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Francisco</ln>
                        <fn>C. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>J. Wayt</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sterrett</ln>
                        <fn>William G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces that John D. Brown, C. C. Francisco, J. Wayt Bell, and William G.
                    Sterrett will be voted for for magistrate in the 1st magisterial district.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Announcements</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Jacob S. Long</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Long</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces his candidacy for justice of the peace for the Churchville
                    district.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Announcements</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Thornton Berry</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Berry</ln>
                        <fn>Thornton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces candidacy of Thornton Berry for justice of the peace in the 1st
                    district.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Announcements</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donoho</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces candidacy of Thomas M. Donoho for commissioner of revenue in the
                    1st district.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Announcements</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stover</ln>
                        <fn>John G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces candidacy of John G. Stover for commissioner of revenue in the
                    second district.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Removal of the Remains of Henry Clay</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the remains of Henry Clay have been moved to a cemetery in
                    Lexington, Kentucky, to be near his wife's grave.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>An Example</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges readers to follow the example of General Lee, who reportedly has cut
                    back to eating meat only twice a week.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="j">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>In Augusta County Court</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>April 25th, 1864.</p>
                    <p>On motion it is ordered, that the order of this Court entered on the 22d day
                        of Feb., 1864, be, and the same is hereby so modified as to empower the
                        county agents authorized to procure and distribute supplies to the families
                        of soldiers to <emph rend="italic">disregard</emph> the limit of prices
                        prescribed by said order, and to purchase such supplies as may be absolutely
                        necessary for the support of the needy families of Soldiers at the best
                        prices at which they can be bought, and that in making distribution and sale
                        of such supplies to the Soldier's families the said agents, at their
                        discretion, in cases of absolute necessity, may furnish the supplies
                        required to protect such families from actual want, even to an amount
                        greater than can be paid for out of the funds allowed to such families, and
                        that such agents shall keep accurate accounts of the excess and report the
                        same for levy at the next June term; and that the said order is further
                        modified so as to authorize the said County agents to make the purchases and
                        impressments authorized by said order, not only within their respective
                        Magisterial Districts but anywhere within the county. </p>
                    <p>And it is further ordered that hereafter the families of persons who entered
                        the Military service as substitutes for others, and who are now and may
                        continue in active service, shall be provided for as other Soldiers'
                        families, such substitutes being now liable to service themselves under the
                        act of Congress.</p>
                    <p>A Copy-Teste [sic], <lb/>May 3-3t WM. A. BURNETT, D.C. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>William A. Burnett, D. C.</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on a recent order of the court which empowers county agents to
                    distribute supplies to soldiers' families, regardless of the prices.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Reports of a battle in Louisiana, column 3; previously published court
                reports, columns 6-7</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
