<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1864/va.au.ss.1864.03.15">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Amy Murrell</taggerName>
            <tagDate>8/28/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 9/5/97</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1864-03-15">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day>15</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1864.03.15.01">
            <div type="c">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>To the Farmers of Augusta County</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The undersigned, a Committee appointed to disburse the funds of the
                        Corporation for the relief of the families of Volunteers now in the field
                        are prepared to purchase wheat, flour, corn, rye, and wood. They sell to the
                        above families at about one half prices, and they earnestly request those
                        farmers who have the above articles for sale to give them a call before
                        disposing of them else where.</p>
                    <p>J. W. CRAWFORD. <lb/>W. B. HAYSER. <lb/>J. C. WHEAT. </p>
                    <p>November 3--tf.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>J. W. Crawford, W. B. Kayser, J. C. Wheat</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kayser</ln>
                        <fn>W. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wheat</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces intention to purchase wheat, flour, corn, rye, and wood on behalf
                    of the corporation for the relief of the families of volunteers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Supplies for the Soldiers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>H. M. Bell, Major &amp; Q.M.</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>H. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Major &amp; Q.M.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces that a car will leave Staunton every Friday morning to send
                    supplies to soldiers from friends in Augusta County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>$100 Reward</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Geo. Harnsberger, Ex'or</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harnsberger</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf>Ex'or</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harnsberger</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn>Kit</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that Kit, a slave woman belonging to the Waynesboro estate of Jacob
                    Harnsberger, ran away on February 28.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Legislature</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on recent proceedings of the Confederate Congress, including
                    consideration of bills that would provide relief to indigent soldiers and their
                    children.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>For the Spectator: A Card</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>R. Turk</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turk</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Turk declines the offer to become a candidate for sheriff.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Applications for Exemption or Detail</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Outlines process involved in obtaining an exemption or detail from service.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Mr. Sheffey's Address</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"I hear already the stirring notes of the song of victory, thin at first,
                    but swelling on the ear, coming up from every outpost of the army, from every
                    skirmish and battlefield of the opening campaign."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prints copy of speech delivered by Hugh W. Sheffey, Speaker of the House of
                    Delegates, that expresses optimism about the future of the Confederacy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Watery Potatoes</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Offers suggestions for drying out watery potatoes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Poetry, column 1; reports of skirmishes in Mississippi, Alabama, and Georgia,
                column 6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1864.03.15.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Change</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Asks patrons of local businesses to bring small bills when making
                    purchases.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Home Soldiers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The 'Home Soldier' wields the peaceful implements--the plough, the shovel,
                    the hoe--whilst the soldier in the battle's front uses the gun, the sabre, the
                    bayonet--the former laboring to save, whilst the latter strives to destroy life;
                    yet both are using means for the accomplishment of the same end--Liberty and
                    Independence."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In several issues of the "Rockingham Register," the Editors stated that they
                        had been informed that there were some of the members of these churches, the
                        members of which are exempt in consequences of religious faith and the
                        payment of five hundred dollars, who did not intend to raise any more
                        produce than would be necessary for their own families. We were astonished
                        at the statement, and thought that there must be some mistake about it, and
                        are pleased to learn from the last issue of the "Register" that our
                        confidence in the loyalty of that class of citizens was not misplaced. Those
                        who will do all they can to raise supplies will perform as efficient service
                        as if they were in the field, for it is necessary to plant corn as to plant
                        batteries, and as necessary to reap wheat as to reap victories. The enemy is
                        now making war upon our means of sustenance, and every one is efficiently
                        defending his country who is engaged in increasing the supplies of
                        subsistence. The "Home Soldier" wields the peaceful implements--the plough,
                        the shovel, the hoe--whilst the soldier in the battle's front uses the gun,
                        the sabre, the bayonet--the former laboring to save, whilst the latter
                        strives to destroy life; yet both are using means for the accomplishment of
                        the same end--Liberty and Independence. The soldiers in arms will do their
                        duty and we hope those at home will do theirs also. We are pleased to hear
                        that more ground than usual has been already ploughed, and that the prospect
                        for planting a large crop of corn is very flattering.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Expresses astonishment at reports that men exempted from service for
                    religious reasons are not assisting the army in other ways, such as the
                    production of food.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Negro Genius</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Some time since, a colored boy, "Bob," 15 years of age, the property of Mrs.
                        Margaret A. Crawford, went to the depot where the Engine, "H. D. Whitcomb,"
                        was standing. A gentleman observing that he seemed interested in the engine,
                        asked him what he thought of it. He replied, "pretty big work, Master, but I
                        think I can make one like it." The gentleman addressed laughed at what he
                        conceived to be the absurdity of the negro boy's presumption. The boy went
                        home with his mind full of the project of vindicating the truth of his
                        assertion, and, sure enough, with no tools but an axe, hammer, saw, knife
                        and gimblet, he made in wood an exact counterpart of the Engine, complete in
                        all its parts. This model can be seen at the Law office of Mr. Wm. B. Kayser
                        of this place, where it has excited the admiration and wonder of all
                        beholders. They all agree that "Bob" must be a boy of remarkable mechanical
                        genius. Such genius should be cultivated, and "Bob" ought to be placed in
                        some good machine shop where his genius can be made serviceable to the
                        country. "Bob" would be as happy in a machine shop, as a "common nigger"
                        would be at a dance or "shucking."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn>Bob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kayser</ln>
                        <fn>William B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports on the creation of a wooden steam engine by Bob, a slave of Mrs.
                    Margaret A. Crawford. The author says that this indicates "genius" on Bob's part
                    and he argues that Bob should be given work in a machine shop.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Enrolling Officer Colonel Peyton</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Colonel</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes that Colonel Peyton has been transferred from Lynchburg to Staunton
                    to act as enrolling officer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Dwelling Burnt</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that the Middlebrook home of Joseph A. Miller was destroyed by an
                    accidental fire on March 7. Only two feather beds remain, and the loss is
                    estimated at $10,000.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Mill Burnt</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCormick</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Suggests that the recent fire that destroyed the mill of Thomas McCormick
                    on March 5 was set by a traitor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Lt. Gov. Samuel Price</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Those who cannot fight must cultivate the ground; those who cannot handle
                    the musket and sabre, must handle the plow and the hoe. They must raise corn,
                    beans and potatoes for the army."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prints portion of a speech given by Lieutenant Governor Samuel Price that
                    urged those at home to contribute to the war effort.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Loss and Gain</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on the loss and gain of horses, livestock, and slaves in seven
                    Virginia counties between 1860 and 1863. According to state figures, Augusta
                    County had 4,708 slaves in 1860 and 4,515 in 1863. Staunton had 909 slaves in
                    1860 and 749 in 1863.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Lauadble [sic] Conduct</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Praises a Shenandoah County man for turning down speculators and instead
                    selling his wool to his poor neighbors. Urges Augusta County residents to show a
                    similar spirit of benevolence.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>A Detective Detected</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on the arrest of a Confederate detective on charges of treason.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Decision of the Court of Appeals</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Summarizes recent court decisions that declared constitutional the law of
                    conscription and the law against the exemption of men who employ substitutes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>A Brilliant Affair</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fitzhugh</ln>
                        <fn>Thadeus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports on the recent success of the 5th Virginia Cavalry in surprising a
                    Yankee picket in Northampton County and destroying its supplies.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Speed the Plough</head>
                <origin>Richmond Whig</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"How would it be here in Virginia if the noble army of Lee had to be
                    removed or disbanded for lack of supplies. The armed mercenaries of Lincoln
                    would immediately swarm through the State, like the destroying locusts of
                    Egypt."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that in producing food and supplies for soldiers, farmers and
                    planters have an important responsibility in ensuring the success of the
                    Confederacy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>J. Marshall McCue, Esq.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>J. Marshall</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes that J. Marshall McCue, state delegate from Augusta County, was among
                    those who successfully repelled General Dahlgreen's column.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>States that General Ross killed fifty-five black soldiers while in pursuit
                    of General Sherman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Look to your Gardens!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Let the music of the hoe and spade now be heard resounding from every
                    garden in the South, and we may bid defiance to 'General' Starvation, as well as
                    to the Yankees."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges readers not to delay in planting their gardens with vegetables.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"There are thousands who, stimulated by the cry of scarcity, have put away
                    as 'supplies for the year,' unaccustomed amounts. These things are very wrong.
                    The army is suffering while gluttons are surfeiting and negroes wasting, and
                    while timid providers are watching their swollen hoards."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Let our people plant early and largely of vegetables. Let every one who has a
                        perch of ground tax it to its utmost. Let us economise in consumption; and
                        especially, let us deny ourselves meat that the army may eat. There are many
                        who are indulging their families, white and black, with unabated profusion.
                        There are thousands who, stimulated by the cry of scarcity, have put away as
                        "supplies for the year," unaccustomed amounts. These things are very wrong.
                        The army is suffering while gluttons are surfeiting and negroes wasting, and
                        while timid providers are watching their swollen hoards. We must economise
                        that we may have to spare; and out of what we have, whether much or little,
                        the army must be supplied.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Chastises those who are not giving their excess harvests to the army.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>To the People of Augusta</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Jos. N. Ryan</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ryan</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Joseph Ryan announces his candidacy for clerk of the superior court of law
                    and chancery.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>To the Voters of Augusta</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>A. F. Kinney</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>A. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A.F. Kinney announces his candidacy for the office of clerk of the circuit
                    court.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>J. C. Matheny</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Matheny</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J.C. Matheny announces his candidacy for clerk of the circuit court.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Religious Notice</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces that Reverend J. H. Davis will preach in the Lutheran church in
                    Staunton next Sunday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richardson</ln>
                        <fn>William T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dold</ln>
                        <fn>James A.</fn>
                        <sf>C.S.A.</sf>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brooke</ln>
                        <fn>Mattie E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brooke</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf>dec'd</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lieut. James A. Dold married Mattie E. Brooke, daughter of John Brooke, on
                    February 23 at the bride's residence.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bryan</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shirey</ln>
                        <fn>J. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coiner</ln>
                        <fn>David W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Colonel</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>Fannie D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Colonel David W. Coiner married Fannie D. Young on March 10 at the home of
                    Mrs. Bryan, near Arbor Hill.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>A Friend</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reach</ln>
                        <fn>James Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James Henry Reach, a 27-year-old private in Company D 2d Regiment Virginia
                    Infantry, died on February 19 after a six-week illness. Author notes that this
                    is his family's second death since the war began.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Layman</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Rebecca Layman died at home on February 3, at the age of 62. The
                    obituary notes that she had been a strong supporter of the Confederacy and even
                    opened her home to Southern soldiers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>$50 Reward</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>D. &amp; H. Forrer</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>E. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn>Hartwell</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Timberlake</ln>
                        <fn>J. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Offers reward for return of Hartwell, a slave hired out to J. R. Timberlake
                    to work in wood chopping.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>$25 Reward</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>D. &amp; H. Forrer</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Timberlake</ln>
                        <fn>J. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Offers reward for return of Henry, a slave hired out to J. R. Timberlake,
                    who may be with his wife in Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Poetry, classified ads, and reports on military success in Florida and
                Georgia, columns 2-3</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
