<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1864/va.au.ss.1864.01.19">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Amy Murrell</taggerName>
            <tagDate>9/20/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 9/30/97</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1864-01-19">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day>19</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1864.01.19.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Escape of Capt. T. Henry Hines, An Interesting Account</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Provides narration of the adventures of Captain T. Henry Hines of the 9th
                    Kentucky Cavalry, who escaped from the Ohio penitentiary with Major General John
                    H. Morgan, was captured, and then escaped again.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Gen. Morgan at the Capitol</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes Major General John H. Morgan's visit to the Virginia legislature.
                    Notes that the Speaker of the House praised the Kentuckyian for his heroism on
                    behalf of the Confederacy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Remember the Soldiers</head>
                <origin>Augusta Chronicle</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"In the security of our homes we should remember the soldiers, for they and
                    they alone secure to us all the immunities that we enjoy. Mothers, wives,
                    sisters, remember your protectors, and send them whatever you can spare that
                    will add to their comfort."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges readers to send blankets, coats, and shoes to the soldiers for the
                    winter.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Whiskey</head>
                <origin>Examiner</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Expresses surprise that the Confederacy produces nearly two million gallons
                    of whiskey each year. Suggests that if the government really needs this much
                    whiskey, then it should be produced in areas with abundant grain, not in
                    Virginia and North Carolina.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>The Ladies 'Fashions'</head>
                <origin>Lynchburg Republican</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on the style of women's dress that is in vogue this winter in the
                    North. Notes that large hats are entirely out of fashion, having been replaced
                    by smaller, more closely fitting ones.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>The Yankee Debt</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Cites a report from the Yankee Secretary of Treasury that estimates U.S.
                    debt at eleven hundred million dollars.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"If she were to offer less to her enemies, or attempt to do less, she would
                    be unworthy of the spirit and manhood of her people."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Explains that, while the South has to defend against the enemy on its own
                    soil, it will not make any attempts at peace.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Maxims for Husbands</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"If breakfast is not ready for you chuckle and grin pleasantly at the
                    delay, remembering that a merry heart as a continual feast; and go to your daily
                    business with a pleasant smile."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges husbands to relax and remain cheerful.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Leap Year</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"No man will be entitled to the benefit of Clergy who doth refuse to accept
                    the offers of a lady, or who doth in anywise treat her proposal with slight or
                    contumely."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prints excerpt from a 1606 publication entitled, "Courtship, Love and
                    Matrimony."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 1-4</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1864.01.19.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Yankee Congress</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Declares that a recent call by the Yankees for more volunteers will be
                    matched by the South. Says that such action by the North is only intended to
                    prolong the war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Hon. Mr. Miles and His Champagne</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the house of the Confederate Congress Military Committee
                    Chairman was burglarized and nine baskets of champagne were taken. Questions why
                    the chairman found it necessary to purchase the champagne in the first place,
                    when so many soldiers' families are in need.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Correction</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Rockingham <emph rend="italic">Register</emph> says that we did injustice
                        to the Provost Guard of Harrisonburg in stating several weeks since, that
                        "some persons mistaking the Harrisonburg Provost Guard for the Augusta Home
                        Guard erroneously stated that a portion of the Home Guard ingloriously fled
                        on the near approach of the enemy." We are pleased to hear that the
                        Harrisonburg provost Guard did not run, for then we are satisfied that no
                        running was done except by the Yankees. Our statement was made under the
                        following circumstances: Whilst in Rockingham we heard some of the citizens
                        of that county charging that some of the Home Guard ingloriously fled on the
                        near approach of the enemy. A portion of the Home guard and the Provost
                        Guard of Harisonburg [sic] were the only parties present on the occasion
                        spoken of by those citizens. </p>
                    <p>Upon inquiry, we learned, that the Home Guard did <emph rend="italic"
                        >not</emph> run as reported, and as the Provost Guard of Harrisonburg was
                        the only other body of troops present, we supposed that those persons
                        claiming to be eye-witnesses of the scene who made the charge mistook the
                        Home Guard for the Provost Guard. This is the "head and front of our
                        offending." It would now seem that these persons were altogether mistaken,
                        and that in fact there was no running done save by the Yankees. May this
                        always be the case, and may the citizens of Rockingham always be willing to
                        stand by the noble sons of "Old Augusta." </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Clarifies an earlier report and states that neither the Harrisonburg
                    Provost Guard nor the Augusta Home Guard ran away from the enemies.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Soldiers and the P.O. Department</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Asks the Confederate Congress to pay the postage on newspapers sent to
                    soldiers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Substitute Exempts</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Those who have furnished substitutes will be interested in General Order No.
                        3, published in our advertising columns. It will be seen, from this Order,
                        that those who have furnished substitutes are required to report as
                        volunteers or conscripts, without delay, to the enrolling officers; and all
                        who delay beyond the 1st day of February, 1864, will be considered as having
                        renounced the privilege of volunteering, and held for assignment according
                        to law.</p>
                    <p>Previous to enrollment as conscripts, all such persons will be allowed to
                        volunteer in companies in service on the 16th of April, 1862, provided the
                        company chosen does not at the time of volunteering reach the maximum number
                        allowed; and upon such company being selected, the volunteer will receive
                        from the enrolling officers a certificate to the effect that he has so
                        volunteered; and to volunteer will be received into any company except on
                        such certificate. Persons who fail to make their selection at the time of
                        enrollment will be assigned according to existing regulations.</p>
                    <p>Persons who report to the enrolling officers will be enrolled, and may be
                        allowed a furlough of ten days before reporting to the Camp of
                    Instruction.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Calls attention to a recent order requiring all men who employed
                    substitutes to enroll in the service themselves.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Capt. Blackford Killed</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on the death of Capt. Jno. C. Blackford, who was killed in Newtown,
                    Virginia, by three Yankees dressed in Confederate uniforms.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Mosby's Attack</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Tells about the attack by Major Mosby and his men on a Yankee camp near
                    Harper's Ferry. Six prisoners and forty horses were captured by the
                    Confederates.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>American Hotel in Staunton</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nadenbousch</ln>
                        <fn>J. Q. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McChesney</ln>
                        <fn>William M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woodward</ln>
                        <fn>Jos. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes that the American Hotel, under the ownership of Col. J. Q. A.
                    Nadenbousch and Dr. William M. McChesney, is now open for guests. Mr. Jos. N.
                    Woodward is the chief manager.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Duty of Those at Home</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The poor of the country have got to be taken care of some way, and the
                    wealth of the country has got to do it."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges readers to assist the families of soldiers in obtaining food.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Danger</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We are confronted by two foes, neither one less dangerous than the other.
                    The Yankees and want of food menace us on each side, and we must have a vigilant
                    eye to both. Abstract the whole white male population from production, and
                    famine stalks over the land."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Warns the Confederate Congress that some men must stay home to keep
                    producing food.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Wholesale Conscription</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"If the whole population is dragged into the army, where are the supplies
                    for the army, and bread and meat for women and children to come from? We have
                    found it difficult to provision and clothe the army and the people heretofore,
                    and how much more difficult, indeed, how impossible will it be, when the
                    laborers are all withdrawn from their avocations--when the producers are all
                    turned into consumers?"</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Marietta (Geo.) <emph rend="italic">Rebel</emph> says that from the tenor
                        of our articles heretofore, our readers will understand that we are
                        necessarily opposed to the enactment of the law reported by the military
                        committee of the Senate, providing for the levy en masse of our male
                        population. The law provides than [sic] every able-bodied man shall be put
                        in the army, and that there shall be no exemptions, except such as the
                        Secretary of War and the President see proper to make. The passage of this
                        law would constitute the most extraordinary transfer of power, from the
                        legislature to the Executive, ever known under a Republican system of
                        government. It would create a condition of things without a parallel in any
                        species of government, except that of an unmixed despotism. It will place
                        every man in the Confederacy under absolute military authority, and
                        substitute military rule for civil law at once. </p>
                    <p>We cannot for a single moment tolerate the idea of the necessity for any such
                        law. Its effect will certainly be pernicious at home, and unwholesome
                        abroad. It will produce great dissatisfaction among our own people, and fix
                        upon outside nations the conclusion that we are reduced to desperate
                        extremities. Confidence in our ability to work out our independence, will be
                        seriously impaired, if not totally destroyed, when it is seen that we are
                        driven to the adoption of such an unprecedented measure as the absorption of
                        the entire male population into the army. The world will ask, as our own
                        people will also ask, how is the army and the nation to be sustained, how
                        fed and clothed, if the men are all to be withdrawn from the pursuits of
                        agriculture, and the mechanic arts?</p>
                    <p>If we were reduced to such a strait that it was absolutely necessary to make
                        one last desperate stand against the foe, to inflict all the damage we could
                        upon him, and then fall and leave the nation to expire, there would be
                        philosophy and heroism in the resolution, for it is better to "die all
                        freemen, than to live all slaves," but we are not yet driven to any such
                        desperate resort. Our armies still face the foe, and hold him in check. Our
                        gallant boys are full of spirit, and if properly cared for, well fed and
                        clothed, are able to hold the portals of the Republic against all comers.
                        Our present troubles have grown out of bad management with the men in the
                        field, and not for any want of men. Our soldiers have been badly fed, and
                        worse clothed. There has been too much straggling of both officers and men
                        permitted. There are too many soldiers scattered through the country
                        guarding the doors of Provost Marshals' offices, and too much incompetency
                        in the commanders. Make our present army efficient, and there will be
                        nothing to fear.</p>
                    <p>But, if the whole population is dragged into the army, where are the supplies
                        for the army, and bread and meat for women and children to come from? We
                        have found it difficult to provision and clothe the army and the people
                        heretofore, and how much more difficult, indeed, how impossible will it be,
                        when the laborers are all withdrawn from their avocations--when the
                        producers are all turned into consumers?</p>
                    <p>We have endeavored to consider the proposed law, without prejudice or
                        excitement, but have failed to find in it one redeeming feature. It is
                        either the profoundest folly or a most dangerous and wanton assault upon the
                        public liberty, and we cannot believe, that after due deliberation, the
                        Congress will be found so wanting in statesmanship, and so false to the
                        public interests, as to enact it into a law.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Explains opposition to any Confederate law that would conscript most all
                    men.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Confederate States Congress</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Summarizes recent proceedings of the Confederate Congress, including a bill
                    that would require the confiscation of the property belonging to all those who
                    evaded military service by fleeing to the North.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Leve En Masse</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"It is a confession of weakness nor warranted by the circumstances of the
                    case, calculated to create distrust in the minds of our own people of the extent
                    of our resources, and has already given new encouragement to the hopes of our
                    enemies."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We have seldom seen, says the <emph rend="italic">Richmond Dispatch</emph>,
                        more universal concurrence in the press of the country upon any subject than
                        there is in its opposition to the desperate expedient of a levy <emph
                            rend="italic">en masse</emph> of the population of the Confederacy. It
                        is a confession of weakness not warranted by the circumstances of the case,
                        calculated to create distrust in the minds of our own people of the extent
                        of our resources, and has already given new encouragement to the hopes of
                        our enemies. To put boys of sixteen to eighteen in the army is to destroy
                        the "seed corn" of the population, as President Davis aptly characterized
                        it; and to force men over the age of forty-five into the ranks is to furnish
                        food for disease and death, and to crowd the hospitals and graveyards
                        without adding appreciably to the strength of the army. Prussia, when
                        beleaguered by the most colossal military power on the earth, never called
                        men of that age from their homes. At their homes they are good for
                        something. There, they, and the unmature striplings whom a cruel radicalism
                        would devote to the perils of battle, may provide food for an army which is
                        already pressing strongly on the means of subsistence, and under State
                        organization render the only military service of which they are capable, the
                        defence of the soil against raids of the enemy. Bring back the stragglers
                        and the absentees, place negroes in the place of white teamsters, nurses,
                        &amp;c., and we shall have as large an army as the people can feed. What
                        we need is skill and produce in the development and husbanding of our
                        resources, rather than an increase of numbers. Look at the shameful manner
                        in which Confederate property has been squandered and the negligence and
                        blunders by which so many of our men have fallen into the hands of the
                        enemy. These are the evils which must be remedied, and, as long as they
                        continue, no increase of our strength will be of any permanent value. It
                        will be like a new inheritance to a spendthrift, who will run through it
                        just as rapidly as his former possessions. What we want to see in Congress
                        is coolness, combined with energy, and in the army, vigilance and
                        discipline, united with courage. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Voices opposition to the conscription of boys between the ages of 16 and
                    18.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Legislature</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on the latest proceedings of the Virginia legislature. Notes that
                    the Senate passed a bill providing relief to the families of soldiers living in
                    counties within the lines.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Mr. Editor: As gigantic efforts will be made next spring by the enemy to
                        subjugate us, I ask the attention of the proper authorities, if their
                        attention should not be turned [to] deserters, who are skulking about their
                        homes since last summer; and harbored by their friends.</p>
                    <p>A CITIZEN.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>A CITIZEN</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Asks that the proper authorities turn their attention to the deserters that
                    are lurking about.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Fulton W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>Mary A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On January 6, Rev. Smith married Fulton W. Brown and Mary A. White.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McFarland</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Mildred</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf>Sr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. Dr. McFarland married Capt. James Bumgardner, Jr. of the 52nd Virginia
                    Regiment and Mary Mildred Bumgardner, daughter of James Bumgardner, Sr., on
                    January 27.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rikelberger</ln>
                        <fn>Martha A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rikelberger</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rikelberger</ln>
                        <fn>Eli</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rikelberger</ln>
                        <fn>Mary J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>At the age of 5, Martha A. Rikelberger died of diphtheria on December 2,
                    1863. Her brother, John W. Rikelberger, died of the same disease on January 1,
                    at the age of 6. They were the children of Eli and Mary J. Rikelberger.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Larew</ln>
                        <fn>James M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James M. Larew died of a wound received at Gettysburg on July 5, 1863. A
                    former member of the Augusta Lee Rifles, he was a member of Capt. McClung's
                    Company, 1st Virginia Regiment, when he died. He was 20 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 6-7; reports of skirmishing around Wilmington and
                Mobile, columns 3 and 5</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
