<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1864/va.au.ss.1864.01.26">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Amy Murrell</taggerName>
            <tagDate>9/21/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 9/30/97</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1864-01-26">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day>26</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1864.01.26.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Confederate States Congress</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on the proceedings of the Confederate Congress, including
                    consideration of bills to regulate impressment and to curtail desertions.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Legislature</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Provides an update on the proceedings of the Virginia Legislature,
                    including discussion of bills related to deserters and salary increases for
                    certain Confederate officials.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>The Press</head>
                <origin>Columbia South Carolinian</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Outlines the contributions made by Confederate newspapers to the Southern
                    cause thus far. The South Carolinian suggests that conscripting newspaper
                    editors and writers would be destructive.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Diabolical Attempt to Burn the Presidential Mansion</head>
                <origin>Richmond Examiner</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on the attempted burning of President Davis's home in Richmond.
                    Suggests that either Yankee prisoners in that city or the President's own house
                    servants may be to blame.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 1-4</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1864.01.26.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Habeas Corpus--The Criminal's Writ</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"In these times we hear some strange sentiments uttered. Some seem
                    disposed to dispense with the chart furnished by our wise fathers, and to
                    entrust, in the storm of revolution, the ark of our liberty to the waves without
                    any thing to enable them to direct its course to prevent it from being engulphed
                    in the Charybdis of despotism. "The price of liberty is eternal vigilance." and,
                    in times of revolution and trial, the friends of liberty are called upon to
                    exercise increased vigilance. We were surprised to find the following sentence
                    in an editorial article in the "Richmond Enquirer" of the 21st inst.:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                    <p>"Habeas corpus is the criminal's writ; good men have very little use for it,
                        and can dispense with it altogether by obeying the laws, and devoting their
                        whole time and energy to the defence of their country."</p>
                    <p>Was the Constitution of Virginia adopted for the <emph rend="italic">special
                            protection of criminals</emph>?" Did the framers of that instrument
                        consider "<emph rend="italic">Habeas Corpus</emph> as the criminal's writ?
                        The first sentence of the fifteenth section of the 50th article of the
                        Constitution of Virginia reads as follows: </p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">"The privilege of the writ of habeas corpus hall not, in
                            any case, be suspended."</emph> v</p>
                    <p>Is the constitution of Virginia to be trampled in the dust? Shall the
                        Juggernaut of military power crush beneath its ponderous wheels all
                        individual and personal rights?</p>
                    <p>The 13th section of the "Virginia Bill of rights" says, "<emph rend="italic"
                            >that in all cases the military should be under strict subordination to
                            and governed by the civil power."</emph></p>
                    <p>We have been under the impresion [sic] that we have been expending our
                        treasure and spilling the life's blood of thousands of our best citizens to
                        preserve the inestimable boon of liberty, and have been so unsophisticated
                        as to believe that the way to preserve the liberties of all is to preserve
                        intact the right of each individual. There can be no liberty for the country
                        when individual personal rights are disregarded and trampled in the dust.
                        Our motto is "Liberty and Independence," and not simply independence; for
                        independence without liberty is not worth the price we are paying.</p>
                    <p>Deprive our people of liberty and they will no longer have an incentive to
                        exertion.</p>
                    <p>Their energies will be relaxed, and their patriotism will whither as flowers
                        beneath the Simoom's breath.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Opposes suggestions that the writ of habeas corpus be suspended. Explains
                    that the South cannot fight for liberty while eliminating the individual
                    liberties of its citizens.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>An Important Question</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>By the recent legislation of Virginia all distillation of Whiskey, upon any
                        pretext whatever, is forbidden in the Commonwealth. The law expressly
                        provides that no whiskey shall be distilled, in fulfilment [sic] of any
                        contract with the Confederate States.</p>
                    <p>It furthermore makes it the duty of the Judge of the circuit, when he shall
                        be informed of any violation of the law, to call a special term of his court
                        and to empannel [sic] a special grand jury to investigate the matter.</p>
                    <p>At the last form of the county court, measures were taken to inform the Judge
                        of this circuit of a violation of the law in this county, and we learn he
                        has called a special term of his court for the 2nd of Feb. to investigate
                        the case.</p>
                    <p>If this be the case, it will present a very important question in regard to
                        the relative powers of the State and Confederate authorities. It will bring
                        up the question of State sovereignty. We will then learn whether the
                        Commonwealth of Virginia has a right to regulate her own domestic police, or
                        whether she is, according to Mr. Seward's notion, a mere municipal
                        corporation subject to the paramount authority of the Confederate
                        Government.</p>
                    <p>The theory of our system is, that the States are the principals and the
                        Confederate Government their agency. Is the agent subordinate to, or does it
                        over-ride, the principals?</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>States that the recent ban on distilling whiskey in Virginia has raised
                    questions about the relationship of state and national authority in the
                    Confederacy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Presentation of a Flag</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The enemy will never get that flag, if it be within the power of the brave
                    soldiers who march beneath its folds to prevent it."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>HEAD Q'RS 52d VA. INFANTRY, <lb/>Dec. 31, 1863.</p>
                    <p>COL. GEO. W. MUNFORD, <emph rend="italic">Secretary of the Commonwealth of
                            Va:</emph></p>
                    <p>Colonel: By the hands of Adjutant William Galt, I return to the custody of
                        the Commonwealth, to be laid up among her treasures, the tattered remnant of
                        a flag, which was during last year, presented to the 52d Virginia Infantry,
                        by his Excellency, the Governor. It has floated over the Regiment on the
                        fields of Cedar Run, 2d Manassas, Sharpsburg, 1st Fredericksburg, 2nd
                        Fredericksburg, and Gettysburg. Under its folds many a brave son of Virginia
                        has fallen in maintenance of the Confederate cause, and, on the bloody field
                        of Sharpsburg "the last enemy, Death," arrested it from the hands of a
                        gallant bearer, * who, while living, was ever prompt to carry it defiantly
                        in the face of his country's foes.</p>
                    <p>Let it then be cherished as a memorial of the honorable services of the men,
                        who, amid fiery trials, have never faltered beneath it; and be pleased, sir,
                        to send in its stead, as you have kindly promised to do, another, upon whose
                        folds, yet unbaptised in blood, and untarnished by the smoke of battle, may
                        be read, with fresh inspiration, the just doom of tyrants, and Virginia's
                        everlasting resolve of resistance to oppression.</p>
                    <p>I am sure I but utter the heartfelt wishes of my countrymen, when I pray
                        that, in the coming year, and ere the new flag can have lost its freshness,
                        it may please God to vouchsafe to our bleeding country the balm of peace,
                        and the blessings of Independence.</p>
                    <p>Very Respectfully, <lb/>Your obedient servant, <lb/>JAMES H. SKINNER,
                        <lb/>Col. Comd'g 52d Va. Infantry. </p>
                    <p>* The color-sergeant, Charles Bush, a native of Henrico county, fell mortally
                        wounded, and in his last moments bequeathed the undrawn balance of his pay
                        to purchase a flag for his regiment.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Calls attention to the presentation of a new flag to the 52nd Virginia
                    Regiment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Exemption from Impressment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kayser</ln>
                        <fn>W. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wheat</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Explains that anyone with extra corn they do not want impressed should sell
                    their harvest to J. W. Crawford, W. B. Kayser, and Rev. J. C. Wheat, who have
                    formed a committee to sell these goods to the soldiers' families.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Subjugation Impossible</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that a New York Times writer has pronounced the subjugation of the
                    South impossible, owing to the unity and determination of the Southern people.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Socks for Soldiers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cowan</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Asks readers to donate woolen cloth for the production of socks and other
                    items for the suffering soldiers of the 25th Regiment. Explains that the
                    donations should be sent to the Staunton bookstore of Mr. R. Cowan.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Whiskey Accounted For</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Condemns dishonest distillers of whiskey, who are impressing grain and then
                    selling the product in the general market in Richmond.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Currency Bill</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that a bill being considered by the Confederate Congress would reduce
                    redundant currency by increasing taxes on personal property.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>President Davis and the Pope</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on correspondence between President Davis and Pope Pius IX, in
                    which Davis assures the Pope that the Confederacy is striving for peace.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Funeral Notice</head>
                <origin>Richmond Whig</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Publishes a notice mimicking an obituary that mourns the death of "Habeas
                    Corpus."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Rival Administrations</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces the publication of a two-volume history of the war, "The Rival
                    Administrations," by Mr. E. A. Pollard.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Porcelain and Earthenware</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that the Confederate Congress passed an act incorporating a company
                    to produce porcelain and earthenware in Augusta County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Northern News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on recent political developments in the North, including the
                    introduction of a bill in Congress that would put all free black men between 16
                    and 60 into military service.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>In For the War</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Suggests that most soldiers ending their three-year volunteer enlistment
                    will reenlist and points to the reenlistment of an entire Georgia brigade as
                    evidence.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>General Lee's Pardon</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"His reason for doing so was to encourage the wives of all soldiers to act
                    as the wife of this man had done. . . . Let other wives take note."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that General Lee pardoned a deserter for the sake of his wife, who
                    had turned him in to Confederate authorities.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Crisis</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Compares the people of the Confederacy to the Israelites.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Longstreet Advancing</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on General Longstreet's successful defense against the Yankee
                    troops that attacked his quarters near Morristown.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Chaplain</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lackey</ln>
                        <fn>Harvey</fn>
                        <sf>Color-Sergeant</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Galt</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>James H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Colonel</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Tells about the ceremonies surrounding the presentation of a new Virginia
                    flag to the 52nd Virginia Regiment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Presentation of a New Flag to the 52nd VA. Regiment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>James H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Prints correspondence between Colonel James H. Skinner, 52nd Virginia
                    Regiment, and George W. Munford, Secretary of the Commonwealth, in which Skinner
                    presents the tattered remains of a Virginia flag in return for a new one.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Address of Colonel James H. Skinner to the Soldiers of the 52d Va. Regiment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The flag of our Confederacy may, and does claim, and is entitled to, your
                    cordial attachment, but your heart's best devotion is due to this, the symbol of
                    your State's sovereignty."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Publishes transcription of speech given by Col. James H. Skinner during the
                    flag ceremonies of the 52nd Virginia Regiment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"They were large, thick, warm socks, and were appreciated by many of the
                    men as only those can appreciate them who are destitute of this article of
                    clothing, and who have not seen their homes since the war commenced, and do not
                    expect to see them until it is ended."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>R. D. Lilley, Lieut. Col. 25th, Va. Regt.</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>Alex</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cowan</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wayt</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On behalf of the 25th Virginia Regiment, author thanks Mrs. Robert Cowan,
                    Mrs. Wayt, and Mrs. Alex. Taylor of Staunton for the socks they donated to the
                    soldiers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Jno. C. Higginbotham, Col. Com'd'g. 25th Va. Infty.</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Thanks the ladies who comprise the Soldiers Aid Society at Zion's Church
                    for donating clothing and other provisions to the 25th Virginia Regiment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>J. Woodbridge Bosworth, 1st Lieut. Comdg. Co. H, 31st Va. Reg., and J.
                    French Harding, Capt. Co. F, 31st Va. Reg.</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Withrow</ln>
                        <fn>Annie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Withrow</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Thanks the women of the soldiers aid societies of Brownsburg and Newport
                    for donating shoes, socks and other clothing to Companies F and H, 31st Virginia
                    Regiment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>States that the Northern people have grown weary of war and are mistaken to
                    assume that the Confederacy is weak.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Another Capture in Lee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that Confederate forces took 100 Yankees prisoner in Lee County last
                    week.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Wm. H. Gamble</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gamble</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Declines to declare himself a candidate for sheriff.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henkel</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coiner</ln>
                        <fn>Elijah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reid</ln>
                        <fn>Anna E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reid</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On January 13, Rev. S. Henkel married Lieut. Elijah Coiner, Company E, 1st
                    Virginia Cavalry, and Anna E. Reid, daughter of Thomas Reid Esq., of New Market,
                    Shenandoah County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Killian</ln>
                        <fn>George K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Killian</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. C. Beard married Mr. George K. Killian, son of Rev. J. Killian, and
                    Sarah M. Anderson on January 7.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>C. B.</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>Martha</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf>Sr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Martha Hanger, wife of Peter Hanger Sr., died at age 66 on January 6.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Tax In Kind</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>O. Smith, Capt. &amp; Post Quarter Master, 11th Congressional Dist. of
                    Va.</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Asks farmers who have delivered their tithes of wheat or buckwheat to
                    submit their millers' receipts to the quarter master.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>$100 Reward</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>John A. Patterson</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Offers $100 reward for the return of Isaac and Oliver, both 17-year-old
                    slaves of John Patterson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Report of skirmishing in east Tennessee, column 2; classified ads, column
            7</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
